[Whimsical instrumental music]
[Whimsical music continues]
PRINCETON UNIVERSITY - SEPTEMBER 1947
Mathematicians won the war.
Mathematicians broke
the Japanese codes...
...and built the A-bomb.
Mathematicians, like you.
The stated goal of the Soviets
is global Communism.
In medicine or economics...
...in technology or space...
...battle lines are being drawn.
To triumph, we need results...
... publishable, applicable results.
Now who among you
will be the next Morse?
The next Einstein?
Who among you will be
the vanguard of democracy...
... freedom, and discovery?
Today, we bequeath America's future
into your able hands.
Welcome to Princeton, gentlemen.
MAN 1: It's not enough Hansen won
the Carnegie Scholarship.
MAN 2: No, he wants it all for himself.
It's the first time the Carnegie Prize
has been split. Hansen's all bent.
MAN 1: He has his sights set on
Wheeler Lab, MIT's military think-tank.
They're only taking one this year.
MAN 2: Hansen's used to
being picked first.
MAN 1: Yeah, he's wasted on math.
MAN 2: He should be running for president.
There could be a mathematical explanation
for how bad your tie is.
[Laughs]
NEILSON: Thank you.
Neilson, symbol cryptography.
Neils here broke a Jap code.
Helped rid the world of Fascism.
At least that's what he tells the girls,
eh, Neils?
The name's Bender. Atomic physics.
NEILSON: And you are?
SOL: Am I late?
BENDER: Yes, Mr. Sol.
SOL: Oh, good. Hi.
SOL: Sol. Richard Sol.
MARTIN: The burden of genius.
- There he is.
- So many supplicants, and so little time.
- Mr. Sol.
- How are you, sir?
MARTIN: Bender.
BENDER: Nice to see you.
BENDER: Congratulations, Mr. Hansen.
MARTIN: Thank you.
I'll take another.
Excuse me?
MARTIN: Pardon me.
I assumed you were the waiter.
BENDER: Play nice.
SOL: Nice is not Hansen's strong suit.
MARTIN: Honest mistake.
Well, Martin Hansen.
It is Martin, isn't it?
Why, yes, John, it is.
I imagine you're getting
quite used to miscalculation.
I've read your preprints...
...both of them.
The one on Nazi ciphers...
...and the other one
on nonlinear equations...
...and I am supremely confident
that there is not a single seminal...
...or innovative idea in either one of them.
Enjoy your punch.
[Snickers]
Gentlemen, meet John Nash...
... the mysterious West Virginia genius.
The other winner
of the distinguished Carnegie Scholarship.
BENDER: Okay.
SOL: Yeah?
BENDER: Of course.
[Choral music plays on record-player]
CHARLES: [Coughs] Oh, Christ.
The prodigal roommate arrives.
Roommate?
Oh, God, no.
[Music slows to a stop]
CHARLES: Did you know that
having a hangover...
...is not having enough water
in your body...
...to run your Krebs cycle?
Which is exactly what happens to you
when you're dying of thirst.
So, dying of thirst...
...would probably feel...
... pretty much like the hangover
that finally bloody kills you.
John Nash?
Hello.
Charles Herman.
Pleased to meet you.
PLAYER: [Outside] All right! Well done!
CHARLES: Well, it's official.
I'm almost human again.
Officer, I saw the driver who hit me.
His name was Johnny Walker.
Whew.
CHARLES: Well, I got in last night
in time for...
...English department cocktails.
Cock was mine...
...the tail belonged to a particularly
lovely young thing with a passion for...
...D.H. Lawrence.
You're not easily distracted, are you?
- I'm here to work.
- Are you? Right.
I see. Crikey!
Is my roommate a dick?
Hmm?
Listen.
If we can't break the ice...
...how about we drown it?
CHARLES: So what's your story?
You the poor kid that never got to go
to Exeter or Andover?
Despite my privileged upbringing,
I'm well-balanced.
I have a chip on both shoulders.
[Chuckles]
Maybe you're just better with
the old integers than you are with people.
JOHN: My first grade teacher said
I was born with two helpings of brain...
...but only half a helping of heart.
[Chuckles]
CHARLES: Wow! She sounds lovely!
The truth is that I...
I don't like people much.
And they don't much like me.
But why,
with all your obvious wit and charm?
[Laughs]
Seriously, John.
Mathematics...
Mathematics is never going to lead you
to a higher truth.
And you know why?
Because it's boring. It's really boring.
You know, half these schoolboys
are already published?
I cannot waste time
with these classes and...
... these books.
[Coughs]
Memorizing the weaker assumptions
of lesser mortals!
[Chuckles]
I need to look through...
...to the governing dynamics.
Find a truly original idea.
That's the only way
I'll ever distinguish myself.
- It's the only way that I'll ever...
- Matter.
Yes.
MARTIN: All right, who's next?
SOL: I've played enough go for today.
- Come on.
- I hate this game.
Cowards, all of you!
None of you rise to meet my challenge?
Come on, Bender. Whoever wins,
Sol does his laundry all semester.
- Does that seem unfair to anyone else?
- Not at all.
MARTIN: Look at him.
BENDER: Nash!
Taking a reverse constitutional?
I'm hoping to extract an algorithm
to define their movement.
Oh.
Psycho.
SOL: I thought you dropped out.
You ever going to go to class or...
Classes will dull your mind.
Destroy the potential
for authentic creativity.
Oh, I didn't know that.
Nash is going to stun us all
with his genius.
Which is another way of saying
he doesn't have the nerve to compete.
You scared?
Terrified. Mortified. Petrified.
Stupefied by you.
No starch.
Pressed and folded.
Let me ask you something, John.
Be my guest, Martin.
Bender and Sol here correctly completed
Allen's proof of Perron's conjectures.
JOHN: Adequate work...
...without innovation.
- I'm flattered. You flattered?
- Flattered.
MARTIN: And I've got two weapons briefs
under security review by the DOD.
Derivative drivel.
But Nash achievements: zero.
I'm a patient man, Martin.
Is there an actual question coming?
What if you never come up
with your original idea?
MARTIN: How will it feel
when I'm chosen for Wheeler...
...and you're not?
What if you lose?
You should not have won.
Hmm.
I had the first move, my play was perfect.
The hubris of the defeated.
The game is flawed.
MARTIN: Gentlemen, the great John Nash.
CHARLES: You've been in here
for two days.
You know Hansen
has just published another paper?
I can't even find a topic for my doctorate.
Well, on the bright side,
you've invented window art.
This is a group playing touch football.
This is a cluster of pigeons
fighting over breadcrumbs.
And this is a woman who is chasing a man
who stole her purse.
John, you watched a mugging.
That's weird.
In competitive behavior,
someone always loses.
Well, my niece knows that, John,
and she's about this high.
See, if I could derive an equilibrium...
...where prevalence is
a non-singular event...
...where nobody loses.
Imagine the effect that would have
on conflict scenarios...
When did you last eat?
- When did you last eat?
- Currency exchange?
You know, food.
You have no respect for cognitive reverie,
you know?
Yes. But pizza...
Now, pizza I have enormous respect for.
And, of course, beer.
I have respect for beer.
I have respect for beer!
[Indistinct chatter and laughter]
BENDER: Good evening, Neils.
MARTIN: Hey, Nash.
Who's winning? You or you?
BENDER: Good evening, Nash.
SOL: Hey, guys. Hey, Nash.
WOMAN: He's looking at you for sure.
Hey, Nash.
Neils is trying to get your attention.
BENDER: You're joking.
SOL: Oh, no.
- Go with God.
- Come back a man.
- Fortune favors the brave.
- Bombs away.
Gentlemen, might I remind you
that my odds of success...
...dramatically improve with each attempt?
This is going to be classic.
Maybe you want to buy me a drink.
I don't know what I'm required to say...
...in order for you
to have intercourse with me...
...but could we assume
that I've said all that?
Essentially we're talking about
fluid exchange, right?
So, could we just go straight to the sex?
Oh, that was sweet.
WOMAN: Have a nice night, asshole!
NEILSON: Ladies, wait!
CHARLES: I especially liked the bit
about fluid exchange. It was...
...really charming.
PROFESSOR: Walk with me, John.
I've been meaning to talk with you.
The faculty is completing mid-year reviews.
We're deciding
which placement applications to support.
Wheeler, sir.
That would be my first choice.
JOHN: Actually, I don't really have
a second choice, sir.
Your fellows have attended classes.
They've written papers. They've published.
I'm still searching, sir, for my...
- Your original idea.
- Governing dynamics, sir.
It's very clever, John, but I'm afraid
it's just not nearly good enough.
- May I?
- Thank you.
I'm working on manifold embedding.
My bargaining stratagems
show some promise.
If you could just arrange another meeting
with Professor Einstein.
I've repeatedly asked you for that.
I'd be able to show him
my revisions on his...
John.
Do you see what they're doing there?
PROFESSOR 2:
Congratulations, Professor Max.
MAX: Thank you, sir. Thank you.
It's the pens.
Reserved for a member of the department
that makes the achievement of a lifetime.
Now what do you see, John?
Recognition.
Well done, Professor.
Well, try seeing accomplishment.
Is there a difference?
You haven't focused.
I'm sorry, but up to this point, your record
doesn't warrant any placement at all.
Good day.
PROFESSOR:
And my compliments to you, sir.
MAX: Thank you so much.
[Poignant instrumental music]
JOHN: I can't see it.
[Whimpers]
CHARLES: Jesus Christ, John.
I can't fail.
JOHN: This is all I am.
CHARLES: Come on, let's go out.
- I have to get something done.
- John!
- I can't keep staring into space.
- John, enough!
JOHN: Got to face the wall,
follow their rules, read their books...
...do their classes.
Come on! Go on, bust your head!
Kill yourself.
CHARLES: Don't do it. Don't mess around.
Bust your head! Go on,
bust that worthless head wide open.
JOHN: Goddamn it, Charles!
What the hell is your problem?
It's not my problem.
And it's not your problem.
It's their problem.
CHARLES: Your answer isn't,
"face the wall."
It's out there...
... where you've been working.
[John gasps]
That was heavy.
That Isaac Newton fellow was right.
- He was onto something.
- Clever boy.
[Giggles]
JOHN: Don't worry, that's mine.
I'll come and get it in a minute.
CHARLES: [Laughing] Oh, God.
NEILSON: Incoming, gentlemen.
SOL: Ay-yi-yi.
Deep breaths.
SOL: Nash, you might want to stop
shuffling your papers for five seconds.
I will not buy you gentlemen beer.
BENDER: We're not here for beer,
my friend.
JOHN: Oh.
Does anyone else feel
she should be moving in slow motion?
Will she want a large wedding, you think?
Shall we say swords? Pistols at dawn?
Have you remembered nothing?
Recall the lessons of Adam Smith...
...the father of modern economics.
"In competition...
SOLINEILSON: "...individual ambition
serves the common good."
Every man for himself, gentlemen.
BENDER: Those who strike out
are stuck with her friends.
MARTIN: I'm not going to strike out.
SOL: You can lead a blonde to water,
but you can't make her drink.
SOL: Nobody move.
She's looking over here.
She's looking at Nash.
MARTIN: Oh, God.
He may have the upper hand now...
... but wait until he opens his mouth.
Remember the last time?
BENDER: That was one
for the history books.
- Adam Smith needs revision.
- What are you talking about?
If we all go for the blonde...
... we block each other.
Not a single one of us is going to get her.
So then we go for her friends...
... but they will all give us the cold shoulder
because nobody likes to be second choice.
Well, what if no one goes for the blonde?
We don't get in each other's way...
... and we don't insult the other girls.
That's the only way we win.
That's the only way we all get laid.
[Chuckles]
Adam Smith said:
"The best result comes...
"...from everyone in the group
doing what's best for himself."
Right. Incomplete. Okay?
Because the best result will come...
...from everyone in the group...
...doing what's best for himself...
...and the group.
If this is some way for you
to get the blonde, go to hell.
Governing dynamics. Adam Smith...
...was wrong.
SOL: Here we go.
NEILSON: Careful, careful.
Thank you.
"C" of "S" equals "C" of "T."
[Indistinct muttering]
[Muttering continues]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
You do realize this flies in the face
of 150 years of economic theory?
Yes, I do, sir.
- That's rather presumptuous, no?
- It is, sir.
Well, Mr. Nash...
... with a breakthrough of this magnitude...
... I'm confident you will get
any placement you like.
Wheeler Labs...
... they'll ask you to recommend
two team members.
PROFESSOR: Stills and Frank
are excellent choices.
Sol and Bender, sir.
Sol and Bender
are extraordinary mathematicians.
Has it occurred to you that Sol and Bender
might have plans of their own?
BENDER: [Laughing] We made it!
Wheeler, we made it!
Cheers, cheers, cheers!
Okay, awkward moment, gentlemen.
Umm...
Governing dynamics.
MARTIN: Congratulations, John.
BENDER: Toast! To Wheeler Labs!
SOL: To Wheeler!
THE PENTAGON 1953 - FIVE YEARS LATER
MAN: General, the analyst
from Wheeler Lab is here.
Dr. Nash, your coat?
Thank you, sir.
General, this is Wheeler team leader,
Dr. John Nash.
- Glad you could come, Doctor.
- Hello.
Right this way.
GENERAL: We've been intercepting
radio transmissions from Moscow.
The computer can't detect a pattern,
but I'm sure it's code.
JOHN: Why is that, General?
GENERAL: Ever just know something,
Dr. Nash?
Constantly.
GENERAL: We've developed
several ciphers.
If you'd like to review
our preliminary data?
GENERAL: Doctor?
JOHN: [Voiceover] 6-7-3-7.
0- 3-6...
8- 4-9-4.
9- 1-4-0-3-4.
I need a map.
JOHN: 46-13-08, 67-46-90.
Starkey Corners, Maine.
48-03-01.
91-26-35.
Prairie Portage, Minnesota.
These are latitudes and longitudes.
There are at least 10 others.
They appear to be routing orders
across the border into the U.S.
Extraordinary.
Gentlemen, we need to move on this.
- Who's Big Brother?
- You've done your country a great service.
- Captain!
- Yes, sir.
Accompany Dr. Nash.
What are the Russians moving, General?
Captain Rogers will escort you
to the unrestricted area, Doctor.
Thank you.
ROGERS: Dr. Nash, follow me, please.
[Over radio] None of those
who said they don't like the method...
... have told us any other method
they could use that would be effective.
DRIVER: It's Dr. Nash.
GUARD: All right.
WHEELER DEFENSE LABS
MIT CAMPUS
- Thank you, sir.
- Home run at the Pentagon?
Have they actually taken the word
"classified" out of the dictionary?
Hi. The air conditioning broke again.
How am I supposed to be in here
saving the world if I'm melting?
Our hearts go out to you.
Two trips to the Pentagon in four years.
- That's two more than we've had.
- It gets better.
Just got our latest
scintillating assignment.
You know, the Russians have the H-bomb,
the Nazis are repatriating South America...
...the Chinese have a standing army
of 2.8 million...
...and I am doing stress tests on a dam.
You made the cover of Fortune again.
Please note the use of the word "you,"
not "we."
That was supposed to be just me.
[Chuckles]
Not only do they rob me
of the Fields' Medal...
...they put me on the cover
of Fortune magazine with these hacks...
...these scholars of trivia.
Exactly what's the difference
between genius and most genius?
Quite a lot.
He's your son.
Anyway, you've got 10 minutes.
JOHN: I've always got 10 minutes.
BENDER: Before your new class?
Can I not get a note
from a doctor or something?
You are a doctor, John, and no.
You know the drill,
we get these beautiful facilities...
...MIT gets America's great minds of today,
teaching their great minds of tomorrow.
- Poor bastards.
- Now, have a nice day at school.
The bell is ringing.
[Door opens]
The eager young minds of tomorrow.
[Loud jack-hammering outside]
STUDENT: Can we leave one open,
Professor? It's really hot, sir.
Your comfort comes second
to my ability to hear my own voice.
JOHN: Personally...
... I think this class will be
a waste of your...
... and what is infinitely worse...
...my time.
However, here we are.
So you may attend or not.
You may complete your assignments
at your whim.
We have begun.
Miss.
ALICIA: Excuse me!
FOREMAN: Hey, hey!
ALICIA: Hi!
We have a little problem.
It's extremely hot in here
with the windows closed...
... and extremely noisy with them open.
I was wondering
if there was any way you could...
... I don't know, maybe work
someplace else for about 45 minutes?
FOREMAN: Not a problem.
ALICIA: Thank you so much!
FOREMAN: Break!
WORKER: Got it!
FOREMAN: Let's go. Clean it up a little bit.
As you will find in multivariable calculus,
there is often...
...a number of solutions
for any given problem.
As I was saying, this problem here...
... will take some of you
many months to solve.
For others among you...
...it will take you the term
of your natural lives.
PARCHER: Professor Nash.
William Parcher.
Big Brother...
... at your service.
What can I do
for the Department of Defense?
- Are you here to give me a raise?
- Let's take a walk.
- Impressive work at the Pentagon.
- Yes, it was.
Oppenheimer used to say, "A genius
sees the answer before the question."
You knew Oppenheimer?
His project was under my supervision.
Which project?
JOHN: That project.
PARCHER: It's not that simple.
Well, you ended the war.
We incinerated 150,000 people
in a heartbeat.
Great deeds come at great cost,
Mr. Parcher.
Conviction, it turns out, is a luxury
of those on the sidelines, Mr. Nash.
I'll try and keep that in mind.
PARCHER: So, John, no family...
... no close friends.
PARCHER: Why is that?
JOHN: I like to think it's because I'm a Ione wolf.
But mainly it's because
people don't like me.
[Chuckles]
There are certain endeavors...
...where your lack of personal connection
would be considered an advantage.
JOHN: This is a secure area.
PARCHER: They know me.
PARCHER: Have you ever been here?
JOHN: We were told in our initial briefing
these warehouses were abandoned.
PARCHER: That's not precisely accurate.
[Low radio chatter]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Radio transmits Russian speaker]
PARCHER: By telling you this...
... I am increasing your security clearance
to top secret.
Disclosure of secure information
can result in imprisonment.
Get it?
What operation?
Those are a good idea.
PARCHER: This factory is in Berlin,
we seized it at the end of the war.
Nazi engineers were attempting to build
a portable atomic bomb.
The Soviets reached this facility
before we did, and we lost the damn thing.
The routing orders at the Pentagon.
They were about this, weren't they?
The Soviets aren't as unified
as people believe.
PARCHER: A faction of the Red Army
calling itself Novaya Svoboda...
...the "New Freedom,"
has control of the bomb...
...and intends to detonate it on U.S. soil.
Their plan is to incur
maximum civilian casualties.
PARCHER: Man is capable of as much atrocity
as he has imagination.
New Freedom has sleeper agents
here in the U.S.
McCarthy is an idiot, but, unfortunately,
that doesn't make him wrong.
New Freedom communicates
to its agents...
...through codes imbedded in newspapers
and magazines...
...and that's where you come in.
You see, John, what distinguishes you...
...is that you are, quite simply...
...the best natural code-breaker
I have ever seen.
What exactly is it
that you would like me to do?
Commit this list of periodicals to memory.
PARCHER: Scan each new issue,
find any hidden codes, decipher them.
DOCTOR: Place your chin on the chin rest.
DOCTOR: Stare into the light.
TECHNICIAN: Pulse 88, regular.
DOCTOR: Okay, this may be
a little uncomfortable.
[Groans]
PARCHER: It's got a little zap to it,
doesn't it?
He just implanted a radium diode.
Don't worry, it's safe.
The isotope decays predictably.
As a result,
these numbers change over time.
They're the access codes to your drop spot.
So what am I now, a spy?
[Knock at door]
JOHN: Come.
Boy, you must be really important.
It's all right, Mike.
What are you working on?
Classified.
Everyone waited half an hour.
JOHN: For?
ALICIA: Class.
You missed class today.
Oh. I suspect that...
...nobody missed me.
ALICIA: The problem
that you left on the board...
...I solved it.
- No, you didn't.
- You didn't even look.
I never said that the vector fields
were rational functions.
Your solution is elegant.
Though on this particular occasion...
...ultimately incorrect.
- You're still here.
- I'm still here.
Why?
ALICIA: I'm wondering, Professor Nash...
...if I can ask you to dinner.
You do eat, don't you?
On occasion, yeah.
Table for one.
Prometheus alone chained to the rock...
...with the bird circling overhead,
you know how it is.
[Chuckles]
No, I expect that you wouldn't know...
Leave your address with my office.
I'll pick you up Friday...
...at 8:00 and we'll eat.
One more thing. Do you have a name,
or should I just keep calling you "miss"?
JOHN: Governor...
...may I present...
- Miss Alicia Larde.
PHOTOGRAPHER:
Professor, please. You and the governor.
Wait, one second. I'm sorry.
ALICIA: I want a copy of this.
First big date and all, you know.
So, you boys need to look good...
...which is not a state
you find yourselves in altogether naturally.
There. Better.
- I'm surprising him.
- You just keep on surprising him.
Professor.
[Ambient party noises]
God must be a painter.
Why else would we have so many colors?
So you're a painter?
That's not actually what I said...
...but, yes, I am.
ALICIA: Here.
Me.
Your date.
Practice human interaction
and social comportment.
ALICIA: [Laughing] That's a plan.
Champagne would be lovely.
I'll be outside.
I will get the champagne.
ALICIA: Oh, thank you.
Thank you for that.
No, keep it.
I believe in deciding things
will be good luck.
- Do you?
- No.
I don't believe in luck.
But I do believe
in assigning value to things.
Oh.
ALICIA: I once tried to count them all.
I actually made it to 4,348.
You are exceptionally odd.
I bet you're very popular with the girls.
A pair of odd ducks, then.
Mmm.
Pick a shape.
What?
Pick a shape, an animal, anything.
Okay.
An umbrella.
[Poignant instrumental music]
Do it again.
JOHN: All right. What would you like?
ALICIA: Do an octopus.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Dog barks]
[Alicia chuckles]
ALICIA: You don't talk much, do you?
JOHN: I can't talk to you
about my work, Alicia.
I don't mean work.
I find that polishing my interactions...
...in order to make them sociable
requires a tremendous effort.
I have a tendency
to expedite information flow...
...by being direct.
- I often don't get a pleasant result.
- Try me.
All right.
I find you attractive.
Your aggressive moves towards me
indicate that you feel the same way.
But still, ritual requires that we continue
with a number of platonic activities...
...before we have sex.
I am proceeding with those activities...
...but in point of actual fact...
...all I really want to do is have intercourse
with you as soon as possible.
Are you going to slap me now?
How was that result?
MARCEE: What are you doing?
Trying to isolate patterned reoccurrences
within periodicals over time.
And you?
You talk funny, Mr. Nash.
Do I know you?
My uncle says you're very smart
but not very nice...
...so I shouldn't pay no mind
if you're mean to me.
And who might your uncle be?
CHARLES: The prodigal roommate...
...returns.
[Chuckles]
JOHN: Come here, Charles.
My sister got herself killed in a car crash.
Not too far now, Marcee!
Her cowboy husband was too drunk
to know that he was too drunk to drive.
So, I took her in.
- She's so small.
- She's young. That's how they come.
I'm at Harvard...
...doing the great author's workshop.
D.H. bloody Lawrence.
I really do think
you should buy yourself a new book.
[Chuckles]
CHARLES: Well, I've been reading
a lot about you.
How are you, John?
At first, all my work here was trivial...
...but a new assignment came up and...
I can't really tell you any details.
Top secret? Black bag? Black ops?
Something like that.
- And...
- Yes?
Well, I met a girl.
- No! A human girl?
- Homo sapien.
- A biped?
- Yep. And contrary to all probabilities...
...she finds me attractive
on a number of different levels.
God, that's wonderful.
There's no accounting for taste, is there?
- Should I marry her?
- Oh, God. Right.
I mean, everything's going well.
The job is fine. I have enough money.
It all seems to add up.
But how do you know for sure?
Nothing's ever for sure, John.
That's the only sure thing I do know.
WAITER: Good evening.
JOHN: Alicia, please don't be angry.
I just lost track of time at work...
JOHN: . . Again.
ALICIA: Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry.
I didn't have time to wrap it.
Happy birthday.
JOHN: The refractive faces of the glass
create a full wavelength dispersal...
... so if you look inside, you can see...
ALICIA: Every possible color.
JOHN: Every possible color.
Yeah.
Remember you said that time, God must
be a painter because of all the colors?
At the governor's house you said that.
I didn't think you were listening.
I was listening.
It's beautiful.
[Both chuckle]
Alicia, does our relationship
warrant long-term commitment?
Because I need some kind of proof,
some kind of verifiable, empirical data.
[Nervous laughter]
I'm sorry, just give me a moment...
...to redefine my girlish notions
of romance.
A proof?
Verifiable data.
Okay.
Well, how big is the universe?
Infinite.
ALICIA: How do you know?
- Because all the data indicates it.
- But it hasn't been proven yet?
You haven't seen it.
How do you know for sure?
I don't, I just believe it.
It's the same with love, I guess.
Now...
...the part that you don't know...
...is if I want to marry you.
[Indistinct chatter and laughter]
[Applause]
Smile for the camera!
Well done!
Congratulations.
WOMAN: You look beautiful.
SOL: Hi, how are you?
WOMAN: Bye-bye.
MAN: 'Bye, now.
Be safe!
[Gate opens]
CAMBRIDGE, MA - OCTOBER 1954
Get in. Hurry.
They're following us.
- Who is following us?
- The drop has been compromised.
PARCHER: Get down!
Stay down.
[Horns honking]
[Tires screeching]
[Gunfire]
PARCHER: Take this.
JOHN: I ain't shooting anybody.
- Take the goddamn gun!
- No!
[Screams]
PARCHER: You stay back. Don't move.
[Tires screech]
ALICIA: John?
Hi.
Where were you?
JOHN: Sol...
ALICIA: Yeah, I talked to Sol.
He said you left the office hours ago.
Why didn't you call me?
Are you all right?
ALICIA: Honey?
[Bolt locks]
ALICIA: John...
...please, talk to me.
Tell me what happened.
John, open the door.
Come on, open the door! Let me in!
Talk to me!
John!
ALICIA: [Shouts] Open this door!
[Panting]
WOMAN: Watch for cars, kids.
[Door bangs shut]
PARCHER: John.
William.
This is not what I signed up for.
Every time a car backfires or a door slams...
I understand better
than you could possibly imagine.
You need to calm down, John.
PARCHER: Now listen.
We're closing in on the bomb...
... in large part due to your work.
Now don't you think your fear
is a small price to pay?
William, my circumstance has changed.
Alicia's pregnant.
I told you attachments were dangerous.
You chose to marry the girl.
I did nothing to prevent it.
The best way to ensure
everybody's safety...
...is for you to continue your work.
Well, I'll just quit.
You won't.
Why would I not?
Because I keep the Russians
from knowing you work for us.
You quit working for me...
...I quit working for you.
Parcher!
SOL: John, you all right?
ALICIA: John?
JOHN: [Angrily]
Turn it off! Turn off the light!
Why would you do that?
- Why would you turn the light on?
- What is wrong with you?
You have to go to your sister's.
JOHN: I left the car out in back.
Take Commonwealth, no side streets.
Stay where it's crowded.
ALICIA: John, I'm not going anywhere!
JOHN: When you get to your sister's,
wait for my call.
- Get your things.
- I'm not leaving!
Stop! Stop it!
JOHN: Please, Alicia.
I'll explain when I can.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
HARVARD UNIVERSITY
NATIONAL MATHEMATICS CONFERENCE
MARCEE: Uncle John!
Uncle John!
[Roars]
Hey, baby girl! [Marcee giggles]
Wow, someone needed a hug!
I saw you on the slate,
and I thought to myself:
"How can I miss seeing a guest lecture
by the inimitable John Nash?"
CHARLES: What's wrong?
I got myself into something.
I think I might need some help.
Now you tell me, what is it?
WOMAN: Professor Nash!
Welcome!
After?
JOHN: So, we see that the zeroes
of the Riemann Zeta function...
...correspond to singularities...
... in space-time...
Singularities in space-time then...
And conventional number theory...
It breaks down
in the face of relativistic exploration.
[Ominous instrumental music]
Sometimes our expectations
are betrayed by the numbers.
Variables are impossible
to assign any rational value.
MAN: Professor Nash!
MAN: Hold it!
ROSEN: Professor Nash?
ROSEN: Professor Nash,
let's avoid a scene, shall we?
What do you want?
My name is Rosen.
Dr. Rosen. I'm a psychiatrist.
Forgive me if I don't seem persuaded.
ROSEN: I'd like you
to come with me, John.
Just for a chat.
It appears I have no choice.
[Rosen groans]
Help me! Somebody!
JOHN: [Screams] Somebody!
Help me! Get off me!
I know who you are!
MAN: No, no, don't!
Charles, they're Russians!
They're Russians!
Call somebody! Call somebody!
JOHN: They're Russians!
ROSEN: Steady the leg.
Get away from me.
JOHN: Stay away from me!
ROSEN: There, now.
All better.
ROSEN: Everything's all right here.
Watch your head.
ROSEN: [Faintly] John?
Can you hear me?
Go easy now.
Thorazine takes a little while to wear off.
Sorry about the restraints.
You've got one hell of a right hook.
JOHN: [Weakly] Where am I?
[Clears his throat]
MacArthur Psychiatric Hospital.
I find that highly unlikely.
JOHN: You made a mistake.
My work is non-military in application.
Which work is that, John?
I don't know anything.
There's no good in keeping secrets,
you know.
[Groans]
[Buzzer]
Charles?
JOHN: Charles?
I didn't mean to get you involved in this.
JOHN: I'm sorry.
Charles?
The prodigal roommate revealed.
"Saw my name on the lecture slate"?
You lying son of a bitch!
Who are you talking to?
Tell me who you see.
How do you say
"Charles Herman" in Russian?
How do you say it in Russian?
ROSEN: There's no one there, John.
There's no one there.
He's right there. He's right there.
JOHN: Stop! I don't know anything!
Stop! I don't know anything!
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held against my will.
Somebody call the Department of Defense.
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held against my will!
ALICIA: What's wrong with him?
John has schizophrenia.
People with this disorder
are often paranoid.
But his work.
He deals with conspiracy.
Yes, I know.
ROSEN: In John's world,
these behaviors are accepted...
...encouraged.
As such,
his illness may have gone untreated...
...far longer than is typical.
What do you mean? How long?
Possibly since graduate school.
At least that's when his hallucinations
seem to have begun.
What are you talking about?
What hallucinations?
One, so far, that I am aware of.
An imaginary roommate
named Charles Herman.
Charles isn't imaginary.
They have been best friends
since Princeton.
Have you ever met Charles?
Has he ever come to dinner?
He's always in town
for so little time, lecturing.
- Was he at your wedding?
- He had to teach.
Have you seen a picture,
or talked to him on the phone?
This is ridiculous.
I phoned Princeton.
According to their housing records,
John lived alone.
Now, which is more likely?
That your husband...
...a mathematician
with no military training...
...is a spy fleeing the Russians...
- You're making him sound crazy.
Or, that he has lost his grip on reality?
The only way I can help him,
is to show him the difference...
...between what is real
and what is in his mind.
Come on.
What's he been working on?
His work is classified.
He mentioned a supervisor...
...by the name of William Parcher.
Maybe Mr. Parcher
can clarify things for us.
But I can't get to him without clearances.
You want me to help you get the details
of my husband's work?
John thinks I'm a Russian spy.
Is that what you think?
- What did the doctor say?
- Is he sick?
I don't know.
I want to see
what John's been working on.
- You can't go in his office.
- It's classified, Alicia.
Stop.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Oh, my God.
Why didn't you say something?
Alicia, John has always been...
...a little weird.
He said he was doing code-breaking.
- It was eyes-only.
- Top-secret, part of the military effort.
Was he?
It was possible.
Directives come down all the time
that some aren't cleared for.
- It was possible.
- Possible, but not likely.
Lately, he'd become much more agitated,
and then when you called...
So, is this all he's been doing every day?
Cutting up magazines?
Well, not all.
[Dramatic instrumental music continues]
[Door opens]
ALICIA: [Sobs] I'm so sorry.
JOHN: It's okay.
I missed you.
I have to talk to you.
ALICIA: Okay.
Alicia, I've been thinking about it...
...and I do realize that my behavior...
...and my inability
to discuss the situation with you...
...must have appeared insane.
I left you with no other choice.
I do understand...
...and I'm truly sorry.
- That's okay.
Everything will be all right.
[Whispers] We just have to talk quietly.
They may be listening.
There may be microphones.
I'll tell you everything now.
It's breaking with protocol,
but you need to know...
...because you have to help me
get out of here.
I've been doing top-secret work
for the government.
There's a threat that exists...
...of catastrophic proportions.
I think the Russians
feel my profile is too high.
That's why they won't do away with me.
They're keeping me here
to try to stop me from doing my work.
You have to get to Wheeler.
JOHN: You have to find William Parcher.
ALICIA: Stop.
Stop!
I went to Wheeler.
Good, good.
There is no William Parcher.
Of course there is.
I've been working for him.
ALICIA: Doing what? Breaking codes?
Dropping packages in a secret mailbox
for the government to pick up?
How could you know that?
Sol followed you.
ALICIA: He thought it was harmless.
JOHN: Sol followed me?
ALICIA: They've never been opened.
It isn't real.
There is no conspiracy, John.
There is no William Parcher.
It's in your mind.
Do you understand, baby?
You're sick.
You're sick, John.
ALICIA: John?
ALICIA: [Sobs] John!
Code red.
[Over P.A.] Dr. Rosen, code red.
Observation Room 2.
Dr. Rosen, code red. Observation Room 2.
[Door opens]
John?
The implant is gone.
I can't find it.
It's gone.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
ROSEN: You see,
the nightmare of schizophrenia...
... is not knowing what's true.
Imagine...
... if you had suddenly learned
that the people and the places...
... and the moments most important to you
were not gone, not dead...
... but worse, had never been.
What kind of hell would that be?
NURSE 1: Administering insulin.
NURSE 2: 8:42 a.m.
[Dramatic instrumental music continues]
ALICIA: How often?
ROSEN: Five times a week for 10 weeks.
PRINCETON UNIVERSITY - 1 YEAR LATER
ALICIA: John always spoke so fondly
of being here at Princeton.
Hansen is running the department now.
SOL: So he keeps reminding us,
and reminding us.
ALICIA: [Chuckling] Yeah.
John won't come near the campus, though.
I think he's ashamed.
[Baby cries]
ALICIA: Hey. Hey.
Want this?
SOL: So, Alicia, how are you holding up?
The delusions have passed.
They're saying with the medication
and low stress environment...
I mean, how are you?
I think often what I feel...
...is obligation.
Or guilt over wanting to leave.
Rage against John, against God, and...
But...
...then I look at him...
...and I force myself to see the man
that I married.
And he becomes that man.
He's transformed into someone that I love.
And I'm transformed into someone
who loves him.
It's not all the time, but...
...it's enough.
I think John is a very lucky man, Alicia.
So unlucky.
ALICIA: This is us.
SOL: This is it?
ALICIA: It's near where I work.
ALICIA: [Brightly] John?
You have a visitor.
Hi.
ALICIA: [Softly] I hope it's okay.
Hey, chief.
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
I quit, actually.
- Hello.
- Hey, John.
Have you met Harvey?
[Sol stammers in embarrassment]
- There's no...
- Relax, it's okay.
There's no point being nuts
if you can't have a little fun.
SOL: [Laughs nervously] Jesus Christ.
I should have known.
Here you go.
- I can take those later.
- You're supposed to take them now.
- Can I bring you something?
- I'm okay.
ALICIA: Okay.
So, I was in town giving a workshop.
I go back tonight.
Bender really wanted to stop by...
... you know, see you. Say hi.
Squeamish?
Yeah.
I suppose I would be, too.
But, alas, I'm stuck with me.
I'm trying to solve the Riemann hypothesis.
Uh-huh.
Oh, yeah?
JOHN: I figured if I dazzle them...
...they will have to reinstate me.
But it's difficult with the medication...
...because it's hard...
...to see the solution.
[Poignant instrumental music]
SOL: You know, John, you should go easy.
There are other things besides work.
What are they?
[Baby cries]
[Alicia coos maternally]
[Door closes]
What are you thinking about?
What do people do?
It's life, John.
Activities available, just add meaning.
You could try leaving the house.
You know, maybe...
...talk to people.
You could try taking out the garbage.
[Indistinct, muffled voice]
JOHN: [Muffled] And there's some more,
there's some more in...
Who were you talking to?
Garbage man.
Garbage men don't come at night.
I guess around here they do.
[Man whistles]
[Truck approaching]
[John giggles]
Sorry.
ALICIA: Is it the medication?
[Door bangs shut]
[Alicia screams]
ALICIA: [Sobs] I don't know what to do.
[Sobbing continues]
[Car door opens]
ALICIA: My mother's going to
keep the baby a little longer tonight.
I can get three hours of overtime.
[Classical music plays on radio]
I'm going to bed.
- Good night.
[Ominous instrumental music]
[Clattering]
[Gun cocks]
[Second gun cocks]
PARCHER: It's good to see you, John.
It's been a while.
Parcher?
Yes, sir.
You're not real!
Of course I am. Don't be ridiculous.
[Rifles cocking]
I don't think that I would go that way.
PARCHER: It's time for you
to get back to work.
The bomb is in its final position
here in the U.S.
Knowing your situation requires you keep
a low profile, "Mohammed"...
...we've brought the mountain to you.
[Generator whirs]
[Radio signals]
We've narrowed the bomb's location
to somewhere on the eastern seaboard.
But we haven't been able to pinpoint
its exact position.
[Man speaking Russian over radio]
PARCHER: Their codes have grown
increasingly complex.
Look at this, John.
What?
- Dr. Rosen said...
- Rosen! That quack!
"Schizophrenic break from reality," right?
Psychological bullshit!
PARCHER: Look at me, John.
John, look at me.
Do I look like I'm imagined?
Wheeler has no record of you.
Do you think we list our personnel?
PARCHER: I'm sorry you had to
go through all this.
I've gone to a great deal of trouble
to get you back.
I can restore your status at Wheeler.
I can let the world know what you did.
But I need you now, soldier.
I was so scared you weren't real.
Princeton, New Jersey - April 1956
ALICIA: There's a storm coming.
I'm just going to grab the laundry.
JOHN: I'll draw his bath.
It's okay.
Okay.
[Faint radio feedback]
[Indistinct voices over radio]
[Radio feedback and voices continue]
[Baby whimpers]
[Gasps]
[Baby cries]
ALICIA: [Shouts] John!
JOHN: I've almost got it!
Charles, you just watch the baby.
No!
ALICIA: [Sobs] I need a towel.
[Baby cries]
- Charles was watching him. He was okay.
- There is no one here.
There is no one here!
He's been injected with a cloaking serum.
I can see him because of a chemical
that was released into my bloodstream...
...when my implant dissolved.
I couldn't tell you,
it was for your own protection!
JOHN: Alicia!
- No!
- Hello, I need Dr. Rosen's office, please.
PARCHER: You've got to stop her, John.
You leave her out of this.
- Who are you talking to?
- It's not her fault.
PARCHER: She'll compromise us again.
NASH: She won't.
PARCHER: You'll go back to the hospital.
- Answer me!
- Countless people will die.
Alicia, please put the phone down.
- I can't let that happen.
- Yes, hello?
Hi, I need Dr. Rosen. Is he in?
I'm sorry, John.
JOHN: No!
PARCHER: You know what you must do.
ALICIA: Get away from me.
- She's too great a risk.
- Get away!
I didn't mean to hurt you!
Finish her. She knows too much now.
MARCEE: Uncle John?
PARCHER: Take care of her, you pathetic
piece of shit, or I'll take care of you.
CHARLES: Christ, John,
please do what he says.
Move, soldier.
Now.
MARCEE: Uncle John?
CHARLES: John, please!
Now!
JOHN: [Voiceover] Alicia and Charles never
coexist in the same interactive field.
Parcher and Charles...
[Murmuring, confused voices]
Charles and Marcee
cannot coexist with Alicia.
[Voices grow stronger, more insistent]
I understand.
[Engine revs]
[Tires screech, Alicia screams]
She never gets old.
Marcee can't be real. She never gets old.
You see them now?
Yes.
Why did you stop your meds?
Because I couldn't do my work.
I couldn't help with the baby.
I couldn't...
I couldn't respond to my wife.
You think that's better than being crazy?
We'll need to start you on a higher run
of insulin shocks and a new medication.
No.
JOHN: There has to be another way.
ROSEN: Schizophrenia is degenerative.
Some days may be symptom-free,
but over time, you are getting worse.
It's a problem. That's all it is.
It's a problem with no solution.
And that's what I do, I solve problems.
ROSEN: This isn't math.
You can't come up with a formula to
change the way you experience the world.
- All I have to do is apply my mind.
-There's no theorem, no proof.
- You can't reason your way out of this.
- Why not?
Because your mind is where the problem is
in the first place.
I can do this.
I can work it out. All I need is time.
Is that the baby?
The baby is at my mother's, John.
[Marcee hums]
ROSEN: Without treatment, John...
... the fantasies may take over...
...entirely.
ALICIA: You almost ready?
Rosen's waiting outside.
I can't go back to that hospital.
I won't come home.
He said that if you said that...
...he has commitment papers
for me to sign.
Well, maybe you won't sign them.
Maybe you'll just give me some time.
I will try to figure this out.
Whatever you do...
... Rosen is right about one thing.
You shouldn't be here.
I'm not safe anymore.
Would you have hurt me, John?
I don't know.
Maybe you should let Dr. Rosen
drive you to your mother's.
ALICIA: He told me to leave.
[Rosen responds, indistinct]
ALICIA: I understand.
[Car doors close]
[Engine revs]
[Car departs]
[Footsteps approaching]
Rosen said to call if you try and kill me,
or anything.
You want to know what's real?
This.
This is real.
Maybe the part...
...that knows the waking from the dream...
...maybe it isn't here.
Maybe it's here.
I need to believe...
...that something extraordinary is possible.
[Poignant instrumental music]
Princeton University - Two Months Later
[Knock at door]
MARTIN: Come.
Hello, Martin.
Jesus Christ.
No. I...
I don't have that one. My savior complex
takes on a completely different form.
[Nash chuckles]
I heard what happened and...
...I wanted to write,
and I tried you at MacArthur's...
...but you'd left, and I just...
This is Helinger's old office.
Yeah.
Yeah, I stole it from him.
Seems that you won after all, Martin.
They were wrong, John. No one wins.
Please, have a seat.
MARTIN: God, it's so good to see you.
What brings you back to Princeton?
CHARLES: John?
John, I'm sorry, but you have to tell him.
Tell him you're a genius. You're a genius!
Tell him your work is critical.
John, please!
Is there any chance
that you could ignore what I just did?
Of course, what are old friends for?
Is that what we are, Martin? Friends?
John, of course.
Of course. We always have been.
Alicia and I think...
...that fitting in,
being part of a community...
...might do me some good.
That a certain level of attachment,
familiar places, familiar people...
...might help me...
...elbow out...
...these certain delusions that I have.
It's a lot to ask, and now that I'm here...
...I'm quite certain
that you will just say no.
But I was wondering if I could hang around.
[Sighs]
Huh.
Will you be needing an office?
No.
No, I could just work out of the library.
MAN: This guy tries to wander into
the library...
MAN: . . But he has no ID.
MARTIN: Why can't people read memos?
Then he goes totally nuts.
JOHN: [Shouting outside]
You're not real! You're not real.
There's no mission.
Oh, shit. Shit.
JOHN: You're not real! You are not real!
Is this what you are, soldier?
Some useless ghoul?
The local madman?
JOHN: I'm not a soldier.
PARCHER: You'll end up in a cell!
Old, worthless, discarded.
JOHN: There's no mission.
PARCHER: While you rock and drool,
the world will burn to ashes!
You are not real! You are not real!
You're still talking to me, soldier.
JOHN: There's no mission!
I'm not a soldier!
MARTIN: John? John?
John! It's okay.
I just heard what happened, I'm sorry.
- I'm not a soldier.
- John. Hey, Nash.
Nash, hey. You're all right.
Nash, hey.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the great John Nash!
John?
JOHN: You should've seen their faces.
Everybody was just staring at me.
John, you know that stress
triggers the delusions.
I know.
But then, on the way home...
... Charles was there.
Sometimes, I really miss talking to him.
Maybe Rosen's right.
Maybe I have to think about going back
into the hospital again.
ALICIA: No. Come here.
Maybe try again tomorrow.
John, now you can't ignore me forever.
You've been a very good friend to me.
The best.
But I won't talk to you again.
I just can't.
Same goes for you, baby girl.
[Sniffles]
Good-bye.
I was wondering
if I might audit your course.
It's an honor, Professor Nash.
Is something wrong?
This will be my first class.
Good morning...
...eager young minds.
[John mutters]
It's never going to work, John.
You're just humiliating yourself.
It's pathetic!
You are being pathetic.
I'm ashamed of you!
[Snickering]
STUDENT: [Laughing] Oh, man!
ALICIA: Are you coming?
You're going to be late.
- Dad, you've got my book.
- What?
- You've got my book.
- Oh, right.
Thanks.
- Good-bye.
- 'Bye.
See you tonight.
ALICIA: 'Bye, honey.
[Poignant music]
Princeton University - October 1978
Did you just solve Riemann?
Well, what do you think?
TOBY: That's an analog to Frobenius
for noncommutative extensions.
Yes, it is.
JOHN: But it only appears
to work sporadically, so, no.
But...
...I believe I'm making progress.
You're...
You're John Nash, right?
- Toby Kelly.
- Hello.
I've been studying your equilibrium
that you wrote here at Princeton.
To come up with something
totally original, the way you did...
You know, I was young.
I've been developing a theory.
I believe I can prove...
...that Galois extensions
are covering spaces.
That everything is connected.
That it's all part of the same subject.
When was the last time you ate?
- Excuse me?
- You know, food.
Oh, uh...
My wife...
...she loves mayonnaise.
Thank you.
Go on.
The functor...
...is in the two categories.
MARTIN: Alicia!
Alicia!
JOHN: Coming together
at a maximum speed of...
... let us say, 10 miles per hour.
So you have a fly
on the tire of bicycle "B"...
... and the fly,
who can travel at 20 miles an hour...
...leaves the tire of "B"
and flies to the tire of bicycle "A"...
...and backwards and forwards
until the two bikes collide...
...and the poor little fly is squashed.
This is the important thing about
actually focusing in and comprehending...
... the area you're dealing with.
Mathematics is very specific...
...and it is an art form,
no matter what people here will tell you...
...especially people from biology.
Don't listen to those people.
Let me go back to what you were doing.
I might want to steal this...
... write a book and get famous.
I was thinking that I might teach.
A classroom with 50 students
can be daunting for anyone.
John, besides, you're a terrible teacher.
I'm an acquired taste, Martin.
I was hoping there still might be
something I could contribute.
What about the...
Well, you know.
Are they gone?
No, they're not gone.
And maybe they never will be.
But I've gotten used to ignoring them,
and I think they've given up on me.
You think that's what it's like with
all our dreams and our nightmares, Martin?
You've got to keep feeding them
for them to stay alive?
MARTIN: John, they haunt you though.
They're my past, Martin.
Everybody is haunted by their past.
JOHN: Well, good-bye.
MARTIN: John, I'll talk to the department.
Maybe in the spring.
Hey, Nash.
You, uh...
You scared?
Terrified.
Mortified. Petrified.
Stupefied by you.
Now you ought best ring Alicia,
or you'll get me...
- I'll ring her.
...in a lot of trouble.
- Thanks, Professor.
- Good-bye.
- Have a nice day.
Princeton University - March 1994
Papers in hand, Mr. Bayer.
Professor Nash?
- Can you see him?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
- [Giggles] Yes.
Positive? He's within your vision?
[Laughing] Okay. Good.
Forgive me,
I'm just always suspicious of new people.
- See you next week, Professor.
- See you next week.
So now that I know that you're real,
who are you, and what can I do for you?
Professor, my name is Thomas King.
Thomas King?
I'm here to tell you that you're being
considered for the Nobel Prize.
JOHN: Forgive me,
but I'm just a little stunned.
KING: Over the past years, your
equilibrium has become a cornerstone...
...of modern economics.
Suddenly everybody likes that one.
What about my work on other some
such projects like manifold embedding?
The application
of your bargaining problem...
...to FCC bandwidth auctions
or to antitrust cases...
- Antitrust cases?
- Yes.
I never would have considered that.
Have I just reached some level of honesty
that borders on stupidity?
KING: [Laughs] No, you haven't.
JOHN: I wouldn't have thought of that.
Shall we have tea?
I don't go in there.
I usually take my sandwich in the library.
Come on, John. Let's have some tea.
It's a big day.
Most commercially available brands of tea
are not suitable to my palate.
I'm not...
There are some Northern Indian teas
which are dense enough...
I enjoy the flavor that they have.
I have not been in this room...
...for quite some many years.
I wonder what tea they serve.
JOHN: Why, thank you, young lady.
Things have certainly changed around here.
I have a son that age.
Harvard.
JOHN: Hmm.
I would have thought the nominations
for the Nobel Prize would've been secret.
I would have thought you'd only find out
if you won or lost.
That is generally the case, yes,
but these are special circumstances.
The awards are substantial.
They require private funding as such...
...the image of the Nobel is...
I see, you came here
to find out if I was crazy?
Find out if I would screw everything up
if I actually won?
Dance around the podium,
strip naked and squawk like a chicken?
Something like that, yes.
Would I embarrass you?
Yes, it is possible.
You see, I...
I am crazy.
I take the newer medications...
...but I still see things that are not here.
I just choose not to acknowledge them.
Like a diet of the mind,
I choose not to indulge certain appetites.
Like my appetite for patterns.
Perhaps my appetite to imagine
and to dream.
MAN: Professor Nash.
It's good to have you here, John.
Thank you.
- It's an honor, sir.
- Thank you very much.
A privilege, Professor.
Professor.
[Poignant instrumental music]
- Nicely done, John.
- Thank you, Tom.
Thank you.
Thank you, Ed.
That was certainly most unexpected.
[Applause]
Nobel Prize Ceremony - Stockholm, Sweden
December 1994
JOHN: Thank you.
I've always believed in numbers.
In the equations and logics
that lead to reason.
But after a lifetime of such pursuits...
... I ask, what truly is logic?
Who decides reason?
My quest has taken me
through the physical...
... the metaphysical...
... the delusional...
... and back.
And I have made the most important
discovery of my career.
The most important discovery of my life.
It is only in the mysterious equations
of love...
... that any logical reasons can be found.
I'm only here tonight because of you.
You are the reason I am.
You are all my reasons.
Thank you.
JOHN: So nice to have met you.
I'll call for the car, Dad.
- Bye-bye.
- Are you ready to go now?
- Yes, I am.
Yes, indeed, and yes, please.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
What is it? What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
- Come with me, young lady.
- Oh.
JOHN: I have a car outside.
Are you interested in a ride?
ALICIA: Where's it going to?
Nash's theories have influenced
global trade negotiations,
national labor relations and
even breakthroughs in evolutionary biology.
John and Alicia Nash live in Princeton, NJ.
John keeps regular office hours
[Poignant instrumental music]
in the Mathematics Department.
He still walks to campus every day.