[ Bird Chirping ]
[ Insects Buzzing,
Chittering ]
[ Gasps ]
No, no, no.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
I'm lost!
Where's the line?
It just went away.
What do I do?
- Help!
- We'll be stuck here forever!
Do not panic.
Do not panic!
We are trained professionals.
Now, stay calm.
We are going around the leaf.
A-Around the leaf?
I don't think we can do that.
Oh, nonsense. This is nothing
compared to the twig of '93.
- [ Whimpering ]
- That's it. That's it. Good!
You're doing great!
There you go. There you go!
Watch my eyes.
Don't look away.
- And here's the line again.
- Thank you. Thank you, Mr.Soil.
[ Laughing ]
Good job, everybody!
Oh, my.
There's quite a gap, Mr.Soil.
- Shouldn't we tell the queen?
- I don't think we need
to involve the queen in this.
She's got enough on her plate already,
training her daughter.
Oh, yes.
Princess Atta, the poor dear.
Oh, wind's died down.
They'll be here soon.
- Just be confident, dear.
You'll be fine.
- [ Gasps ] There's a gap.
There's a gap in the line.
What are we gonna do?
It's okay, Your Highness. Gaps happen.
We just lost a few inches, that's all.
Oh. Right.
Your Highness, I can't count
when you hover like that.
Oh, of course.
I'm sorry. Go ahead.
- Guys, go shade
someone else for a while.
- [ Pet Chirps ]
Okay, Atta.
Now what do we do?
Ahh-- Oh! Don't tell me.
I know it. What is it?
- We relax.
- [ Chuckles ] Right.
Oh, it'll be fine.
It's the same, year after year.
They come, they eat, they leave.
That's our lot in life.
It's not a lot, but it's our life.
[ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Isn't that right, Aphie?
Oh, you're such a cute little aphid.
[ Rumbling ]
- Ditch Dot!
- Yeah, yeah!
Hey, come back here!
[ Strains, Grunts ]
- Dot!
- Yes, Mother.
What did I tell you
about trying to fly?
Not until my wings grow in.
- Right.
- But Mom--
Dot, you're a young queen ant
and your wings are too little--
I was talking to Mother.
You're not the queen yet, Atta.
Now, Dot,
be nice to your sister.
It's not my fault
she's so stressed out.
[ Sighs ]
I know, I know.
- I'm always acting
like the sky is falling.
- Look out!
- Atta!
- Princess Atta!
- Oh!
- Hey!
- Stop that!
- What do you think you're doing?
- You could have killed
somebody over here.
- [ Gasps ] I'm sorry!
- Oh, it's Flik.
- Oh--
I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry!
- Please forgive me. I'm sorry!
- [ Coughing ]
- [ Screams ] Princess Atta!
- Flik, what are you doing?
Oh, this! This is my new idea
for harvesting grain.
No more picking individual kernels.
You cut down the entire stalk!
- We don't have time for this.
- Exactly! We never have time
to collect food for ourselves.
We spend all summer
harvesting for the offering.
- But my invention will
speed up production.
- Oh, another invention?
Something for you too.
Since you're gonna be queen, you could
use this to oversee production.
- Dr.Flora, if I may.
- This is all very nice, but--
- Just an ordinary blade of grass
and a bead of dew, right?
- Flik, please.
- Wrong! It is, in fact, a telescope.
- [ Both Laugh ]
- It's very clever, Flik, but--
- Hello, Princess! Aren't you
looking lovely this morning!
Not that you would need
a telescope to see that.
Listen! The princess doesn't
have time for this!
You wanna help fill this thing?
Get rid of that machine,
get back in line and pick grain
like everybody else!
- Like everybody else!
- Please, Flik. Just go.
I'm sorry,
I was really just trying--
trying to help.
Harvester. Why, we harvested
the same way ever since I was a pupa.
[ Sighs ]
Where were we?
- The food pile, Your Highness.
- Oh, yes, yes.
Hey, Flik! Wait up!
Oh. Hello, Princess.
You can call me Dot.
Here, you forgot this.
Thanks. You can keep it.
I can make another one.
- I like your inventions.
- Really? Well, you're the first.
- I'm beginning to think
nothing I do works.
- This works.
Great. One success.
[ Sighs ]
- I'm never gonna make a difference.
- Me, neither.
I'm a royal ant and I can't
even fly yet. I'm too little.
- Being little's not such a bad thing.
- Yes, it is.
- No, it's not.
- Is too!
- Is not. Is not! Is not!
- Is too. Is too! Is too!
Oh! A seed.
I need a seed. Ahh--
Ohh!
Ah, here, here.
Pretend-- pretend
that that's a seed.
- It's a rock.
- I know it's a rock.
But let's just pretend for a minute it's
a seed. We'll just use our imaginations.
Now, do you see our tree?
Everything that made
that giant tree...
is already contained
inside this tiny little seed.
All it needs is some time, a little bit
of sunshine and rain, and...
voila!
This rock will be a tree?
Seed to tree. You've gotta
work with me, all right?
You might not feel
like you can do much now,
but that's just because,
well, you're not a tree yet.
You just have to give yourself
some time. You're still a seed.
But it's a rock.
I know it's a rock!
Don't ya think I know a rock
when I see a rock? I've spent
a lot of time around rocks!
You're weird, but I like you.
[ Horn Sounds ]
[ Gasps ] They're here.
- [ Gasping ]
- [ Horn Continues ]
[ Panicked Chattering ]
- They're coming!
- Run!
- Dot! Dot!
- Mom!
- Thank heavens!
- Food to the offering stone.
- [ Whistles ] Everyone, single file.
Food to the offering stone
and into the anthill. Now let's go!
Go, go, go, go!
Come on, keep movin', keep movin'!
Good. [ Panting ]
Okay. That's everyone.
[ Flik ]
Hey!
Hey, wait for me!
Get the food to the offering stone,
then into the anthill.
[ Screams ]
No! No, no, no, no, no!
Oh, oh!
Oh, no.
Princess Atta!
[ Rumbling ]
[ Whimpering ]
They come, they eat, they leave.
Excuse me, pardon me.
Pardon me, excuse me. Coming through.
Sorry. Coming through. Princess Atta,
there's something I need to tell you.
- Not now, Flik. Shh!
- But Your Highness,
it's about the offering!
- [ Rumbling Stops ]
- [ Male Voice ] Hey, what's goin' on?
Yeah, where's the food?
[ All Gasp ]
- What did you do?
- It was an accident?
[ Laughs Maniacally ]
Boo!
[ Laughs ]
- Where's the food?
- [ Whimpering ]
- Hopper.
- [ Gasps ]
So, where is it?
Where's my food?
- I-I-Isn't it up there?
- What?
- The food was in a leaf
sitting on top--
- Excuse me.
Are you sure
it's not up there?
- Are you saying I'm stupid?
- No.
Do I look stupid... to you?
Let's just think about the logic,
shall we? Think about it for a second.
If it was up there,
would I be coming down here,
to your level,
looking for it?
- Uh, I--
- Why am I even talking to you?
You're not the queen.
You don't smell like the queen.
Sh-She's learning
to take over for me, Hopper.
Oh, I see. Under new management.
So it's your fault.
No, it wasn't me, it was--
Uh-uh-uh. First rule of leadership:
Everything is your fault.
- But-But I--
- It's a bug-eat-bug world
out there, Princess,
one of those circle-of-life
kind of things.
Now, let me tell you
how things are supposed to work.
The sun grows the food,
the ants pick the food,
the grasshoppers eat the food--
And the birds eat the grasshoppers.
Hey, like the one that nearly ate you,
you 'member? Oh, you shoulda seen it.
This blue jay has
him halfway down his throat,
and Hopper's kickin' and screamin'.
And I'm scared.
I'm not goin' anywhere near, okay?
Aw, come on.
It's a great story. Ow, ow, ow.
I swear, if I hadn't promised
Mother on her deathbed...
that I wouldn't kill you,
I would kill you.
- And believe me, no one
appreciates that more than I do.
- Shut up!
I don't want to hear another word
out of you while we're on this island.
- Do you understand me?
- [ Whimpers ]
- I said, do you understand me?
- How can I answer? You said
I couldn't say another word.
- Remember Ma!
- [ Growls ]
Hey, I'm a compassionate insect.
There's still a few months
till the rains come,
so you can all just try again.
But, Hopper, since it's
almost the rainy season,
we need this time
to gather food for ourselves.
Listen, if you don't
keep your end of the bargain,
then I can't guarantee your safety.
And there are insects out there
that will take advantage of you.
Someone could get hurt.
[ Snaps Fingers ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Snarling, Screeching ]
[ Gasps, Squeals ]
What's the matter?
You scared of grasshoppers?
[ Whimpering ]
- Dot!
- You don't like Thumper?
- [ Snarls ]
- Leave her alone!
You want her?
Go ahead-- take her.
No?
Then get back in line.
It seems to me that you ants
are forgetting your place.
So let's double
the order of food.
- [ Gasps ]
- No! But-But--
We'll be back
at the end of the season,
when the last leaf falls.
You ants have a nice summer.
Let's ride!
- Yee-ha!
- [ Grasshoppers Shouting ]
[ Laughing ]
Ooh!
[ Chuckles Nervously ]
Flik, what do you have
to say for yourself?
Sorry. I-- I'm sorry
for the way I am.
I didn't mean for things
to go so wrong.
I especially didn't want
to make you look bad, Princess.
- Well, Flik, ya did.
- I was just trying to help.
- Then help us-- don't help us.
- Help, help. Help?
Flik, you are sentenced to
one month digging in the tunnels.
Excuse me, Your Highness.
Need I remind you of Flik's
tunnel-within-a-tunnel project?
Helpers to help us.
That's it! We could--
It took two days to dig him out.
Send him to Health and Ant Services.
Heavens, no!
We could leave the island,
the river bed's dry.
We could walk across and get helpers.
We could! We could go
find helpers to help us.
- It's perfect!
- Perfect? What's so perfect?
Your Highness, don't you see?
We could send someone to get help!
- [ All Gasp ]
- Leave the island?
Why didn't I think of that?
Oh! Because it's suicide!
- She's right! We never leave the island.
- Never leave!
There's snakes and birds
and bigger bugs out there!
Exactly! Bigger bugs!
We could find bigger bugs
to come here and fight...
and forever rid us
of Hopper and his gang!
- Ludicrous!
- Who would do a crazy thing like that?
- I'll volunteer.
I'd be happy to volunteer.
- [ Laughing ]
You got a lot of spunk, kid,
but no one's gonna help a bunch of ants.
At least we could try. I could travel
to the city! I could search there!
If you went, you'd be
on that silly search for weeks.
Royal huddle.
- Great idea, Princess. It's perfect!
- Exactly.
- Wait a minute.
What did we just decide here?
- To let Flik leave.
While we keep harvesting
to meet Hopper's demands.
- You see, with Flik gone, he can't--
- He can't mess anything up!
Flik, after much deliberation, we have
decided to grant you your request.
- Really?
- Uh, really.
Oh, thank you, Princess.
Thank you so much for this chance.
- I won't let you down,
I promise, I promise, I promise.
- That's fine. No, forget it.
- I should help repair
the damage before I go.
- [ All ] No! No, no!
[ Elderly Ant ]
Just leave!
[ Breathes Deeply ]
Hey.
Don't worry!
The colony is in good hands!
Bye, now.
[ Ants Cheering ]
All right.
Hey, fellas.
Beautiful mornin', huh?
My dad gives you one hour
before you come back crying.
Does he, now?
- My dad doesn't think that.
- He doesn't, huh?
- Naw, he's bettin' you're gonna die.
- Oh.
He says if the heat doesn't get ya,
the birds will.
I think he's gonna make it.
- Nobody asked you, Your Royal Shortness.
- Yeah, Dot. What do you know?
Hey, hey, hey.
Ease up. Come on.
She's entitled
to her opinion too.
[ Gasps ]
[ Birds Cawing ]
Ohh.
- So go, already.
- [ Exhales ]
- Hey!
- The city's that way.
- I know.
- You're supposed to look for bugs,
not dandelions.
You leave him alone.
He knows what he's doing.
That's right.
Here I go. For the colony,
and for oppressed ants everywhere!
Whoa-oh.
- Wow!
- Hey!
- Hey-hey!
- Bye, Flik!
Wow!
[ Chuckling ]
Wow. Ohh!
Whoa!
[ Dot ]
Good luck, Flik!
Bye! Whoa-oh!
Flik!
[ Muffled ]
I'm... okay!
- Your dad's right. He's gonna die.
- You just watch.
He's gonna get the bestest,
roughest bugs you've ever seen!
[ Growls, Roars ]
Get back! Get back!
Get back, you horrible beast!
- [ Roaring ]
- I have no fear! Aye-eee!
- Ooh!
- Oh, my goodness.
- [ Sobbing ]
- Oh, no!
[ Crowd Boos, Hisses ]
- Oh, I'm so sorry, Dim. An owie?
- Owie! Owie, owie.
Please show Rosie the owie.
All right, Dim. It's okay.
I have been in outhouses
that didn't stink that bad.
This is ridiculous.
What a disappointment!
- Oh, no!
- You! Come here! I want my money back!
Uh, no refunds
after the first two minutes.
Popcorn! Stale popcorn!
We're losin' the audience!
You clowns get out there now!
- I hate performing on an empty stomach!
- Do your act, Heimlich.
- Then you can eat. Not now, Slim.
- P.T., what's the point?
What's the point of going out there?
They'll only laugh at me.
- That's because you're a clown!
- No, it's because I'm a prop!
You always cast me as the broom,
the pole, the stick, a splinter.
You're a walkingstick.
It's funny!
- Now go!
- You parasite.
[ Fanfare Plays ]
Tra-la-la-la-la.
Spring's in the air.
And I'm a flower with
nothing interesting to say.
- [ Screams ]
- A bee!
I am a cute little bumblebee!
Here I come!
[ Screams ]
Slow down, you flowers!
[ Groans ]
Candy corn! Here,
let me help you to finish it.
Hey, cutie! Wanna pollinate
with a real bug? [ Laughs ]
Ooh, come to papa!
So, bein' a ladybug automatically makes
me a girl, is that it, flyboy? Huh?
- She's a guy!
- Francis, leave them alone.
- They are poo-poo heads!
- Not again.
Judging by your breath, you must have
been buzzin' around a dung heap all day.
- Come on, Francis.
You're making the maggots cry.
- [ Wailing ]
[ Vocalizing ]
All right, we're dyin' out there.
Gypsy, quick! You and Manny--
- Shh! He's in a trance.
- [ Humming ]
Well, get him out of it!
You and your husband are up now.
Manny, we're on.
Oh? Yet again it is up to me
to rescue the performance.
- Gypsy, come.
- [ Humming ]
[ Crashing ]
- The stage is the other way, dear.
- Yes, of course.
Anytime, pal!
- I'm gonna pick the hairs
out of your head one by one!
- Take your best shot!
- You name the place!
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, 'cause when you
get there, you are dead!
- Francis, let me handle this.
- That's no way to speak to a lady.
- I heard that, you twig.
Ladies and gentlemen, allow me
to present Manto the Magnificent...
and his lovely assistant, Gypsy!
From the most mysterious
regions of uncharted Asia,
I give you the Chinese Cabinet...
of Metamorphosis!
Rosie, whole troupe.
Onstage! Finale! Now!
- Okay, I just need time to--
Coming, coming.
- Now!
Tuck, Roll, let's get moving, guys.
We're up next.
[ Speaking Foreign Language ]
Don't you understand?
We are up!
- ''Up-a.''
- [ Chattering ]
- Hey!
- Hey! They don't understand me.
I summon the voice
of Confucius--
Get off the stage,
you old hack!
[ Shrieks ]
I demand to know who said that!
- [ Laughing ]
- How dare you!
Ingrates!
[ Gypsy ]
Manny? Manny!
I only got 24 hours to live
and I ain't gonna waste it here.
Come on.
[ Screams ] I've just about
had it with these losers!
Flaming death!
I hold in my hand the match--
the match that decides whether two bugs
live or die this very evening.
In a moment, I will light
this trail of matches...
leading to a sheet of flypaper
dowsed in lighter fluid!
Aimed directly at the flypaper
are Tuck and Roll,
the pill bug cannonballs!
The cannon
will be triggered by Dim,
trained to jump
at the sound of this bell...
set to go off in 15 seconds.
Our pill bugs' only hope
of survival is...
our mistress
of the high wire, Rosie!
Secured to a web line
of exact length,
Rosie will plummet down
to these two posts,
spinning a web of safety
in less than 15 seconds!
Not good enough, you say?
Well, what if they were all...
blindfolded!
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I suggest that those of you...
with weak constitutions
leave the arena,
- for this act is so dangerous...
- [ Bickering ]
that if the slightest thing
should go wrong--
- No!
- Go? Okay, through the tunnel--
- Whoa!
- [ Bell Dings ]
- [ Chuckling ]
- Whoa!
- [ Screams ]
- P.T.!
- Oh, no!
- Oh!
- [ Whimpering ]
- Water! We need some water!
- Water, water, water!
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Grunting ]
Get me outta here!
Oof!
[ Laughs ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Wow!
- It's the web. I'm sorry.
- You're all fired.
- We got the water!
- Here we come, P.T.!
Whoo! Whoa!
Burn 'im again!
No, Harry, no!
Don't look at the light!
I can't help it!
It's so beautiful!
[ Screams ]
Try not to look
like a country bug.
Blend-- blend in.
[ Male Voice ]
Hey, buggy!
What do you expect?
The guy's a tick.
Wow! The city!
[ Laughing ]
Wow!
Whoa-whoa-whoa!
Making all stops to the septic tank,
including standing water,
empty bean can and dead rat.
- Watch your stingers. All aboard!
- Whoa!
- Hey! Oh, sorry.
- Get out of the way!
- Watch where you're goin'!
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean to do that.
- [ Violin Sound ]
- [ Gasps ] Oh, sorry!
Oh. I'm really, really sorry.
That was
an-an-an ac-ac-accident.
- Hey, let go of me!
- I'll show ya who's tough!
- And stay out!
- Tough bugs!
- I knew an old lady
who swallowed a fly--
- Wow!
- Move it!
- Whoa!
[ Male Fly ]
Hey, waiter! I'm in my soup!
I've been workin' out.
Feel my wing.
Yo!
Two Black Flags over here!
- All right.
- Hair of the dog you bit.
Hey, who ordered
the pu-pu platter?
Here ya go, slick. Enjoy.
Ow! Aah!
Hey, I said no salt!
Pardon me, sir.
I represent a colony of ants,
and I'm looking for tough bugs,
you know, mean bugs--
Fired by a flea--
how humiliating!
Let's face it: We stink.
- You fired!
- Oh, will you shut up?
Someday I will be
a beautiful butterfly,
and then everything
will be better.
I can't believe the troupe is
breaking up. We've always been together.
- Farewell, my friends.
- To the audience we'll never have.
[ Gasps ] Francis! Your boyfriends
from the circus are here!
- [ Gasps ]
- There she is.
- Hello there, girly bug.
- Shoo, fly. Don't bother me.
Say, why don't you
tell our pal, Thud,
- what you said to us at the circus.
- Yeah.
- Somethin' about buzzin'
around a dung heap?
- [ Growls ]
Excuse me. Hi. I represent
an ant colony, and we're--
Hey, bartender!
Bloody Mary, O-positive.
Aha!
- [ Sighs ]
- Sir?
Ladybug, ladybug
fly away home
- [ Laughs ]
- Not so tough now, are you?
All right, clown.
Get up and fight like a girl.
- Get ready to do the Robin Hood act.
- I want to be Little John!
- What part can I play?
- You see, I'm looking for
tough, warrior bugs.
Stand back, ye flies! We are
the greatest warriors in all bugdom!
- Warrior bugs!
- My sword!
Swish, swish. Clang, clang.
- Little John?
- What ho, Robin?
Justice is my sword
and truth shall be my quiver!
Wait, wait! No, no!
I want to watch this!
- Jawohl!
- Thrust, parry, lunge!
- [ Growls ]
- Me thinketh it's not working!
[ Gasps ]
Back to Sherwood Forest!
- Schnell! Schnell!
- What's going on in there?
[ All Screaming ]
Help! Help! Get me out!
[ Grunting ]
Wow.
- Oh, ow-ow-ow-ow.
- [ Flik ] You're perfect!
Oh, great ones! I have been scouting
for bugs with your exact talents!
- [ Gasps ] A talent scout.
- My colony's in trouble.
Grasshoppers are coming! We've
been forced to prepare all this food.
- Dinner theater!
- Food?
Please!
Will you help us?
- [ Growling ]
- Where are they?
- We'll take the job!
- Really?
- Yes, yes, yes!
You can explain
the details on the way.
Hey!
[ Chattering ]
- Okay, come on, everyone. Break a leg!
- Whoa, you're vicious!
Hold on, Mr.Ant.
Amazing!
This is too good to be true!
[ Laughs ]
Ooh!
So, you see, it was my fault
that Hopper's coming back.
But then, Princess Atta--
boy, is she one in a million--
she let me go out and find you.
And after seeing you
fight off those flies--
Boy, are those grasshoppers
in for a surprise!
[ Laughing ]
[ Chattering In
Foreign Language ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Moans ]
- Dr.Flora!
- Oh, dear. Not another one.
- This is insane.
- Insane.
There's just not enough
food left on the island!
No way we can make double quota
before Hopper comes.
Well, we have to try, Thorny.
We don't have any choice.
Yeah, I know.
Hey, look who's playing
lookout again-- little Speck!
- The name is Dot.
- Well, Spot, still lookin' for Flik?
Forget it, Dot.
That loser's never coming back.
Flik!
He did it! He did it!
What? Quit shoving!
This is it!
This is Ant Island!
Flik! Over here!
Flik! Flik!
- Hey!
- He did it! He did it! Yea!
- He did it!
- Cool! [ Screams ]
At the rate these leaves are dropping,
we're gonna need a miracle.
That's right!
We need a miracle!
- Run for your lives!
- [ Anxious Chattering ]
Ta-da!
[ Bird Cawing ]
[ Sighing ] Once again,
our reputation precedes us.
Hey, everybody!
Hey! I'm back!
Hey, guys! Hey-ey!
Look-look-look who's here with me!
Flik! Flik! Flik! You're back!
I knew you could do it!
- Flik?
- It's Flik!
[ Chattering ]
- Flik has returned!
- He's back?
And he's accompanied
by savage insects!
What? How? He wasn't supposed
to actually find someone!
Oh, look at this.
This is great. Look.
- Oh, my ticker!
- So, what are you supposed to be?
He's a stick, stupid.
You hit bugs with him.
- Well, that's an oversimplification.
- That's right, kids. Like this!
- No! Put me down!
- Ow!
- Hey!
- My, you just pop
right open there, dontcha?
- Ooh! Wow!
- Uh-oh. Kids, He's kinda ticklish.
- [ Laughing ]
- Let's come on out. Careful.
[ Laughs ]
Well, my boy, you came through.
- Aphie and I are very impressed.
- [ Aphie Barks ]
Princess Atta! Hey, guys, Princess Atta!
She's the one that sent me to find you!
- Did you see that
really big bug over there?
- He looks absolutely ferocious!
- They're our ticket out of this mess!
- They came just in time!
So, Princess Atta,
what do you think?
No-no-no, wait!
This was not supposed to happen.
Mayday, Mayday.
We're losin' the job.
We don't fight grasshoppers.
- We don't, but they will.
- Bingo!
We gotta sweeten the deal.
Your Majesty,
ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls of all ages,
our troupe here guarantees
a performance like no other!
Why, when your grasshopper friends
get here, we are gonna...
knock them dead!
[ Cheering ]
Boy, these folks are sure
hard up for entertainment.
Come on, come on. Hurry!
[ Panting ]
Wow!
[ Lively Dance Beat ]
Honey, relax.
You should be proud of yourself.
- Your instincts on that boy
were right on the money.
- [ Chuckles ]
[ Music Ends ]
And to make our official
welcome complete-- Mr.Soil?
- Yes, Your Highness?
- He's our resident thespian.
Last year he played the lead
in Picnic. [ Laughs ]
The children-- and myself--
have quickly put together...
a little presentation
in honor of our guests.
Dot, Reed, Daisy, Grub?
Oh, aren't they adorable!
Ooh, they're cute!
The South Tunnel Elementary School
second grade class...
would like to present you with this,
a mural we have drawn...
of you bugs helping us
fight the grasshoppers away.
Oh, look at the beautiful colors
of the blood.
We drew one of you dying because our
teacher said it would be more dramatic.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Ants Applauding ]
- [ Playing Harp ]
- I tell you a tale of heroes so bold,
who vanquished our
grasshopper enemies of old.
Look, the last leaf has fallen.
[ Together ] We are the grasshoppers!
Where's our food?
Who will come
to save us poor ants?
We are the warriors,
here to defend you!
I die! Die! Die!
[ Cheering ]
- [ Chattering ]
- Thank you, thank you! Oh, thank you!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- I say we go.
- Okay, honey. You're up.
- Oh. Um--
- Oh, oh, I-I--
- We're all very grateful to have...
- Here, here.
- [ Amplified ] the warriors--
Thanks.
[ Clears Throat ]
- I'd like to thank the warriors
for helping us in our fight...
- [ Arguing ]
against the grasshoppers.
Secondly, I would like
to thank Flik...
- for his forthright thinking--
- Thank you, Your Highness.
Oh, sure, I'd like to take credit for
all of this, but that wouldn't be right.
Because it was you, Princess Atta.
You believed in me--
- Tell that ant that we need
to talk to him right now.
- Okay, okay.
I know I've made mistakes in the past,
and I hope that this will make up--
- Flik!
- Not right now, Rosie.
I'm making a speech.
[ Grumbles, Whispers ]
Now, I truly believe these bugs
are the answer to our--
No, there's no circus around here.
So, I-- [ Gasps ]
[ Whimpers ]
Your Highness, the warriors
have called for a secret meeting
to plan for a circus--
circumventing the oncoming hordes so
they can trapeze-- trap them with ease!
- Shouldn't I come too?
- No! [ Laughs Nervously ]
No, classified in the D.M.Z.
Gotta go A.S.A.P. You know,
strictly B.Y.O.B. Bye!
Sorry. Sorry I have to take
the warriors away so early,
but you know they have a lot to get
done, with the battle looming and all.
So, uh, please,
everyone enjoy the party.
''B.Y.O.B.''?
Thanks again. Bye. Bye-bye.
Okay, just--
just get in there. Go!
Go! Go, go, go!
Circus bugs?
How can you be circus bugs?
- What?
- Hey, hey, hey.
- You said nothin' about killin'
grasshoppers. You lied to us!
- Ja!
Are you kidding?
Do you know what this is?
This, my friends,
is false advertising.
How dare you! You, sir,
are the charlatan in this scenario--
touting your wares
as a talent scout,
preying upon the hungry souls
of hapless artistes.
Good day to you, sir.
Wait! No, no!
Wait, wait, wait, wait! You can't go.
You have got to help me. Give me
some time, I'll come up with a plan.
- Just go tell them the truth!
- They can't know the truth.
The truth, you see, is bad.
I will be branded for life.
My children's children will
walk down the street,
people will point and say, ''Look! There
goes the spawn of Flik, the loser!''
Oh-- oh, you know, all right, fine.
Yeah, okay. Just go.
But if you could just do me
a little favor before you leave.
If you could squish me,
that would be great, because, uh,
when they find out,
I'm as good as dead.
- [ Princess Atta ] Flik!
- [ Gasps ]
I really do think I should be
part of this meeting. Flik!
Aah! Princess Atta!
What a nice... surprise.
Just what exactly is going on?
I would like to speak
with the so-called ''warriors.''
You can't! They are in the middle
of a top secret meeting right now,
and they really should not
be disturbed... now.
Right, guys?
[ Gasps ] Could you ex-- pl--
Could you excuse me, please?
- Wait, wait, wait! Please, don't go!
- I'm not going anywhere.
What is going on? Flik?
Flik! [ Groans ]
Ooh, I knew it!
[ Flik In Distance ] Wait! Wait,
wait, wait, wait! Please! Don't go!
- No!
- Quick, he's losin' it!
- You can't go! I'm desperate!
- Really? I couldn't tell.
Hmm. Come on, wings.
[ Screams ]
Help!
Mother,
Flik is up to something.
Okay, Flik, time to put ya down.
Get him off me!
He's cutting off the circulation.
- No, no, no, no!
- Let go!
- Please, please, don't go!
- [ Rosie ] Put the stick down.
Flik, I mean it, now.
- Drop the stick.
- [ Screams ] Run!
Boy, he runs fast
for a little guy.
- [ Squawks ]
- Tweet-tweet! Tweet-tweet!
[ All Gasp, Scream ]
This way.
- There they are.
- [ Bird Chirping ]
- [ Gasps ] A bird!
- [ Screams ] Flik!
- Look!
- Dot!
- [ Whimpers ]
Flik!
- [ Screaming ]
- Dot!
- My baby!
[ Gasps ]
I gotcha! I gotcha!
I gotcha, I gotcha!
- [ Grunts ]
- Oww!
Oooh.
- I can't see!
- Somebody do something!
- Are they all right?
- Did anyone see?
- What is happening?
- Dot?
- Good heavens, they're in trouble!
- Francis, Francis, Francis,
Francis, Francis, Francis--
- Oh, you guys, I've got an idea!
Here! I've got it!
Please, ma'am, wake up!
Wake up!
[ Screaming ]
- Help! Help!
- Yoo-hoo!
Mr. Early Bird! How about
a nice, tasty worm on a stick?
I'm going to snap.
Nice and juicy, succulent--
[ Flik ]
Let's go!
- There they are!
- Flik! Help!
Okay.
- Flik!
- It's going to be okay, Dot.
Ooh-hoo-hoo!
Bye-bye, birdie!
Help! I'm stuck!
Pull me down!
Schnell, schnell, schnell!
- The caterpillar's using
himself as live bait!
- How brave!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Screeching ]
- Suck it in, man!
Ow. My leg!
[ All Screaming ]
[ Flik Screaming ]
[ Chirping ]
[ Gasps ] The bird!
Look out for the bird!
- Flik!
- [ Gasps ]
- Up-a, up-a!
- [ Screams ]
[ All Pant ]
- [ Distant Applause ]
- What is that?
That, my friends,
is the sound of applause!
[ Cheering ]
Applause-- I'm in heaven!
[ Sighs ]
Our Blueberry troop salutes you bugs
for rescuing our smallest member,
Princess Dot.
And as a tribute to Miss Francis,
we've changed out bandannas!
We voted you
our honorary den mother!
- [ Ants Cheering ]
- What? Great.
- [ Chattering ]
- All right, girls. Let's move
your keisters outta here now.
The patient needs her rest,
you know. Come on.
Excuse, me, Flik.
Can I talk to you for a second?
- Huh? Oh, sure.
- Oww!
Again, thank you all,
very, very much.
- Oh, stop it.
- You're too kind.
- Thank you.
You don't think I've offended
the warriors, do you?
You? No.
Oh, good. Because, you see,
when you first brought them here,
I thought you'd hired a bunch of clowns.
Ya did?
[ Laughs Nervously ]
Don't tell 'em I said that.
Boy, that's all I'd need,
another royal blunder like that.
- Princess, you're doin' a great job.
- Thanks, you're sweet.
You're wrong, but sweet.
- I know what everyone really thinks.
- I don't follow you.
Everyone-- the whole colony. Nobody
really believes I can do this job.
It's like they're all watching me,
- just, just--
- Waiting for you to screw up.
- Flik, I owe you an apology.
- For what?
Well, I haven't been that nice
to you, and... I'm sorry.
If there's any way I can
make it up to you--
Hey! I know!
How would you like to be the queen's
official aide to the warrior bugs?
- Me?
- Oh, sure. You've got
a great rapport with them,
especially after that rescue--
it was very brave.
- Really? Naw, naw--
- Well, not every bug would face a bird.
- I mean, even Hopper's afraid of 'em.
- Yeah, well, I guess maybe I--
- Say that again?
- I said, even Hopper's afraid of birds.
Thank you.
- Hopper's afraid of birds!
- And I don't blame 'im!
Oh, oh, oh,
this is perfect.
We can get rid of Hopper,
and no one has to know that I messed up.
You just keep pretending
you're warriors.
Whoa, Flik, honey. We are not
about to fight grasshoppers, okay?
You'll be gone before the grasshoppers
ever arrive. Here's what we do.
Not another word.
I don't know what you're concocting
in that little ant brain of yours,
but we'll have no part of it.
Excuse me? Could we get
the warriors' autographs?
Autographs? Ja!
- Wow! Great!
- So, you fellas catch the action today?
Oh! The bird went-- [ Whooshes ]
and it just missed you!
- Aren't you sweet?
- And the way you pretended
to be stuck in that crack!
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, that's just all part of the plan.
And then you dive-bombed
into the bush!
- There you go, my boy.
- Wow! Thanks!
''M-M-Maa-jor--''
That's Major Manny, young cadet.
- I outrank everyone here. Remember that.
- Yes, sir!
- Dismissed!
- Wow!
- When I grow up,
I'm gonna be a praying mantis!
- I'm gonna be a stick bug!
Oh, they're all so cool,
I can't pick!
[ Chuckling ] Delightful lads.
You were saying, Flik?
All right.
We are going to build a bird--
a bird that we can operate
from the inside, which would then be--
...hoisted above the anthill
and hidden high in the tree.
Then, right when Hopper
and his gang are below,
we'll launch the bird
and scare off the grasshoppers.
Now it's going to take
everyone's involvement--
...to make this plan
a reality.
I know it's not our tradition
to do things differently,
but if our ancestors were able
to build this anthill,
we can certainly rally together
to build this bird!
[ All Cheering ]
[ Laughing ]
- Perfect!
- Okay, hit your marks!
- Whoa!
- Whee-hee!
- [ Giggles ] Hi, Flik.
- Oh.
[ Snickering ]
[ Chuckles Nervously ]
[ Chattering ]
- I love what you did with your antenna.
- Oh, thank you.
Oh, look.
She's a natural mother.
[ Growling ] All right, that's it!
Out! Everybody out!
[ Whimpering ]
Now you're gonna cry, right?
See if I care. Go ahead, cry.
- [ Sobbing ]
- Please, don't cry. Please.
- [ Continue Sobbing ]
- Huh?
- Ta-da!
- [ Cheering ]
- Okay, lower, lower--
- [ Dim Chuckles ]
- You got it. And that's it!
- Whoa!
[ All ]
Up, up, up, up!
Rabbit through the hole, chicken in the
barn, two by two by, there's the yarn.
- Done!
- Ruben Kincaid!
- Hey!
- Good job, guys! Nice work!
Up, down.
Up, down. Up, down.
- Hmm.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Ah-ah-ah. Read 'em and weep.
- Huh?
- [ Girls Giggle ]
Whoo-whee! Yahoo!
- Flik, watch out!
- Whoa!
- Look! I'm a beautiful butterfly!
- [ Laughs ]
There ya go. Good job, fellas.
Keep up the good work.
Huh?
Okay!
[ Together ]
You're fired! [ Laughing ]
[ Ants Cheering ]
Yes!
[ Mariachi Band ]
Whoo-hoo! Look at me!
I'm barefootin'! Whoo-hoo!
Yo, bugito,
dos granitos, pronto!
[ Skier ]
You gotta try this, man!
[ Buzzing ]
La cucaracha, la cucaracha
Da-da-da-da-da-da-da
[ Whimpering ]
[ Buzzing ]
...all the way back there
and it starts to rain, we might
as well be suckin' bug spray.
Ooh, don't even say that!
You know somethin'?
You're makin' a lot of sense.
I mean, why take the risk?
- You should tell Hopper.
- Good idea.
But, you know,
it's really not our place.
You're his brother.
That makes you, like...
the vice president of the gang.
Wow! It kinda does,
doesn't it?
Okay, I'll tell 'im.
I should talk to you guys more often.
- What if Hopper doesn't like it?
- Then the genius'll get smacked
and not us.
Vice President Molt.
[ Laughing ]
Ooh, yeah, that's good.
Oh, that's good.
- Ooh, a little lower. Ahh, lower.
- Hey ya, Hop.
- Go away.
- That's fine.
Then I won't tell ya my idea.
- Good!
- Okay, okay. I'll tell ya anyway.
I've been thinkin'-- which is somethin'
I do, bein' vice president and all.
This is a thought, and it was mine:
Why go back to Ant Island at all?
- You don't even like grain.
- What?
You're right. I didn't think
it was such a good idea myself.
It wasn't even my idea.
It was Axle and Loco's!
They talked fancy to me.
I got confused!
- [ Grumbles ]
- La cucaracha, la cucaracha
Da-da-da-da-da-da-da
[ Music Stops ]
Guys, order another round...
because we're stayin' here!
- [ Cheering ]
- Yeah!
What was I thinking?
Going back to Ant Island.
I mean, we just got here,
and we have more than enough food
to get us through the winter.
Right? Why go back?
[ Music Resumes ]
But there was that ant
that stood up to me.
- Yeah, but we can forget about him!
- Yeah, it was just one ant.
- [ Mock Scared ] Ooo-oooh!
- One ant!
Yeah, you're right!
It's just one ant!
- Yeah, boss. They're puny!
- Hmm, puny.
Say, let's pretend this grain
is a puny little ant.
- Didn't that hurt?
- Nope.
- Well, how 'bout this one?
- Are you kiddin'?
- [ Laughing ]
- Well, how 'bout this?
[ Screaming ]
You let one ant stand up to us,
then they all might stand up.
Those puny little ants
outnumber us a hundred to one.
And if they ever figure that out,
there goes our way of life!
It's not about food.
It's about keeping those ants in line.
That's why we're going back!
Does anybody else wanna stay?
He's quite the motivational
speaker, isn't he?
Let's ride!
[ Caribbean Band ]
- [ Ant ] To the bird!
- [ Ants ] The bird!
Hey!
- Hey!
- Whoo-hoo!
Hey!
- Hey!
- Whoo!
- Get down, roly boys!
- [ Laughing ]
- How low can you go? Sing it now.
- How low can you go?
- Do it, Princess.
How low can you go?
- [ Laughs ]
And that's how my 12th husband died.
[ Laughs ]
So, now I'm a widow. I mean,
I've always been a black widow,
but now I'm a black widow widow.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughing ]
Whoo!
- Thorny! Any sign of those fiends?
- Lemme check.
No, not yet.
But we'll be ready for 'em.
Blueberries, dismissed!
- [ Giggling ]
- And, uh, quit beatin' the boys up.
Those little raisins
do grow on ya.
Hey, how you guys doin'?
Some party, huh?
Is that grain dip fresh or what?
Okay, I've told everyone you'll be
stationed deep in the command bunker.
Party quiets down,
I sneak you out the back way
and then you're outta here forever.
Dim don't wanna go.
Well, if Dim stays he's gonna
need me here. He's not fully trained.
- I mean, house-trained.
- [ Chuckles ]
I, uh, I kinda promised the Blueberries
I'd teach 'em canasta.
It seems we've been booked
for an extended engagement.
[ Smooching, Laughing ]
Will you look at this colony?
Will you just look at this colony?
I don't even recognize it.
[ Chuckles ]
I feel 70 again!
Work that ab, baby!
[ Laughs ]
And I have you bugs to thank for it.
So-- thank you!
And, uh, thank you
for findin' 'em, Flik.
Me? Oh, ooh--
uh, uh, I'll get it.
I mean, if you don't mind,
I'll just--
- It's all tangled up.
- [ Laughing Nervously ]
- There.
- Ow!
I think I'll go check
on the bird. [ Giggling ]
- Bird's this way.
- [ Laughing Nervously ]
Yeah, the bird's that way.
[ Chuckling ]
She-- What?
[ Gasps ]
Jiminy H. Cricket!
[ Horn Blares ]
They're back!
Get ready, everybody!
Get to your posts!
Battle stations, everyone.
This not a drill.
Come on, everyone. You know your jobs!
Let's go, go, go, go!
- [ Screams ]
- Look out!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa there.
Steady, girls. That's it.
- Oh, it's P.T.
- P.T.?
Greetings and salutations!
Ooh-boppa-doo and how do you do?
I am the great P.T. Flea!
[ Laughs ]
I'm in need of your assis--
Oh, let's just cut to the chase.
Look, I've been goin'
from anthill to anthill.
I'm lookin' for a bunch of circus
performers. Have you seen 'em?
- [ Crowd Groans ]
- [ Gasps ]
Wait a second.
Ain't that Staff Sergeant Slim?
No, no, no. I'm sorry, no, but uh--
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
- [ Rustling, Groaning ]
- [ Whispering ] Be quiet!
Hey!
[ Flik ] You'll probably--
you'll probably want to get goin'.
I guess you got a lot of other anthills
to check into, so, bye!
- [ All Gasp ]
- Ah, guys, I've been lookin'
all over for ya!
- Flaming Death is a huge hit!
- P.T.! Sh--
- I'm serious. Word of mouth got around.
- P.T.! No!
The next day, there was a line of flies
outside the tent went on forever!
- It must have been a foot long!
- [ Rosie ] P.T., no!
So, I figured it out. You guys burn me
twice a night, I take a day off to heal,
and then we do it
all over again!
We'll be the top circus act
in the business! [ Guffaws ]
You mean, you're not warriors?
Are you kiddin'? These guys are the
lousiest circus bugs you've ever seen.
And they're gonna make me rich!
[ Chortling ]
You mean to tell me that
our entire defensive strategy...
was concocted by clowns?
Hey, hey, hey, hey. We really thought
Flik's idea was gonna work.
[ Crowd Gasps, Groans ]
- Oops.
- Tell me this isn't true.
- No, you don't-- You don't--
- This couldn't have happened
at a more inopportune time!
The last leaf is about to fall!
[ Dr.Flora ] We haven't collected
any food for the grasshoppers!
If Hopper finds out
what we almost did--
Hopper is not going
to find out.
We're going to hide all this,
and pretend it never happened.
You bugs were never here.
So I suggest you all leave.
But the bird!
The-The bird will work.
I never thought I'd see the day
when an ant would put himself...
- before the rest of his colony.
- What?
- The point is, Flik, you lied to us.
- No, no, no! I-I--
You lied, Flik. You lied to her.
You lied to the colony!
You lied to me!
And like an idiot,
I believed you.
But I-I was just afraid that...
if you knew I'd gotten circus bugs--
[ Sighs Deeply ]
- I just wanted to make a difference.
- I want you to leave, Flik.
And this time, don't come back.
[ Crowd Gasps, Murmurs ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Whimpers ]
Tough crowd. Yee-haw!
Flik!
[ Thumper ]
Get those bugs!
[ Panting ]
[ Crowd Chattering ]
[ Grunting ]
That's it? But there's got
to be more food on the island!
If we give up any more,
we'll starve.
- Hopper won't accept this!
- [ Roaring ]
[ Roaring Intensifies ]
- [ Whimpering ]
- Mother, it's not enough.
- What do we do?
- I-I don't know.
- [ Roaring Stops ]
- [ Gasping ]
[ Gasping, Swallowing ]
[ Heavy Footsteps ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Growling, Screeching ]
- [ Crowd Gasping ]
- You little termites!
I give you a second chance,
and this is all I get?
- [ Screaming ]
- But Hopper, we ran out of time!
Have you been playing all summer?
You think this is a game?
- No, no, please!
- Well, guess what?
You just lost.
- [ Screeching ]
- Not one ant sleeps...
until we get
every scrap of food...
on this island!
Just do what he says. You don't
want to make him mad. Believe me!
No, no, no.
You're staying with me, Your Highness.
- [ Screaming ]
- What do you think you're doing?
- Get over there.
- Quick! To the clubhouse.
- [ Rustling ]
- [ Gasping ] Hurry!
- Shh!
- [ Grasshopper ]
Shut up a minute, will ya?
- I think I heard something over here.
- Have you checked over there?
- No, not yet.
- Then get over there and check it out!
- Wait a minute.
- [ Gasps ]
- Hey, I think I found something.
- [ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Laughs ]
Cool. Hey, how do I look?
Like an idiot.
Oh, I don't know, maybe
it'll keep me dry in the rain.
You moron, we'll be out of here
before it rains.
Didn't you hear Hopper?
After the ants pick all the food,
he's gonna squish the queen
to remind 'em who's boss.
Then she's dead. They cry-- boo-hoo--
we go home. End of story.
Oh! Cool. I love our job.
Stay here.
I'm gonna get help.
[ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
Ooh!
- [ Snarling ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Panting ]
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Grunting ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
Come on, wings, fly. Fly!
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Fades ]
[ Growling ]
[ Screeching ]
Yeah! Whoa-oh!
[ Panting, Grunting ]
[ P.T. Humming, Indistinct ]
I'm gonna be
rich, rich, rich
I'm gonna be rich, rich, rich
I'm gonna be the richest flea
in the land
Ka-ching! The streets'll
be paved with golden retrievers
I'm rich, rich, rich
That's who I am
[ P.T. Continues Singing,
Indistinct ]
- Poor fellow.
- Hey, maybe we can cheer him up a bit.
Don't worry, Flik.
The circus life isn't so bad.
- Yes, you can be part of our act.
- Here! Like this.
Oof! Ahh.
Slapstick! Get it?
I-I'm a walkingstick.
[ Laughs Weakly ] Oh, never mind.
- [ Dot ] Flik!
- Dot?
Flik, wait! Wait!
Dot, you're flying!
What are you doing here?
[ Panting ]
You... have to go back.
Hopper moved into the anthill,
and his gang's eating everything!
- Oh, no!
- Good heavens!
And I heard a grasshopper say
that when they're finished,
Hopper's gonna squish my mom!
- Oh, not the queen!
- Do something!
- How?
- [ Rosie ] Come on, you guys, think!
- I know. The bird.
- Yes, of course.
- The bird! That's brilliant.
- Ja!
- The bird won't work.
- What are you talking about?
It was your idea.
- But you said that everything--
Forget everything I ever told you.
All right, Dot?
Let's face it. The colony is right.
I just make things worse.
That bird is a guaranteed failure.
[ Sighs ]
Just like me.
You listen to me, my boy. I've made
a living out of being a failure.
And you, sir, are not a failure!
- Oh, but Flik, you've
done so many good things.
- Oh, yeah?
Okay, show me one thing
I've done right.
- Umm--
- Us.
- [ Bugs ] Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- Dim is right, my boy.
You have rekindled the long-dormant
embers of purpose in our lives.
And if it wasn't for you,
Francis would have never gotten
in touch with his feminine side.
Oh yeah? Well-- Hmm.
[ Chuckles ]
You know what? He's right.
Lieutenant Gypsy
reporting for duty.
- Kid, say the word
and we'll follow you into battle.
- We believe in you, my boy.
Flik, please?
Pretend it's a seed, okay?
[ Chuckles ]
Thanks, Dot.
- Hey, what's with the rock?
- Must be an ant thing.
All right, let's do it.
- [ Laughing, Cheering ]
- That's the Flik we know and love.
- We're on!
- So, what do we do first?
Bugs will pay
big bucks to see
A bonfire that is starring me
[ Laughing ]
P.T., look. Money!
[ P.T. ]
Where? Where? [ Screaming ]
All right. Get movin'! Get goin'.
Move your abdomens, now!
[ Flik ]
They're rounding everyone up.
- [ Gasps ]
- Hey! Turn your butt off.
Psst! Hey, guys!
Get me out of this thing, will ya?
I promise to start thinkin'
about payin' ya.
Hey! Wait, wait!
Okay, I'll pay ya! I'll pay ya!
[ Flik ] Oh, no!
They've finished collecting the food.
We've got to get the queen now.
Once she's safe,
we move on Gypsy's signal.
- [ Rattling ]
- [ Gasps ] Someone's coming!
[ Rattling Continues ]
Hello, kids! Ready to make
some grasshoppers cry?
It's payback time,
Blueberry-style.
- [ Grunting ]
- Blueberries rock!
- [ All Cheering ]
- All right!
- [ Growling ]
- [ Drum Rolling ]
[ Slim ] Ladies and Gentlebugs!
Larvae of all stages!
Rub your legs together for
the world's greatest bug circus!
- Wait a minute.
- [ Brakes Screeching ]
- I think I'm going to wet myself.
- Steady--
- What's going on here?
- Well, uh--
Uh, yes.
[ Chuckling ]
We were invited
by Princess Atta...
as a surprise for your arrival.
- Squish 'em.
- [ Gasping ]
Ooh--
[ Gasps ]
[ Together ] Hey!
[ Gibberish ]
[ Continues, Alone ]
[ Yelling Gibberish ]
[ Bickering Continues ]
Now that's funny.
That is funny.
I guess we could use
a little entertainment.
Looks like you did something right
for once, Princess.
- [ Laughing Uneasily ] On with the show!
- Hi-ya!
Hey!
The circus, the circus
I love the circus
[ Cheering, Yelling ]
[ Panting ]
- [ Sucking ]
- Ba-ba all gone!
Baby wants pie!
Pie? He asked for it.
Should I give it to him?
Yeah! Give 'em pie!
Give 'em pie!
- [ All Cheering ]
- Yeah! Hah!
Thank you, gentlemen.
Always an intellectual treat.
Say, how many roaches does it take
to screw in a light bulb?
Can't tell. As soon as
the light goes on, they scatter!
[ Hysterical Laughing Continues ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Panting ]
Ah, almost there.
From the most mysterious
regions of uncharted Asia,
- I give you the Chinese Cabinet...
- Come on, girls. Quick. Quick.
of Metamorphosis!
Utilizing psychic vibrations,
- [ Gasps ] Ooh, ohh, pick me!
- I shall select the perfect volunteer.
Ooh, no! Come on,
I'm askin' ya with my brain.
- [ Moaning ] Aha! Why, Your Majesty!
- Me?
- [ Snarling ]
- No, no. Thumper, down. Let her go.
Maybe he'll saw her in half.
[ Snickering ]
As you ascend the dung beetle
to the unknown,
put your trust in the mysteries that
are beyond mere mortal comprehension.
Ooh, this is gonna be good!
- Blueberries ready?
- [ All ] Ready.
- [ Amplified Voice ] Ready!
- Shh!
I call upon the ancient
Szechwan spirits...
to inhabit the body
of our volunteer!
No, no.
Just stay in there, Your Majesty.
Transformation.
Transformation!
Wow.
Manny's gettin' good.
- [ Gasps ] Not now.
- If it rains, that bird'll
get ripped to shreds!
Shh!
And now, insectus...
transformitus!
[ All ]
Ooh!
- Ooh!
- Ooh, pretty!
- [ Applauding ]
- Thank you, thank you.
- Thank you.
- That's the signal. That's the signal!
[ Grunts ]
This is it, girls.
Get ready to roll.
- Huh? It's stuck!
- That was amazing!
I have no-- How did they do that?
I have no idea where she went.
- Thank you. Thank you, thank you.
- [ Audience ] More, more, more!
Wait!
- Where is she?
- Well, now, uh, actually--
I am sorry. A magician
never reveals his secrets.
That's very true, Hoppy. Where would the
mystery be if we all knew how it was--
- Shutting up.
- [ Grunting ]
- You can do it!
You've got to make it work!
- Hey!
I said, where is she?
- [ Whimpering ]
- Ohh!
[ Grunting ]
[ Screaming ]
Hold on!
[ Amplified Cawing ]
[ Screaming ]
Bird! It's a bird!
[ All Yelling ]
[ Cawing ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Let's get out of here! Go!
Don't let it get me!
Help me! Aaah!
[ Cackling ]
[ Dot ]
Up, down, up, down.
- And turn!
- [ Grunting ]
[ Screaming ]
- Oh, my eye! Help me!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
Mmm, boysenberry.
Huh?
Aah, no, no, no, no, no!
[ Grunting ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Moaning ] Oh, the pain!
There goes my magic act!
- Flaming gas!
- No! P.T.!
[ Screaming ]
A direct hit! Ah-hee-ha!
- [ Screaming ]
- Run!
- [ Gasps ]
- Flik! Help us!
[ Snarls ]
[ Gasps ]
Dot!
[ Flik ]
Okay! Everyone out! Hurry!
[ Coughing ]
Where's Dot?
Anyone seen Dot?
- [ Screaming ]
- Whose idea was this?
Huh?
Was it yours, Princess?
Just get behind me, girls.
It'll be okay.
[ Flik ]
Leave her alone, Hopper.
The bird was my idea.
I'm the one you want.
[ Snapping ]
[ Shrieking ]
[ Blows Landing,
Flik Grunting ]
- Ohh.
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Shrieking ]
- [ Snapping ]
[ Growling ]
Where do you get the gall
to do this to me?
[ Panting ] You were--
You were gonna squish the queen.
- [ All Gasping ]
- It's true.
I hate it when someone
gives away the ending.
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Moaning ]
You piece of dirt!
No, I'm wrong.
You're lower than dirt.
You're an ant!
Let this be a lesson
to all you ants.
Ideas are very dangerous things.
You are mindless,
soil-shoving losers,
put on this earth to serve us!
[ Flik ]
You're wrong, Hopper.
[ Inhaling Deeply ] Ants are not meant
to serve grasshoppers!
I've seen these ants
do great things.
And year after year,
they somehow manage...
to pick food
for themselves and you.
So-So who is the weaker species?
Ants don't serve grasshoppers.
It's you who need us.
[ Crowd Gasping, Chattering ]
We're a lot stronger
than you say we are.
And you know it, don't you?
[ Grunts ]
[ Chuckles ]
Well, Princess!
Umm, Hopper?
I hate to interrupt, but, um--
You ants stay back!
- Oh, this was such a bad idea!
- You see, Hopper,
nature has a certain order.
The ants pick the food,
the ants keep the food,
and the grasshoppers leave!
[ Yelling ]
- I'm so proud of you, Flik!
- Charge-a!
Where are you going?
They're just ants!
Oof!
- [ Screams ]
- [ Snarls ]
No! Bad grasshopper!
Bad grasshopper! Go home!
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Roaring Louder ]
[ Whining, Yelping ]
- [ Chuckles ]
- Yeah!
[ Hopper ] Come back here,
you cowards! Don't leave!
- [ Flik ] To the cannon!
- [ Ants ] To the cannon!
[ Hopper ]
No!
[ Hopper Screaming ]
[ Chuckles ]
Happy landings, Hopper!
- [ Thunder Crashing ]
- Huh?
Rain!
[ Growling ]
[ Roaring ]
- Flik!
- Quick! After them!
- Yaah!
- Aah! Aah!
Aah! Slim!
- Francis! Francis! Francis, I'm stuck!
- Where are ya?
- I'm over here! Here!
- Where?
I'm the only stick with eyeballs!
- Help! Help!
- Get him!
- Yes! Yes!
- [ Thunder Crashing ]
No!
- [ Giggling ]
- [ Chattering ]
[ Screaming ]
- Go that way! I've got an idea!
- But the anthill's over--
- [ Hopper Roaring ]
- [ Atta Screaming ]
- Flik!
- Come on!
[ Screaming ]
[ Flik ]
There!
[ Atta Grunts ]
Come on!
We've gotta hide!
No matter what happens,
stay down!
Flik, no!
What are you doing?
- Uh-- Hopper!
- You think it's over?
No, no, no.
No, I-I can explain.
- All your little stunt did
was buy them time!
- No, please!
Please, Hopper!
I'll get more grasshoppers
and be back next season,
but you won't!
[ Chirping ]
- [ Choking ]
- Well, what's this?
Another one of
your little bird tricks?
- Yup.
- Are there a bunch of little
girls in this one too?
- Hello, girls!
- [ Screeching ]
[ Screaming In Terror ]
No! No!
No, no, no, no!
No! Aah!
[ Screaming ] No!
Oh, no!
Oh, no! No, no, no!
[ Screams ]
[ Horn Blowing ]
Come on, boys!
- Hey, Princess Dot! Wait up!
- [ Giggling ]
[ Sighs ]
I finally get a second to relax,
and I gotta get out of my chair.
- Come on! You can rub lotion
on me later, shade boy.
- Yeah, hubba-hubba.
[ Both Laughing ]
- [ Laughing, Chattering ]
- [ Heimlich ] Oh, thank you!
- Oh, you're too kind!
- It was the least we could do.
All in a day's work.
Dim!
- Ohh!
- [ Kids ] Ohh!
I'm so sorry, kids.
I wish you could come along too.
- [ Kids Weeping ]
- I'm not gonna cry. I'm not gonna cry.
[ Chattering ]
[ Laughing ]
Hey, let's go. We got a schedule
to keep. Come on, let's go.
- Hup, hup, hey!
- Hey, Tiny!
Let's get this show packed up!
We got paying customers hatching!
Yes, Mr.Flea. Yes, sir.
Of course, sir. Right away, sir.
And, um, I just wanted to
thank you for giving me a chance,
because it's an honor to work
with creative giants such as yourself.
- Shutting up.
- You sure you can't
come on tour with us?
- Sorry. My place is here.
- Good answer.
Oh, well. Your loss.
One minute, insects!
I wanna thank all of you...
for giving us back our hope,
our dignity, and our lives.
And to you, Princess Atta.
You have given us so much.
Please accept this gift
from us bugs...
to you ants.
- For you!
- Oh! It's a rock.
- [ Chuckling ]
- What's with the rock?
Must be a circus thing.
[ Giggling ]
Well, Flik, you really goofed up.
- Thanks.
- Yeah, you too.
[ Gasps ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
- [ Giggling ]
- [ Sniffling ] All right.
Now it's gettin' mushy.
- We're outta here! Hy-aah!
- [ Whip Cracking ]
- Whoa!
- [ Rosie ] See ya next season!
- [ Francis ] See ya, Flik!
- Bye! We miss you already!
- You fired!
- [ Gasps ] We forgot Heimlich!
I'm finished! Finally,
I'm a beautiful butterfly!
[ Grunting ]
Mein wings!
Oh, they're beautiful!
[ Flik ] Heimlich! The wagon's
taking off! You better start flying!
But I am flying! And from way up here,
you all look like little ants!
Auf Wiedersehen!
Bye!
Present stalks!
Harvester, salute!
Was a bug, little bug
Hardly there
How he felt, what he dreamed
Who would care
- Without any evidence
- His flaws were many, ooh
- He was full of confidence
- Some people haven't any
- Didn't have much common sense
- It's highly overrated
He just knew
that he'd come through
It's the time of your life
So live it well
We may only go round one time
As far as I can tell
It's the time of your life
So live it well
We may only go round
this one time
- As far as I can tell
- He could be wrong about me
- It's the time of your life
- Time, life
It's the time of your life
So live it well
- [ Beeping ]
- Speed!
- Marker.
- [ Director ] And-- action!
- Are you saying I'm stupid?
- No!
- Do I look stupid... to you?
[ Laughs Hysterically ]
- I'm sorry!
- [ Beeping ]
- Are you saying I'm stupid? Oh--
- [ Laughing ]
- I'm sorry! I got it.
No, no. Do it again. I'm fine.
- [ Beeping ]
- Are you saying I'm stupid?
- Yes! [ Laughing ]
This is the 15th take.
I cannot work like this.
- I will be in my trailer.
- I need a break.
- [ Beeping ]
- Marker.
- Whoa, Flik honey,
we are not about to--
- [ Banging ]
- Is someone hammering?
- [ Sighs ]
- Could we hold the work, please? People?
- [ Ringing ]
Am I in this shot?
You can see me, right?
- [ Beeping ]
- And-- action!
To infinity, and beyond!
- [ Laughing ]
- I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
Really, can you blame me?
- Okay, let's go for real now. Sorry.
- Okay, cut!
Why go back to Ant Island at all?
- I mean, you don't even like grain.
- What?
You're right. I didn't think
it was such a good idea myself.
- Actually, it wasn't
even my idea. It was--
- Watch it!
- [ Crashing ]
- I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Is the camera broke?
Oh, oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry. Did I ruin the take?
- [ Beeping ]
- And thank you for findin' 'em, Flik.
Me? Oh, oops, ow, ow.
- Ow, ow, ow!
- Uh, oh, oh no. Oh no, oh--
- This really hurts, guys.
Can we cut? Ow!
- I'm sorry, I'm s-- Oh!
[ Beeping ]
So, is there a Mrs.Ant
you have to tunnel home to?
Oh, I'm sorry!
I thought he was real.
[ Laughing ] Ooh, dear.
Put that thing in my car.
- [ Beeping ]
- Marker.
Flik, after much deliberation--
[ Screaming ]
- [ Rattling, Banging ]
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Beeping ]
- Ohh, I-- Ow. Oh. My eye!
Oh. No, no. Seriously,
I've got berry juice in my eye!
- [ Laughing Fiendishly ]
- It stings! Stop acting. I'm serious.
- Oh, stop the camera!
- [ Beeping ]
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Gurgling, Liquid Trickling ]
Uh-oh. Towel!
I need a towel over here!
[ Laughing ]
- [ Breaking Wind ]
- [ Director ] Cut!
- [ Beeping ]
- [ Shrieking ] I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- [ Groaning ]
- Can we-- Can we cut? It's just
I don't think I'm comin' across.
Hmm. Oh, oh, I know. I know.
I could lather up a bunch of spit.
Ooh, ooh, that's good.
I got it, J.L. One more for me.
- [ Beeping ]
- Speed!
- Marker!
Action!
Spinning a web of safety
in less than 50-- Bleh!
It's the time of your life
So live it well
We may only go round one time
As far as I can tell
It's the time of your life
So live it well
Like us all he started small
Then he grew
When the time came he knew
What to do
- He knew in order to succeed
- They'd have to work together
- He turned a rock into a seed
- And they were changed forever
Then they had the strength
they'd need
- To get through stormy weather
- Do or die, you gotta try
It's the time of your life
So live it well
You may only go round one time
- As far as I can tell
- You may be wrong about me
It's the time of your life
So live it well
Isn't it a bit surprising
How our fortunes ebb and flow
And only to the enterprising
Does the magic fortune cookie go
Believe me
It's the time of your life
So live it well
We may only go round one time
As far as I can tell
It's the time of your life
So live it well