Charles, you have
finally lost your senses.
This venture is impossible.
For some. Gentlemen, the only way
to achieve the impossible
is to believe it is possible.
That kind of thinking could ruin you.
I'm willing to take that chance.
Imagine trading posts
in Rangoon, Bangkok, Jakarta...
The nightmare again?
I won't be long.
I'm falling down a dark hole,
then I see strange creatures.
What kind of creatures?
Well, there's a dodo bird,
a rabbit in a waistcoat, a smiling cat.
I didn't know cats could smile.
(SIGHING) Neither did I.
And there's a blue caterpillar.
Blue caterpillar.
Hmm.
Do you think I've gone round the bend?
I'm afraid so.
You're mad, bonkers, off your head.
But I'll tell you a secret.
All the best people are.
(LAUGHING)
It's only a dream, Alice.
Nothing can harm you there.
But if you get too frightened,
you can always wake up. Like this.
(LAUGHING) Ow!
(SIGHING)
Must we go?
Doubt they'll notice if we never arrive.
They will notice.
Where's your corset?
And no stockings.
I'm against them.
But you're not properly dressed.
Who's to say what is proper?
What if it was agreed that "proper"
was wearing a codfish on your head?
- Would you wear it?
- Alice.
To me, a corset is like a codfish.
Please, not today.
Father would have laughed.
I'm sorry. I'm tired.
I didn't sleep well last night.
Did you have bad dreams again?
Only one.
It's always the same,
ever since I can remember.
Do you think that's normal?
Don't most people
have different dreams?
I don't know.
There. You're beautiful.
Now, can you manage a smile?
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
At last. We thought you'd never arrive.
Alice, Hamish is waiting
to dance with you. Go.
You do realize it's well past 4:00.
Now everything will have
to be rushed through.
- I am sorry.
- Oh, never mind!
Forgive my wife. She's been planning
this affair for over 20 years.
If only Charles were here...
My condolences.
I think of your husband often.
He was truly a man of vision.
I hope you don't think I've taken
advantage of your misfortunes.
Of course not. I'm pleased
that you purchased the company.
I was a fool for not investing in
his mad venture when I had the chance.
Charles thought so, too.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
Hamish, do you ever tire of quadrille?
On the contrary. I find it invigorating.
(LAUGHS)
Do I amuse you?
No.
I had a sudden vision
of all the ladies in trousers
and the men wearing dresses.
I think you'll do best
to keep your visions to yourself.
When in doubt, remain silent.
(GEESE HONKING)
(GASPS)
Pardon us, sir.
Miss Kingsleigh is distracted today.
Where's your head?
I was wondering
what it would be like to fly.
Why would you spend your time
thinking about
such an impossible thing?
Why wouldn't I?
My father said he sometimes believed
in six impossible things
before breakfast.
(SOFTLY) Come along.
Alice, meet me under the gazebo
in precisely 10 minutes.
(FAITH EXHALING EX CITEDLY)
We have a secret to tell you.
If you're telling me,
then it's not much of a secret.
- Perhaps we shouldn't.
- We decided we should.
If we tell her, she won't be surprised.
- Will you be surprised?
- Not if you tell me.
But now you've brought it up,
you have to.
- No, we don't.
- In fact, we won't.
I wonder if your mother knows
that you two swim naked
in the Havershims' pond.
- You wouldn't.
- Oh, but I would.
There's your mother right now.
Hamish is going to ask for your hand.
You've ruined the surprise!
I could strangle them!
Everyone went to so much effort
to keep the secret.
Does everyone know?
It's why they've all come.
This is your engagement party.
Hamish will ask you under the gazebo.
When you say yes...
But I don't know
if I want to marry Hamish.
Who, then?
You won't do better than a lord.
You'll soon be 20, Alice.
That pretty face won't last forever.
You don't want to end up
like Aunt Imogene.
And you don't want to be a burden
on Mother, do you?
No.
So you'll marry Hamish.
You will be as happy
as I am with Lowell,
and your life will be perfect.
It's already decided.
Alice, dear.
I'll leave you to it.
Shall we take a leisurely stroll
through the garden, just you and me?
Do you know what I've always dreaded?
The decline of the aristocracy?
Ugly grandchildren. But you're lovely.
You're bound to produce
little... Imbeciles!
The gardeners have
planted white roses
when I specifically asked for red.
You could always paint the roses red.
What an odd thing to say.
You should know that my son
has extremely delicate digestion.
(RUSTLING)
- Did you see that?
- See what?
- It was a rabbit, I think.
- Nasty things.
I do enjoy setting the dogs on them.
If you serve Hamish the wrong foods,
he could get a blockage.
(RUSTLING)
Did you see it that time?
- See what?
- The rabbit.
Don't shout.
Now, pay attention.
Hamish said you were easily distracted.
- What was I saying?
- Hamish has a blockage.
I couldn't be more interested,
but you'll have to excuse me.
Aunt Imogene.
I think I'm going mad.
I keep seeing a rabbit in a waistcoat.
I can't be bothered
with your fancy rabbit now.
I'm waiting for my fiancé.
- You have a fiancé?
- Hmm.