Mozart!
Forgive your assassin!
I confess,I killed you!
"S?,I killed you,Mozart.
Mozart,"piet?! Forgive your assassin!
Forgive me,Mozart!
Signore Salieri, open the door,be good now!
"Signore",we have something special for you.
Something you're going to love.
Is that good!
"Signore",believe me...
...this is the most delicious thing I ever ate in my life!
Really,you don't know what you're miss...
All right,that's enough! Open the door.
"Signore",if you don't open this door...
...we're gonna leave nothing for you.
And I'm never gonna come see you again!
Good morning,Father.
Herr Salieri?
Leave me alone.
I cannot leave alone a soul in pain.
Do you know who I am?
That makes no difference.
All men are equal in God's eyes.
Are they?
Offer me your confession.
I can offer you God's forgiveness.
How well are you trained in music?
I know a little. I studied it in my youth.
- Where? - Here in Vienna.
Then you must know this.
I can't say that I do.
What is it?
It was a very popular tune in its day.
I wrote it.
Here,how about this?
This one brought down the house when we played it.
Well?
I regret it is not too familiar.
Can you recall no melody of mine?
I was the most famous composer in Europe.
I wrote 40 operas alone.
Here!
What about this one?
Yes,I know that!
That's charming!
I'm sorry,I didn't know you wrote that.
I didn't.
That was Mozart.
Wolfgang...
...Amadeus Mozart.
The man you accuse yourself of killing.
You've heard that?
Is it true?
For God's sake,my son...
...if you have something to confess, do it now.
Give yourself some peace.
He...
...was my idol.
Mozart.
I can't think of a time when I didn't know his name.
I was playing games...
... when he was playing music for kings and emperors.
Even the pope in Rome.
I admit,I was jealous...
... when I heard the tales they told about him.
Not of the brilliant little prodigy...
... but of his father, who had taught him everything.
My father,he did not care for music.
When I told him...
...how I wished I could be like Mozart...
... he would say,"Why? Do you want to be a trained monkey?
You'd like me to drag you around, doing tricks like a circus freak?"
How could I tell him...
...what music meant to me?
While my father prayed earnestly to God...
... to protect commerce...
... I would offer up...
... secretly...
... the proudest prayer a boy could think of.
"Lord,make me a great composer."
"Let me celebrate your glory through music...
... and be celebrated myself."
"Make me famous through the world."
"Make me immortal."
"After I die...
...let people speak my name with love for what I wrote."
"In return...
...I will give you my chastity...
...my industry...
...my deepest humility, every hour of my life."
"Amen."
And do you know what happened?
A miracle!
My life changed forever.
I knew God had arranged it all. That was obvious.
One minute I was a frustrated boy...
...in an obscure little town. The next I was here...
...in Vienna,city of musicians...
... and Emperor Joseph, the musical king.
In a few years,I was his court composer. Isn't that incredible?
Every night I sat with the emperor of Austria...
... playing duets with him...
... correcting the royal sight-reading.
Actually,the man had no ear at all.
But what did it matter?
He adored my music.
Tell me...
If you had been me...
...wouldn't you have thought God had accepted your vow?
And believe me,I honored it.
I was a model of virtue.
I kept my hands off women.
I worked hours every day teaching students,many for free!
Sitting on endless committees to help poor musicians.
Work,that was all my life.
And it was wonderful.
Everybody liked me.
I liked myself.
Until he came.
He came to Vienna to play some of his music...
...at the residence of the Prince Archbishop of Salzburg.
Eagerly,I went there to seek him out.
That night...
... changed my life.
As I wandered through the salon...
... I played a little game with myself.
This man had written his first concerto at the age of 4...
... his first symphony at 7, a full-scale opera at 12!
Did it show?
Is talent like that...
... written on the face?
Which one of them...
... could he be?
Mozart is not here.
- Stop it! - I am.
- Stop it! - I am stopping it.
I am! I'm stopping it. Slowly.
There. You see? I've stopped.
- Now we're going back. - No!
Yes! You don't know where you are.
Here,everything goes backwards.
People walk and dance and sing and even talk backwards.
- That's stupid. - Why? People fart backwards.
Ssa-ym-ssik!
Yes,you are. You are very sick.
No! Say it backwards,shitwit!
Ssa-ym-ssik.
Ssik,kiss.
Ym,my. Ssa.
Kiss my ass.
Em-yrram!
- I'm not playing! - Say it,it's serious.
It's very serious.
Yrram.
Marry me.
I'm not gonna marry you. You're a fiend.
Uoy-evol-I-tub.
Tub.
But I...
...love...
But I love you?
- Tihs-ym-tae. - What?
- Eat. - Eat.
- Ym,my. - My.
Tihs. Eat my shit.
You filthy fiend!
You filthy...!
My music.
They've started without me.
That was Mozart!
That giggling,dirty creature I'd just seen crawling on the floor.
- I think that went well,don't you? - Indeed.
The Viennese know good music, don't you think?
Certainly.
Your Grace.
Ah,Mozart.
- Why? - Why what,sir?
Why do I have to be humiliated in front of my guests...
...by one of my own servants?
The more license I allow you, the more you take.
If His Grace is not satisfied, he can dismiss me.
I wish you to return immediately to Salzburg.
- Your father is waiting for you there. - No,Your Grace!
I would prefer you dismissed me. It's obvious I don't satisfy.
I have no intention of dismissing you. You will remain in my service...
...and learn your place.
On the page it looked...
Nothing!
The beginning simple,almost comic.
Just a pulse.
Bassoons,basset horns...
...like a rusty squeezebox.
And then,suddenly...
...high above it...
...an oboe.
A single note,hanging there, unwavering.
Until...
...a clarinet took it over...
...sweetened it into a phrase of such delight.
This was no composition by a performing monkey.
This was a music I had never heard.
Filled with such longing, such unfulfillable longing.
It seemed to me I was hearing the voice of God.
Excuse me.
But why?
Why would God choose an obscene child to be his instrument?
It was not to be believed.
This piece had to be an accident. It had to be.
It better be.
How good is he,this Mozart?
He's remarkable,Majesty. I heard an extraordinary opera of his last month.
-Idomeneo,King of Crete.  - That?
A tiresome piece. I heard it too.
Tiresome?
A young man trying to impress beyond his abilities.
Too much spice.
Too many notes.
Majesty...
...it was the most promising work I've heard in years.
Then,we should make some effort to acquire him.
We could use a good German composer in Vienna,surely?
I'm sure he could be tempted with the right offer. Say...
...an opera in German for our National Theater.
Excellent,sire!
But not German. I beg,Your Majesty.
Italian is the proper language for opera.
All educated people agree on that.
What do you think,chamberlain?
In my opinion,it's time we had a piece in our own language.
Plain German for plain people.
Kapellmeister?
Majesty...
...I must agree with "Herr Direttore".
German is...
...too brute for singing.
Court composer...
...what do you think?
I think it's an interesting notion to keep Mozart in Vienna.
It should infuriate the archbishop...
...if that is Your Majesty's intention.
You are "cattivo",court composer.
I want to meet this young man. Arrange a pleasant welcome for him.
Well,there it is!
This is a beautiful wig for you.
It looks so marvelous and I love it.
The other one.
Here is the other one. I think you will love it.
Here's the third one. So? Here we go.
- How do you like it? - They're all so beautiful!
Why don't I have three heads?
This is funny!
Three heads!
Gentlemen.
- Good morning. - Morning,Your Majesty.
What do you have for me today?
- Your Majesty,"Herr Mozart". - Yes,what about him?
He's here.
Well,there it is. Good!
I hope you won't find it improper, but I've written a march in his honor.
What a charming idea,court composer. May I see?
Just a...
Just a trifle,of course.
May I try it?
Let's have some fun.
Delightful,court composer!
May I play it when he comes in?
- You do me too much honor. - Bring in "Herr Mozart".
But slowly.
I need a minute to practice.
Good,continue.
G,Majesty.
Excellent!
Good,Majesty.
Continue. Very good.
Very good,Majesty.
Tempo! Up.
Lightly,then strongly! It's a march,Majesty.
Again.
Bravo,Majesty!
Gentlemen,please. A little less enthusiasm,I beg you.
No,please. It's not a holy relic.
You know,we have met before. In this very room.
You don't recall. You were only 6. He was giving a delightful concert!
As he got off the stool,he fell.
My sister Antoinette helped him up. Know what he did?
He jumped into her arms and said, "Will you marry me? Yes or no?"
You know all these gentlemen. The Baron Van Swieten.
- I'm a great admirer of yours. - Thank you.
Kapellmeister Bonno.
My pleasure.
The Director of Opera, Count Orsini-Rosenberg.
Sir,yes. The honor is mine, absolutely!
Here is our illustrious court composer...
...Maestro Salieri.
At last,such immense joy!
I know your work well.
You know,I composed some variations on a melody of yours.
- Really? Which one? - "Mio Caro Adone."
I'm flattered.
A funny tune, but it yielded good things.
And now he has returned the compliment.
"Herr Salieri" composed this little march for you.
Really?
Well,there it is.
Down to business. We're going to commission an opera from you.
What do you say?
Did we vote in the end for German or Italian?
Sire,if you remember, we did finally incline to Italian.
Did we?
I don't think it was really decided, Your Majesty.
- German. Please let it be German. - Why so?
Because I've already found the most wonderful libretto.
Have I seen it?
I don't think you have,"Herr Direktor". It's quite new.
- I'll show it to you immediately. - I think you'd better.
Well...
...tell us about it. Tell us the story.
Well,it's quite amusing,Majesty.
It's set... The whole thing is set in a...
Yes? Where?
In a harem,Majesty. In a seraglio.
- You mean in Turkey? - Yes,exactly.
Then why especially does it have to be in German?
It doesn't,especially. It could be in Turkish if you really want.
No,my dear fellow,the language is not finally the point.
Do you really think that subject is appropriate for a national theater?
Why not? It's charming.
I mean,I won't actually show concubines exposing their...
It's not indecent. It's highly moral,Majesty.
It's full of proper German virtues.
Excuse me,Majesty,but what do you think these could be?
Being a foreigner,I'd love to learn.
Well,tell him,Mozart.
Name us a German virtue.
- Love,sire. - Oh,love!
Of course,in Italy we know nothing about love.
No,I don't think you do.
Watching Italian opera, all those male sopranos screeching...
...stupid,fat couples rolling their eyes about. That's not love. It's rubbish!
Majesty,you choose the language.
I'll set it to the finest music ever offered a monarch.
Well,there it is. Let it be German.
This is yours.
Keep it. It's already here in my head.
What? On one hearing only?
I think so,sire. Yes.
Show us.
The rest is just the same,isn't it?
That doesn't really work,does it?
Did you try...?
Shouldn't it be a bit more...?
Or this?
This. Yes.
Better? What do you think?
Grazie,Signore.
All I ever wanted was to sing to God.
He gave me that longing...
...and then made me mute. Why?
Tell me that.
If he didn't want me to praise him with music...
...why implant the desire...
...like a lust in my body?
And then deny me the talent?
Madame Cavalieri is here for her lesson,sir.
Maestro.
Well...?
How do you like it?
It's Turkish.
My hairdresser said everything this year's going to be Turkish.
Does he?
What else did he tell you today?
Come,come! Give me some gossip.
Well,I heard you met "Herr Mozart".
News travels fast in Vienna.
And he's been commissioned to write an opera. Is it true?
- Yes. - Is there a part in it for me?
- No. - How do you know?
- Do you know where it's set,my dear? - Where?
In a harem.
- What's that? - A brothel.
Come.
Let's begin.
- What does he look like? - Mozart?
- You might be disappointed. - Why?
Looks and talent don't always go together,Katerina.
Looks don't concern me,maestro.
Only talent interests a woman of taste.
Shall we continue?
There she was.
I don't know where they met or how.  There she stood!
On stage,for all to see.
Showing off like the greedy songbird she was.
Ten minutes of ghastly scales. Arpeggios!
Whizzing up and down like fireworks at a fairground.
Understand,I was in love with the girl.
Or at least in lust.
And I swear to you, I never laid a finger on her.
All the same,I couldn't bear to think of anyone else touching her.
Least of all,"the creature".
Brava,madame! You are an ornament to our stage.
Your Majesty.
Well,"Herr Mozart". A good effort.
Well,decidedly that.
An excellent effort! You have shown us something...
...quite new tonight. - It is new.
- It is,isn't it,sire? - Yes,indeed.
So then,you liked it? You really liked it,sire?
Well,of course I did! It's very good!
Of course,now and then, just now and then...
...it seemed a touch...
What do you mean,sire?
Well,I mean,occasionally, it seems to have...
How shall one say...?
How shall one say,"direktor"?
- Too many notes,Majesty? - Exactly. Very well put.
- Too many notes. - I don't understand.
There are just as many notes as I required,neither more nor less.
My dear fellow,there are in fact...
...only so many notes the ear can hear in an evening.
I think I'm right in saying that, aren't I,court composer?
Yes. On the whole,yes,Majesty.
This is absurd!
Young man,don't take it too hard. Your work is ingenious.
It's quality work.
And there are simply too many notes. Just cut a few and it'll be perfect.
Which few did you have in mind?
Wolfgang!
Wolfgang,my dear!
- Wolfgang! - Majesty,this is "Frau Weber".
She's my landlady.
- Enchanted,madame. - Sire,such an honor!
This is my dear daughter,Constanze.
- She's the fiancée of "Herr Mozart". - Really?
How charming. Please.
Well...
...when do you marry?
We haven't exactly received my father's consent yet.
Not entirely. Not altogether.
- Excuse me,but how old are you? - 26.
My advice is for you to marry this charming young lady...
...and stay with us in Vienna. - You see?
I told him that, but he won't listen to me.
Your Majesty, you give such wonderful...
...such royal advice. May I...?
Well,there it is.
Wolfie,will you get some water?
Will you get some water,please?
Wolfie,get some water!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Did you know?
- What? - The marriage.
What does it matter to you?
Nothing. He can marry who he pleases, I don't give a damn.
How was I?
You were sublime.
And what did you think of the music?
Extremely clever.
Katerina,I...
Excuse me.
Is that woman still lying on the floor?
- No,she's fine. - Oh,I'm so relieved.
Dear Mozart, my sincere congratulations.
- Did you like it then? - How could I not?
It's the best music in Vienna today,don't you agree?
She must be dazzling in bed.
I assume she's the virtuoso in that department.
No other reason why you'd marry someone like that.
Come in.
Excuse me. Wolfie,Mom isn't feeling very well.
- Can we go home? - Yes.
No,no,no. You can't take him away now.
This is his night.
Won't you introduce us,Wolfgang?
Excuse us,"Fräulein". Good night,"signore".