This business
is a living organism
Multiplying constantly
surrounded by predators
There's no rule for
idle time or second guessing,
New discovery are made hourly.
New ideas
are ready to be devored and redefined.
This business is binary
you are a one or a zero,
alive or dead
AntiTrust
There is no second place.
It has been suggested
by the median congress..
that you're violating antitrust laws and
threatening competition
Mr. Winston, Can you reasonably deny that
you have a monopoly in this area ?
Well, the only monopoly...
we have at N.U.R.V,
is monopoly on excellence.
It is still a free market.
But a free market encourages competition
You prevent it
You don't need to remind you the essence
of competition is always been quite simple,
Any kid working in a garage anywhere
in the world with a good idea can put us out of business
Let's try a communication scheme
if you have a good driver..
Move, move
Teddy, I think I have found
our bottle neck
You did it !
Yee-Haw!!
God! That feels good
Gorgeous!
We're geeks
Three months from today,
N.U.R.V will launch Synapes
transforming the way
humans communicate,
With Synaps,
the entire world will be able
to send or receive
any message be in audio, video
or text on any medium
any medium, any medium, ...
SYNAPSE will fully unite
the global village.
You set yourself real ticking clock here, Gary
All of your competitor are desperate to get
to the market place with this technology before you.
It has even been suggested that you won't hit
this very ambitious launch date
We're going to hit that date,
you can bet on it
How can you be sure?
We'll do whatever it takes
to get there
Pace yourself, Brian
It can go here
Milo, what do you think of this?
I know I promise my mom
we're gonna make this garage famous
but I really don't think
we're gonna be here that long
'Cause I’ve got us 3 appointment
with the venture capitalists
Oh, that is fantastic
I can stop taking calls from
those corporate recruitment, losers
I'll do the talking, Brian
Guys, what are these?
Don't you know the worse you look,
the smarter they think you are
They are going to think
you're a genius, Brian
I just have Milo and Ted,
and the wallets flew open,
They were dying to give me their money.
You guys are the greatest duo,
since Hewlett and Packard
Lenon and McCartney
Ben and Jerry
Ha Ha Ha
I'm Lennon, okay Teddy
Does that make me Yoko?
Look Alice, you got to make him
do the start up with Teddy and me
Larry, if he wants to go and take a few interviews
check out his options as his friend
I think you should support him in that
What to know the best way
to manipulate somebody
Yeah
Don't try
As graduating students
of the Standford University, Science department,
you have a magnificent foundation in theory
what you need is a creative innovative...
A monopolist
Exactly
the guy knows how to get peoples attention
Shut up, shut up, shut up
I'm trying to listen !
who will fill your questions?
Thanks for taking the time to check us out
I look forward to seeing some of you up here
at the NURV campus, in the near future
Questions, cool
I got a question for him, alright?
Why not make SYNAPSE open source?
Don't you have enough money?
Huh, nice
Here is an interesting question
What kind of beverage do you
offer your programmer?
Oh come on
He is avoiding the issue, man !
He should run for president or something
I'm just going to throw these at you, you know,
like they do at the zoo
Hello?
It's for you
Hello
Milo, this is Gary Winston,
I've heard great things about your work,
I'm hoping you and your friend Teddy
can come up here.
Hey, Larry, you still have got
my Union Jack CD
No, I gave it back..
Ok, I don't know who this is but
your timing really blows
'cause I just saw him in a live chat
Right, well, a pair of airline tickets are
on there way to you,
I would love to show you
some of the things we are doing here
Who was it ?
Garry Winston
Ha, that would be funny
I just spoke to Garry Winston?
I can't believe you are not going to take that ticket
Give it to me!
You don't want to work there, Brian
They squeeze everybody out of business,
they get bigger and fatter
That's why I want to work there
You sure he didn't ask for my number?
Milo, we can't go up there
They don't even know
the meaning of open source
You know this,
we have talked about this
They just want to own everything
They clone stuff, they reverse engineering it
I, I know. / Everybody is stuck
with their inferior proprietary version
They are being investigated
by the justice department for christs’ sake
Tell him, Harry
I think that he should go up there and
check it out if he is curious
You do?
Sure, I mean it's your life
I need another beer
So, you couldn't convince
your friend Teddy to come home
No, he is pretty tight with his folks
You know we can move them up here
same goes for yours
My parents are dead
I'm sorry man
So how far is the campus?
We're not going to campus.
All I can say is it's unfortunate,
we offered a lot of money.
A substantial amount of money, Gary, no sell
Can we buy into their stock?
Or is that a justice department problem too?
There is no stock, Randy
I mean there's no company
Garry Winston's office
May I help you?
Thanks for holding. Yes, he is in a conference
right now. Can I take a message?
The cold, hard facts are
that anything is possible.
Anything, anything you're just not
thinking creatively.
I have every confidence that you can do that, Phil.
- This is difficult one but we're gonna prevail
- Alright, alright
Garry Winston's office
Let me check that for you
I'm sorry, I don't see anything here
Milo
Hi.. not every day
we have genius in the house
- Want a soda pop or something?
- No, thanks
Come on in
Digital canvas
The house knows the paintings I like,
knows my favorite music,
same for anybody else
that's in the system
There's a little sensor
that defects who's in the room
Doesn't Bill Gates have
something like that?
Bill who? ha, ha. ah,
no, no. his is primitive.
So I understand you are thinking of
doing a start up
Yeah.
My friends and I have been planning on
doing a media delivery system for a long time
It would be open source, we offer it free
to everybody, just charge for tech support.
Wow, free.
It's a cut-throat business we're in Milo
It's just a matter of time before someone borrows
your technology, improves it and makes a billion dollars on it.
What would you do with a billion dollars Milo?
Mmm, I don't know
I'll tell you what you could do
You could take that money and put it back into
technology, education, the arts
You can transform culture
I founded opera companies, symphony orchestras,
museums, theatres, ..
I have donated thousands of computers
to schools through out the country
The question
really is,
How many of the people you share discoveries with
will be outulistic?
and how many will make fortunes of
your generosity?
Come on in here
Check this out.
huh
- This is the SYNAPSE satellite.
- You bet.
I have 240 of these up there
12 different orbital patterns,
20 satellites,
mother satellite of each ring
passes over us
every night at 10 o'clock
to allow for station keeping,
re-programming, etc.
They in turn pass the data along
to the sister satellites in their realm
That's the coolest I ever seen.
I'm total wrapped up in this
It's like I’ve got my mission control
right here on my PC
Activation codes,
IP address, flight pass..
- It's the best train set ever, hum?
- You bet
We've loaded a back door
to receive SYNAPSE transmissions
and all of our OS software
for the past 6 years,
We've developed compression schemes and
file formats that achieve connectivity, but..
We have a problem
You know what that problem is?
Ah, your adaptors can't overcome
the band width limitation of wireless hand helds
That's right
Data takes too long to download
so your image get's..
Image, ah, goes fuzzy
- Fussy, yeah,
- Ha ha
Can you get this done in time
to meet your date?
With you, I can
So I understand your friend Teddy is
kind of attached to his parents.
It's very commendable
Ah, the truth is he's ah..
Milo, I know, he thinks
we're cloned
too many programs
an forced people to buy our inferior versions
and blah, blah, blah..
add infinite item and nauseousm
I've heard it all before.
I even understand it,
it's the nature of competitive business.
When you're on top
people attack the quality
of your product.
It comes with the territory
So when the attacks get personal
that Gary Winston is satan web sites,
digitising my wife's face on porn star bodies
I don't like that
You're one of maybe
twenty programmers in the world
with the mastery it going to
take to finish this thing
We'd love for you to join us
The future holds limitless possibilities, Milo
You decide what the future holds for you.
Let me know
You know I look at you and
see something I haven't seen in 20 years
- What?
- I see me!
- Alice
- Umm,
So when is Brian coming from the T.V?
I don't know
I'm going to leave you two alone, o.k?
Why are you doing this?
Teddy, come on
He can't hit his date without you, can he?
Remember that lecture Ginnings gave?
about open source
Yeah
He said human knowledge
belongs to the world
Like Shakespeare or Asprin
Teddy, I know you are disappointed,
I just feel like this is the right thing
to do for now,
They were interested in you too,
Gary even mentioned you
Yeah, well.. I'm not interested in them
That's fine.
I get what's important to you
This is important to me.
And I know your are going to
get your venture capital
We did, We had to settle for 850,
because we lost you
So, it will be enough.
It'll be enough because they got you
We're both going to do something great
Sure
I just thought we were
going to do it together
Milo, this is Mr. Barton
from the...
Department of Justice
- Sorry about the glass
- No problem
How are you, Milo. I am here as a friend
I understand you signed up
with Gary Winston
You know Milo, we're at
a great disadvantage with NURV
I mean our experts are not
as smart as theirs
The truth is we could do with a real smart guy
on our team to help pick our fights
Ha, I’m going to take a real shot
in the dark here, O.K?
I can offer you $42,000
a year and a Buick
if you change your mind and join us.
I'm hoping you have a feeling
that is the right thing to do
Well, I’m sure what you're doing
is important, Mr. Barton
I just fell like this is a...
kind of my time to make my mark
Well, like I said,
it is a shot in the dark
No, no, no,
please, please, keep it.
If you see something up there
that rubs you the wrong way
do the right thing
What are they building?
Oh, That's a...
Building number 21
it's way behind schedule.
It's still off limits.
It's our digital broadcast base.
Taking forever to get the fiber optics
linked in there
This is the day care center
Gary has put a lot of money in there.
And the people with kids are not hot shot geeks
or anything. They just payroll clerk or whatever
That's cool
I know, that's really cool
The card is encoded.
It tells who came through the door
and when
If you see a tailgater
that someone coming on your swipe, report him
If you see someone wandering around without ID,
it is your duty to challenge him
I don't give a shit
if you are a stock option billionaire
If you don't challenge,
I'll have your butt
He seems a little tense
Oh, ??? , yeah, yeah
He gets his chain pulled a lot
by the geeks around here
because he is non-tech
Because he is a ex-cop or whatever
Whoa..a, Lisa actually looked at you
She has a heavy graphics background
She's programming scalable user interfaces
for the SYNAPSE modules
She's a smart girl
Every geek has a thing for Lisa, but
she won't let anyone get near her
I have a girl friend
What ?
you got like, you got like a girl friend
A 3 dimensional girl friend
That's really rare around here
So, welcome to the egg
Ah.., everybody listen up
Can I have your attention, please
This is Milo. Milo, This is everybody
Hello, Milo
This is Lori, Dorren..
You'll get to know everybody, I’m sure
And this is your world
Your are now officially an egg man
Whew...
Wheeww
Ah, oh, O.K,
so we got a, electronic copy of
Gary's book with complementary player, as well as
an audio version narrated
by Gary of course.
A.. hand held digy, cell phone, and
the keys to your brand new car
Guess that's it man
A, your counselor will be by to fill you
in on the rest of the details
You're going to love it here
- Thank you and thanks for...
- My pleasure,
Good luck
Hey, Milo,
Just a little advice,
don't get to close to Stinky
You're hysterical Dessy
What do they do for a village idiot
when you're here?
Dude, What do they do with all the air fresheners
when you're here / I don't know
Busy?
No,
umm, I just actually waiting for my counselor
to come by and introduce himself
Oh, hello Milo, I’m Gary
Okay
Come on let me introduce you
to the rest of the team
Hey, Stinky
Oh, Hi, Gary,
how's it going?
Hi Gary, how's it going
Dessy and Stinky are
working on compression
Josh and Vancat are
writing protocol handlers
This is Milo
- Milo is working on the all important adaptor
- Alright, Milo
When I announce the launch date
for SYNAPSE
it wasn't arbitrary,
but it wasn't based on
our progress either, as you know
If we do not have a workable version of
SYNAPSE by then, it's over folks
And this is the glib of little headline
you will be seeing through out the world
-
- Not gonna happen, is it?
- No
- Is it?
Not going.. to happen
There are no constraints, no boundaries
Surprise me,
challenge me,
Defy me,
Defy yourselves
You have a choice.
You can be forgotten,
or you can be remembered
as one of the noble few
who made it
Now's the time,
to go way beyond your potential
to dig down deep folks.
Now's the time,
to show why you are the elite
The chosen few.
The rare lights that give
this company
its uniqueness
its lumineses.
Now's the time to shine
Corporate condo's are almost
as romantic as they sound associate
She brought me here.
Well, I think it's...
I...
What do you think?
Did I tell you he has never been
anyone's counselor before?
I did.
I'm sorry the house is great
It's great and so are you
Yeah Yeah, yeah, yeah
- Really?
- Really.
- Come on, I love you
- You do?
Show me the bedroom
most of us who write software achieve
our greatest work before 8:30
As I grow older I know how important..
Are you going to keep working?
Oh, hi, Gary
In the middle of something?
- No.
- Check this out.
Huh,
huh!
Wow!
Who did this?
A Josh or a vangetta or what..
Somebody, yeah.
Think you can use it?
- Yeah,
- the compression is awesome
Struction is perfect
Ha,ha,ha
Oh, god,
oh
So much fun,
love doing this
the governor of Missouri has called
upon the president to declare a state of emergency.
In local news,
a tragic car accident took the life of Portland area
computer software entrepreneur, William Sud..
computer scientist of Messachusets Institute of technology
and a genius in his field
Sud was found to have both
protract and alcohol in his car
- Milo
- Hi
You're pretty famous around here / Yeah,
but getting a bit of a teachers pet rep.
I wouldn't worry about it
I mean you have to figure that most people
around here were their teachers pets
- Were you?
- We moved around a lot
- Barely knew my teachers
- Me too, I..
- What were you?.. An army brat or something?
- Yes, something like that
What do you got there?
I wanted to show you
the interface systems... for SYNAPSE
OK, here
I'm Lisa by the way
Yeah, I know
Hi, you have reached the office of Skullbox
Teddy and Larry are out right now,
Leave a message and we will call you back
when you are out and leave you one
Hey Teddy, it's Milo
Uh, just calling
because it has been a while and
uh, guess I’m kinda hoping
you're not still pissed at me
- Hi
- Hey, how's it going?
- OK, I guess
- And Larry?
- Good, yeah
- So, you guys making progress?
- Sorry, that's classified information,
we had to sign all those non-disclourser forms.
You know how it is
Oh yeah, yeah,
me too, me too, yeah
Still, work is not the only thing
to talk about is it?
Oh, of course not
So, what's you been up too?
Working
It's good to hear from you
Even though you are the enemy now
Gary Winston's office, can you hold please, thank you
Thank you so much for holding,
How may I help you?
Let me just check that for you
The Department of Justice says that if we acquire
net mail they will view it as anti-competitive
Well, why didn't you tell me this
before we decided to forego R and D..
Well, at the time, they indicated
that it wouldn't be a problem
But they have a bureaucratic
mind set, Gary they..
They do?
I count on you
to solve problems, whatever it takes
show me some creativity
Gary, we're talking about the law
It's not like making software,
There are limits
--;
No limits!
Stop thinking like a lawyer for a second
and show me some kind of creativity
Yes, Sir.
He'll have to get back to you
Gary Winston's office
You can go on in, Milo
Gary Winston's office.
Yes, he is in a conference right now,
May I take a message?
Gary
- You wanted to see me?
- Yeah,
Take a look
This is amazing.
Who's doing all this?
What does that mean?
- What does that mean, huh?
- Nothing, I, I...
I'm sorry
that wasn't meant for you
Justice Department is driving me nuts
They make everything strategic I do,
look sorted
Every good chess player knows his
opponents moves before he makes them
Everyone in business tries to get ahead
I get there first,
I’m a bad guy
What are we doing here?
Are we making chemical weapons?
Kiddy porn?
Are we strip mining?
No!
Why are they after me?
The software business
is binary
you're a one or a zero,
alive or dead
- It scares, don't you think?
- Definitely, yeah
It’s your copy
I don't want to speak too soon,
but I think I cracked it, Larry
I really think I cracked it
Huh
Are you going to tell me
what's bothering you are not?
- Ok
- Ok.
Gary gave me a
new compression scheme today
I said " Who's doing all this ",
cause I was impressed
I wanted to know where
it was coming from
Right ?
He just lost it, like...
he was, he shouted at me,
he had this look in his eyes, like..
How horrible!
Yeah
- But where did it come from?
- I don't know
That's what I’ve been asking myself
I asked around. Nobody knows
anything about it, uh.
You know, so does he have
some genius stored away somewhere?
And if does, why not
let him write SYNAPSE?
- I not saying if makes any sense...
- Hey! Honey
Sesame Seeds.
Jesus.
Excuse me...
Could you take that away, thank you
- I'm so stupid
- Hey!
He is a genius. Don't forget.
If anybody other than you could
write this thing as quickly as you're saying
wouldn't it maybe be him?
- Yes, yes, you are right,
The guy's a genius,
SYNAPSE is all he cares about
and I’m being over sensitive for a change
To geniuses
You know what?
Sometimes it helps to get out of here.
Just for an hour or so.
Hey, Milo
Brain
Just dropped off my resume,
Nearly got in the door.
You're living up here now?
I'm systems administrator
at the load public access station,
Where any whack Job
with 100 bucks gets his own show.
God is it suck.
Can you help me?
- Put it the word
- I'll see what I can do. Yeah
- Well, I’m parked illegally
- Ok.
They pushed up all the schedules
on the SYNAPSE's applications
How fast you go?
There is no second place.
Plus every time I get jammed up.
Gary comes up with something.
Did uh... Gary give you a new design
or something? - Yeah
I must have offended him,
'cause he a...
he yelled at me.
People don't ever just,
like, hand you stuff
Maybe once.
I reconfigured it anyway.
You're compulsive.
Moments,
precious moments
that you want to hold
that you want to share,
at home, at school, at work.
You'll keep in touch with the one's
you love through SYNAPSE
the first satellite delivered
global communications system
Share live voices, music, pictures
or video, data or text,
with anyone, anywhere, instantly...
Look, Daddy
SYNAPSE links every
communication device on the planet.
Because every moment matters.
I think you do
- Hi, honey
- Hi
I didn't expect ..ah..
Uh.. Lisa this is my...
this is Alice..
Lisa is doing the user interfaces
for SYNAPSE. - Oh
Hi
Milo tells me
you are a really great artist
Oh, yeah he always exaggerates.
Well um, I got a lot to do..
it was nice to meet you.
How are you?
I'm so surprised
- Are you ok? Is everything alright?
- Yeah yeah.
No. I just wanted to come out
and you know. ..see what these faces like.
- It's really good to see you.
- Yeah.
What did the girl say?
There maybe a little less trust
after you snapped at him
- It hasn't effected his work though.
- Nothing does.
It's pretty amazing.
What's wrong?
Teddy's been killed.
They've done this before.
Just never killed anybody until now.
But it's their writing
on the wall
Their hate literature
was scattered everywhere
They hold MO, it's like they were
asking to be caught.
And they've been arrested twice
for beating up Asians.
How come they weren't in jail?
People told us to be careful
in this neighborhood.
I guess he didn't take them
too seriously.
Yeah. well.
that's our problem.
We don't take anything seriously, do we?
It's not on the hard drive.
Hey, I didn't know you guys
were working with fiber optics.
We're just a bounch of crazy assholes.
And he was on the verge of something.
He was right there.
He was going to show us the next day.
He told me, I should get the VC to line up
appointment with a bunch of companies.
You know.
He said, the answer is not in the box.
It's in the band.
- You know I called him last week to uh...
'cause... - I know.
He was happy you did.
Be strong, Larry
Milo.
- May I join you?
- Yeah
Heard about what happened.
- I'm very sorry.
- Thanks
Had you talked to him... much, lately?
Just once.
Things weren't that great between us
and we couldn't talk about work
because it was off limits.
Did you have something
you wanted to show me?
- Look. we can save it for another day.
- No, it's okay. I..
it will help take my mind off things.
Really
- Yeah. yeah
- Okay.
Well, I haven't been able to sleep all week.
Thinking about the push mechanism in the handler.
And then it just came to me.
It's in the wrong place.
- The wrong place.
- Yeah
The answer is not in the box.
It's in the band.
Hey, are you sure you're alright?
I think I ate something,
I gotta go.
Alice!
Teddy was on to something
very specific,
now he is dead. There's got to be
a connection, Alice, I can feel it.
So what are you saying?
You think they have something
to do with Teddy's death
I don't know what I am saying,
all I know is
all these ideas keep flying in.
He says that any kid working in his garage
could put him out of business,
It's almost like they know
what every kid is doing.
They're hacking into people's computers.
I guess they can get into some people's
machines, but, not ..not Teddys.
He always had the most paranoid
firewalls to protect his data.
They'd have to been like
watching him physically
Watching him physically.
Oh shit
I think it is part of a camera
Number 21 isn't just a broadcast studio.
It's a surveillance post or something.
That's why they have those disks on the roof.
Milo, think about that you're saying,
You honestly think that
he would murder somebody?
I don't know,
I gotta get in there
There's over 20 buildings over there,
and they all filled with computers
No no no, this is the only one
with disks on the roof
The studios a front,
That's why they keep
postponing the opening.
Ok, now you're scaring me.
Do you wanna just go?
'Cause we can go,
you wanna just... leave
Go where, go where Alice?
You can't get away from people like this!
People like this.
This is Gary you are talking about
You don't think I know that?
They're under investigation
by the Justice Department
I mean, you said yourself that
there are guys showing up all the time.
Then how could they possibly hope
on hiding a surveillance force,
How could they hope on hiding anything,
You can't get in there anyway,
they have swipe cards, they have cameras,
I mean it's like Fort Knox for christ sakes
I'm implicated, I’m implicated Alice
No, you're not - Yes, I am.
- No, you're not
- No
Yes, who's been using this code, huh?
Teddy's code.
Whoever code this is. I have,
how do you think that makes me feel?
This is my best friend,
You need to calm down, now
- I can't just walk away from this
- Yeah, but you can't just walk in either.
- You're right
- Yeah
You're right
Uh.. the construction is
finished by 6 or 7,
the parking lot is cleared
by 2 or 3 in the morning.
Even the earliest geeks don't get is till 5.
Honey, what are you talking about?
What, what are you saying right now?
Listen to me, I thinking about
how I gotta get in there
and find out what the hell is going on.
Okay but was it true or was it true,
did you ever really notice,
you're just sounding like a mad man.
I won't pretend like
everything is okay, Alice
that's how I got into this mess
I, just tell like..
Alice listen, listen,
I'm not, I don't mean to,
I’m not mad at you, listen to me,
I think I can figure out
a way to get in there.
But I can't do it on my own,
so I need you to help me.
What am I to do ?
So you believe me?
Just tell me what to do.
Whoa, whoa , whoa, Whoa, Sir,
you got to use your own. Where's your ID?
I caught him tailgating. Building 20.
These cards are your own responsibility
- There was an explosion in the closet
in buiding 12
- What?
Hey, you can't wander around without ID,
just park your ass in that chair
Well, what can I tell ya ?
It's pretty basic operation guide
You got your time clock, fuse goes in here
you just hook it in the switch over here
So, what we got here Bob?
Some glorified cherry bomb,
some geeks' idea of fun.
I've been saying
we need a camera in this hall
To protect what,
the mops?
somebody is pulling the chain again Bob.
Unless it's a diversion,
Milo Hoffman is in my office.
- He was tailgating
- Bob. Milo is not just another geek
He is very important to Gary,
So let's not go there, all right?
Okay, we'll see you later
Is everything okay, Bob?
- Hey!
- Hi Gary
- Working kinda late, huh?
- Yeah , uh..
- Can I take a look ?
- Yeah
- Oh, that’s nice. That's excellent.
- Thanks.
You seem kinda jumpy, Milo.
No. I'm just a.... I'm a little surprised
to see you out here, now.
Well, I like to sneak in late at night sometimes
to see who the obsessive ones are
Don't work too late.
I got my eye on you
- How's it going?
- Big night
switched from tea to coffee.
Brought new meaning to my work.
Well, now he knows.
Nothing in there.
- Maybe he'll get back to work now.
- Yeah, copy that.
- Speaking of which.
- Okay. I'm on my way back.
- Did you download code San Jose.
- Oh shit.
I'll do it.
- Shame we can't just walk in the front door.
- Yeah, wouldn't Bob love that.
Ooh!
Jesus
Yes, I gonna need a thorough background check.
I want to know every organization
he's been involved with, church groups, all..
- Ahh, Mr. Barton?
- Yes
Excuse me, uh..
do you remember me?
Meelo, isn't it?
- Milo
I really need to talk to you Sir, like..
Right, uh.. give me a few seconds
with Lasy here
you can go into my office
I won't be late but a moment
- Milo
Hey! uh.. Yeah!
Thank you for seeing me, Sir
- No problem, have a seat
- I’m ok.
You look a little upset
I am Sir, I am
What's the problem, son
Ah..well,
my friend, my best friend Teddy
He was killed in Silicon Valley and I..I thought
maybe there is some way
l could help find the suspects
- You mean Teddy Chan
- Yes, Sir
Well, I guess you didn't see
the 11 o’clock news last night
San Jose police picked up a suspect
and they're holding them without bail
That's great.
That's um.. I hope I'll sleep better tonight
Well um, I’m a little disappointed
I thought that you decided to join our side.
No Sir, no, I’m a real happy there at NURV.
but um..
Thank you
and thank you for your time.
- So he didn't mention he was going to
the Justice Department? - No
You're not losing your hold on him,
are you, Rebecca?
Don't forget your part of the deal.
You got a very good thing going here.
Phill, he'll tell me
when he gets back.
Well, that will be the test,
won't it?
Prick
It's l0 o’clock,
I’ve been so worried about you
What did you see in there?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
It's exactly what they said it is,
an unfinished broadcast studio
You know, I think I’ve been
putting my own guilt on Gary
Guilt?
Yeah. If I’ve done the start up,
Maybe Teddy would still be alive.
Or maybe you would be dead, too.
Anyway, I figure instead of evolving
all these paranoid delusions
and scaring you
I should do something useful with my grief.
So I went to see that guy Barton at the DOJ.
Do you remember him?
Yeah
I wanted to see if I could help him
find Teddy's killers
and it turns out they got
the guys last night so..
I have been so worried about you
You were right
to let him break into 21
He felt pretty foolish afterwards
He said it was all to do
with his own guilt you know.
Not being there.
No doing the start up
I mean his best friend was just killed.
You're convinced he is completely focused
on SYNAPSE again.
- He's not acting?
- No
he is pretty honest with his feelings
I don't think he knows how to act.
Alright?
Good.
That's all for now.
Lisa, I had to tell someone.
They know everything
about everybody.
There're stealing code
from all over the place.
And sometimes, if someone gets ahead
of them, like Teddy
- It's all undetectable.
- What?
The crimes are hand tailored.
These guys are in the information business.
It's a Chinese guy, frame a local racist.
Plus, I’m sure
Gary has maximum deniability.
He tells his people,
surprise me, solve the problem,
defy me,
they turn around and tell the next
person the same things.
That sounds crazy why would he
put himself on the line like that?
SYNAPSE
the guy has invested billions
on getting there first.
He will do anything to get his date
He has to....
Lisa, they killed my best friend
Maybe others
I'm living with someone
they pay to sleep with me
- we have to do something
- Like what, what could we possibly do
I don't know yet. But we
are one step ahead of them
they don't know I’ve been in the
Daycare center, Just 21.
They let me do that.
That's all they know though.
Lisa
Lisa!
I'm sorry, Milo
Alright? I'm sorry
Lisa, I know why
you won't let anyone near you.
I know what he did to you
If you leave now,
you could be in danger
They would use my step father
They could frame him
if they had too, yeah.
What about the FBI?
Too risky
I went to the DOJ, but they got a guy
on payroll over there, maybe others.
Who knows who there're paying?
Well, who can we trust?
I mean how do you let go of a secret
without telling the wrong person?
I don't know
We tell everybody at once
See, that way there is no secret
left to protect.
If everybody knows,
they can't touch us.
Right
What about 60 minutes?
CBS news is partnered
with NURV information system
in a cable news network
due to launch Fall of June,2001
AOL-Time Warner has a 40% stake in
Gary's setup device and it also takes out CNN..
Disney Join NURV's adventure
ABC is out
Look, any of these places
could a more or all of them
- Wait
- What?
How close are you to finishing SYNAPSE?
He's got all the satellites up.
There's dishes on top of 21.
He's building this mega network just for SYNAPSE.
We can connect to everybody
on every device simultaneously.
That's what SYNAPSE is
That's what we'll use ...
Got him.
So what's in the Daycare Center is
a top of raw material that's all over the place
What I need you to do is
design some kind of a graphic format
so people could follow
what there're seeing
No problem
- Shit
- What?
I would have to get into Gary's house
to get the satellite address.
He's running the whole thing
from his work phone.
You mean break in?
I don't know,
I don't know...
And what if the dishes
on top of 21 aren't hot yet
the place isn't even finished.
I'll go up
You're not afraid?
testing.. UPLINK ACTIVE..
Welcome back to Good morning Portland
This Thursday, 50 of Portland's
elite couples will attend
a gala party at the home of
Gary Clarisa Winston
to raise money
for the Portland Art museum.
Julie is at the museum.
Last year party's goers pledged over
2 million dollars for this museum.
- Look at this
- What?
Why doesn’t he invite us to his party
He's never even met you.
Milo, he has thousands of employees
I know Alice
But this is for the art
museum and you're an artist.
- If anybody should be invited, you should
- Ah, hum
This is not at line feed.
This is play back from some other day
It's been messed with
- We call Randy and Phil?
- Not yet.
I'll have to bust my ass
because I’m not a frementra
I swear to god it's that kid Milo
Let's run a check on card entries.
Go back two weeks.
Skull Box, Larry speaking
Hey Larry, it's Milo
Hey buddy
- How's it going
- a... I'm good.
I'm ah.., back in the garage
Didn't want to stay at that other place
what's up?
Milo?
you there?
Larry, you got a second.
I might your help with something
You bet man, name it.
Milo
Giving a benefit for the
art museum Thursday night and
I thought you might like to bring Alice.
That's great. Thank you.
Sorry about the late notice.
You went into 21 twice
without coming out.
You came out twice
without going back in
who are you, Harry Hudinny?
No, No, No, this things is screwed up.
Look
it also got me going
into daycare that night.
Daycare center is not in your tour
Exactly, I’ve never been in there
Milo, we're late.
I'm coming I ah.., just gotta ah..
find some scissors for this um...
They call the house. They ask if you..
- Alice, I’m Gary
- Hi
This is my wife Clarisa.
Alice, hello
- Gary tells me you are an artist.
- Yes I am.
Milo, this is Barry Linden.
He's visiting us from Hollywood.
- Barry's studio is going to help us fill the SYNAPE pipeline
- Oh, good
Marketing implication epic.
Kids are watching a movie
points and clicks
at the laser blaster
and before the real is even over,
he's bought the toy... to hell with story,
how many toys can you sell
what about the arts?
The only art left in America
is business.
And you are standing
in the venchee's house
Excuse me, where is the bathroom?
It's just around the corner
- Thank you
You left the party to work?
I got inspired
I, I didn't want to forget it,
so I came here to write it down
I'm sorry if I was rude.
I know what you're doing
I just want to know that it
is not affecting your work
I don't know what you men
Milo, I’m not blind
Lisa is very attractive young woman.
God knows and
your private life is your own.
But we are very close
to our launch date.
and I need you to keep
your eye on the ball.
- I understand Gary
- Good
Let's go have a drink
Hit the back slash, hit the colon.
Keys kids don't use but geeks do.
What would Milo want in here anyway?
They know.
Just don't trust me with it,
so we will get
the evidence first,
ask questions later, here,
get started on that one
What if he knows what we are doing.
Do you think he is toying with us??
- How much time do you need?
- Two days
Now did you write the code
to sequence the video files?
Yes and the audio is done.
The text file feeds
your voice synchronizer
Hey, you're back
I bought a hu-din cook book.
'Cause we're always afraid for you eating
in Chinese restaurants
I've been mincing and chopping things
into tinny weenie pieces all afternoon
But you never cook
I know
I'm gonna go change
no escaping
- You look beautiful
- Thank you
Milo
Ah, I'm gonna go upstairs and get changed
I love the way you look
Thanks
Hey, do we have any chopsticks?
Yeah
Great
Wait, um....
right, a toast.
To a long life
- Is it good?
- It's delicious
Yeah
There's something
that I need to tell you
What?
I love you
- Rebecca
- Yeah
Come on, Come on, Come on,
see.
Who needs computers
Gary believe me,
I am looking at his prints right now.
You want Phil to handle it.
Whatever you say.
Bastards!
Oh no,
you don't get by me twice kid !
- You gonna call Gary?
- Screw Gray?
Bob, these guys are criminals.
Now, I am gonna go out on a limb here
because there's very good chance that you're
not gonna believe a word of what I’m about to tell you.
You'd be surprised what I believe
about these people
Show me what you got there
- Milo
- Get your laptop. We're going tonight.
You said two days
So, I’m a genius
- We're not ready.
- Yes, we are - You said two days
Lisa, you gotta trust me, okay?
I need you to trust me
Okay
All right
He left campus,
he taken some surveillance data with him
Don't worry,
we know where he is
Is Brain here?
Brain Vissel ?
Who wants to see him?
What's going on here?
You sounded insane on the phone.
We need to do a live broadcast, right now.
You can't, preempt yoga
that's our biggest show
Brain, you want to be
a big deal in life, right?
That's your dream, isn't it?
Will it mean
I will get to work for NURV?
After this,
there won't be a NURV.
We're ganna bring him down
and you're going to help us
- That's the most insane thing I ever..
- Come on, man, what have they ever done for you?
- Okay
- Great
You wanna be a part of history?
- Not really
- All right,
how about, not sure.. 132 bucks.
Forward your hands behind your back.
Lift the stardom bone, lift the arms,
through the hip... slowly
- You're interfaced with the dish
- ok
Read me these IP addresses
starting with number one.
Wait..
Phil, come over here,
it's almost 10 o’clock,
- we're going to shutdown
the mother satellites.
- What?
Read me the IP addresses
starting with one - Gary
Just do it, Phil
It's gone way too far already.
Go!
10.
24.
53.
192.
Come on, come on..
It's your software?
Is it your dish?
Alright, number 2
Go
Give me number 2
Milo, you got some weird
looking guys just pulled in !
Brain, don't worry about it.
Just give me number 2
10.
43.
84.
143.
Come on, come on..
Damn it
Okay, get out of the hell!!
- Checked your connection?
- Yes
- He knows
- What?
He's shutting down
the satellites one step ahead
Go to the end.
Give me number 12
- 42.
- Wait,
he knows I am shutting them down
-What?
- I know how his mind works
Give me the last one, Number 12
- Gary
- Just do it!
Ah, give me number 5
48., 29.
Hurry up, hurry up
230.
Open the door Milo!
One more second
Guys, we're okay.
Got it under control
Give us the disks Milo,
come on!
The disks, Milo, now.
come on, it's over
Hey, hey, asshole!
What's with the mission impossible 3,
bull shit, Milo ?
You're a geek
Excellent!
They'll be back here in five minutes
with Milo and the disk.
Good
What do you want to do with him?
Surprise me.
Ok, Mr. Schride,
I need the disk that Milo gave you
You got something
non-geeky I can do?
- Yeah, we're gonna need a TV set in here
- You got it
So what are you typing
in there, Larry?
IP address, it's like calling
up a satellites on the phone
The first two haven't picked up.
Come on pick up man.
Thank you
And thank you.
You have achieved a miraculous thing
I'm so proud of you
Forgive me of my method's but
when you got off courses, we had to
motivate you to keep working on SYNAPSE
Without Lisa here urgings you on,
We might not have made it
It's true, Milo,
what we have done is so important.
Oh my god.
What?
Gary
Who's got SYNAPSE, Milo?
Does that mean we did it?
Does this mean we did it?
Wow, yeah man
That's what I’m talking about,
- That's fantastic!!
Yeah, you're Jim brooklin
a never seen us coming and
were coming
Consumers don't care where new ideas come from
just so long as they're offered at a competitive price,
the Software business violent.
There're a one or a zero,
alive or dead
You're a one or a zero.
Alive or dead, or dead
We do have a monopoly,
we do have a monopoly here.
Those who don't innovate are doomed
to die doomed to die.
to die. to die.
doomed to die.
There is no second place
SYNAPSE will fully unite
the global village
New ideas are ready to be
devoured, devoured, re-defined
This business is binary,
either a one or a zero,
a zero, a zero,
alive or dead, alive or dead,
alive or dead, alive, dead, alive.
Surrounded by predators.
Those who don't innovate
are doomed to die
There is no second place
Consumers don't care where new ideas come from
just so long as they are offered at a competitive price
anywhere in the World
with a good idea can put us out of business
Alive or dead
We do have a monopoly here at NURV.
There's no second place
You're a one or a zero, alive or dead
Are you insane? What do you think you're doing?
I'm letting people know
what you've been doing
Phil, where is this signal coming from?
I'm working on it, I am working on it.
Work faster!!
A good chess player always knows
his opponents moves before he makes them.
Isn't that right Gray?
- You think you know all my moves?
You arrogant little bastard
You think they gonna come after me,
now that SYNAPSE is here !
This is the technology that'll
fuel business for the next 30 years
You think they gonna allow foreign
competitors an opening like that?
Undermined the entire economy
Over what? A cyber prank?
Then you don't have anything
to worry about. Do you?
The Lawyers at the gate Gary.
They say the Feds are on their way.
Oh Jesus.
It's coming from NURV, it's building 21
Call security, get someone over there now.
Break down the door, if yo have to
but get me that disk. Get it here
- How did this happen Phil?
- I don't know,
she called, she said Milo
had SYNAPSE, he'd left the campus and..
You lied, for him...
You're playing with fire
If you think for second I won't
send you back where you came from.
Hey Gary
I want you to see this
Are you still proud of me?
You guys know where you need to be..
Go, go, go!!
Rany, Danny come on lets get out of here
Come on, Let's go, let's go.
Rebecca, Rebecca come on, let's go.
I'm not going with you
I would rather stay here and
face the consequences of my own actions,
than be associate with yours
This was mine, Milo
You tell that to the people
you stole it from, tell it to Teddy
Come on, it's only a matter of time
before someone owns the information
You can't stop it, you slowed it down
I slowed you down Gary.
That's what matter to me
This isn't a game.
In the real world, when you kill people,
they die. For real!
And in the real world,
you're Fucked!
Are you coming?
Let them go
Tomorrow, he is
the most famous geek in the world
Gary, we need information
I’ve been betrayed
Randy and Phil are missing?
Something's going on! Take this down
Come to my attention,
Certain rouge elements of my company
have been involved in illegal activities
in an attempt to discredit me and
risk control of my company.
I'm most shocked and upset by this betrayal.
I will do everything in my power
to co-operate with the authorities
and  bring these criminals to Justice.
News that the FBI agent have arrested
NURV CEO Gray Winston,
TV's, cell phones and PC's were
interrupted world wide last night
by a huge broadcast
initiated by programmer Milo Hoffmann.
Police have also arrested these other members of
Winston’s team at a Portland airfield
as they attempted to board a private jet.
Justice officials reacted swiftly..
Man, Clinton testimony didn't get this many hits
This is, this is awesome
I mean there is 400 requests a second, Brain.
We did this! I'm surprised
this isn't blowing the server
Wow, Whoa get over here
Come here, Come here
Already over 18 million people have
downloaded the source code for
SYNAPSE from the Skullbox website.
Now Skullbox is thought to have originated
right here in this Palo Alto garage
- Hi there, I just have a couple of questions for you
- Is Milo Hoffmann going to testify
Do you know where he is now?
How many hits have you guy's registered?
What's your relationship to Milo Hoffmann?
- Good luck
- Okay
Milo
It wasn't all false
I Know
Bye
Do you consider this an
ultraman victory for open source
Excuse me
We did it partner
Are you going to testify?
Winston always said
that any kid in a garage
could put him out of business,
is that what you've done Milo?
This is a garage
Hey, there he is.
Just now getting word that,
yes, yes here he is,
here is Gary Winston
being led by US marshals
to the federal court in Portland....
Milo, when did you first realize
Gary Winston's stealing code
What is it exactly that you think
you have done Milo?
And what does it all mean?
It means we've given SYNAPSE back
to the people it was stolen from.
Human knowledge belongs to the world
Can we get a picture of the Skullbox team?