All my life, I've lived
and worked in the big city
which, now that I think of it,
is kind of a problem,
since I always feel
uncomfortable around crowds.
I mean it.
I have a fear of enclosed spaces.
Everything makes me feel trapped.
I tell myself there's gotta be
something better out there.
But maybe I... I think too much.
I think everything
goes back to the fact...
that I had a very anxious childhood.
My mother never had time for me.
When you're the middle child
in a family of five million,
you don't get any attention.
How is it possible?
And I've had
these abandonment issues.
My father was basically a drone,
like I've said.
And the guy flew away
when I was a larva.
And my job, don't get me started,
because it really annoys me.
I-I was not cut out to be a worker,
I'll tell you right now.
I-I-I feel physically inadequate.
My whole life,
I've never been able to lift...
more than 10 times
my own body weight.
And, when you get down to it,
handling dirt is, you know... urgh,
is not my idea
of a rewarding career.
It's this whole gung ho,
superorganism thing...
that... that, you know, I can't get.
I try, but I don't get it.
I mean... I'm supposed
to do everything for the colony.
A-and what about my needs?
What about me?
I've gotta believe
there's someplace better than this.
Otherwise, I would just curl up
in a larval position and weep.
(Sighs) The whole system
makes me feel...
(Exhales) insignificant.
(Doctor) Excellent.
You've made a breakthrough.
- I have?
- Yes, Z. You are insignificant.
I am?
(Chattering)
(Ant) Ground floor.
(Babies crying softly)
- (Cries)
- Uh, worker.
Soldier.
Ooh. (Giggles)
- Uh-oh.
- Worker.
(Cries)
(Ant) Let's try it again.
Firm grip. Swing hard.
Back straight. Concentrate.
Follow through.
(Grunts)
OK. Got to keep a positive attitude.
Even though
I'm utterly insignificant.
I'm-I'm insignificant, um,
but with attitude.
- (Coughs)
- (Woman) Oh, sorry, Z,
- I didn't see ya.
- Great, Azteca.
I'm so meaningless, I'm invisible.
- (Grunts)
- (Laughter)
Now, you're getting it.
After all, it's not about you.
It's about us... the team.
It's about... this.
Uh, a giant hole in the ground?
- OK, people. Are we feeling good?
- (All) Yeah!
- Yeah.
- Great.
Now, R-1734 through Z-7829,
you guys are on wrecking ball.
- You got it.
- Swell.
- (Ant) All right.
(Enthusiastic shouts)
Now, remember, Azteca,
"Be the ball."
That's the main thing.
You know, be one with the ball.
Would you cut it out already?
Jeez. I love my work.
And you, well...
You think too much.
Come on, Z. Help us build
a bigger, better colony.
And try to be happy about it.
Sure, you know. I mean, why...
How could I be unhappy being
construction equipment?
- OK, workers, remember.
- Here it comes.
- Be the ball.
- Oh!
(Foreman)
Let the energy flow through you.
G-grin and bear it. This is...
this is for the colony. Oh.
- (All yelling)
- Ow!
T-this is just a lawsuit
waiting to happen.
- Hang on. Here we go.
- Faster. Harder.
Did you know
heights make me nauseous?
No.
(Ant) This is a ball!
- (All yelling)
- Hey!
- (Azteca) Oh, Z.
- Yes, yes. I dropped the ball.
(Ant) Workers. They're weak.
They lack discipline.
They lack commitment.
General, I know there's
been a glitch or two,
but everybody is working full tilt,
as it is...
You can't help it, it's your nature.
But in spite of your limitations,
you will finish
this tunnel on schedule.
Come hell or high water.
Anyone who falls behind
will explain why to Colonel Cutter.
And let me assure you, the colonel
is not as understanding as I am.
Dismissed.
Four more days, Cutter.
Four more days.
Then we can bid farewell
to their kind of incompetence.
Yes, sir.
A fresh start.
- Imagine it!
- A strong colony, sir.
A colony we can be proud of.
Yes, but we're not there yet.
We just got word that a termite army
has mobilised against us.
- Against us?
- We'll have to send troops...
to attack their colony.
Attack a termite colony, sir?
- That's suicide.
- Exactly.
- Do you have the list I asked for?
- Yes, General.
These are the units
loyal to the queen.
Hm. Then they're
the ones we'll be sending.
It's a shame.
There's some fine officers here.
Don't we need the queen's
approval to declare war?
Our very next stop, Cutter.
General,
we've been at peace for years.
- Why would they attack?
- They want our land.
They're desperate for new territory.
Perhaps they think we've grown soft.
Why don't we dispatch an ambassador,
negotiate a new treaty?
- We don't need to send soldiers.
- Believe me,
every ant in this colony
is so precious to me.
- (Grunts)
- That's why we must strike now.
We have the element of surprise.
If the termite troops
enter our colony...
Yes, General,
I know what they can do to us.
- Very well.
- You've made a wise decision.
In fact, you've ensured
the future of this colony.
Hello, General.
Princess Bala. What a nice surprise.
You look lovelier
each time I see you.
Thanks. I hope you're not
just here on business.
Oh, of course... (Chuckles)
of course not.
Because, um, it might be nice...
if we had a conversation once
before we get married.
You're absolutely right. Schedule me
some private time with Princess Bala.
Uh, sir, there is time now
for a personal moment.
We're a few seconds
ahead of schedule.
Excellent. Princess.
Well, a few seconds isn't much,
but I guess if it's quality time...
So, how was your day?
Anything interesting happen?
- We declared war.
- Declared war?
Boy, talk about a rough day.
Sir, I hate to interrupt,
but time stands still for no ant.
Princess.
Mom, could you remind me,
why am I marrying this guy?
Bala, do we have to argue
about this again?
We don't have anything in common.
The guy's a stiff.
Yes, darling.
I know the General is...
a little gruff
and somewhat overbearing at times,
but I know that he cares about you.
He's just not particularly good
at showing it.
But he was very persistent
when he asked to marry you.
But why me?
Because you're the one
who has to continue my work.
- What if I don't like my place?
- Everyone has their place, Bala...
you, the soldiers, the workers.
It's not that bad
being princess, is it?
Would you rather be
carting around dirt all day?
Mother, don't be so dramatic.
(Music plays)
At least they have some fun
every now and then.
- Two aphid beers.
- Why'd I have to be born a worker?
You soldiers get glory,
plus you get to go outside.
You meet interesting insects,
you kill them.
Yeah. But you get to spend
all day with those...
beautiful worker girls.
Weaver, they're career girls.
They're obsessed with digging.
I don't think I'm ever
gonna meet the right girl for me.
A girl for you?
I was talking about a girl for me.
Don't you want your aphid beer?
Call me crazy, but I can't drink
from the anus of another creature.
Suit yourself.
Ahh. Me, I'm cuttin' loose.
We got royal inspection comin' up.
Standing around like an idiot while
a bunch of blue-bloods smirk at you.
How do you put up with it?
Z, I've known you
for a long time, right?
You were born two seconds after me.
And ever since then
I've listened to you complain.
What are you bitching about?
We ants are running the show.
We're the lords of the Earth.
Hey, don't talk to me
about earth, OK?
Cos I just spent all day
hauling it around.
(Sighs) There's just
gotta be a better place.
There is. I've been there.
Sorry? Were you talking to me?
There is a better place...
Insectopia.
Oh, really?
Lunatic at three o'clock.
You can't understand till you
go there and see it yourself.
You can be your own ant there.
The streets are paved with food.
Nobody tellin' you what to do.
No wars.
No colony.
- I shoulda never left.
- Oh. Fascinating.
We were on a long-range recon.
I got cut off from my unit.
Nothing like post-traumatic stress
disorder to complete your day.
- Then I saw it! Insectopia!
- Hey!
You head towards the monolith.
Ten clicks past the canyons
to the land of red and white.
You've had enough for one night.
Come on. Before you get in trouble.
Head for the monolith. Listen to me!
The monolith!
That guy's got a screw loose.
- Across the lake!
- Insectopia. Hmm.
It'd be great if it were that easy.
- Yeah. Dream on, Z.
- Cross the lake!
Look for the land of red and white!
Wow!
This is so... gritty.
Ten minutes, right?
This place is off limits.
Just blame me.
Say it was all my idea.
- It is all your idea.
- Besides, no one will recognise us.
Come on, girls. What do you say?
Let's take a walk on the wild side.
(Dull voice on PA)
'OK, everybody, 6:15. Time to dance.'
- Time to cut a rug, Z.
- Oh, no. That's OK.
I'm gonna leave the rug
just the way it is, Weaver.
(# Slow jazz)
Step back, ladies.
I'm gonna ask one of these
workers to dance with me.
Oh.
What a bunch of losers.
Mindless zombies capitulating
to an oppressive system.
Hi. Wanna dance?
Absolutely.
Follow me.
So, how come I haven't seen you
around here before?
Oh, I don't get out much.
I, uh, I work over at the palace.
The palace?
I bet those royals really live it up.
Course they're all...
you know... from inbreeding.
What?
Yowch!
Y-y... yowch! Yowch.
- Yooowch.
- What on earth are you doing?
Well, actually, to tell you
the truth, I'm sort of making it up.
Really?
Why does everybody have to dance
the same? That's completely boring.
It's no fun.
(# Samba)
Hey. Watch your step, worker.
You watch yours
or you'll be in big trouble!
Th-th-that's OK.
I'll... let him off this time.
Are you crazy?
He's built like a pebble.
- Aren't you gonna defend yourself?
- Hey, buddy. Get back in place.
- Me? Uh... uh...
- What if he doesn't want to?
Yeah. What if I don't like my place?
- We got us a troublemaker.
- Buckle up, Spanky.
This one goes out
to all the lazy workers.
(Grunts)
Watch that aggressive behaviour,
buddy.
He's just a worker. (Muffled)
- (Ants shouting)
- (Chuckles)
Princess Bala! Princess Bala!
The guards are coming.
- Let's get outta here.
- Wait.
(Shouting and fighting)
Princess? You're a princess?
Uh... I gotta go.
- When can I see you again?
- Let me think.
Never.
- Bye.
- No, wait!
Oof!
# What a day it has been
# What a rare mood I'm in
# Why, it's almost like
being in love
# There's a smile on my face
for the whole insect race
# Why, it's almost like
being in love #
(Whistle blows)
Yowch.
(General chatter)
- Can I get you another one, pal?
- No... thanks.
- I think I'm gonna go.
- Yeah. I don't blame you.
It's always slow in here
before those royal reviews.
I guess soldiers need their shuteye
before they meet the queen.
That's it!
You know, I was once...
See ya.
(Snoring)
Psst. Weaver.
I figured it out. Weaver. Weaver!
What? What?
I got a great idea.
Switch places with me.
Let me go to the inspection
instead of you.
- What time is it?
- The royal family will be there.
- This is the only way I can see her.
- See who?
- Princess Bala.
- Are you nuts?
You want me
to switch places with you?
Do you know how much trouble you can
get into for impersonatin' a soldier?
It's trouble
just listenin' to someone
talkin' about
impersonatin' a soldier.
You have to help me.
If I can't see her again,
my life is not worth living.
P-p-please, Weaver. Please.
Switch jobs with me just, you know,
for a day.
Th-think of everything
I've done for you.
Hm. I can't think of anything.
OK. So, think of all the things
that I'm gonna do for you.
Would I meet some worker girls?
Are you kidding?
They always go for the new guy.
It's like a sport for them.
And they will definitely go for
an adorable little insect like you.
Weaver, I... I have to see her again.
Z, what kind of chance
do you have with a princess?
I mean, she probably
won't even remember you.
(Sighs) I-I know it sounds nuts...
but I have to try.
- Oh, boy.
- (Marching music)
Princess, fancy meeting you here.
What do you say we... lose this crowd?
Oh, me?
You know, I... I wear many hats.
You'd have to call me
a Renaissance ant.
(Man) Eyes right!
- Beautiful! Just beautiful!
- Mm.
- The precision. The order.
- Oh.
Princess Bala! Princess Bala!
Hey. It's me.
Remember Z from the bar?
Princess Bala!
Princess Bala! Princess...
Bala, you must encourage the troops.
Wave.
Oh. She sees me.
Excuse me, guys. I-I... Sorry.
- I just got a better offer. Excu...
- Company halt!
Princess! (Princess Bala!)
Quiet there! Get back in rank.
- You new, kid?
- Y-yes, but I'm gettin' out soon.
I got a trial membership.
Trial membership. (Chuckles)
Good one!
- Name's Barbatus.
- Z.
- Right face!
- Psst.
(Whip cracks)
Sacrifice.
To some, it is just a word.
To others, it is a code.
- I'm bad at word games.
- (Chuckles)
A soldier knows that the life
of one ant doesn't matter.
What matters is the colony.
He'll live for the colony,
fight for the colony,
die for the colony.
- This guy's crazy.
- I hear ya.
At 0800 hours, we received word
that the termite enemy has mobilised.
We have no choice
but to launch a pre-emptive strike.
You are the queen's finest.
I know you will all do your duty.
I am proud to send you into battle.
Into... I'm... I'm sorry. Into battle?
- Dismissed.
- Left face! Forward march!
I think there's been
a terrible mistake.
The truth is
I just... came for the speech.
Don't worry, kid.
I'll watch out for ya.
- Sound off.
- One!
- Two!
- Three!
- Huh?
- Five!
- Six!
- Seven!
- Eight!
- Nine!
- Ten!
- Eleven!
- Twelve!
- Thirteen!
# We ants go marching one by one
hurrah, hurrah
(All) # We slaughter termites
just for fun, hurrah, hurrah... #
So, these termites, th-they're...
We're talkin' pushovers, right
Not really,
they're five times our size.
And they shoot acid
from their foreheads.
Hey! Keep it movin', shorty!
(All) # We ants go marching
two by two, hurrah, hurrah
# We'll all be dead before
we're through, hurrah... #
Say, exactly... what exactly
does our platoon do?
I mean, will we be serving beverages
or processing paperwork?
Our platoon has the best assignment -
first into battle.
# We ants go marching three by three,
hurrah, hurrah
(All) Hurrah! Hurrah!
# We're off to face our destiny
hurrah, hurrah... #
Let's not...
We're being too hasty here.
These guys sound like bruisers.
How were you figuring
on beating them?
Superior numbers, kid. Overwhelm
their defences and kill their queen.
Fellas, you're being
a little extreme.
Let's influence their political
process with campaign contributions.
I like you, kid.
You got a sense of humour.
Forward!
Come on!
Let's kick some termite butt!
Over the top!
- (All shouting)
- Yeeow!
Yee-ha!
(Shouting stops)
- Where is everyone?
- Something's not right.
Don't be scared, kid.
- (Gasps)
- (Growls)
They're here! Ahh!
Attack!
(Shouting, roaring and screaming)
(Groans)
Come on!
- (Roars)
- Ahh!
Barbatus, you saved my life.
Don't get all sappy about it.
- Hey, guys! Behind you!
- (Roars)
Hey... hey, guys?
Can somebody help me here?
Anybody...?
Yeah!
(Grunting)
OK, mama! Unh!
Yeah. Oof!
Oh, yeah. Big guy comin' through.
(Grunts)
I love it.
Hey, hey, hey!
Take it easy, muscles.
You're makin'
the rest of us look bad.
What happened to Z?
He's... takin' a personal day,
so I'm filling in.
You fill in any more,
and you'll explode.
Eh, you got a problem?
No, uh... uh... Nobody told me
digging was so much fun.
You know, you pick the dirt up.
You move it.
You pick it up again.
You move it again. Lots of reps.
You exercise the arms
and the thorax.
Yes, I... I see what you mean.
- Yeah. Fascinating.
- Sorry, sir!
I was just chattin'
with my friend, sir.
You know, I just had a chat
with General Mandible.
Anybody who doesn't meet his quota
is going to be downsized.
Come on. Cut him a break. He's new.
Hey. What do you say we help
your attitude a little bit...
by taking away
your rations for the day.
Thanks for your time.
I don't know what came over me.
Talking back like that?
I must be losin' it.
Sorry I got you in trouble.
But, you can...
share my rations... Whoa!
If you want.
- Are you askin' me out to dinner?
- (Chuckles)
Oh, no. I...
Well, if you don't have
anything else planned...
(Laughs) I'll check my calendar.
You know,
I'm kinda glad Z's takin' a breather.
Kid!
Kid, over here.
Barbatus.
Be honest, kid. Am I hurt bad?
N-no. N-not at all. You're...
Actually, you're lookin' terrific.
You got, you know,
swell colour in your cheeks.
No. I can see it in your eyes.
I'm a goner.
Help me up, Z.
(Sniffs)
I c-can't feel my legs.
You gotta hang in there, buddy.
I know you're gonna make it.
Just take... take deep breaths.
Because I'm gonna try
and find your body.
It's bound to be...
out there... s-somewhere.
(Coughs, sighs)
B-Barbatus, hang on.
- B-Barbatus.
- Don't make my mistake, kid.
Don't follow orders your whole life.
Think for yourself. Ohh...
Barbatus.
(Cutter) We're on schedule. Work
is completed on "A" section, sir.
We're clearing "D" section now.
I want double shifts
around the clock.
- Is that clear?
- Crystal, sir.
Good. What about section...
- Excuse me, sir.
- This better be important.
It's the termite battle, sir.
The enemy was destroyed, but it was
a disaster for our troops, as well.
Well, that's terrible. Terrible.
There is good news, sir.
One soldier made it back.
- No kidding.
- What?
Word is spreading. The Queen
wants to meet the war hero.
Damn!
Good. Damn good.
Uh, I'll handle this.
(Footsteps approaching)
- Congratulations, soldier.
- (Ahem)
You're a little short for a war hero,
aren't you?
A war hero? Sir, I-I don't
actually think that I'm a hero.
Good. I don't like heroes.
But, sir. You don't understand...
(Crowd cheering)
I... I didn't do anything.
I mean, it was all horrible.
It was just... just a massacre.
A-a massacre upon a massacre.
That's good, soldier. Now, wave.
(Cheering)
There was nothing
you could do, Weaver.
You didn't know
they were going to war.
I just feel horrible.
Poor Z.
I should have never let him go.
Wait a minute.
That's no soldier. That's Z!
Z? The little guy made it!
(Chuckles)
(Crowd cheering)
Let's go, soldier.
(Cheers)
As I was saying, son,
you are an ant after my own heart.
An ant that looks Death
in the face and laughs.
Well, the truth is,
I-I just make belittling comments...
and snicker behind Death's back.
(Chuckles)
(Queen) General Mandible.
Keep your comments to yourself.
Let me do the talking.
(Yawns)
May I present
Her Majesty the Queen.
Charmed. Charmed.
And the Royal Princess Bala.
(Purrs)
Welcome home, soldier.
We cannot begin to express our
gratitude for your heroic efforts.
The private asked me to convey
his humble appreciation.
Please, please,
it was nothing, really.
Just run-of-the-mill valour...
and extraordinary courage, you know.
In battle,
there's very little time to think.
One must attack! Attack! Attack!
- (Chuckles) Well, indeed.
- (Muffled)
As you can see, Your Highness, the
battlefield is fresh in his mind,
so this is the perfect time
to debrief the private.
Oh, please, General.
Not on our first date.
(Chuckles) "Not on our first date."
Haven't I seen you somewhere before?
Well, maybe. Then again, maybe not.
And then... then again...
Yowch.
That's it! The guy from the bar.
- Don't... Shh.
- Bar? What bar?
I danced with this guy at the bar
the other night.
He was just a worker, then.
- What were you doing at a bar?
- That's what I want to know.
No. This isn't about me. I mean,
look what this worker's done.
You're thinkin' of someone else.
I am a soldier.
Exactly. You WERE a worker
but now, you're a war hero.
- He's a worker?
- A worker danced with my fiancée?
F-fiancée?
W-w-wait a minute.
This is not how it looks.
I can explain.
She was the one making all the moves.
Arrest him.
H-hey, wait, can't we discuss this?
What are you doing? Let go of her!
- He's taking her hostage!
- Huh?
No. No, I'm not.
I mean, yes, I am.
One more step
and the princess gets it.
Oh, let go of me!
Ow! Don't make me hurt her.
Get off!
(Both screaming)
(Groans) Ugh. Oh.
What are you doing, you creep?
Are you out of your puny little mind?
(Ant) There they are! Let's go! Move!
Oh, good.
Here they come,
to rescue me... and kill you.
Kill?
- Hey, you guys!
- Stop! What are you doing?
Get off, you little twerp!
Don't throw away
everything we've got!
What're you waiting for? Hello! Guys!
- Huh?
- What is it?
It's beautiful.
Ridgeway, get out of there!
- Oof!
- Oh!
(Both sigh)
- Oh, don't worry. I'm OK.
- You?!
You're OK?
Hey, who cares about you?
- I almost died.
- Calm down.
Don't let a little
near-death experience ruin your mood.
Hey, this is not a mood.
You're not listening to me.
Where am I?
Look, what's-your-name, just climb up
that tree and find out where I am.
Look, th-the trick is not to panic.
You know,
h-h-he w-who panics is lost.
What am I saying? We are lost.
- Whoa!
- (Gasps)
(Chuckles)
Ow!
I've been kidnapped
by the village idiot.
Who's the bigger idiot -
the idiot, or the idiot
who gets kidnapped by the idiot?
Did you talk those termites to death?
I can't believe you tried
to pass yourself off as a soldier.
Why are you stalking me?
Don't you realise that I'm...
out of your league?
YOU were cruising the worker bar
for action,
And you happened to find it...
the swarthy, earthy, sensual worker.
Please. I was slumming it.
Don't you get it?
I chose you because you were the most
pathetic little bug in the joint.
I was gonna let you become part
of my most erotic fantasies,
but now, you can forget that.
You know, I guess what you prefer
is Old Blood and Guts.
His idea of a romantic night out
is two seats at an execution.
You really chose the right husband.
For your information,
the General and I
are deeply, deeply in...
engaged.
You come right back
down here this instant!
We are marching straight back
to the colony so that I...
(Bala continues in background)
The monolith!
Wonderful. That's an appealing offer.
But, considering the options, you go.
I'm going to Insectopia.
Oh, come on. Insectopia?
You're crazier than I thought.
Yeah? Well, I happen to have it
on a very reliable source.
(Ahem) Or... or should I say,
a drunk, raving source?
But the point is, I'm convinced
the place definitely exists.
Stop! I order you to stop, worker!
Hey, I got a name, OK? It's Z.
And out here,
you can't order me around.
All right. Fine. No problem.
Oh...!
(Rumbling)
Wha-what? (Screams)
- (Growls)
- (Gasps)
Worker! Worker! Where are you?
Z? Z? Wait for me.
No more excuses, General.
I want my daughter back.
I'm beginning to doubt
your ability to handle this.
Your Highness, we will
spare no effort to bring her back.
Princess Bala is... essential
to all our plans for the future.
So he kills himself 100 termites,
gets a few medals, then bada-bing,
bada-bip, bags himself the Princess.
- He looks him in the eye...
- And says, "Bite me."
To General Mandible?
Buddy. Hey, hey, buddy.
You heard about the war hero named Z?
Runs off with the Princess, right?
When they sent the guards after him,
he just looks at 'em and boom!
- They burst into flames.
- Z? (Chuckles) You talkin' about Z?
I know Z. He's a friend of mine.
I think you...
- You know Z?
- Yeah. He's a worker.
A worker? That's impossible.
A worker can't do anything,
except work.
Yeah. We got no choice.
We do have a choice.
Uh, I mean, look at Z.
He wanted something,
and he went for it.
He's not alone. I was a soldier
and I switched places with him.
You're tellin' me...
- I don't have to be here?
- We've got a choice?
They don't want you to know,
but we don't have to work.
Workers control
the means of production.
If Z don't dig, I don't dig.
People, what is this,
an encounter group? Get back to work.
Why?
...on the tunnel! This guy, Z,
he's leadin' a revolution!
I'll... get back to you.
(All chattering)
Think about it, Z... two ants.
Who ever heard of two ants?
Two million ants, maybe. But two?
Look, I'm hungry, I'm thirsty...
And this whole desert thing?
- It just doesn't work for me.
- Yada, yada, yada...
It's about time you took me back.
Take yourself back. Phew.
Excuse me!
You kidnapped me, remember?
That means you have
certain responsibilities.
You can't just abandon me here.
- It's better than the colony.
- You're not serious?!
Maybe you were living it up,
but personally, this beats digging.
If you'd ever done
a day's labour you'd know.
Labour?
What do you know about labour?
How would you feel
if you had to give birth
every ten seconds
for the rest of your life?
- Gee.
- Water!
Ahh. All you think about is yourself.
Nobody else ever thought about me.
So I don't need anybody else.
Unh!
(Muffled) Help! Help me, Bala!
Help! B-B-B-B-Bala!
I'll get you out. Hold on.
Help, Ba...
(Both gasping)
- Thanks.
- Don't mention it.
Now, maybe we can put
this fantasy behind us...
and head back to the colon...
Oh, Z! What are you doing?
- We've gotta cross the lake.
- Am I missing something?
Didn't we just get OUT of the water?
Bala, look,
what have you got to lose?
I mean, think about it. Do you really
want to be Mrs Raving Lunatic?
There's a better place.
Z, please.
Just... gimme one chance.
If we don't find Insectopia soon,
I promise
I'll take you back to the colony.
(Bala) I hope you know
what you're doing.
(Z) Yeah, me too.
(Indistinct shouting)
(Chanting) We want Z! We want Z!
People, come on. I know some ants
who won't make their quota.
Buzz off, pawn of the oppressor.
(Chanting continues)
We want Z! We want Z!
Sorry, sir. I came as soon as I
heard. I was debriefing the trackers.
- And? What's the report?
- Well, this Z, sir...
He's one slippery character.
They lost Bala's trail
at the edge of the lake.
The lake?
(All) # All we are saying
# Is give Z a chance... #
What's that soldier doing there?
It appears he's holding hands, sir.
With a worker.
I don't like the way
things are going, Cutter.
I'm counting on you for results.
- Can I depend on you or not?
- Yes, sir.
All right. Let's wrap this up.
(Chanting)
We want Z! We want Z! We want Z!
I've heard a lot about this Z.
I even had the pleasure
of meeting him once.
But where is he now?!
Can anyone point him out?
I mean, if this Z
cares so much about us,
then why isn't he here?
I'll tell you why.
Because Z doesn't
give a damn about us.
(Ants murmuring)
That's why he kidnapped our princess
and ran away.
Z is no hero.
We are the heroes.
We are the ones ensuring
the future of our great colony.
And when we've completed
this magnificent structure,
we will reap the benefits -
more food and less work for everyone.
(Murmurs of approval)
And as further reward
for your efforts,
every one of you
will get the day off...
(Excited murmurings)
so you can be the guests of honour at
the MegaTunnel dedication ceremonies!
(All cheering)
Mandible! Mandible!
(Chanting) Mandible!
Mandible! Mandible! Mandible!
Now, bring me that soldier.
(Chanting) Mandible! Mandible!
(Yawns)
(Gasps) Oh, my God! Z! Come here!
It's Insectopia!
You were right. It really is here.
- Huh?
- All right. All right!
- You're a genius.
- Let's eat.
Mmph!
Huh. (Nervous chuckle)
(Muttering)
Well? What's the problem?
- There's some kind of force field.
- (Buzzing)
Uh, excuse me. Excuse me!
How do you get in?
Yes, well, I'm afraid
this is a private function.
- Who are your friends, dear?
- Crawling insects, poopsie.
Oh. The poor dears.
(Slowly) Uh, good morning.
- Huh?
- Darling, really.
Greeting every insect
that emerges out of the grass?
Pardon me!
I guess you don't recognise me!
I've been travelling
and I'm all... schlumpy.
I'm Princess Bala.
Oh! It's even worse.
They're Eurotrash.
Darling, they're poor.
They're dirty. They're smelly.
We have to help them.
If you'll just wait right here,
we'll fetch you a little something.
Oh, please, Muffy.
Not another crusade.
Chippie, we have a social obligation
to the less fortunate.
I know you laugh at my hobbies,
but this is important to me!
Mm. You have such a big heart.
That's why you're
my little cuddly-widdles.
Oh, my big, strong pheromone factory.
- Mmm!
- Oh!
Oh, brother.
Suddenly I've lost my appetite.
- You know...
- Muffy...
I guess I had imagined Insectopia...
I don't know... a little differently.
- Oh, Muffy!
- (Gasps)
- No! Oh, no! (Sobbing)
- Oh, no.
- Rumbling
- Look out!
Z, help me! Z!
Don't let me... Don't let me go, Z.
Get me out of here!
Bala!
Whoa, this is not good.
Whoa!
Whoa-oa-oa!
(Bala screaming)
Whoa!
Hi.
(Both screaming)
(Thud)
- Z?
- Yes?
It looks like this is it, just
when... I was starting to like you.
(Both scream)
Who the hell is that?
Uhh!
That's enough.
I ain't tellin' you nothin'.
Soldier, the princess is vital
to the future of this colony.
She must be returned
to take her proper place as queen.
We already have a queen.
As for your friend Z,
why should I hurt him?
(Chuckles) He's not important.
Now, soldier,
we all know that one individual ant
doesn't matter.
Not you...
- not Cutter...
- (Door opens)
- (Azteca grunts)
- Not even her.
Azteca! (Groaning)
Don't tell that tight-ass! Aagh!
- (Grunting)
- Where is Z?
- I don't know where he is!
- Hmm.
That's too bad.
(Azteca groaning)
Wait!
Insectopia.
I know it sounds crazy,
but that's where he'd be going.
Soldier, you think this is a game?
Insectopia does not exist.
As a matter of fact...
it does.
- Sir?
- I'll brief you on the co-ordinates.
You're gonna bring
the princess back.
And as for Z... Kill him.
But you said he didn't matter.
It's for the good of the colony.
You made the right decision.
Gentlemen, now you can see...
how dangerous individualism can be.
It makes us... vulnerable.
Let's go.
(Door slams)
Take him back to the MegaTunnel.
Put him on the front line.
Dismissed.
(Sighs) Jeez, what was I thinking?
I almost got you killed.
Z, you know, you really
shouldn't be so hard on...
(Straining) That's it.
I'm taking you back to the colony.
- Uhh! Ow! Oh.
- Uhh!
Insectopia.
You know, I must've been crazy.
- Z?
- But you know what?
- I admit it when I'm wrong.
- Z.
And this time, I gotta tell ya,
I was absolutely, 100%...
correct.
Have... have you ever seen
anything more beautiful in your life?
- It's... Insect...
- Shh! Don't jinx it. Come on!
# I can see clearly now
the rain is gone
(Burps)
# I can see all obstacles in my way
# Gone are the dark clouds
that had me blind
- (Ladybug) Pardon us.
- # It's gonna be a bright
# (Bright, bright)
Bright sunshiny day
- (Insects squealing)
- # It's gonna be a bright
# (Bright, bright)
Bright sunshiny day
# Look all around
nothing but blue skies
# Look straight ahead nothing but
# Blue skies
# Whoa
# I can see clearly now
the rain is gone
(Buzzing)
# I can see all obstacles in my way #
All right, everybody.
I want all teams in place,
fully prepared
to seal the doors here and here.
'Make certain the digging crew
stays on schedule...
'for breakthrough
midway in the dedication ceremony.
'Now all we need is the princess.'
(Sniffs) Mm.
- This stuff tastes like crap.
- Really? Let me try some.
Hey, it is crap. Not bad.
- Somebody needs to feed that fire.
- Dude, I did it last time.
I'm not gonna get it.
It's not my job.
What about the new guy?
He hasn't contributed yet.
And... (Sighs) You know,
he just died in my arms like that.
I... You know, I don't think
he ever once in his life...
made his own choice.
I never knew it was like that.
I mean, up in the palace...
Well, I guess we just let the general
make all the decisions.
Let me ask you something. What
made you come to the bar that night?
I guess I was looking
for a little trouble.
Well, (Chuckles)
trouble's my middle name.
Actually, my middle name is Marion,
but... don't spread that around.
You're pretty strange.
You do know that?
Well... (Ahem) Strange
isn't the word I would use.
I like it.
You're not like anyone else.
Actually, now that you mention it,
there is a certain strangeness to me.
I mean, it's, you know, kind of
a bizarre quality. Some said "freak".
But it's, uh, you know, complimentary.
Hey, new guy!
We need more wood.
I'll be right back.
Just hold that thought...
whatever it is you were thinking.
Hey, you ever wonder why
they call you guys "pests"?
(Mosquito) What if, like,
we're just these tiny things...
and we're just, like, part of
this whole other huge universe...
that's, like, so big
we don't even know it exists?
(Ladybug chuckles)
Man, that is so deep.
Perfect.
Nothing like manual labour...
on the most romantic night
of my life.
(Buzzing)
Hi. I was in the neighbourhood
and I thought I'd drop in.
This is, uh, very bohemian.
Aloha, dude. Welcome to Insec...
- (Groans)
- (Insects gasp)
Sorry for interrupting.
You see, our princess has,
uh, gone missing,
and we're just sick about it.
She's about yea tall,
fairly easy on the eyes.
- Anybody seen her?
- (All) That's her.
Don't worry, Princess,
you'll be back home soon.
Listen, Cutter, I'm...
I'm not going back.
(Sighs) The thing is, Princess,
I got orders.
Orders? Can't you just once
think for yourself?
Well, that was very impressive.
Where's Z?
- Z? He's, uh...
- Dead.
Z's dead.
You don't need to worry about him.
Well, he was an ant with ideas.
Too bad for him.
Princess, your colony needs you.
- (Grunting)
- (Bala) Cutter!
- Stop right now! Let go of me!
- Bala!
Stop, you...
Oh, no.
(Muttering) What am I gonna do?
All right, look.
Let's be rational about this.
You know, Bala and I,
she's a princess...
and I'm a...
I'm a soil-relocation engineer.
So... You know...
On the other hand, uh...
I've gotta go back for her.
(Chippie, drunk)
I'll... give you a lift.
Sss... Whoa! Ohh!
It's the least I can do.
Besides... it's what my waddly-kiddles
would want.
(Sniffling and sobbing)
Uh, look, how about
a cup of joe...?
- Well, old boy... saddle up.
- I saw a puddle of coffee there.
It... Whoa!
(Both groaning)
(Z) Look out!
(Bala grunting)
Ah, Princess.
- You're just in time.
- Take your hands off me!
General, what is going on here?
- I DEMAND an explanation.
- I'll explain... afterwards.
- Is the south-east entrance secure?
- Yes, sir.
Not afterwards. Now.
I don't like the way you think
or the way you run this colony.
And I don't like you.
The wedding is off.
- Things are going to change here.
- You're right, Princess.
Things are going to change.
Make her more comfortable.
- (Gasps)
- She'll be here for a while.
What do you think you're doing?
My mother will have your head.
I doubt that. (Chuckles) Ah, you've
got a fighter spirit, Bala.
Just what we need
to start our new colony.
We'll rinse away
the filth from our gutters.
We'll start anew,
with you by my side as my queen.
You're crazy.
I believe history
will see things differently.
All right, gentlemen.
Take your positions.
Someday... someday you'll thank me.
(Chippie and Z moaning)
(Z) Pull up! Pull up!
Aah! There it is!
(Chippie mutters and hiccups)
Oof! (Coughs) Oh!
Well, then, go get
the woman you love, Z.
So long, Chip. And thanks.
You there.
Where do you think you're goin'?
Me? Oh, no, I was just...
You know, I...
You're not supposed to be here.
Workers are to report
to the tunnel-opening ceremonies.
Yes, yes, of course. Well, I should
get going, then. I... (Ahem)
You know, the-the...
(Soldier) Hey!
- I'm going to the... the t-tunnel...
- Get moving.
- Better get...
I'm going to the
tunnel-opening ceremonies...
Excuse me, please.
Tunnel-opening ceremonies.
- Hey!
- Opening the tunnel. They need me.
- I'm the key man.
- Where are you going?
Tunnel-opening ceremonies.
- (Crashing)
- (Bala) Hey! Let me outta here!
Hey!
Gosh, this-this day just keeps
getting better and better.
(Bala shouting in distance)
(Bala) Are you listening to me
out there? I'm the princess!
Damn it!
- Wow, your manners haven't improved.
- Z!
(Gasps) Whoa! Whoa!
- (Gasps) Ooh!
- It's you. You came back for me.
Well, yeah, I came back for you.
I have strong feelings for you.
Let's face it, you're... you're...
you're beautiful...
A little combative at times,
but I think we can work on that.
You talk too much.
Gee, I think I'm about to become
the strong, silent type.
Come on. The city's deserted.
We'd better get outta here.
Z... (Sighs) We can't go.
Mandible's insane.
He... he keeps talking about...
washing away the filth
and-and changing history and...
and I think he's going to try
to kill my mother.
(Z) Not just your mother... everyone.
- What's going on?
- Look.
Here we are, safe in the city.
But they're gonna seal
everybody off in the MegaTunnel.
And... here's the lake.
You're right.
We can't leave now.
Come on. We gotta get down there.
Today is the realisation of a dream.
A dream of a proud colony.
A pure colony. A colony reborn.
(Cheering)
Moments from now
this tunnel will open.
The past will be washed away
and a new day will dawn.
(Cheering)
A stirring speech, General.
I wish my daughter
were here to appreciate it.
Your Majesty, I know
how concerned you are about Bala.
But my scouts
are on her trail and...
I don't want to discuss it.
Just find her.
I will, Your Highness.
Goodbye.
(Soldiers talking)
(Ants chattering)
Seal up the doors.
- Cutter, did you hear me?
- Sir, I've been thinking.
Do we need to do this?
Look at what these workers have done.
They got the right stuff.
Isn't there any other way?
Cutter, you're a fine officer.
You have discipline,
courage, ability.
But you seem to have a weakness for
the lower orders I find disturbing.
- Now, are you with me?
- Sir, uh... I apologise.
- All right, then. Seal it up.
- Yes, sir.
(Grunting)
(Queen) As I look out
on this magnificent tunnel,
I am filled with pride.
- (Z) Jump!
- In these difficult times,
it is a great solace to know
that you, our workers...
- (Queen continues)
- Mom! Wait!
Every worker in the colony is here.
Hey, that guy owes me money.
(Queen) This tremendous
accomplishment is a testimony to...
Go warn your mother.
I've gotta get to those diggers.
- There's not enough time.
- Leave the pessimism to me, OK?
- (Queen continuing)
- Ow!
- Ooh!
- Yeeow!
Excuse me! Sorry. Excuse me.
When our expert diggers
break through to the surface...
- Mom! Stop!
- The sun will pour in...
Bala! Where've you been?
Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- What happened?
Mother, we're in terrible danger.
(Panting)
(Sighs)
Put your backs into it, people!
Wait! Hold... Hey, stop digging!
- Z? Is that you?
- We must stop!
- Z! You're back!
- (Bones crunch)
- Oh, Z! Oh.
- (Gasping) Weaver!
Z! What's the matter?
H-hold up, everyone.
Stop! Stop digging.
- On whose authority?
- Your own authority.
If you break through, we'll...
Drown. This tunnel is going to flood.
We've got to get everyone out.
(All murmuring)
Look, I got orders,
and those orders say "dig".
What if someone ordered you
to jump off a bridge?
Oh, I'm asking the wrong guy here.
Look, think for yourselves!
Gimme that!
I've had enough out of you.
Get back to work.
(Weaver) What's that noise?
Uh-oh.
- Let's get outta here!
- Run!
(All screaming)
(Weaver) Run! Keep going!
Everyone, listen to me.
We've all been deceived.
We need to calmly
head toward the exits.
- Run for your lives! Flood!
- No. Don't panic.
- Don't panic!
- Every ant for himself!
(Gasps)
(All screaming)
All the exits are blocked!
- What do we do?
- There's nothing we can do!
Yes, there is.
Weaver, give me a leg up.
Everyone, listen to me!
- Who the heck are you?
- He's Z!
(All murmuring)
Listen, we gotta help each other
get out before we all drown.
- How?
- By making a ladder.
A ladder!
Hey, if we built this,
we can do anything.
- OK, let's move it!
- All of you, gather round.
You, start climbing.
- Grab my arm.
- All right. Here I go.
- Go, go, go!
- Right!
- Excuse me, Your Majesty.
- (Grunting)
Z, I've gotta help my Mom.
Don't worry. I know almost
exactly what I'm doing.
I'll see you at the top.
(Mandible) Gentlemen,
there comes a time...
in the evolution of a colony...
when the strong are meant
to rise above the weak.
Now is that time.
'Below us right now,
'the weak elements of the colony...
'are being washed away.'
Oh, God, we're not gonna make it.
- We need more ants.
- You two better get up there.
Weaver, you can't hold it alone.
Get going.
Hang in there, buddy.
- Got it!
- Hurry up! Go, go, go, go!
(Gasps)
Our princess is secure,
and a glorious future is at hand.
We can all stand proud.
It is time for a new beginning.
- (Soldiers gasp)
- What the hell is that?
I think that's the weak element, sir.
- Gimme... gimme a hand!
- Z! You?
Let go! Don't you understand?
It's for the good of the colony!
Wha-what are you saying?
We are the colony!
(Soldiers gasp)
Cutter... what are you doing?
Something I should've done
a long time ago.
This is for the good
of the colony, sir.
You useless, ungrateful maggot!
I am the colony!
- Look out!
- Oof!
(Screaming)
Z!
Men, let's move it!
Get these ants up here.
- Keep it moving.
- Thank goodness we made it.
Wait here.
- Uhh! OK.
- Thank you.
Weaver.
Where's Z?
Oh, no.
(Weaver) Back up, everybody, back up!
- Give him some air. Back up.
- Z, oh, Z.
Please wake up.
Oh, no...
(Inhales)
Huh?! (Coughing)
(All cheering)
Yowch!
You know, Weaver,
you still owe me that dinner.
- (Kissing)
- Babylove.
- We made it, Z!
- You da ant!
- Eh!
- You did it.
We did it.
- Oh!
- Fellas! Fellas, please!
- This is very embarrassing!
- (Laughing)
On the other hand,
I probably could get used to this.
(Z) 'There you have it,
your average "boy meets girl,
'"boy likes girl, boy changes
underlying social order" story.
'So what else can I tell you?
We rebuilt the colony.
'It's even better than before cos now
it has a large indoor swimming pool.
'Bala and I are thinking
of starting a family.
'You know, just a few kids...
maybe a million to begin with.
'I'm workin' with a new therapist,
you know, absolutely terrific.
'He's putting me in touch with my
inner maggot, which is helping me.
'And I finally feel like
I've found my place.
'And you know what?
It's right back where I started.
'But the difference is,
this time I chose it.'
# Just what makes that little old ant
# Think he'll move
that rubber tree plant
# Anyone knows an ant
can't move a rubber tree plant
# But he's got high hopes
# He's got high hopes
# He's got high apple pie
in the sky hopes
# So anytime you're gettin' low
# 'Stead of lettin' go
just remember that ant
# Oops, there goes
another rubber tree plant
# (There goes
another rubber tree plant)
# Oops, there goes
another rubber tree plant
# Once there was a silly old ram
# Thought he'd punch a hole in a dam
# No one could make that ram scram
# He kept buttin' that dam
# Cos he had high hopes
# He had high hopes
# He had high apple pie
in the sky hopes
# So anytime you're feelin' bad
'stead of feelin' sad
# Just remember that ram
# (Oops, there goes
a billion-kilowatt dam)
# Oops, there goes
a billion-kilowatt dam
# (Oops, there goes
a billion-kilowatt dam)
# So keep your high hopes
# Keep your high hopes
# Keep those high apple pie
in the sky hopes
# A problem's just a toy balloon
# They'll be bursting soon
they're just bound to go pop
# Oops, there goes another problem
Ker-plop
# (Oops, there goes another problem
Ker-plop)
# Oops, there goes another problem
Ker-plop
# (Ker-plop) #