The following film is
based on real-life events.
Hey, Ebony!
You bastard! I'll knife you in the back!
-Get this guy out of here!
-There's no more room.
We've got to use this cell!
Cool it or there'll be trouble!
Get off me!
I wanna see that. Come on!
You've betrayed me!
Dagger! I'll kill you, you hear?
Stick you like a pig.
Ebony, Lula's freaked out...
...says it's his right to kill Dagger.
Lula needs to be taught a lesson!
Whatever's happened...
...it's not for you to decide,
you little shit!
-Dagger!
-Dagger's gonna die!
-Gonna die!
-Calm down!
You think you're gonna decide this?
Come on, then, I'm ready.
-What's this?
-Gonna die! Gonna die!
Like I said, I've got no one
waiting for me on the outside.
I'm in no hurry to get out.
Anyone wants a fight,
let's get on with it.
I'll crush all of you.
What the fuck's wrong with you guys?!
Let's cool it here!
What's going on, Dagger?
-Lula attacked me from behind, Ebony.
-He's a badass!
He went for Dagger from behind!
Right out of line, man!
Gonna die!
-You locking me in there, Ebony?
-First get in there, then speak!
-Don't throw Dagger in here, Ebony.
-We don't want trouble.
Step away, damn it!
So? I'm all ears.
How come he's so mad at you?
You heard.
Lula came out of nowhere with a knife
and tried to kill me.
I dodged.
We scuffled till they broke us up.
The rest you know.
Good morning, Mr. Pires.
I do apologize for this
disgusting behavior...
...which has invaded our household
today.
Only this idiot Lula,
a young, inexperienced con...
...suddenly got this attitude,
without even asking permission!
Dagger killed my father!
He killed my father!
I sure did, kid.
And not only him,
I've killed plenty more besides.
Ebony! Mr. Pires!
Dagger killed my father...
...in front of my mother.
He's been telling everyone!
You gonna deny that, asshole?!
Are you gonna deny it? Are you?
-Ebony, please.
-What?
Tell the kid he doesn't know
half the story.
-lf he did....
-Son of a bitch! I'll kill you!
Tell him to ask his mother if she
was really as upset as all that.
Or was it a relief when I came
and grabbed his belt from him?
Lies! That's a lie!
Like hell it is! I saw it for myself.
He'd have thrashed her to death.
I thought you'd have heard
by now, kid!
Your mother paid me
to kill your father.
Get it now?
It was your mother who wiped him out!
Hear that?
He's calmed down!
I want them both out here
in their underwear.
Lula, as far as I'm concerned,
we're quits.
Let's forget it, shall we?
You've put me to shame, and on
the day of the doctor's first visit.
So, Lula, what brought
you back in here?
I left here...
...went home and found
my wife in bed with someone else.
The son of a bitch had the nerve
to tell me, "That's life."
I shot him three times just
to prove the contrary.
You should know that whatever
goes on outside gets settled outside.
In here, anyone who behaves
knows we'll do what we can...
...to show him the front door,
where his family is waiting.
But anyone who's proud of being
a criminal, with blood in his eye...
...we'll do everything to
prolong his life in here.
We usually forget people
like that in here.
Doctor, this is Ebony.
Yes, doctor,
Ebony's got a problem.
My kitchen knife is still missing.
Whoever took it,
I'll give you one chance.
Return it or there'll be
one prisoner dead every day!
I'd like to ask our visitors
to turn their backs...
...since there's an ashamed
crook present.
But when I turn around...
...I sure would like to see that knife.
I'll count to three.
One...
...two....
I'm turning.
Three.
-From your kitchen?
-Yes, sir.
This is the yellow wing, doctor,
because they're afraid.
It's like a jail within the jail.
They're locked up here for their
own safety. They're scared.
Career killers, rapists,
stool pigeons, bad payers.
In here, you know,
prisoners never forgive.
Mr. Pires, don't these people
ever get sun? It's so musty!
Anyone want to go outside?
Take a walk in the yard?
Get some fresh air?
-What do these people do all day?
-They come and go all day long...
...think they're busy,
but it gets them nowhere.
Doctor, 7000 men in jail!
There are 1800
in this pavilion alone.
If they knew how AIDS is spread,
that would already help.
They catch the disease and have sex,
so there's no stopping the epidemic.
The only ones who'll listen to your
advice are the really smart ones...
...who only want to get out alive
in order to keep robbing.
That's their whole life.
Maybe. But they're living
at the center of the disease.
-They're the prisoners here.
-Prisoners?
They own this cell. This place doesn't
explode because they don't want it to.
God bless you, child.
I didn't know you had a family.
I thought I'd lost it.
My whole life in jail...
...but even so I raised 18 kids...
...and not one of them has even been
near a police station.
That girl, my youngest...
...she said she doesn't remember
my face...
...so she's decided to come and visit.
I'd like you to authorize me to see her.
I don't want my daughter
around all the scum.
That's going to be tricky.
What if the 7000 others
ask me the same thing?
Excuse me.
Good morning.
Hey, what's up?
Need anything, doctor?
Coffee, sugar, chocolate, toothpaste?
Joints are only two packs
of Marlboros each. Want one?
I don't smoke.
Too bad! Commerce, doctor!
Makes the world go round!
Let's go.
Easy, now. That's it.
Slow.
He can't spit there.
Tuberculosis. Anyone steps
on that, spreads the disease.
If he had the strength,
he'd go to the sink.
It's not easy.
He must be isolated.
But where, doctor?
Name?
Everyone calls me the Beard.
Why are you here?
Well...
...my brother was killed.
Two days later, the murderer
had a little meeting with death...
...so suspicions fell upon my
good self.
Some said I did it and others came
along and said they saw it wasn't me.
With some saying it was me
and others saying not...
...here I am, five years now,
waiting for the judge to decide.
Do you have sex here in jail?
-Anyone who denies that is a liar.
-Use condoms?
If I've got one, I do.
-IV drugs?
-How dare you, doctor?
I wonder, Beard!
What's that mark on your arm?
Beard is next!
My name's Alipio.
Do you use drugs?
Needles?
No way, doctor. I got AIDS from
all the ass I've had in jail.
Plenty of ass.
Is it still worth taking the test?
I listen, give advice...
...a little tenderness,
hold them tight...
...and then they always give us
something nice in return.
A pack of cigarettes, some candy,
a slice of cheese.
So many men shut up
in here, doctor...
...without our feminine support.
Yeah, I've got AIDS,
but I didn't get it in here.
I brought it in off the streets,
and I can't complain.
You come in here sick and they
treat you with respect, dignity...
...and that's the greatest thing
in a crook's life.
I'm a junkie and a dealer.
In my business, if a guy doesn't
pay up, I can't take back...
...what I sold him. The bastard's
already smoked it, snorted it.
I take whatever he's got.
If he's got nothing, I kill him.
The other day I tried to get
an extra banana from the guy...
...who delivers lunch. The bastard
said only if I kissed his banana.
So what the hell,
I'm just crazy about bananas.
Doctor, everyone in my cell's
got this itch.
It's unbearable.
Scabies. I'll give you some medicine.
So how are you getting along?
Doctor, after shooting cocaine
in the dark with a blunt needle...
...drawing blood with this rig...
...is hardly fair play.
Too bad!
See what you did?
-Who are you?
-I'm the doctor.
I was taking blood samples.
-Just ask--
-Watch out!
Like you have
to tell me who to ask.
I'm calling the duty officer.
Wait here.
If no one can identify you,
you're staying right where you are.
Don't take it personally.
It's their job to escape...
...and mine not to let them.
Doctor!
You coming back?
I knew many of those men hadn't
shown their victims any mercy...
...but society has its judges.
And I wasn't one of them.
At the same time,
what did I have to do with all that?
I had two choices.:
Forget or go back.
Take a deep breath.
Smoker?
Just cigarettes.
-No crack?
-Never.
Sleep well?
Hardly, doctor.
The mind never stops...
...what with one guy trying to settle
a score outside, collecting a debt...
...another trying to dig a tunnel.
And there goes another day.
-You still got much time to do?
-A few more years.
And why did you come here?
-Legitimate self-defense, doctor.
-That lands you in jail nowadays?
It did in my case.
Here's what happened.
It was Christmas...
...the bells ringing,
snow in the windows.
Me, Bristles and Fatso arranged
to do a jewelry store job.
Neat work, doctor.
Never even fired a shot.
The problem was later.
How are we going to split it up?
Fatso and I will make three
piles and you choose first.
Son, not now.
Get out! Go on!
Go on, son!
You fucking moron!
We're splitting the loot and you
come at me with your hand covered?
It's his own fault he died.
What the fuck's going on?
So you shot him in the heat of
the moment...
...but we had agreed for me
to shoot you...
...so we could take your share.
So shoot!
Go on, fire away!
I can't, damn it.
Give me your rod.
Oh, my God!
Being betrayed by your buddy for
nothing, doctor...
...like Judas, the guy who
spat in the face of Jesus.
So how does the story end?
It ends with me in here,
before your eyes, doctor.
Fatso was arrested in
under two months.
Doctor, ever seen a fat man
being beaten? They talk too much.
A man was killed here.
Did you see anything?
No.
Jesus, Fatso. You turned me in
for Bristles' murder!
You could have just squealed
about the robbery.
I fingered you for murder because
Bristles' brother would kill me.
We left his place together
for the jewelry store...
...then I came back alive
and he got back dead.
I'm very upset.
I could turn you in as an accomplice...
...but I won't. I'll back your story up.
I killed him and I threw him
in the river all by myself.
Thanks, Ebony!
I knew I could count on you.
I'll forgive you,
but you owe me one.
And did Fatso ever pay his debt?
No way! Fatso died trying to escape.
They spent two years
digging a tunnel.
Wait!
Let's go, come on!
I'm stuck!
Go on, Fatso!
Hurry up, you big pile of shit!
Go on, damn it!
Give me a hand!
-I'm stuck.
-Breathe in, man.
-Suck yourself in.
-What do you mean?
-I can't!
-Go back, then.
-Go on!
-Give me a break, Cadao.
-Pull, go on, pull!
-Shit, Fatso, I told you!
-Eating everyone else's leftovers.
-Pull, go on!
Fatso's frustrated brothers knifed him.
Hell of a way to die, eh, doctor?
Right under the Virgin Mary
and not even she could protect him.
Too bad.
What about this pain?
Your problem, Ebony, is stress.
What bigshot executives get.
Take one of these before bed.
They'll help you sleep.
-lf you don't get better, come back.
-God protect you, doctor.
Doctor, come and see...
...Chico's balloon, quick!
It's the old man's obsession,
doctor.
Oh, too bad!
May I?
Hi, I'm Lady.
-Lady Di. I've come to take the test.
-Please, take a seat.
First I'd like to ask you
a few questions.
I've seen this movie before,
doctor.
I've never needed a blood transfusion
and I never pierce my veins.
The only drug I use is
a joint now and then...
...when I watch TV
or for a little romance.
And partners? How many?
Oh, about 2000.
The silicone you used
isn't meant for that.
As if I had the money
for something better, doctor.
Ever taken hormones?
No way! Hormones are dreadful!
You take them and nothing happens.
And what our clients like, maybe
you know, is to play the girl.
Well, Lady, I think the time's come
for you to find out if you're sick.
I'll do it, doctor.
Will it hurt?
Just a little.
Get out, man!
Hallowed be thy name,
Thy kingdom come
Thy will be done,
On Earth as it is in heaven
Give us this day
Our daily bread
Any room in there?
Sure.
Only it'll cost you 200.
Pay for a bed? I'm in jail, man!
So? Did you live for free
on the outside?
If you want to stay, sleep on the floor.
Deusdete ain't sleeping on no floor.
He already has a place.
Deusdete.
Just like I said, right, brother?
You ended up doing something
you shouldn't.
Men with cell phones...
...were patrolling the neighborhood.
It was 4 p.m., the day before
yesterday. It was 4 p.m....
And the rat?
I smashed it against the wall
about 10 times!
Damn thing wouldn't let go!
It died?
Like hell it did! So I grabbed it
and stuck my teeth into its brain.
Then I just brushed my teeth
and that was that.
Easy, man! You've been beaten with
iron bars and never made a sound.
Sweet Mama, pray for me!
Cut your finger, Highness?
Jesus, Lula, smoking crack?
You can't operate like that!
Sorry, doctor, only I operate
better when I smoke.
What?! You can't keep
a steady hand on crack!
That's where you're wrong. I see the
veins all shining and fluorescent.
Looks like that casino
in Las Vegas!
Take it easy, man!
See, doctor, isn't that great?
Steady as a rock and hardly
a millimeter between stitches.
God protect you, Lula.
God bless you, God bless you all.
That's enough of God, Highness,
you're not kidding anyone.
What, you married twice?
Well, doctor, to me life's
a merry-go-round...
...and just the one horse isn't enough.
That one there. That's Dalva's.
My princess.
Honey, score a goal for me?
Score a goal for me, please?
Like it?
Yeah, I bet you do.
-You believe in love at first sight?
-What?
Come with me. I'm going to ask
your parents for your hand.
-You don't even know me!
-You're wrong!
-Wrong? You don't know me.
-Sure I do.
-I know you just love spicy....
-Sausage.
And I know you look gorgeous
in that pretty dress.
And I know you deserve better
than that klutz over there.
My fiance!
-Fiance?!
-Fiance.
You're wasting your time.
Look...
...what a great blend!
We'll have one kid of each color.
I'll be waiting in the car.
Were you serious?
Never been more.
What the hell is going on, Dalva?
What are you doing there?
Go on, go away, will you?
What?!
Honey, who is this?
-I'm her husband.
-Husband?
Sure. We're marrying.
-Come on, Dalva.
-Don't grab me like that!
-Stop it!
-Get out of here, go on!
-What's this?
See? See that?
If he were in love with you,
he wouldn't have run off!
Jesus! Letting some guy steal his girl!
Tomorrow at 8:00,
get your family together...
...and I'll ask for your hand.
Best thing that could
have happened to me, doctor.
Dalva gave me a family.
So you stopped stealing.
Of course not, doctor.
With her by my side, I went upmarket.
Took imported cars and
drove them to Paraguay.
With cash in my pocket,
I returned to the peace of home life.
-Any kids?
-Three with Dalva.
And one with Rosirene.
You know how it is: the devil
only tempts those close to God.
That ever happened to you?
Uncontrollable passion?
What's with the babe over there?
What do you think?
She's over there.
Don't you dance samba, miss?
What am I, a monkey jumping
around for nothing?
Looking for something to jump to?
Seems like you're the one wanting
to jump. Jump shit.
Look, I'll take my wife home.
Get your bikini...
...and I'll come and fetch you.
We'll spend the weekend at the beach.
-Does she know you belong to me?
-Ease up! I was going to the john.
Like hell you were. And that?
Why is that so hard, then?
Doesn't look like it's being
properly cared for.
-Watch your mouth, you black bitch!
-Wait!
Get away from my man
or you'll be sorry!
You'll be sorry!
Hey, handsome!
So I guess the beach is off, then?
So, what happened
to the black girl?
Now, that's where I had to do
a bit of juggling, doctor.
From Monday to Thursday, Dalva.
And the rest, Rosirene.
I rented a little room for us
near the old bus station.
We had this great
love affair going, doctor.
Morning!
-Give me that!
-It's mine!
Stop, you're messing me up!
Stop!
Don't let go of me, Highness.
Don't let go!
You just can't quit this life,
can you?
I told you I'd take care of you.
I've always earned my own money.
And that guy you were with,
know who he is?
What are you doing here?
I thought it was Snow White's day.
Don't change the subject.
You know who he is?
Sure. So what?
So what?
So I told you,
do your thing if you have to...
...but don't screw friends of mine
or I'll break your neck.
Powder's your friend?
Highness, you're a nobody.
He said that when he leaves his wife
we'll move to Miami.
I'm off!
Where to?
To Miami, honey!
-Miami!
-You're taking a souvenir of mine.
No! Get off me!
Highness, get off me!
Get off!
That was rough, screwing a friend
of mine and the two making plans.
That night, I went back to the room.
And what do I see?
Jesus. Get out of here.
No way.
Get out of here right now.
I won't go.
Get out, damn it!
No way, I'm staying.
Come on, Highness, bite me.
Come on...
...bite me...
...bite me the way I like it.
Bite!
Bite, go on, bite!
Bite harder...
...harder!
Harder!
Bite harder!
It's over!
Damn it!
There, that's so you learn
not to take what's not yours.
You arsonist bitch!
Slut!
Well, you might as well know that
this slut is expecting his child.
No!
Son of a bitch whore!
I'll kill you!
You son of a bitch whore!
You haven't heard
the last of this, Highness!
-You haven't heard the last of this!
-Son of a bitch!
Come here! Come here!
Get your hands off my son!
To keep Dalva out of trouble,
I took the blame for the fire.
Only, the law was already
on my back for other stuff...
...so I got 16 years for the fire...
...reduced to 10.
-And was it worth it?
-The black chick put a spell on me.
I'm out of here!
Therefore, perfectly calmly,
we shall overcome the niggling...
...irresponsible and lying attempts
to inv olve the government....
So, what's up?
Letter from Franci?
Your sister mention me at all?
Of course she does, right?
Hey, Deusdete! What does
your sister say about me?
She asks if you're okay.
That's all?
What do you think?
If she knew what you've been up to,
she wouldn't even be asking that.
I think she would...
...but you think you know better.
Wasn't it you who used to say,
" If you sell it, don't use it"?
Wasn't it you?
May I?
So, what's up?
Come to settle your debt?
Hey, man, right now Ezequiel's
in a tight spot.
So he thinks to himself,
"Zico's a reasonable guy.
He'll take the surfboard
as collateral for the debt."
Then Ezequiel can have another
little rock of crack, right, man?
Wrong.
Pay what you owe!
Don't drink that, it's blood!
Shit!
I thought it was water.
Doctor, this guy was
sweating all night long.
I've put him on antibiotics,
but if you ask me, it's no use.
It's AIDS.
Doctor!
Who took away his oxygen?
I don't want to die.
Get me out of here, please!
That's hardly likely.
He's 213. Rape.
To us he's a patient.
I can't....
I need...
...to get somewhere safe.
-I don't want to die!
-I'm sorry, doctor.
I'm against the death penalty,
but not for rape.
If you ask me, it's just too bad.
So that's it, doctor.
Come on, old man. It's past lockdown.
Get a move on!
What is it? What are you looking at?
You think your kids
will jump over the wall?
You were asking for it this time,
weren't you?
See you in 30 days.
Doctor, we're here to make
our relationship official.
With all due respect.
You understand, doctor.
So we can be more open.
It's not the same with a rubber.
There's not much sense,
her taking the test and not you.
See? I told him, doctor,
but he's scared.
Scared of what?
-Scared of injections.
-Too Bad!
-It's not that.
-So you're scared of getting married!
Doctor, you're needed, urgently!
Come on!
Down you go, come on!
It's all right now, doctor.
I blacked out, doctor.
Giving us all a fright, Zico?
It's just as well, doctor.
Maybe he'll learn what drugs do.
Tell him!
What's there to tell? Drugs kill.
-And you, who are you?
-That's Deusdete.
We grew up together.
You know, doctor...
...one day my mother
didn't come home.
I was left alone.
I waited...
...and waited...
...until he and his sister, Franci,
came and took me to live with them.
We grew up together.
Wait!
Come on, Zico!
Wait, Zico!
Zico!
Help!
Zico saved me, doctor.
That's right. I've always
looked after him, from early on.
Then you went the wrong way.
What's wrong with buying some dope
and selling it to folks who like it?
It wasn't even that much!
Another two years and I'm free.
But I've never killed anyone.
Unlike Deusdete here.
What was your crime?
Answer him, Deusdete!
To tell you the truth,
he's not even a real criminal.
So, what are you in here for?
One night, I was at home...
...when my sister arrived,
acting strange.
Franci!
What's wrong, Franci?
What happened?
Franci!
Franci, what happened?
Open up, come on.
What happened?
What happened, Franci?
What happened? Tell me.
What happened?
Tell me!
There were two of them...
...they grabbed me...
...lifted my skirt.
One said he wanted to suck me.
-I told him to go suck his mother!
-What did they do to you?
-They beat me.
-What else?
What else?
-That's all, Deusdete.
-Who was it?
Who was it?
-I just ran off!
-Did you know them?
Hey, Zico!
Deusdete?
What are you doing here, man?
I need to talk.
Is Mother all right?
It's not her.
Some guys messed with Franci.
What did they do to her?
Nothing much, she says.
But I reported it to the cops anyway.
The cops?! You think the cops
will do anything?!
The problem is, the guys found out
and now they're after me.
-Leave it to me. I'll sort them out.
-No, Zico. Not your way.
I want--
I just want a gun, to defend myself.
Take your pick.
Even with a gun, doctor, I never
thought anything would happen.
But it was my destiny,
and theirs, when they found me.
So!
-Where's the stool pigeon off to?
-I'm not looking for a fight.
-Let me go home.
-Sure thing...
...but first we're going to caress you...
...just like we did your little sister.
Hey, man!
Give me a Coke.
You know how old I'll be
when I get out of here, doctor?
Forty-eight.
There!
One...
...two...
...three...
...four...
...five...
...six...
...seven...
...eight.
Found it.
So it's Visitors Day, is it?
If you like...
...you can go now.
I've got a problem, I need to talk.
This problem got a name?
Ezequiel.
He still owes me and now he's
trying to get more on account.
He comes to my cell, raises his voice.
What's he playing at?
-And you?
-Me?
If I don't get paid,
I can't pay Highness.
I want your permission
to kill the bastard.
This goes on much longer,
I'll start losing respect around here.
Cool it.
I'll tell Ezequiel to get
the money from his family.
If he doesn't pay,
you can go ahead.
This man has already lost a lung...
-...and the other's in pretty bad shape.
-Take the medicine, man, go on.
See, doctor? He won't take it.
What are you, a kid?
You won't get better...
-...if you don't take it.
-Come on, that's right.
That's it.
Come on.
Right.
-Good.
-And on the outside? What did he do?
We used to rob armored trucks.
Just the two of us.
We planned everything. Remember?
Doctor, we'd spend six months
just gathering information.
We'd even make friends
with the guards' families.
And that paid off?
Sure, plenty. Although
we'd only use half the money.
The rest we'd put aside
for a rainy day...
...or to bribe the cops.
It's coming.
Stop!
You going to sit there
on top of other people's money?
If you don't come out it'll be
too bad for your widows.
Open that door,
for Christ's sake!
Come on, get out!
So we paid off the others...
...and each went his own way
back to the family.
So anyway, Antonio,
what's on your mind?
Miro...
...your wife's cheating on you.
With a cop.
-Says who?
-Says no one. I saw her.
They were making out in a squad car.
Near the old bakery.
Dina doesn't buy bread there.
Miro, I saw her.
And it wasn't bread she was after.
Celia...
...is Antonio Carlos gay?
What a question, Dina!
He made up this story and told Miro
I've been going out with a cop.
Like hell I made it up.
I saw you crawling all over him.
-You nibbled his ear, damn it!
-Then it's me he's really after.
You forgot the best part...
...how you asked me to run away
with you...
...and that I turned you down...
...because I love my husband...
...and your wife's my friend.
Liar!
Evil slut!
Miro, you don't believe that bitch,
do you?
Man, how many jobs have we
pulled off together?
And our agreement!
Celia, see if you can keep your man
around the house.
I don't want him pestering me
in the street anymore.
Miro!
-Miro!
-Bastard! You dirty bastard!
You've never fooled me.
I always knew you had a crush on her.
You can't even respect your
best friend's wife, you dog!
-Calm down.
-Dog!
Miro, I'm telling you the truth!
I lost my friend and partner.
The first robbery without him,
there were so many cops...
...it looked more like a military parade.
-What about him?
-I only found out when he got here.
I thought I'd gone to hell, doctor.
But him? I'll tell you.
Come here, come on.
Come on.
Miro.
Miro, don't you think it's time you quit?
Take what you've got and start
a decent life someplace else?
In a new city?
Give the kid a better chance?
Stop! Police!
Party's over, Miro.
I'll cut you in.
It's cheaper for me to cut you guys in
than give it to a lawyer.
You don't get it.
We're taking the lot. Everything.
Hand it over, the dough.
Come on, quick.
Too bad, a smart guy like you
trusting his own wife.
Some guys are born
to be cheated on.
Are you all right?
Doctor...
...do infants remember
everything we do?
No, not a thing.
Doctor, let him go.
And with you now...
...our untamed diva of dance...
...the woman who lives in all
thieves' hearts...
...here at the detention center...
...the one and only Rita Cadillac!
-Rita!
Hello!
I know you all...
...fool around a lot, right?
Yes!
But do you take care
of yourselves?
Yes!
Our friend, the doctor,
came here today...
...and he's taught me enough
to teach you too, right?
That's right!
Okay, so some of you are
careful and some forget...
...so I'm going to teach you what to do.
This one's orange!
-Dona Graca, Ebony sent you this.
-Thanks.
-Oh, look. My man. Want some?
-No, thank you.
See, Franci?
That's the sort of man I want.
-You think Deusdete will like me?
-That's up to the two of you.
It's easier for him if he has a
sweetheart waiting on the outside.
You're right.
You need a heart full of love
to put up with this life.
Take my boy. He's always
asking about his father.
What did he say when
you told him I was coming?
That you could come,
if you felt like it.
Good work, man.
Agenor Barbosa, inmate 15027.
Your brothers Pedro...
...Luiz and Felicio are waiting
for you at the barbershop.
-Deusdete, this is Catarina.
-Hello.
This is me.
Franci's told me a lot about you.
Nothing bad, I hope.
Only the best.
She was even a bit jealous when
I said I wanted to meet you, right?
Zico.
Hi, Franci.
You're so thin.
-Been eating too much junk?
-Sure thing.
But that's the least of it, right, Zico?
Son, have you been taking
good care of your brother?
You bet, Godmother.
The game's starting...
...the referee blows the whistle
and they're off!
There goes Neto, and he's through...
...to the penalty area, playing
beautifully, passing one player...
...slowly, beautifully,
there he goes...
...dribbling that ball.
And Highness takes a shot!
Inmate Josue "Highness" dos Santos,
section 9302...
...come immediately to the entrance
of Pavilion 9.
Darling...
...l'll be right back.
Hi, honey!
Kiss me on the mouth!
Come on.
Oh, honey, today is not a good day.
You haven't worked a day in your life,
now you tell me you've changed?
-You have to understand--
-You've got that white trash in there.
-No way, I swear!
-Really? So let's go and take a look.
Because I think that white slut
is in there with you!
-Cut it out, honey.
-I'll show you!
Do you think I'm stupid, an idiot?
I know she's in there!
What are you looking at?
There!
I just knew you were with that whore.
Oh, so now I'm the whore, am I?
-Listen!
-Stop, stop!
Let's all sit down.
Sit down, Dalva.
Sit down, please.
Rosirene, sit down.
Right, now you're here,
there's no turning back.
The three of us are going
to come to an agreement.
Rosirene, Dalva's no whore, all right?
She works at the textile factory
and raises our kids.
They're my kids, damn it!
And you too. You said Rosirene's
worthless, and that's not true either.
If it weren't for her bringing me
some decent stuff to sell in here...
...we'd all be going hungry.
If you like both of us...
-...that's your problem.
-Oh, Jesus!
Yeah, Highness. You're going to have
to choose between us right now.
Damn right.
Shit. You're breaking my heart
in two, damn it!
Two women, doctor!
What do these crooks have
that we haven't?
-Have you kissed your wife today?
-No, why?
I rest my case.
Can I join you?
So. Nothing to tell?
You're the one who never told us
what happened that day.
That's ancient history, Zico.
You never told me
what they did to you.
When you get out of here,
promise me you'll let your hair grow?
You believe in promises?
Deusdete was right...
...you're not the Zico we used to know.
Anyone home?
What's up, Dagger?
I've got a message for a friend.
I know.
What's that look on your face?
I pretended I had AIDS
so they'd leave me alone...
...but it was no use.
The bastard who did me is infected.
Forget it, kid. He told me
to tell you he lied too.
He hasn't got AIDS either.
What is it?
Ezequiel wants to pay.
You don't owe me anything, man.
Ezequiel spoke to her
and she said yes.
I don't get it.
Ezequiel wants to pay with her.
Ezequiel's sister sleeps
with some of the guys...
...raises some cash
and pays the debt with Zico.
Ezequiel has no other possessions.
Do whatever you think is best.
I was blind.
I was blind, I believed her.
Will you ever...
...be able to trust me again?
I never stopped trusting you.
He's our family now.
-Let's sing " Happy Birthday" !
-Shall we?
Here, sit on my lap.
One, two, three.
Happy birthday to you
Sir, we're in love.
Lady and I would like your blessing.
It's Dirceu.
His name is Dirceu.
Son, do you believe in him?
Mother, I've never met anyone
like Matias.
I don't get this kid.
We're too old to know what's right,
Antonio.
If it's what Dirceu wants,
what's the harm?
In here they can get up to all
the disgusting things they live.
Son.
Goodbye.
Your attention, please.
Visitors Day is almost over...
...so will family members please
go to the exit.
The gates will close in 10 minutes.
Excuse me, doctor.
This is my boy.
I know he's done wrong,
but when I think of him...
...I can't believe he took
someone's life.
I wanted to ask you to keep
an eye on Davilson for me.
I can't look after him in here.
-Come and see me at the infirmary.
-Yes, sir.
Thank you, doctor.
So can I come back next time?
If you think it's worth it.
It'll be so long before I get out.
I'm in no hurry.
Mr. Pires, his body was already
hanging here when we woke up.
This one won't be raping anyone else.
The doctor said it
should read positive.
No! Positive means you've
got it in your blood.
It has to be negative.
HIV-negative.
I'll go first.
My case is more desperate.
I'm clean!
Well, you've had your fun.
You've had over 2000 men
and you're clean.
And me, as square as they come?
It's just too bad.
I'm clean too, Lady.
What's wrong?
They're letting me out, Lady.
So why aren't you happy?
And leave you here?
All alone?
I'm not alone.
I have you.
No one works for me
who can't be trusted.
You ask permission to kill,
then change your mind?
But Ebony, I'll be out in two years.
Better keep quiet and settle the score
on the outside, right?
Ezequiel...
...you owed and didn't pay.
You're alive, but you can't stay here.
Get your things and go
to the yellow wing.
As for you, Zico, you're no criminal.
You're a clown.
It's all right, doctor.
So many years locked up...
...the mind learns to control the body.
Chico, how come you're in here?
Oh, doctor, you want to hear
yet another lie?
No one in here is really guilty,
haven't you noticed?
-Much longer to go?
-I should have been out long ago.
It's in the hands of the judge.
Oh, doctor, I can't wait.
Best thing about jail is getting out.
And leave behind all your friends?
Friends?
I don't want inmates for friends.
I finish talking to you,
close the door and that's that.
In here you have to walk alone...
...or maybe with God.
What about your daughter?
What are you thinking, Chico?
I was imagining these two...
...flying up...
...higher into the sky.
It's weird.
This is weird!
Weird.
Come out, you son of a bitch.
Come out!
What can you see?
It's trying to stab me in the eye!
Want to stab me?
Son of a bitch!
There's no one there, man.
There's no one there.
What's wrong, man? It's me!
Jesus, brother, you're too crazy, Zico.
It's me, man!
Give me the knife.
Get a grip, Zico.
You're trying to get yourself killed?
Stop smoking, Zico.
Stop smoking, man.
I don't want that shit in here anymore!
So, Mr. Pires, shall I go
and fetch the old man?
No, let him be.
When I went to visit Zico, Deusdete
didn't let us do crack in there.
-That's no reason to kill!
-I was scared shitless.
-Went to bed and woke up burned.
-How dare he kill without asking us?
Mind your own business.
He was a childhood friend.
If you had a friend to advise you,
would you have done the same thing?
That's their problem.
You're wrong.
Now it's our problem.
Here she comes!
Too Bad, honey...
...do you take Lady as your true wife?
Yes.
And do you, Lady...
...take Too Bad as your husband?
I do.
Then, as the presiding queen,
I hereby declare you...
...man and wife!
Kiss!
-Kiss!
-First, I want to propose a toast.
To the doctor!
Because thanks to all the
medicine this gentleman...
...has taught me, I'm going out
to open my own clinic.
While I wait for you, my beauty...
...so we can start our own family.
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Highness...
...can't I have some on account?
What the fuck?!
Son of a bitch!
Jesus, he chickened out.
Ezequiel.
Come here.
Come here, Ezequiel!
Hey, Ezequiel, you think
that bastard Zico...
...is to blame for all your misery, right?
Sure...
...but Ezequiel's life has
always been miserable.
And wasn't it Zico
who made Ezequiel...
...offer his sister for the drugs?
Sure, what was I supposed to do?
So forget it.
You did it.
Ezequiel stabbed Zico...
...over 30 times.
But Highness...
...Ezequiel will be out
in just two years.
-lf I do that, I'll get another 20!
-Two years, 20 years...
...what's the difference to Ezequiel?
Ezequiel has AIDS.
At least you'll get a cell to yourself...
...laundry...
...and, of course, crack to smoke.
I was the one who wiped out Zico.
Now I don't owe anyone a thing.
Bye, Chico!
Have faith!
Go in peace!
See you.
Good luck, Chico!
Old man?
Go in peace.
Keep it.
You need all the peace
you can get in there.
Why didn't you knife me?
I couldn't. What about him?
He won't leave me alone.
Follows me everywhere.
So, Zico, up in heaven,
did you meet anyone?
No one you know, just him.
No, Zico, what about God?
Not God in person.
I haven't seen him yet.
What's wrong?
Doctor, how can you tell whether
you're going mad?
Zico came back to haunt me
because I couldn't kill him.
You been seeing ghosts, Dagger?
A guy like me...
...unable to kill?
Never happened before!
Isn't that a good thing?
I only know how to kill.
That's how I grew up.
We change, Dagger.
Doctor...
...I have to know what's
happening to me.
Am I no longer myself?
Maybe it's your guilt over having
killed so many.
Doctor...
...is there a cure for guilt?
If there were,
everyone would want some.
Father.
Enter, brother.
Come!
Did you know the Lord
has a plan for you?
Enter!
This is your home.
You're lost, brother.
You don't know it,
but it was he who brought you here.
-Who, Father?
-Jesus!
He knows you can't sleep
if you haven't harmed someone...
...that you have sleepless nights
unless you've thrown a man down.
Isn't that what it's like every day,
brother? Come on, isn't it?
Yes, Father!
Yes, it is!
There is so much blood on me,
Father!
So, brother, kneel down.
Come on, kneel down!
Will you accept Jesus?
Will you accept Jesus? Will you?
Well, brother, will you accept Jesus?!
Which of you has accepted Jesus?
-I have!
Hallelujah!
Criminals of Brazil,
the big day is here:
The Pavilion 9 finals!
Marsh going for the trophy
with Valiant, Samuel, Dada, Saint...
...Indian Boa Ventura,
Minimum Wage, Valdir...
...AR15, Hildo, Ribeiro and Gerere!
Tornado 2000 is here with Little Eye,
Sleeve, White Feather, Gringo...
...Salomao Ayala, Eddie Murphy,
Greenhouse Joe, Zelao...
...Flavinho, Ebony 10 and Tafarel!
To kick off this glorious sporting
event, none other than our healer...
...the wizard of medical alchemy
and official trainer of the criminals!
And they're off!
Saint passes to AR15,
Dada covering him.
Marsh on the attack!
Forcing the ball back...
...into the hands of Tafarel!
Up goes the ball! And it's out.
This is one fast kick.
Eddie Murphy gets the ball...
...and they go on the attack.
They go onto the opposite field.
Capote blocks.
Hello.
-So, Beard, you all right?
-Couldn't be better.
Have a good weekend.
Unfortunately, the Beard was wrong.
He needed some of Chico's wisdom...
...who once said to me.:
"A quiet, obedient jail?
Sure sign of trouble. "
Two weeks later,
when I got back...
... there were nothing but bullet holes
covering the walls.
Hey, you!
-Go find your own line.
-I'll use this one.
Go away!
-Are you crazy, man?!
-Let me dry my clothes!
-You've got some nerve, man!
-What's it got to do with you?
Stop!
Stop or I'll shoot!
Some say it started because of
a debt for five packs of cigarettes.
Others say that it was a fight
over the soccer game.
One or two say it was about
a pair of underpants.
Like they say:
"Jail's no home for the truth."
And Dada's down, it's a penalty!
Dada's taking the penalty himself.
Getting ready...
...concentrating.
Go on, Dada!
Goal!
Mangue wins!
Dada's touched.
Jesus Christ!
-Let your head--
-Watch out, Rabbit's gang is coming.
-Just look what you did to him.
-Greedy bastard!
-You could have used your hand, man!
-Just over a pair of underpants!
What's wrong with you?
-Wait!
-Let me go!
-Why couldn't you have waited?
-What's it got to do with you?
-Stop it!
-Wait!
-What is it, man?
-Go fuck yourself, damn it!
We're the champions!
Yeah, yeah!
I was scared, doctor.
All hell broke loose...
...and when the blood boils,
criminals lose all control.
With the confusion, I could
easily have gotten hurt badly.
Riot in 9!
The place is ours!
Forget it, let them die if they
want. Let's get to our cell!
The war's started!
War! Let's torch the place!
Another explosion in the
overcrowded Detention Center...
...which is the biggest
in Latin America...
... with a total capacity
of 4000 inmates.
Only, nowadays it's more crowded
than ever...
...with 7500 prisoners!
The riot squad has been called
and is storming the jail...
... with over 300 men with rev olvers,
machine guns and tear gas.
By then, no one could
hear a damn thing.
Through the bars we could see
a bunch of masked cops.
All you could see was their eyes,
the dogs, machine guns...
...and a helicopter flying real low,
pointing a machine gun at us.
Certainly, sir, right away!
Orders from the governor.
-You're in charge now, colonel.
-The troops will do what's necessary.
You're an experienced man.
-lf you need to move in, go ahead.
-No, he can't! This is my jail!
Squad, attention!
Pay attention, men!
Return to your cells!
Back to your cells,
otherwise the cops are coming in!
If they come in here, they'll all die!
Mr. Pires, plenty of men should
have been released by now!
We want better conditions!
Mr. Pires, send the riot squad away!
Go back to your cells!
Everyone back to his cell
or you'll regret it!
No regrets in here!
How many hostages do you have?
Are there hostages in there?
We're no hostages, Mr. Pires!
This is our fight, Mr. Pires!
See, colonel?
They've no hostages, no water,
no electricity. They'll give in soon.
Save us, Mr. Pires!
Don't let them come in here.
Send the riot squad away!
I'm having a tough time
holding them back!
Let's keep calm!
Now, hand over your weapons!
Surrender your weapons!
See, colonel? Everything's calm.
You can send them away.
Pay attention!
Everyone back to your cells!
Return to your cells!
Let's stay calm!
Back to your cells!
With an election coming up, the
governor wouldn't let the jail explode.
Go on, get in!
You!
Show us the way, let's go!
We may be a bunch of ignorant
thieves and murderers...
...but we're not stupid.
No one wants to die.
As they came in,
we ran to our cells.
We couldn't put up a fight
with knives and sticks.
Go back, I'm warning you!
We've got AIDS! You're gonna die!
They came in to kill us, doctor,
shouting we all had AIDS...
...that they'd catch it
if they touched us.
Turn right!
And left!
Hey, get out!
I want to stay with you!
Sergeant, let's play
cops and robbers.
You're going to live
to tell the tale.
I changed my mind.
Like hell he changed his mind!
It was pure spite.
He fed Ezequiel a glimmer of hope
so he could come back and kill him.
You two been causing trouble?
No way, we're sports fans.
So, you thief, how do you like
some of your own medicine?
You got lucky this time.
Who knows?
I guess he didn't have the courage
to shoot a woman.
It was our love that saved us.
It was the cop's son
who saved my life.
God bless the cop's son.
God bless that cop's son!
I'm unarmed!
Out of your cell!
Put your hands on the wall!
-I know you killed a cop!
-I never killed anyone, sir!
I'm only in for three years.
Spare me! Spare me!
Listen here. The only reason
this is your lucky day...
...is because you look like my son.
Anyone alive, undress
and come out naked!
I want to hear you say:
" Long live the riot squad!"
Go on! " Long live the riot squad!"
Louder, you murderer!
Long live the riot squad!
Everyone, now!
Go on!
Move it, come on!
-There's no one alive inside!
-Let's go, then!
Undress, everything! Come on!
Undress, everything!
-Undress!
-Heads down!
" Davilson, dearest son...
...your mother weeps when she thinks
of you when you were little...
...laughing deep into my eyes.
I know you never
believed in my God...
...but today, as I read the Bible...
...it was as if you were here
in my lap again.
My heart trembled as
I read Psalm 91.
What beautiful words.
A thousand may fall
at your right hand...
...but no evil will come near you...
...no scourge come near your tent."
In the late '80s, AIDS
prevention work in jails...
... took me to the Sao Paulo
Detention Center. Carandiru.
There I heard stories, made
real friends, learned medicine...
...and penetrated a few
of the mysteries of life in jail...
... which would have remained
inaccessible were I not a doctor.
-Morning, doctor.
-Good morning.
Even today, whenever I hear
the iron gates close behind me...
...I feel that shudder,
just like all those matinees...
... where I'd sit glued to my chair as
I watched all those jail films in B&W.
On October 2, 1992, 111 men died
at the Sao Paulo Detention Center.
There were no police deaths.
The only ones who know what
really happened are God...
...the police and the inmates.
I only heard the latter.
On September 15, 2002,
the last inmates were transferred.
Once empty, Carandiru
closed its doors.
On December 9, Carandiru
was finally demolished.
subs by kitrinipapia