It all started on the day that I died.
If there had been an obituary...
...it would've described
the unremarkable life...
...of an unremarkable woman...
...survived by no one.
But there was no obituary...
...because the day that I died...
...was also the day I started to live.
But that comes later.
This was my life.
Days blended together,
consistently ordinary...
...thanks to a job that was the practical
version of my passion.
- I'm sorry.
- Watch where you’re going!
I was supposed to be an artist by now.
Instead...
...I was designing ads for beauty cream.
- You are so addicted to that stuff, Sally.
- Happily.
- Beau-line is magic in a bottle.
- I don't know how you get it.
- It's not even in production yet.
- We have our ways.
- Hey.
- No!
Headaches again.
My brain's all tight and cranky.
In one week, precisely, we will launch
the most exciting...
...and revolutionary product
to hit the beauty industry since...
...soap.
Beau-line.
Now, Beau-line doesn't
just hide the effects of aging...
...it actually reverses them.
However, with change...
...must come sacrifice.
My husband...
...and I have decided that
it's time for me to step aside...
...as the face of Hedare.
It has been a magnificent 15 years.
But we have decided to choose
a new face to represent Beau-line.
Exactly.
Drina.
The future of Hedare Beauty.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
I look forward...
...to seeing you at the gala, where you
can toast to Drina and our success.
Careful, George.
She's not old enough to drink.
You've got more talent than anybody
in the building, which I hate you for.
Sal, this is my first lead campaign.
It's gotta be perfect. You know that.
What is wrong with you?!
Good luck.
Yeah.
You simply couldn't resist it, could you?
You had to make
a scene out of it, Laurel.
What's the matter, George?
Did I steal your moment?
Come in!
Hi, Mr. Hedare.
Did you still want to see me, or...?
- Sit.
- Right. Okay.
I'm not pleased.
This isn't even close to what I wanted.
I can't imagine what on earth
you were thinking.
I am so sorry-
I mean, look at this red. It's all wrong.
I wanted it darker.
- I specifically heard you say-
- I know what I said.
- Okay. Maybe I misunderstood you.
- Clearly.
Mr. Hedare, I know I can fix it.
If you give me a chance,
I know I can fix it.
I do not reward incompetence.
I have no idea why I expected your art
to show better taste than your wardrobe.
Oh, and do try and get
a manicure, will you?
Oh, for God's sake, George.
Let her fix it.
She's good and you know it.
Whatever.
By tomorrow night.
Midnight.
Right. Thank you.
Excuse me. Hi!
Do you think you could just
maybe turn the music down...
...just a little bit?
No? Okay.
Kitty! Kitty.
How'd you get up there?
Come down here.
What, are you stuck?
You're gonna make me come out there.
Hey! Easy! Hold on a minute!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Whatever you're thinking or feeling...
...it's not worth it, you understand?
I'm a cop. Maybe I can help.
Okay. I'm fine.
- It's just that-
- Listen to me.
We'll get through this together.
What's your name?
Patience Phillips.
But this cat...
Sure, sure, Patience,
and it's a real beauty.
- Very cute.
- The cat's not up here anymore.
Okay. And I'm sure that
makes you very sad.
- What's your apartment number?
- Twenty-three!
Hold on!
Hurry.
I got you.
- You okay?
- Thanks.
You sure you're okay?
That was the cat.
You weren't kidding.
You actually climbed out there
to rescue your cat?
Yeah. I mean, no.
It's not my cat, it's a cat.
To rescue somebody else's cat?
Well, that's something else.
Oh, my gosh, I'm late for my job!
- I'm on a deadline today.
- Yeah? Well, good luck with that.
Thanks.
Thank you!
After all, no one can defeat Father Time.
Though you did put up
a hell of a fight, didn't you?
Beau-line works wonders, doesn't it?
Yes, it does.
I have a busy day today.
Drinks, then dinner.
Don't wait up, will you, darling?
I stopped waiting
a long time ago, George.
Oh, and that lunch tomorrow?
- Cancel that too, will you?
- Problems?
I doubt it...
...but Slavicky won't stop calling.
You know scientists.
They're worse than models. You have to
coddle them all the time like little children.
I'll have Wesley reschedule. Bye.
Hey! Man sandwich, 12 o'clock.
Oh, my God.
Hello, Miss Phillips.
Hi.
This is the officer I was telling you
about from earlier.
Detective Lone.
- Tom Lone.
- God, that is such a good name.
Tom Lone.
Rhymes with cone, phone, bone.
Not that rhyming's all that important.
I'll just be in my cubicle.
Alone.
- Hi.
How'd you get...?
You dropped something.
You can really cover a lot of ground
when you're in a hurry.
Thanks.
Is this yours?
Yeah.
- It's nice.
- Thanks.
Yeah, it kind of reminds me
of early Chagall.
Elegant, but whimsical.
Very much in the...
...tradition of the old Dutch Masters.
- I'm impressed.
Don't be. I noticed all the art in your
apartment, so I Googled it at the office.
- No, but really, I like it.
- Thanks.
Listen, I wanted to apologize about this
morning for thinking you were a jumper.
I was hoping to make it up
by taking you to coffee.
I know this great Italian place
around the corner, Grecchio's on 6th.
Or, listen, maybe tomorrow's better.
Say, 1:00?
Yes.
- Okay.
- Yeah?
Okay. So tomorrow then, 1:00.
- You make sure she gets there.
- Yes, officer.
- Counting on you.
- I screw it up...
...you can throw away the key.
See you tomorrow.
Okay, bye.
Patience.
- That is a man in serious like with you.
- You think?
- Hello.
- We got a lot of work to do.
First, you gotta shave those legs.
Second, wear that leather outfit
we got you for your birthday.
- Remember?
- First, it's only coffee.
And second, I will never, ever,
ever wear that leather outfit.
Good night!
Hi, this is Patience
in the art department.
Yeah, I'm expecting a messenger
to come and pick up-
But it's gotta be there by midnight.
Well, I...
I know it's not your fault, but...
Okay.
I'll take it myself.
Hello? Is anybody in there?
Oh, come on, Slavicky.
When did you grow a conscience?
I don't care that the FDA never saw
the headaches...
...and the nausea
and the fainting spells.
Those are symptoms I can live with.
Hello?
And with what we stand to make
from consumers demanding their fix...
...I can live with it being addictive.
But these side effects
from the long-term studies...
That won't happen if they keep using it.
And we'll make sure they do...
...because that's where
the money comes from.
I'm not sure anymore.
Hello? Hello?
I thought I could live with it...
...but I can't live with turning
people into monsters.
Oh, my gosh!
You've gotta let me pull the plug.
We can't let this go on the shelves.
Who's there?
- Armando, come in.
- I'm on my way.
You can come out now.
It's okay.
We'd just like to ask you
a few questions.
Sorry.
But I think maybe I'm in the wrong-
- What are you doing?
- Don't ever do that again.
Where is she?
She ran down to waste treatment,
jumped in a pipe.
We don't know who she is,
but we know what she heard.
We can't risk it.
Get rid of her.
Seal the door.
Patience Phillips,
I've never been so proud of you.
You 're probably sipping
your decaf soy whatever...
...fantasizing about licking
the foam off his lips.
Wait, that's what I'm doing.
How'd the presentation go?
Did you get me free samples of it?
Listen, call me.
What...?
Hi, I'll take a decaf latte.
Hey, Patience, it's Tom Lone.
I'm here at Grecchio's waiting...
...and you 're not here.
Anyway, I gotta get back to work, so...
Bye.
Okay, kitty.
It's time for you to go home.
Now...
- Are you Ophelia Powers?
- Yes.
- I got your cat off a ledge and ever since-
- Why, Midnight.
You've never brought a stranger
home before.
Please, come in.
No, I can't come in.
I've got to go to- I'm late.
- Midnight.
- I'm sorry?
Her name.
She's an Egyptian Mau,
the rarest of breeds. Temple cats.
It's said that Maus have
special powers.
Like popping out of nowhere? I know.
Among other things.
Your cat...
Socrates!
No caffeine.
It makes him irritable.
You look a little out of sorts yourself,
my dear.
The cats, perhaps.
They seem to be taking quite
an unusual shine to you.
This has been a really bad day
for me already.
- I can't even remember most of yesterday.
- Perhaps I can help you.
Right.
This really isn't your problem.
I don't even know why I'm here.
- It's all right. Tell me.
- Really. I'm late for work.
- I'm sorry. I shouldn't even...
- Come back anytime. I'm always here.
Catnip.
No-
I'm fine. I am fine.
What the hell is wrong with you?!
You never delivered the design!
You don't even know where they are.
You do not know where they are because,
and I quote you, you "cannot remember"!
Your incompetence is staggering!
Are you even listening to me?
I'm sorry!
"Sorry"?
Sorry's not nearly enough.
Okay.
Then let me try the remix.
I'm sorry for every second I wasted...
...working for an untalented,
unethical egomaniac like you.
Clean out your cubicle. You are fired.
Wait! Mr. Hedare!
I didn't mean it.
Did I?
My hero.
Where did that come from?
I don't know,
it's like I can't describe it.
I was saying it, but I wasn't saying it.
Do you understand?
Whoever said it has the thanks
of a grateful art department.
You don't understand, Sal.
I wanted to cause him pain.
I'm sorry.
- What was that?
- Allergies?
Maybe?
You just got fired, remember?
But it's so pretty.
Sal? Sal?
Sally?
Sally! Sally?
Hey.
Ever noticed when they keep you for
observation no one really observes you?
- Did they tell you what was wrong?
- Oh, they have no idea.
They did run a million fun tests, though.
Hey, upside, you gotta see my doctor.
I can see you're feeling better.
Reminds me, what's up with the
"hot yet modest, but who cares...
...because he's so hot" detective?
It's not gonna work out, Sal.
Patience, you never think
it's gonna work.
Because it doesn't. I've got a good
reason for saying it this time. Trust me.
Look, this time I refuse
to let you sabotage a good thing.
If it's broke, fix it.
All right? Now, I love you,
and he is gonna love you. Now, go.
Go give him some brown sugar.
I gotta meet my hottie doctor.
Tell me I look vulnerable.
Being good is something you keep
in your heart because you put it there.
I'm not saying it's easy. I'm not saying
some people don't choose to be bad.
But I want something different for you.
I want something better.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
- Can I see your gun?
- No.
- You know what makes somebody-
- Will you shoot it?
No.
I want you to be
the good guys, got it?
- Yeah.
- Let's go shoot some hoops.
I called the police station
and they said you might be here.
You never got your coffee.
Well, you're a brave man to be facing
a mob like this. No backup?
I'm used to working alone,
most of the time.
- Is that by choice, or-
- Yeah, theirs.
No, I've had partners before.
Turns out I take my job too seriously.
You know my friend Sally?
That's what she says about me.
She says that I'm fun-deficient.
- I don't believe that.
- That's what she says.
One-on-one?
- Who? Me and her?
- Yeah, come on.
You wanna do this?
One-on-one
I haven't done that since I was a kid.
Come on.
Can we have our ball back?
You don't seem so fun-deficient to me.
Mr. Hedare wanted me to inform you
he'll be at the factory the rest of the day.
If by "factory"
you mean the Four Seasons...
...teaching Drina
to unlock the minibar...
...consider me informed.
- He'll be working with-
Wesley, George hasn't said anything
meaningful to me since he said "I do."
- Hello?
- You'd think with the advances...
...in medicine, this place
would have a wet bar.
- Seems like you're feeling better.
- Some new medication I can't pronounce.
- So, what's up?
- Nothing. Just fixing a little snack.
What I'd like to know is
did you fix it with the cute cop?
I think I did.
Details! And make it good, honey.
I'm sitting here in a paper dress,
for God's sakes.
All we did was talk.
And play a little one-on-one.
- You know how to play basketball?
- Apparently I do.
- I even went Shaquille on his butt.
- Patience, have I taught you nothing?
You never beat a guy at sports.
It messes them up.
They end up in a men's group,
banging on a drum.
It's not like I meant to.
It just happened.
I'm telling you, Sal, something really,
really weird is happening to me.
- I practically jumped him.
- That's called lust, sweetheart.
- Animal attraction.
- You think?
What if it gets worse?
- I mean, what if the next time-
- Next time? He asked you out again?
- I love this guy.
- So do I. But it's me I'm worried about.
- I felt like I couldn't be myself.
- Well, feel free to be me next time.
- Sally-
- I'm teasing. Just be yourself.
Myself.
Okay.
- I'll try.
- Oh, I gotta go.
Future father of my children's coming.
Sweet dreams, honey.
Excuse me.
I think I might have a fever.
Hey!
- Shut that off!
- Get a life!
Yeah, get a life, you loser!
Sorry, babe.
This ain't the slumber party.
However...
...in your case,
I can make an exception.
I'm flattered.
But do you think this one time...
...you could turn the music down
just a little...
...bit.
Tell you what,
why don't I do it myself?
Hey! Hey! Listen, you freak-
I'm sorry, what did you say?
Is the music still too loud?
Hey!
You hear that? It's called silence.
That's all I ever wanted.
Now, keep it down.
Thanks for the party. I had fun.
- Time to accessorize.
- My bike!
Amateurs.
You boys thought you could come in here
and steal all these beautiful things?
What a perfect idea.
Meow.
That was one of a kind.
- From Egypt.
- That's a hell of a profile.
Thieves said she jumps around
like a cat.
What should we call her?
"Cat Chick"? No, no."Cat Broad."
What do you got?
Cupcakes.
Midnight.
I knew you'd come back
when you were ready.
The goddess Bast.
The Maus are sacred to Bast.
They're her messengers.
- You wrote this?
- I was a professor for 20 years...
...until I was denied tenure.
Male academia.
Bast is a rarity.
A goddess of the moon,
and of the sun.
She represents the duality in all women.
Docile, yet aggressive.
Nurturing, yet ferocious.
But what does all of this
have to do with me? I mean-
What happened the other night?
- I don't remember.
- Do you want me to tell you?
Yes.
You died.
What?
I didn't die. Look at me, I'm right here.
You died.
- But you were reborn.
- Oh, you're crazy.
- You are a crazy cat lady.
- Midnight knew your fate.
That's why she tested you.
To see if you were worthy
of a gift she could give you.
A gift that could change your life...
...and give you a new one.
You're not alone, child. He's saved
others before you. Look.
Catwomen are not contained
by the rules of society.
You follow your own desires.
This is both a blessing and a curse.
You will often be alone
and misunderstood.
But you will experience a freedom
other women will never know.
You are a catwoman.
Every sight, every smell...
...every sound, incredibly heightened.
Fierce independence, total confidence,
inhuman reflexes.
- So I'm not Patience anymore?
- You are Patience.
And you are Catwoman.
Accept it, child.
You've spent a lifetime caged.
By accepting who you are,
all of who you are...
...you can be free.
And freedom is power.
You saved my life, Midnight.
But somebody killed me...
...and I've got to find out who,
and why.
You dealt with Slavicky?
It's done.
Oh, my God. We danced all night.
- Been here all night.
- Absolutely.
Keep the change.
- What can I do for you?
- White Russian.
No ice, hold the vodka, hold the Kahlua.
Cream. Straight up.
Looking for something?
The other night you killed somebody.
She was a nice girl. Why?
Cat got your tongue?
I don't know. They told me to flush
the pipes so I flushed the pipes.
- Why?
- I don't know why.
Beau-line. There's something
wrong with Beau-line.
She heard something
she wasn't supposed to hear.
And Hedare is covering it up.
I can't live with turning people
into monsters.
Hey, hey, hey.
Wow!
You look amazing.
- Do you like it?
- Love it.
- Like the hair?
- Love the hair.
- Did good?
- You did real good.
This guy is good for you.
Aren't you glad I pushed you into it?
Props to Sally. Let me hear my props.
- Props to Sally.
- Yeah.
Clothes, and a treat.
So are you gonna be okay, or what?
I do feel better. That's maybe laying off
the Cosmos for a couple days.
Check this out.
Some chick in a cat suit
murdered Slavicky last night.
The actions of this lunatic will not
keep Beau-line off the shelves.
We will launch next week as planned...
...because we owe it to the women
of this country.
- Because-
- Please. That guy is so full of himself.
- I'm almost out.
- Let's see.
How long have you
been having headaches?
- About a month.
- Do me a favor.
- Stop using this.
- Why?
Because it's making you sick. Trust me.
Thank you, lieutenant.
You're gonna roll with him.
For Tom, from forensics.
Oh, and Slavicky homicide.
Maybe you'll want to look at that.
Hey, Bob, let me ask you a question.
Would your wife crawl out on the ledge
of a building to rescue a cat?
Maybe, if the cat was carrying a pizza.
Well, there are similarities.
- Shape of the S, harsh stroke of the R's.
- Were they written by the same person?
Well, it's not an exact science.
But this first one. The broad spacing
of the letters? Indicative of loneliness.
And the O reaching out, insecure.
Handwriting of a people-pleaser.
Now, we look at the loop of the Y.
Very self-confident, almost angry.
And the O, well, this person
doesn't like to play by the rules.
- So they're different people.
- Very.
If you put these two women
in the same room...
...you're gonna have one hell of a party.
- You got a big weekend planned, Tom?
- I do now.
Aren't you supposed to let me win?
Not that kind of girl.
- What kind of girl is that?
- A loser.
Hey, can I ask you a question?
You work for Hedare, right?
Somebody was murdered at his factory
the other night.
I'm sorry.
Can you think of anybody who might
have a grudge against the company?
Lots of people. George Hedare isn't
the nicest guy in the world, you know.
He fired me.
What? Am I a suspect now, detective?
No.
Looks like we'll be
up here for a while.
You in a hurry?
Mom!
- Hey!
- Don't move!
Hold on tight. I gotta stop this thing.
- Mom!
- Frankie.
Mom! Mom!
Help, Mom!
Mom!
Help, Mom! Help! Help!
You are one tough little guy,
you know that?
- Take it easy, partner.
- Bye.
It's over.
Well, I'm not sure how you did it,
but I'm impressed.
Well, I saw how you did. And so am I.
- You know what?
- What?
We should celebrate. Why don't you
let me take you to dinner tonight?
I would love to, but I can't.
Not tonight. I've got...
...some business
that I have to take care of.
You picked the wrong house.
You're the cat that killed Slavicky.
You don't believe everything
you see on TV, do you?
- What do you want?
- Your husband. Is he home?
I'm here. Why on earth
would he be home?
Oh, too bad.
If your husband ever comes home,
tell him I know all about Beau-line.
It's disease in a jar.
I wouldn't caulk a sink with it.
- Come on. I've been using it for years.
- It's your funeral.
Because whoever killed Slavicky did it
to keep Beau-line's toxic little secret.
Are you suggesting that my husband
is a murderer?
I'm suggesting that
you tell me where he is.
- So I'll ask him myself.
- I suppose I should be shocked.
Protest his innocence. But the truth is...
...that man's capable of anything.
You wanna find him?
There he is.
- Thanks.
- I'd like to help.
How can I reach you?
I'm not exactly listed.
Take my phone.
Call the cops.
You're not going to believe this.
I think this is a total waste of time.
- Don't.
- What?
Think. Ever.
Consider it a condition
of our relationship.
I love this part.
- Who the hell-?
- Like my nails?
Just got them done.
My bad.
Get your paws off me this instant!
I know about Beau-line,
and your cover-up.
What?
So did my girl, Patience.
That's why you killed her.
- What? I didn't kill her-
- Too bad your last words will be a lie.
Freeze!
Hey!
Hold it right there.
Don't you move.
Now, come down from there
nice and easy.
Cats come when they feel like it.
Not when they're told.
I won't tell you again. You turn around.
Hands on your head.
You're under arrest.
Gotcha!
- You think this is a game?
- Now we're playing.
- You're playing. I'm at work.
- Seems like you love your job.
- Don't I get din-din first?
- I'll feed you in your cell.
Careful. That cable hits us,
we're both fried.
I knew I felt a spark between us.
- Not on the first date.
- Don't flatter yourself. I'm taken.
Does she know about us?
There's no "us."
Too bad.
It's over.
There she is.
Okay, boys.
Show of hands.
Who can see in the dark?
I can.
But this is a disaster!
It's a total bloody disaster.
How does she know all this?
Who is she, anyway? And how come-?
It's all right.
Don't be scared.
Great. You haven't got a clue, do you?
We are in absolute ruin here...
...and your brilliant piece of advice
to me is: "Don't be scared"?
No. My advice to you, George...
...quit the self-tanning.
Stop eating Viagra like they're vitamins.
Resist the urge to date children born the
same day they invented the cell phone.
For once, George,
in your miserable life...
...be a man!
Terrific.
Beau-line works wonders, doesn't it?
Okay, Sal. What do you think?
I don't know. You going to a church
or a Playboy mansion?
Well, that was helpful.
I'm such a freak.
Please, I'm a freak Thursday
through Sunday, big deal.
Okay, but what if he doesn't like...
...the real me?
- He can't pick and choose, Patience.
If he wants this to work,
he's gonna have to like all of you.
- Senora Hedare. Perdon.
- Go.
Pretty.
- Thanks.
- Oh, you too.
But I was talking about the fish.
Detective work is like dating.
It's all about the pursuit.
But when you catch them-
You like your sushi, huh?
That's good.
So tell me about this one...
...that got away.
Catwoman.
- You heard of her?
- Oh, yeah. Hot, black leather, whip.
She kissed me.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- What do you think about that?
- Depends.
- You like bad girls?
- Only if they like me back.
No, listen, bad isn't something
that does it for me.
Okay, bad, good.
Gotta be something in between, right?
Maybe it's a little more complicated.
- Why don't we talk about you?
- Okay.
- What's it like to be an artist?
- Well, I'm not really an artist.
I mean, yeah, I did go to art school...
...but then I got a regular job
at an advertising agency...
...and now I don't really know
what I am anymore.
Well, I know what you are.
You're different.
You're special.
- And I like that about you.
- Thanks.
No, it's true.
And I want to know more about you.
You know...
...I guess there's a few things
I need to explain.
Like what, your new look? Huh?
- Your dunk shot?
- No, that's not what I was thinking.
Hey.
You can tell me anything.
I'm...
I hate the rain!
What were you saying?
Nothing important.
Tom?
It's me.
You were right about Beau-line's secrets.
I can't believe it, but you were right.
Beau-line is toxic.
I have proof. We can stop him,
but we have to stop him together.
George will be launching Beau-line
at a press conference tomorrow.
Beau-line will be on the shelves
on Monday.
So, what'd you find?
Enough evidence to put someone away
for a long, long time.
I was everything they wanted me to be.
I was never more beautiful.
Never more powerful.
And then I turned 40
and they threw me away.
It's all there behind the desk.
How'd I do?
The clawed-flesh thing
was a little tricky...
...but I think I pulled it off.
- You killed him?
- No one is gonna stop Beau-line...
...from hitting the shelves.
Not Slavicky.
Not George. And certainly not you.
I'm sorry. I'm forgetting my manners.
Can I offer you something?
Can of tuna? Saucer of milk?
Smoking gun? Which, sweetheart, you
just emptied into my husband's chest.
Oh, George!
Help, somebody help!
It's Catwoman! She killed George.
Oh, my God!
Patience.
I'm sorry.
I guess you could take this right
out of my hands if you wanted.
If I wanted.
I'm telling you, Slavicky had evidence
that Beau-line was toxic.
That's why Laurel killed him.
George found out and she killed him too.
She was covering it up.
Ballistics show the same weapon killed
both men: The gun in your hand.
- Catwoman's hand.
- What's the difference?
- Guess it doesn't matter.
- Don't you understand?
All of the evidence, every single piece,
it points to you.
There's nothing that shows me
anything else.
There's me.
You can believe me.
Do you remember the first time
you saw me?
Yeah.
What did you see?
A girl...
...rescuing a cat.
No, you didn't.
You saw a crazy person out on a ledge
trying to jump.
And all the evidence pointed to that,
didn't it?
I really need you to believe me.
How can I?
I don't know who you are.
I'm the same girl
you were with last night.
Take her back.
You be a nice kitty, now.
Look at it this way, Lone.
You may have lost your woman,
but at least you got your man.
Did I?
Yeah.
Hello, Midnight.
You've spent a lifetime caged.
By accepting who you are,
all of who you are...
...you can be free.
And freedom is power.
It's not just about me
anymore, Midnight.
You know...
...Lassie would have brought me a key.
Cross your paws.
- We' re gonna shift-change in half an hour.
- All right.
- Dave's gonna take over then?
- Yeah, as far as I know.
Yeah, right through here, pal.
You'll get to talk to a lawyer.
Are you okay?
A girl like me lands on her feet.
Wait! Wait!
My husband dreamed of a world...
...where every woman could be
as beautiful as she wanted to be.
He dedicated his life pursuing that dream.
As Hedare's new chief executive...
...I intend to make that dream a reality...
...by proceeding with tomorrow's launch
of Beau-line.
Thank you!
Thank you so much. I have been dying
to get some of this stuff.
My husband would have wanted you
to have it. He wanted that for everyone.
- Detective Lone. What a surprise.
- Yeah?
Everyone, this is the man that brought
my husband's killer to justice.
Can I talk to you, in private?
Come upstairs to my office.
- Number five, ready to go.
- Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, go ahead. Right there.
Get a move on.
Gotta meet that midnight delivery.
I saw her standing over him.
There were claw marks all over his body.
- But not on Slavicky's.
- Because she didn't have the time.
She also didn't have a motive.
- I don't know.
- What if I told you I know the truth?
That I know who killed your husband,
I know about Beau-line.
Why, detective, you make it sound
like I'm a suspect.
What if I told you I had evidence?
If you have evidence,
then how come I'm not in cuffs?
Well, you're a smart woman,
Mrs. Hedare. Beautiful. Rich.
I thought maybe we could
work something out.
So this evidence... You'll make it
disappear? Pin it on the other girl?
If that's what you want me to do.
And you?
- What do you want?
- You just gave me what I want.
You just told me it was you.
Now, why would you believe it was me?
Because I finally trusted a friend.
Yeah, well, your friend
just got you killed.
Don't be stupid, Laurel.
You don't want to kill a cop.
I'm a woman, Lone.
I'm used to doing all kinds
of things I don't wanna do.
Give my regards to my husband.
How sweet.
Thanks. Now I can kill you both.
Hold on, I gotta stop.
How is it?
Well, there goes my jump shot.
Listen.
I want you to know I'm sorry.
I should have trusted you all along.
You're confusing me
with somebody else.
Come on, Patience.
I'll take this side.
I can't believe I ever trusted you.
- You're a fake.
- And what are you? A hero?
A thief?
A freak?
If you don't have an identity,
why keep it a secret?
Because you killed me.
It was me you flushed down the pipes.
I'm Patience Phillips.
That's who's under there?
- I can't be hurt.
- Beau-line.
You stop using it
and your face disintegrates.
And if you keep using it,
skin like living marble.
And you can't feel a thing.
You're just a scared little girl
playing dress-up.
Nobody. Nothing.
Where do you think you're going?
You're gonna look like a cop-killer.
You wanted to save him.
Honey, you couldn't save yourself.
Game over.
Guess what.
It's overtime.
Give me your hand!
Help me!
I might not be a hero,
but I'm certainly not a killer.
You know...
...once Laurel's boys start talking...
...we'll be able to wrap up
these murder cases pretty easy.
And if Patience is back in her cell
by tomorrow morning...
...it'll be awfully tough to prove
that she was Catwoman.
Exactly.
Delicious, thank you.
You know, the strawberry was good too.
The day I died
was the day I started to live.
In my old life, I longed for someone
to see what was special in me.
You did, and for that
you'll always be in my heart.
But what I really needed
was for me to see it.
And now I do.
You 're a good man, Tom.
But you live in a world that has no place
for someone like me.
You see, sometimes I'm good.
Oh, I'm very good.
But sometimes I'm bad.
But only as bad as I wanna be.
Freedom is power.
To live a life untamed and unafraid
is the gift that I've been given...
...and so my journey begins.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group