Let us praise famous men
and our fathers that begat us.
All these men were honoured
in their generations
and were a glory in their days.
We are here today to give thanks
for the life of Harold Abrahams.
To honour the legend.
Now there are just two of us,
young Aubrey Montague and myself,
who can close our eyes
and remember those few young men
with hope in our hearts
and wings on our heels.
"Carlton Hotel, Broadstairs, Kent.
28th June, 1924."
"Dear Mum, I'm most awfully sorry
about your cold and the general dreariness. "
"We're having quite bad weather here too. "
"Thanks for your letters.
I'm sorry you are disappointed
that I let the Olympic Games
interfere with my shorthand. "
"But if you were my age,
with a chance at the world championship,
you'd be just as big a fool as I am. "
"We've just one week to go now. "
"It hardly seems that
since we arrived at Cambridge,
never suspecting
what extraordinary times lay ahead. "
"Mind you, Harold has hardly changed at all -
as intense as ever. "
"Now, as then, having a go
at anybody who stands in his way. "
I suppose a taxi's out of the question, is it?
- Do you need some help?
- I'll say.
- Let me have those clubs.
- That's jolly kind.
Don't mention it.
Right.
- All set?
- You sure you're all right?
- I'm fine. Lead on.
- Thanks.
Sorry? The clubs and things?
It's all show, really, though I do enjoy it.
- I take it you're not keen.
- I run.
- Really? So do I.
- I'm surprised you find the time.
- Trouble is, I can't stand getting beaten. You?
- I don't know, I've never lost. Top pocket.
- Thank you.
- Carry your suitcase, sir?
Yes. Yes, of course. Yes.
This way.
- Which college, sir?
- Gonville and Caius.
- The same.
- This way, please, gents.
There we are.
- Here, give me that.
- Thanks.
Come along, Bill.
Let's get these cases over here.
That's the way.
Thank you. Thank you, sir.
Thanks very much.
Yes. Thank you.
Good luck.
That's what we fought the bleeding war for.
Give shits like them a decent education.
Hey, come on.
I'll take these.
- See you inside, Aubrey.
- Right.
- Name, please?
- We're new.
I can see that, laddie. What's your name?
Abrahams. HM.
- Top of the list. Repton. That the one?
- That's it. Left a year ago.
Been doing your bit? France?
- No. Joined too late.
- Bad luck, lad.
Many a dead man would've liked a share of it.
You're right there, son.
Welcome to Caius.
Sign here.
Thank you.
Across the courtyard,
right-hand corner, up the stairs.
Thanks. By the way, what are your names?
Rogers, head porter,
and this is Mr Ratcliffe, my assistant.
Mr Rogers, Ratcliffe, I ceased to be "laddie"
when I took up the King's commission.
- Is that clear?
- Yes... Mr Abrahams. Quite clear.
Thank you. I'd be obliged
if you'd remember it.
- See you later.
- Fine.
What's your friend studying, then, son?
Barrack-room law?
I've no idea.
One thing's certain - a name like Abrahams,
he won't be in the chapel choir, now, will he?
- Name?
- Montague.
- What?
I take the war list
and I run down it.
Name after name which I cannot read
and which we, who are older than you,
cannot hear without emotion.
Names which will be only names
to you, the new college,
but which, to us, summon up face after face,
full of honesty and goodness,
zeal and vigour
and intellectual promise.
The flower of a generation.
The glory of England.
And they died for England
and all that England stands for.
And now, by tragic necessity,
their dreams have become yours.
Let me exhort you - examine yourselves.
Let each of you discover
where your true chance of greatness lies.
For their sakes, for the sake of your college
and your country, seize this chance,
rejoice in it, and let no power or persuasion
deter you in your task.
Thursday, October 10th, 1919.
My first day at Cambridge was rounded off
by the freshmen's dinner. A sumptuous affair.
The master gave us a moving speech and I'm
now eagerly awaiting the start of term proper.
Rugby club, golfing society, tennis,
squash club, flora and fauna, philately.
- Is that all? You're idle.
- I can't join everything. I must work.
- Bird watching. Take a book.
- How can I watch if I'm reading?
Follow in the footsteps ofWG.
Any Yorkshiremen?
- There you are, Stallard.
- I can't bat for toffee.
- Abrahams.
- Can you manage tenor?
- We're short of tenors.
- Only under torture. Aubrey? Sing, do you?
- School choir, that's all.
- Stallard?
Not on your life. They kicked me out
of "Ring-a-ring o' Roses".
Sorry. We can't all be gifted.
- Put my friend down as well.
- Steady on.
Splendid. Rehearsals start Monday. lolanthe.
- I was a boy alto.
- Perfect. You can be Queen of the Fairies.
We have a solemn duty
to those lives needlessly slaughtered.
Glad to have you. Good middle-distance men
don't grow on trees.
I can't vouch for those times.
Taken with the school alarm clock,
most of them.
Give or take a second,
they're good enough for me.
Have you come across
a fellow called HM Abrahams?
- He's challenged for the college dash.
- What's so special about that?
It's special because in 700 years, nobody's
ever done it. Right, what do you do?
Right, chaps, thank you. Thank you.
HM Abrahams of Gonville and Caius has
formally made challenge for the college dash.
You show 'em, Harold.
For those unfamiliar with the rules,
they are as follows.
The challenger will run around the court
perimeter, to and from a fixed point,
within the time taken
by the clock to strike midday,
a distance traditionally recognised
as one of 188 paces.
I say, Abrahams,
what have you got on your feet? Rockets?
- The challenge will commence on...
- You haven't got a chance.
Do it for Israel.
The challenge commences on the stroke
of one. He must finish before the stroke of 12.
- Come on, Abrahams, you swank.
- Will the challenger make himself ready?
This Abrahams,
what do you know about him?
Repton chap. Jewish.
His father's a financier in the city.
Financier? What's that
supposed to mean, I wonder?
I imagine he lends money.
Exactly. And what do they say about the son?
Academically sound. Arrogant.
Defensive to the point of pugnacity.
As they invariably are.
Yet possessing
a keen sense of duty and loyalty.
- Do they say he can run?
- Like the wind.
Gentlemen, would you draw back, please?
Away from the course. Thank you.
Mr Abrahams, your position, please.
Owing to the absence of a challenger,
Abrahams will run alone.
Not so, Mr Starter.
- Your name and college, if you please.
- Lindsay. I race beside my friend here.
We challenge in the name
of Repton, Eton and Caius.
- I didn't know you ran.
- Nor I you. Some chap told me about this.
I thought I'd come and push you along.
- Delighted. Good luck.
- Splendid.
Gentlemen, to your marks, if you please.
Now remember, on the first strike of 12.
Come on.
Come on. Stay with it.
Run harder. Come on.
Come on.
Seven.
- Get those legs working.
- Eight.
Nine.
Go on. Go on, Harold.
- Did they both do it?
- I think not.
- Young Lindsay failed by a whisker.
- Pity.
Well, it's been done.
And by a Caius man. You must be very proud.
The first man in seven centuries.
Perhaps they really are
God's chosen people, after all.
I doubt if there's
a swifter man in the kingdom.
Get to your marks.
Get set.
Go on, run, Steve.
Come on, Alan, faster.
He may be your best friend, Sandy,
but he's my best brother.
I'm thinking of him, not your blessed athletics
team. His heart's set on the mission.
Do you not think he's got enough
on his plate without racing?
He's fast, Jennie.
You've seen him with a ball in his hands.
I've seen him with a Bible in his hands.
I know which is the most important.
You can't deny him the chance. On the track,
the right technique, I'm telling you...
Don't tell me, Sandy. I don't want to hear.
Eric's special to me, precious.
I don't want his work spoilt
with all this running talk, do you hear?
There you are. Well done.
You know, ladies and gentlemen,
one of the compensations of achieving
a certain notoriety - if only as a rugby player -
is that occasionally you're asked
to come along and give things away.
It's often said that giving beats receiving.
Let me tell you, the look of delight
on those little boys' faces
was worth ten of any of the tin pots I've got
gathering dust on my Edinburgh sideboard.
When we were in China, my father here
was always waxing lyrical
about his wee home in the glen.
But being oriental-born myself,
like my brothers and my sister here,
I suffered from a natural incredulity.
But looking about me now,
at the heather on the hills,
I can see he was right. It's very special.
Thank you for welcoming us home.
And thank you for reminding me that I am,
and will be whilst I breathe...
.. a Scot.
Mr Provost, sir.
Before you allow Eric here to go,
is it not true that the main event
is still to be run?
It is. Aye. The 200 yards open championship.
It's the last event of this gathering,
by tradition.
Do you not think, if we can find him some kit,
we might persuade Scotland's finest wing
to show us his paces?
- What do you say, Eric?
- Come on.
To your marks. Get set.
Didn't I tell you, Eric? Didn't I tell you?
Surely a touch of liberality
would do no harm?
Sandy, the kingdom of God
is not a democracy.
The Lord never seeks re-election.
There's no discussion, no deliberation,
no referenda as to which road to take.
There's one right, one wrong,
one absolute ruler.
- A dictator, you mean.
- Aye, but a benign, loving dictator.
So much for your freedom of choice.
You've still got a choice, Sandy.
Nobody's forcing you to follow him.
- Do you know what day it is?
- Yeah.
- Tell me, then.
- Sunday.
- The Sabbath's not a day for football, is it?
- No.
- Are you up early in the morning?
- Me ma gets me up at seven.
We'll have a game then, then. OK?
Mr Liddell, is it OK if me da comes?
Sure. Bring your whole family.
I'll give you a five-goal start.
- Your train's at nine.
- There's plenty of time.
Do you want the kid to grow up
thinking God's a spoilsport?
If I may, I'd like to propose a toast.
To the Liddell family, whom
I'm fortunate enough to call my friends.
The Reverend JD, Mrs L, young Ernest.
Bon voyage and safe journey back to China.
May the years ahead be happy and content.
For those who remain, may God protect them,
inspire them, and lead them to glory.
Thank you, Sandy. That was very nice.
I'm relying on you
to keep them out of mischief.
That I will, Mrs L. If they do transgress,
I'll pop the details on a postcard.
You can read all about it
before you can say "Marco Polo".
- Cost you a fortune in stamps.
- Don't worry.
I intend to protect my investment.
I'm going to rule you with a rod of iron.
Careful. We're going
to have to watch ourselves.
You're a very lucky young man, Eric.
You're the proud possessor of many gifts.
It's your sacred duty to put them to good use.
Dad's right. Run like we know you can,
strong and true.
The mission cannot but gain by your success.
What we need now is a muscular Christian.
To make folk sit up and notice.
How good are you, Eric?
Sandy reckons he'll run for Scotland
before the month's out.
Then after that, the sky's the limit.
Meaning what?
The Olympic Games, maybe?
Eric, you can praise the Lord
by peeling a spud if you peel it to perfection.
Don't compromise.
Compromise is a language of the devil.
Run in God's name
and let the world stand back in wonder.
You came to see a race today,
to see someone win.
It happened to be me.
But I want you to do more
than just watch a race.
I want you to take part in it.
I want to compare faith to running in a race.
It's hard.
It requires concentration of will,
energy of soul.
You experience elation
when the winner breaks the tape.
Especially if you've got a bet on it.
But how long does that last?
You go home. Maybe your dinner's burnt.
Maybe you haven't got a job.
So who am I to say believe, have faith,
in the face of life's realities?
I would like to give you something more
permanent, but I can only point the way.
I have no formula for winning the race.
Everyone runs in her own way
or his own way.
And where does the power come from
to see the race to its end?
From within.
Jesus said:
"Behold, the kingdom of God is within you. "
"If with all your hearts ye truly seek me,
ye shall ever surely find me. "
If you commit yourself to the love of Christ,
then that is how you run a straight race.
Cheers. Thanks for coming.
Thanks for coming.
It's an ache.
A helplessness.
And an anger.
One feels humiliated.
Sometimes I say to myself,
"Steady on, you're imagining all this. "
Then I catch that look again.
Catch it on the edge of a remark.
Feel a cold reluctance in a handshake.
That's my father.
A Lithuanian Jew.
He is alien. He's as foreign as a frankfurter.
And a kosher one at that.
I love and admire him.
He worships this country.
From nothing, he built what he believed was
enough to make true Englishmen of his sons.
My brother's a doctor.
A leader in his field.
- Which one is you?
- There's me with the curls. On his back.
He wanted for nothing.
And here am I, setting up shop
in the finest university in the land.
But the old man forgot one thing.
This England of his is
Christian and Anglo-Saxon.
And so are her corridors of power.
And those who stalk them
guard them with jealousy and venom.
You're right to study law.
You're quite an advocate.
A rare ethnic advantage.
It's called the gift of the gab.
So what now? Grin and bear it?
No, Aubrey.
I'm going to take them on.
All of them. One by one.
And run them off their feet.
"England beckons for sprint blue.
From our special correspondent. "
"Clean sweep for Cambridge star.
Abrahams hat trick. "
"From our special correspondent. "
Bravo.
Bravo, Harold.
4-1 Liddell. What are you asking?
€25, Liddell to win.
Mr Mussabini, I believe.
My name's Colonel John Keddie. I'm...
President of the Scottish Three As.
I know, and I'm glad to know you, sir.
How's the leg? Nasty fall you took.
Good luck.
You're very welcome here, of course,
but we do have a strict amateur code.
Colonel, don't worry your head.
I'm here spectating, that's all.
Good. I felt sure you would understand.
Well, to battle. I hope you enjoy the games.
Games? You must be joking.
I've seen better-organised riots.
Come on, Scotland.
Gentlemen, get to your marks.
Get set.
Get up, lad. Get up.
Come on.
He'll never do it.
Don't you believe it. His head's not back yet.
Come on, Eric.
Get back. Give him air.
Well done, Eric, son. Well done.
He'll be right in a jiffy.
I'll away and get his clothes.
You take good care
of this lad of yours, Mr McGrath.
Because if you drop him,
you'll never find another one like this.
It's not the prettiest quarter
I've ever seen, Mr Liddell,
but certainly the bravest.
Get him up. Come on, gently.
Keep your arm around.
Mr Mussabini.
Mr Abrahams, is it?
So you've travelled 300 mile just to see me?
You and Liddell.
I'd heard you were both the best.
- And what do you think now?
- Eric Liddell?
I've never seen such drive,
such commitment in a runner.
He runs like a wild animal. He unnerves me.
So he should. He frightens
the living daylights out of me.
Yes, well, I want you to help me take him on.
- Tell me, Mr Abrahams, are you married?
- No. Why?
Well, when the right girl comes along,
how will you feel if she pops the question?
You see, Mr Abrahams,
like the bridegroom,
it's the coach that should do the asking.
Mr Mussabini,
I can run fast.
With your help, I think I can run even faster.
Perhaps faster than any man ever ran.
I want that Olympic medal.
Now, I can see it there, it's waiting for me,
but I can't get it on my own.
Well, we've an old saying in my game, son -
you can't put in what God's left out.
Now, you leave it to me.
I'll watch you, I'll observe,
and if I think I can help -
if I can see the big prize hanging there -
believe me, I won't waste any time.
When we meet again,
I'll be the one that does the begging.
- So you will watch me?
- Son, if you're good enough,
I'll take you apart piece by bloody piece.
Thank you.
- Didn't I tell you? Isn't she a peach?
- She's magnificent.
Bravo. Bravo.
- I think it went rather well.
- I must say I'm enjoying it.
- What about you, JB?
- I've done better productions myself.
- I don't remember seeing any.
- So the stone heart's frail.
- Abrahams is smitten?
- Smitten? He's decapitated.
- He won't listen to reason.
- The lad's in love.
He's just set eyes on her.
I've worshipped her for years.
- By the way, where is he now?
- He's gone to ask her out to dinner.
- Has he, by Jove?
- In the interval?
- Thank you. Mine, I take it?
- Ah, Harold.
Lovely.
- Well?
- Well what?
- Did you speak to her?
- Yes.
- Is she coming?
- To dinner?
- Yes.
Her kid brother, athletics-mad,
never stops talking about me.
Monty, you'd better have my glass.
I've a feeling you're going to need it.
Sorry, Monty.
Yes, thank you very much, sir.
Yes, of course I will, sir.
Good evening, Miss Gordon.
A triumph, I hear.
Very naughty. You should have come in.
Who was that chap over there?
Music critic of the Star.
Boring old buffer, really.
- He obviously enjoyed it.
- I shouldn't think so.
They always say that. They save the poison
for the print. A bit off tonight, I thought.
- What? You were magnificent.
- Thank you.
One of our little maids has gone
and got herself preggers with a gondolier.
We had to shove her second on tonight.
The trio...
- Your usual, Miss Gordon?
- Thank you, Toffy.
- And you, sir.
- Thank you.
This is Mr Abrahams, a very famous runner.
He's trying your special for the first time.
- I hope you enjoy it, sir.
- I'm sure I shall.
Well, go on, then.
It's a secret concoction of Toffy's,
a sort of cocktail de maison.
So you'd jolly well better enjoy it.
- Excellent.
- There, Toffy.
You've won yourself a friend for life.
My favourite, please.
- For two.
- My pleasure.
What have I ordered?
Surprise. Cheerio.
Cheerio.
Well, the great Harold Abrahams.
My brother will be insanely jealous.
So will mine.
- You don't look very ruthless.
- Should I?
According to my brother.
Tim says that's why you always win.
- Why running?
- Why singing?
It's my job.
No, that's silly. I do it because I love it.
- Do you love running?
- I'm more of an addict.
It's a compulsion. A weapon.
- Against what?
- Being Jewish, I suppose.
You're not serious?
You're not Jewish, or you wouldn't ask.
Fiddlesticks. People don't care.
Anyway, being Jewish
hasn't done you any harm.
I'm what I call "semideprived".
That sounds clever. What does it mean?
It means they lead me to water,
but they won't let me drink.
You're a funny old stick, Mr Harold Abrahams.
Funny, but fascinating.
I'll settle for the fascinating.
Life isn't that gloomy, is it?
Not tonight.
You're so beautiful.
Like you.
Pigs' trotters, sir.
My God.
The train arriving at platform two is the
overnight Flying Scotsman from Aberdeen.
7:30, Mr Liddell. 7:30 on the dot.
- There you are, sir. Hot tea and toast.
- Great.
- You sleep all right?
- Like a log.
You must have a clear conscience.
- Far from it. Are we here?
- Aye, sir. Just pulled in. King's Cross.
And here's the paper, with your picture in.
Expecting great things, from all accounts.
Are they indeed?
- Here you are.
- Much obliged, sir.
No hurry. You've got an hour before
we kick you out. Good luck for this afternoon.
- Thank you.
- Come on, sir.
Aye, Mr Abrahams. So's the Scot.
Mr Abrahams?
Mr Liddell.
- I'd like to wish you the best of success.
- Thank you.
And may the best man win.
Get to your marks.
Get set.
Extraordinary.
Harold.
This is absolutely ridiculous. It's a race
you've lost, not a relative. Nobody's dead.
For goodness' sake, snap out of it, Harold.
You're behaving like a child.
- I lost.
- I know.
I was there, remember? Watching.
It was marvellous.
You were marvellous.
He was more marvellous, that's all.
On the day, the best man won.
I had to look for him.
It's absolutely fundamental. You never look.
He was ahead. There was nothing you
could've done. He won fair and square.
Well, that's that, Abrahams.
- If you can't take a beating, it's for the best.
- I don't run to take beatings.
I run to win. If I can't win, I won't run.
If you don't run, you can't win. Give me
a ring when you've sorted that one out.
Sybil...
Don't go.
- I just don't know what to do.
- Try growing up.
Harold.
You're a great man. You ran like a god.
I was proud of you. Don't make me ashamed.
It's not the losing, Syb.
Eric Liddell's a fine man and a fine runner.
It's me.
After all that work,
now, God knows, what do I aim for?
Beating him the next time.
Sybil, I can't run any faster.
Mr Abrahams.
I can find you another two yards.
Charlie Paddock. Californian Cannonball.
World's fastest human. Winner, 100 metres,
Olympic Games, 1920, Antwerp. Time?
Ten point three.
Jackson Scholz, the New York Thunderbolt.
Runner-up, Olympic Games, 1920.
Lost by looking right.
Look, here's the finish. You see?
Paddock, leaping past him at the tape?
That glance cost Scholz the race.
- Scholz's fastest?
- Ten point three... Four.
Eric Liddell. Well, you know all about him.
Look at them. Think them. Breathe them.
I want their faces leering at you
every time you shut your eyes.
The Flying Scotsman first. That bloody hurt.
What, Eric Liddell? Well, he's no real problem.
He's a great runner, but he needs to go
further out. He's no 100 metres man.
- Could've fooled me.
- Yeah, he's fast.
But he won't go any faster,
not in the dash, anyway. He's a gut runner.
He's all heart. Digs deep.
A short sprint is run on nerves.
- It's tailor-made for neurotics.
- Thanks.
You can push guts, bully them,
but you can hone nerves.
Paddock, Scholz and Eric Liddell.
Come here a minute, Mr Abrahams.
Now, do you know
why you lost the other day?
Because you're overstriding.
Just a couple of inches. Now...
These coins represent the strides
in your hundred metres.
Have you got another two coins,
Mr Abrahams?
Well, maybe we can find them.
As I said, overstriding.
Death to the sprinter.
Slap in the face each stride you take.
Knocks you back.
Like that.
And that.
Now...
I want you to imagine
you're running on hot bricks.
If you leave your feet on the ground,
they'll get burnt.
Up, up, up. Light, light, light.
Light as a feather.
Set.
No. Not your head back again.
Get it level. Go and do it again.
That's it.
Faster.
Pass the car. Go on.
Go on. Go on.
Go on, go on. On, on.
Come on, now. Keep it up, come on.
Rhythm, Mr Abrahams, rhythm.
Training, training. All I ever hear is training.
Do you believe in
what we're doing here or not?
Look, Jennie, I'm sorry.
I was late. I apologise.
- That's all very well, Eric.
- Look, I said I was sorry.
To me. It's not me you've insulted.
Away with your bother.
The Lord won't feel slighted
at the missing of a bus.
Yes, Eric, you missed a bus. But why?
Your mind's not with us any more, son.
It's full of running and starting and medals.
It's so full, you've no room for standing still.
Jennie, Jennie, Jennie.
Don't fret yourself.
I do fret myself, Eric.
I'm frightened for you.
I'm frightened for what it all might do to you.
Please, Mr Liddell.
Would you sign your name, please?
Surely.
You want to pick yourself a pen?
- There you are.
- Thanks.
Come on, Jennie, let's go for a walk.
I've got something to say.
It's a sight and a half, isn't it, Jennie?
Auld Reekie. I'll be sad to leave it.
I've decided. I'm going back to China.
The missionary service have accepted me.
Eric.
I'm so pleased.
But I've got a lot of running to do first.
Jennie.
Jennie, you've got to understand.
I believe that God made me for a purpose.
For China.
But he also made me fast.
And when I run, I feel his pleasure.
To give it up would be
to hold him in contempt.
You were right.
It's not just fun.
To win is to honour him.
Jennie.
I've got my degree to get.
All that work.
Then there's Paris.
The Olympic Games.
There's just not enough of me.
I'm asking you to manage the mission
on your own till then.
Will you do that for me, Jennie?
- Andy, I've lost him. Can't reach him.
- You will, old girl.
He says he needs to clear his mind of me.
He can't love me and say that.
The world's against him, or so he believes.
Now he's got a chance to prove himself.
He can't see or hear anything
beyond that, not even you.
It's hard, but you've got to try
and understand.
- Why should I?
- Because he's what you want, isn't he?
What about you? And Stallard and Aubrey?
The chance is there for you too.
To be a fastest, yes, but not the fastest.
The fastest man ever before.
Father's never going to learn how to do that.
That's immortality.
Just think what it means to a man like Harold.
Well, to me the whole thing's fun.
I don't need that.
"Cast care aside" and all that.
But for Harold, it's a matter of life and death.
- So all I can do is wait?
- 'Fraid so.
And pray like hell that he wins, what?
And if he doesn't?
You mustn't worry, old thing.
I've never ever seen a man
so smitten as our Harold.
It's just that I'm a little envious, that's all.
Andy.
- Your parasol, Miss Gordon.
- Thank you, Mildred.
Good luck tonight.
He's a damned fool.
I always thought the Irish had all the luck.
- John, Savoy Theatre.
- Yes, sir.
Splendid.
Mildred, would you get my spikes?
Ready, my lord.
Now, Coote, if I shed a drop I want to know.
Touch but not spill, what?
Life slips by, Abrahams. Life slips by.
But this fine old university of ours,
she offers some rare consolations.
Beyond measure, sir.
I take it that you would be acutely grieved
to discover that any behaviour or action
on your part were causing her grief?
Naturally, sir. I would, deeply.
Good. I was sure of it.
Here in Cambridge, we've always
been proud of our athletic prowess.
We've always believed
that our games are indispensable
in helping to complete
the education of an Englishman.
They create character.
They foster courage, honesty and leadership.
But most of all,
an unassailable spirit of loyalty,
comradeship and mutual responsibility.
- Would you agree?
- Yes, sir. I would.
There is a growing suspicion
in the bosom of this university -
and I tell you this without decrying your
achievements, in which we all rejoice -
that in your enthusiasm for success
you have perhaps lost sight
of some of these ideals.
May I ask what form
this disloyalty, this betrayal, takes?
- Hardly betrayal.
- The word "grief" was mentioned.
It's said that you use a personal coach.
Mr Mussabini, yes.
- Is he an Italian?
- Of Italian extraction, yes.
- I see.
- But not all Italian.
- I'm relieved to hear it.
- He's half-Arab.
Do we take it that you employ this
Mr Mussabini on a professional basis?
Sam Mussabini is the finest, most advanced,
clearest-thinking athletics coach
in the country.
I'm honoured to be worthy of his attention.
- He's a professional.
- What else would he be? He's the best.
But there, Mr Abrahams,
I'm afraid our paths diverge.
You see, this university believes
that the way of the amateur
is the only one to provide satisfactory results.
I am an amateur.
You're being trained by a professional.
You've adopted a professional attitude.
For the past year, you have concentrated
on developing your own technique
in the headlong pursuit,
may I suggest, of individual glory.
Not a policy very conducive to
the fostering of esprit de corps.
I am a Cambridge man first and last.
I am an Englishman first and last.
What I have achieved,
what I intend to achieve, is for my family,
my university and my country.
And I bitterly resent
your suggesting otherwise.
Your aim is to win at all costs, is it not?
At all costs, no.
But I do aim to win within the rules.
You would rather
I played the gentleman and lost?
To playing the tradesman, yes.
My dear boy, your approach has been,
if I may say so, a little too plebeian.
You are the elite, and are therefore
expected to behave as such.
Thank you, sir, for your hospitality.
The evening has been most illuminating.
Good night to you, sir.
You know, gentlemen,
you yearn for victory, just as I do,
but achieved with
the apparent effortlessness of gods.
Yours are the archaic values
of the prep-school playground.
You deceive no one but yourselves.
I believe in the pursuit of excellence,
and I'll carry the future with me.
Well, there goes your Semite, Hugh.
A different god.
A different mountaintop.
Harold. Harold. We're in.
All of us. You, Henry,
Andy and me, we're all in.
You 100 and 200, Andy 400 and hurdles,
Henry the mile, and me the steeplechase.
Paris, here we come.
Eric Liddell's picked too.
Rivals under the same flag.
Your chance to get even, eh?
I can't wait.
Welcome to Dover, my Lord Birkenhead.
Lord, are the Yanks so well-trained
that they'll wipe the floor with our boys?
It's true that the Americans
have prepared seriously,
some would say too seriously,
to gain success.
But we feel we may, in our
unsophisticated way, have their match.
Do the British stand a chance
against such American athletes
as Charlie Paddock and Jackson Scholz?
You Americans have a number of men
who are rated as world-beaters,
but this contest is in Europe,
not in the rarefied climes of the United States.
Parisian conditions are bound to be
more robust, more combative,
- and certainly more cavalier.
- More cavalier?
Are the Yanks so well-trained
that they will wipe the floor with our boys?
In Abrahams, Liddell and Lindsay,
we have the men who could
give them a run for their money.
Eric.
Sandy. You haven't come all the way
from Scotland just to see me off?
I'm seeing myself off. Come on
up the gangplank, we'll miss the boat.
Mr Liddell. What do you think
of your chances against Abrahams?
- I'll do my best. Can do no less. Right?
- Mr Liddell.
What about the qualifying heats on Sunday?
- What did you say?
- On Sunday. Can you beat the Americans?
There's Mr Abrahams. There he is.
- Mr Abrahams.
- Sorry, I've no time...
- Hello, Jeremy.
- Gilbert and Sullivan will win.
- Harold.
- Sybil.
- I came to wish you luck.
- I'm glad.
I understand. I wanted you to know that.
I'll be here when you come back.
Hurry along there, Mr Abrahams.
She's about to sail.
I must go. I'll see you in three weeks.
Bye-bye.
Mind your step, sir.
We want you to get there in one piece.
- When did you get to know?
- Did you not read the papers this morning?
The heats for the hundred are on the Sunday,
the semis and final a couple of days after.
It's only a heat.
Does it make all that difference?
Yeah.
Yeah, it does.
And strong though the temptation may be
to disport your newly acquired finery
around the streets of Paris -
if they aren't temptation enough -
may I ask you on behalf
of the Olympic Committee
to save your sartorial splendour
until at least after the opening ceremony?
May I remind you, you are the favoured few.
You constitute what is without doubt
the most powerful athletic force
ever to leave these shores.
You are to face the world's best -
brown and yellow, white and black,
young and ardent as yourselves,
fleet of foot and strong of limb,
from every civilised nation
on the face of the earth.
I have no doubt that you
will acquit yourselves honourably
and with distinction.
Good luck to you all.
Your mind's not with us any more.
It's full of sprinting and starting and medals.
- It's so full, you've no room for standing still.
- Jennie, Jennie. Don't fret yourself.
I do fret myself, Eric. I'm frightened for you.
I'm frightened what it all might do to you.
- Do you know what day it is?
- Sunday.
The Sabbath's not a day for football, is it?
It's an awful step you're taking, Liddell.
The whole of Britain will be watching you.
I don't know that they'll understand.
I'm not sure that I understand.
I'm not sure that I do either, sir.
For the last three years I've devoted myself
to my running, just to be on this ship.
I gave up my rugby. My work has suffered.
And I've deeply hurt
someone I hold very dear.
Because I told myself if I win, I win for God.
And now I find myself sitting here,
destroying it all.
But I have to.
To run would be against God's law.
I was mistaken.
My boy, as things stand, you must not run.
But I want you to hold your fire
for a while, Liddell.
Leave everything to me.
Say nothing. Wait until we get to Paris.
I'll have a word with the French.
I'm not without a certain pull.
And we fought in the war together,
they do owe us something.
I don't understand.
They're not a very principled lot, the Frogs.
But, when faced with a stand like yours,
one never knows.
I might get through.
I just might possibly persuade them.
The French, sir? What can they do?
Shift that bloody heat of yours, of course.
Good evening.
Goodbye, sir.
I wish you could see, Ma,
the wonderful spirit now we've left England.
Harold on the piano,
his beloved Gilbert and Sullivan.
We're all laughing and relaxing,
and chatting about anything but running.
We're here for Britain and we know it.
I'm here for you, Ma.
You and Pa. I hope I do you proud.
There's not a chap here who isn't ready
to burst his heart for all we've left behind.
"American champions arrive in France. "
There's Paddock.
Charles Paddock.
- There's Fitch.
- My God.
- And there's Scholz.
- Yes, that's Scholz all right.
A bit more my size. Mean with it, though.
Ten point four.
Got your plate full there, Harold.
Battle on your hands, what?
Charles H Paddock and Jackson Scholz,
the fastest men in the world.
Push it. Push it.
Come on, I said push it. Push it.
One, two. One, two. One, two.
Come on.
Come on, now. OK, push up.
Come on, Charlie. Do it like a champ, will ya?
Keep doin' it like that, Charlie. Come on.
Hey, Scholzy.
Repeat till your brains are dusty. Come on.
Come on, Charlie. Do it like a champ.
- Good luck, Andy.
- Good luck, Harry.
Monty.
Your Highness, may I introduce
Mr Tom Watson, representing New Zealand?
- You've come a long way.
- I'm from Oxford, sir. They wrote to me.
Said as I was here, I might as well take part.
- Economical. But can you run?
- I'll give it a try, sir.
- That's the spirit. Best of luck to you.
- Thank you, sir.
- The royal benediction, no less.
- The chap's invaluable.
- Hear, hear. Henry V and all that.
- Protocol, Monty. Protocol.
He's here to show us what may be done -
and more essentially, what may not be.
I'm Jackson Scholz. How do you do?
I'm Eric Liddell.
Well, we've heard a lot about you.
It's good to meet you at last.
- Ah, Liddell.
- Excuse me.
I was afraid you weren't here.
I'm afraid I am, sir.
Fine. Do you good.
Take you out of yourself a bit.
The Prince of Wales would like to meet you.
No. No.
No, sir. It wouldn't be right.
Liddell, he is your future king.
Are you refusing to shake his hand?
Does your arrogance extend that far?
My arrogance, sir, extends
just as far as my conscience demands.
Fine.
Then let's hope that's wise enough
to give you room for manoeuvre.
- All right, sir.
- Splendid. I'll take you to him now.
Your Royal Highness,
may I present Mr Eric Liddell?
Delighted, Liddell. Delighted.
I saw you play for Scotland.
It depressed me no end.
- Ran in a couple of tries from your own half.
- I believe I did, sir.
Nice to have you on the same side at last.
Excellent effort of Lindsay's, don't you think?
- He did well, sir. He did indeed.
- An example to us all.
May I introduce the Duke of Sutherland,
president of our Olympic Association?
- How do you do?
- And our chairman, Lord Cadogan.
Have a seat.
Make yourself comfortable.
Cigar?
No, of course. You don't. Nor drink.
Such is the resolution of the young man
you have before you, gentlemen.
Lord Birkenhead has told us of your attitude
towards your participation
in the 100 metres heats, Liddell.
- Would nonparticipation be more accurate?
- It would, sir, yes.
We were consulted as to
how we should approach the French.
Something we just can't allow to happen,
going cap in hand to the Frogs, of all people.
Simply out of the question.
A simple matter of national dignity.
Being a patriot, I'm sure you understand.
I must say, sir,
I felt it was an impractical suggestion.
Why didn't you damn well say so?
As an athlete, you value economy of effort.
I wanted to run.
I was desperate enough to try anything.
All that being understood,
we decided to invite you in for a little chat
to see if there's any way
we can resolve the situation.
There's only one to resolve it.
That's for him to change his mind and run.
Don't state the obvious. We've to explore
ways in which we can help him decide that.
I'm afraid there are no ways, sir.
I won't run on the Sabbath and that's final.
I intended to confirm this
with Lord Birkenhead tonight,
- even before this inquisition.
- Don't be impertinent.
The impertinence lies with those
who influence a man to deny his beliefs.
On the contrary.
We're appealing to your beliefs.
In your country and your king.
Your loyalty to them.
Hear, hear.
In my day, it was king first, God after.
Yes, and the war to end wars
bitterly proved your point.
God made countries. God makes kings
and the rules by which they govern.
And those rules say that the Sabbath is his.
And I for one intend to keep it that way.
Mr Liddell,
you're a child of your race, as I am.
We share a common heritage,
a common bond, a common loyalty.
There are times when we are asked to make
sacrifices in the name of that loyalty,
and without them our allegiance is worthless.
As I see it, for you,
this is such a time.
Sir...
God knows I love my country.
But I can't make that sacrifice.
Come in.
Your Royal Highness, Lord Lindsay.
Your Highness, Lord Cadogan, gentlemen.
I do apologise for barging in like this.
The fact is I am fully aware of Eric's dilemma.
I wondered if I could be so bold
as to suggest a possible solution.
Do.
Yes.
Another day, another race.
- What the devil's that supposed to mean?
- It's quite simple, sir.
The 400 metres. It's on Thursday.
I've already got my medal, so why don't
you let Eric take my place in the quarter?
I think that's a splendid idea. Can we allow
him to change events at such short notice?
That's a matter for the committee.
We are the committee.
I think it's a very good idea.
David?
All those in favour say aye.
Aye.
Liddell?
- Andy, I...
- A pleasure, old chap.
Just to see you run.
Aye.
Well, that's settled.
A sticky moment, George.
Thank God for Lindsay.
I thought the lad had us beaten.
- He did have us beaten. Thank God he did.
- I don't quite follow you.
The lad, as you call him,
is a true man of principle, and a true athlete.
His speed is a mere extension
of his life, its force.
We sought to sever his running from himself.
For his country's sake, yes.
No sake is worth that, FE.
Least of all a guilty national pride.
"Lindsay makes way for Liddell. "
"400 metres for defecting Scot. "
"'Smacks of fanaticism,' says official. "
"'Man of principle,' says Primate. "
"'We should be proud. "'
- So that's the Olympic Stadium.
- That's it, Sam.
- It's as good as being in there, isn't it?
- Better. Seeing as I'm persona non grata.
Yeah.
It's tiptop, Mr Abrahams. You've done a grand
job. If we don't win now, we never will.
Have I got everything, Sam?
Everything you need?
Yes. All we need now is Sunday.
My text this afternoon
is taken from Isaiah, chapter 40.
"Behold. "
"The nations are as a drop in the bucket
and are counted
as the small dust in the balance. "
"All nations before him are as nothing. "
"They are counted to him
less than nothing and vanity. "
"He bringeth the princes to nothing. "
"He maketh the judges of the earth
as a vanity. "
"Hast thou not known?"
"Hast thou not heard
that the everlasting God, the Lord,
the creator of the ends of the earth,
fainteth not, neither is weary?"
Juvenile.
- Oldest con in the business.
- I know, Sam.
"He giveth power to the faint,
and to them that have no strength
he increaseth might. "
"But they that wait upon the Lord
shall renew their strength. "
"They shall mount up with wings, as eagles. "
"They shall run,
and not be weary. "
"They shall walk,
and not faint. "
Do you remember when we first
bumped into each other, old man?
We shared a taxi, remember?
You made me feel
an age old, burdened, sour...
Even superior.
That was the miscalculation of my life.
You, Aubrey,
are my most complete man.
You're brave,
compassionate,
kind.
A content man. That's your secret.
Contentment.
I'm 24 and I've never known it.
I'm forever in pursuit and I don't
even know what it is I'm chasing.
Aubrey, old chap, I'm scared.
Sam and I, we've laboured,
rowed and bullied for this.
Day in, day out.
You've seen us -
chuckled over us, I'll be bound.
Out in all weathers. Madmen.
And for what?
I was beaten out of sight in the 200.
I let Paddock trick me in the semi.
Now, in one hour's time,
I'll be out there again.
I'll raise my eyes and
look down that corridor, four feet wide,
with ten lonely seconds
to justify my whole existence.
But will I?
Aubrey, I've known the fear of losing,
but now I'm almost too frightened to win.
Dear Mr Abrahams. You must please pardon
my not coming to see you run,
much as I would like to do so.
However, I believe and hope
you will win the 100 metres.
Go out determined to do your best.
And don't forget, drop down at the first stride.
Get well warmed up,
and then let the gun release you.
I should use the springy old six-spike shoes.
All the best of luck.
From yours truly, Sam Mussabini.
PS. Please accept the charm.
My old father swore by it.
No regrets, Eric,
that you're not down there with them?
Yeah.
No doubts, though.
May I present
Mr Bowman of the United States?
Mr Bowman.
- Mr Murchison.
Mr Watson of New Zealand
I believe you know.
- Yes, Mr Watson. How are you?
- Very well, sir.
Good.
- Mr Paddock.
- Ah, Mr Paddock.
Dinner for your whole team
when we get back to London.
Now, if you win, I pay.
Abrahams wins, you pay, all right?
Sir, you have yourself a deal.
- Done. The best of luck to you.
- And to you, too, sir.
- Mr Scholz.
- Scholz.
And this is our Harold Abrahams.
Good luck, Abrahams.
Do your best. That's all we can expect.
- Good luck, Abrahams.
- Thank you, sir.
Come on, Charlie.
Head down.
Watch the first stride.
Go for release.
Harold.
My son.
- Leave him be. The poor fella's whacked.
- But he won.
Exactly. Now, one of these days, Monty,
you're going to win yourself,
and it's pretty difficult to swallow.
Come in.
Mrs Abrahams just rang, miss. The Daily
Express, they've been on from Paris.
Mr Harold. He won.
She told me to tell you, he won.
Thank you very much, Bill.
It's 15 minutes to curtain-up, miss.
He did it, sir.
Thank you, Matthews.
"Abrahams triumphant. "
"Caius College athlete
wins blue riband at Games. "
Just as I expected.
Yes, you've always thought
of yourself as a ruthless man. Hard.
Bit of a loner, like me.
But actually, you're as soft as a limp pocket.
You care.
Care about things that really matter.
If you didn't, I wouldn't have come
within a mile of you.
Do you know who you won for
out there today?
Us.
You and old Sam Mussabini.
I've waited 30 bloody years for this.
Harold.
It means the world to me, this, you know.
And if all the world can do
is to want to go home to bed,
then they can go to hell.
Because we've had today, you and me,
and we've got it for keeps.
So now it's out of your system,
go home to that girl of yours
and start some bloody living. Yes?
To Sam Mussabini.
The greatest trainer in the world.
Let's get some... Get some more.
Come on, Sam. We're going home.
The final of the 400 metres.
Good luck. Don't expect
I'll see you till after the race.
This guy Liddell, is he a problem?
No problem. He's a flyer.
He's had two races today already. He'll die.
Just swing along, you guys, and wait.
After 300 metres, rigor mortis sets in.
You'll pull him in on a rope.
Good luck, Taylor. Watch out for Liddell.
- Coach says no problem.
- He's got something personal to prove.
Something guys like Coach'll
never understand in a million years.
"It says in the Old Book,
'He that honours me, I will honour. "'
"Good luck. Jackson Scholz. "
So where does the power come from
to see the race to its end?
From within.
Come on, Liddell.
Jennie, I believe God made me for a purpose.
But he also made me fast.
And when I run, I feel his pleasure.
Well, Andy. He did it.
- What's that, old boy?
- He ran them off their feet.