It is a sign of what was done to the
city.
CDC provides the mortality reached
between 5,000,000.
Could reach up to 250 m within 6
months ahead.
Any person showing signs of
contagion.
Receive special treatment right here
in quarantine.
Many new ones are children without
parents.
Quarantine raises riots.
Families are torn.
We are not ready for mass
evacuations.
Survival is now 1 in 500.
Violent incidents in the city center
tonight.
20 people including U.
S.
We lost energy sources.
An influenza virus of simian origin.
All government services ceased until
further notice.
Those who did not die of the virus.
Probably die fighting.
Maybe this is the end.
Soon.
There will be no one.
Planet of the Apes: confrontation.
Caesar.
They arrive.
Koba!
Now, father?
Wait, son.
Thank you, Koba.
Think before acting, son.
Do not worry, eyes-blue.
Your scars make you strong.
Come see your little brother.
Another son.
I realize that we have experienced
so much.
It seems so far.
You still think back to them?
Men?
Sometimes.
I have not known you as.
I have not seen the worst.
Good or bad, it is finished.
They were killing.
Primates also fight.
But we are a family.
They are all gone, you think?
It's 10 winters.
The last 2, no trace of them.
They are gone, then.
Not you have me eyes-blue.
I'm fast.
Shut up, ash!
Nothing to fear.
Primate!
Help!
Fast!
Primate!
Here!
I touched it!
He shot my son, ash!
Rocket, wait!
We do not want to hurt you.
You really think he understand.
Yet it looks like.
I beg.
- It's good.
Let down your arms.
You laugh!
I need regular.
- Do.
Go!
Oh, shit!
Understood?
- Ok.
Ok, we're going?
Go!
Koba!
Follow them!
You found?
Need to talk.
What?
What up?
The.
The dam is good, you can restart in
a week.
But there's a problem, gabe.
We were frightened, not knowing what
to do.
My god, how y '?
Many, perhaps 80.
- Much more.
You do not understand what he says?
They spoke!
- Not.
I swear it was amazing.
Amazing?
Primates speaking with enormous
spears
You believed see or hear something,
I understand.
But calm down now.
And the virus?
There are risks of contagion?
- The survivors are immune I think.
She worked for the CDC, she knows.
- What do we do?
I do not know.
One needs electricity.
- It would have killed us.
Maybe he has spared us for us to
follow.
He spots us and kill us all!
That it?
- It tells me that there was a
leader, be a singular.
A remarkable person!
- Really?
That's what you saw?
- Yes, we all saw.
Not breathe a word to anyone until
we have a plane.
This is a joke.
- It is very serious.
Is not answered panic.
Then you okay?
- I'm fine.
I dropped my bag.
- I know.
Your sketches were in?
- All lost.
We can not talk to anyone about what
happened up there.
They will soon enough.
Tackle them quickly!
Before they attack us!
.
We do not know that there are many.
How they have guns?
Why they come here?
They shot your son, rocket!
You gonna fight?
I will follow Caesar.
Koba's right!
They nearly kill you, ash.
I do not!
If it goes to war.
We risk losing everything we have
built.
Our country.
Our family.
Our future.
I decide tomorrow morning.
Caesar.
I was locked up for years in labs.
They cut me, tortured.
You freed me.
I am entirely devoted to you.
We must show our strength!
It's okay Koba.
This is more than 80.
Malcolm!
Primates.
Do. Want. Not. War!
But we will fight.
If necessary.
Primates.
Have their homeland.
Humans.
Do not return more!
Silence!
Listen to me!
Listen to me, everyone!
They do not want to hurt us.
- How they found us?
Yeah?
It is we who have found.
And if they return?
If they dared, would soundly defeat.
Was perhaps not the arms of the
past, but we have the weapons.
Stocks of weapons we have left the
armed.
Everything is available.
I know.
I know why you're afraid.
And I also fear, know it.
But you just put your trust in me.
We went through hell together!
You all know.
Our current problems.
We almost ran out of fuel.
It means more power.
It means the risk.
To plunge in the prior state.
Dam up there was the answer.
We did not know either that they
were up there too.
What now?
- Yeah!
There is another source of energy.
This energy is not.
That to keep our way of life.
But to empower.
To reconnect with the world, who
else survived.
So we can start rebuilding.
And return.
The world we have lost.
Nice speech.
There is no other source of energy.
This dam is our only chance.
While they fight for him.
In 2
- maximum three weeks there
will be more fuel.
- I know.
And once this is.
We can no longer open to the world,
we call everyone now.
Electricity allows us to operate the
radio.
This is an opportunity to contact
the outside world.
We must find other survivors.
- Indeed.
Unless it is the last.
There are no more victims wants.
We founded this city.
You and me.
Driven by the ambition to restore
your lifestyle.
We must remain united, otherwise we
will not survive.
We lost everything.
The prospect of losing the little
that a.
I want to return up there.
Listen, give me three days.
I talk to him and if it does not
work we follow your plan.
And if it induced, we do not even
know if you will understand.
It is more than just a primate.
I will put pressure on the council
to argue your position.
If it works I try to get you three
days.
In three days you're back or you
climb exterminate.
Carl, prepare vehicles.
Is combined with a small team
carver.
We will take carver?
He wounded one of them? !
We have no choice, it was a
lumberjack, he knows the forest.
Malcolm.
What you will do up there?
Tell them what?
The truth!
I hope they take good.
You think it's crazy?
I'm afraid.
And me too.
I have thought about it.
It takes at least I try, otherwise
the war.
Let me come, I will be helpful if
there is a wounded.
I love you.
I need you here.
You will not be alone, look around
you.
Son, it is not safe.
I feel safer with you here, I'm
going.
Please?
What you gonna tell them?
Do not know.
If I'm not back in two hours, you
can leave the city.
Everything will be alright.
Do not kill me, please.
I have something to tell you.
I know.
Do not come back.
I would not be here if it was not.
Ok!
I have to show you something.
Near here.
Men lie.
I swear.
If I show you, you will understand.
I beg you.
.
Show.
Me.
What a hydropower plant.
For supplying the northern region
energy.
Lines going to our city.
First we used the nuclear and diesel
generators and natural gas.
If we can raise the dam we will base
our energy.
You understand what I'm saying?
The.
Lights.
Yes I am.
This is your country.
Nobody wants you to possess, but.
If we have your permission to work
here.
Where are the others?
There is a small group.
I'm not a threat.
If I am, then kill me.
We give them our weapons.
It is their only condition.
Does that mean?
- You can stay.
They will increasingly threatening.
Why help them?
They seem desperate.
If they are expelled, they will
attack.
They are removed as they are weak.
How primates die?
This is an opportunity for peace.
Do their work and then they leave
men.
Work.
Men?
Men!
Work.
Koba said.
He must hate men?
Enough!
Koba knows hatred because men.
But nothing else.
Hey!
You have to eat.
I want a little.
- You were brave today.
I know they have everything about
you.
It's all the same to me.
He is important to me.
Child, he saw horrors, it will not
extend into barbarism.
I know.
I try to be closer to him.
Thou shalt.
What scares me in them.
They do not require energy.
Light.
Heat, nothing.
This is their advantage.
What makes them so strong.
We should do a tour of duty.
With what?
They have our guns.
A weapon is not the solution.
- They are dangerous.
They have already killed most of the
men.
- What?
You'll not blame them.
- Who else then?
It was the monkey flu.
- A virus designed by our
scientists.
They were testing on primates.
- Always the same salads epidemic.
That you did not horrified all those
people that you wanted to save?
You had a good girl?
She died.
- Enough.
You your wife is dead.
Shut up or I'll shut up!
Ok.
It is surely kidding me that.
It's okay?
You're sick?
A little tired.
Men you worry.
Where Koba?
He's angry.
They're out hunting.
Look, men down.
What are we doing here?
Caesar trusted them.
Koba was not confident.
Most of the arsenal working.
Tests were done behind.
Do not move!
You understand?
Ted, come here, quick!
Whore!
What do we do?
- Do not know.
How he got?
He is alone?
- I do not know.
My bastard nature has not spoiled
me.
I think he's hungry.
He lost the group.
You're lost?
You know back?
Go outside, turns, silly baboon!
Go!
They have enough guns to kill us
all.
Must prevent Caesar.
Men something wrong.
We must close this loophole.
I did not know you'd had a girl.
Yes I am.
Her name?
Sarah.
I understand your sadness.
Now I have you, you and your father.
Like this.
Yes I am.
It worked?
Slowly, we only have one.
What.
2. 1.
Malcolm!
Yes I do!
It hurts.
- Do not touch.
Break!
Thank you.
You saved us.
It will take more time to clear.
Hi friend.
What do you do?
Have you finished?
There's what?
What you doing?
- I'll kill you!
Caesar, do not do that!
I do not!
I was told.
Not. Weapons!
No, please.
I did not know.
You need to.
Get away. Right now!
Malcolm.
Malcolm, where are you going?
Let me just talk to him.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, it's my fault.
You me.
You should not be here.
- I understand.
He is sick.
- Long time no see?
I drugs, antibiotics.
Maybe it can help.
Do. You. Not meddle.
I understand your reaction.
Believe me, we're not all like it.
- I beg you.
Let us help you.
One day.
I leave you again someday.
No, father!
A little more.
- One day.
Primates help.
I do not want help!
It is anything!
- Calm down.
Ok!
Tomorrow asshole!
In their city.
Men are very dangerous.
Where's Caesar?
The relay is blown, should replace.
Caesar?
No, no!
Where's Caesar?
Where Caesar.
Caesar!
Men attacking your son.
.
And you.
Their. Let. Stay.
You put the endangered primates.
Caesar loves men more than primates.
More than his son.
Primates.
Do not kill. Primates.
Forgive me.
You are my son.
You have to listen.
You have not talked to Caesar guns!
Does not mention.
Your father is suspicious of me.
You gotta protect.
His feelings for men.
Blindness.
I know.
As they are here.
I fear for the life of Caesar.
That's yesterday.
A beautiful afternoon.
We stood outside.
In the pool.
We stood.
Stand.
That's good.
What's wrong with you, we told you
to leave!
I do not!
Will it!
He immediately understood.
Hey, hey!
It looks like he likes me!
You want a drink?
You could drink alcohol.
He wants to try at home ish.
Gently!
Oh, oh!
Fuck!
This is good, eh?
I need regular.
This is good.
Quiet, quiet!
Malcolm!
What happens?
- (The weight
- the band) when I
came to Nazareth.
We managed.
Our work is done we can start from
the city.
Goodbye!
A match.
We will take revenge!
[. ].
Lights.
You feel better?
Mother!
Guns of men!
Men killed Caesar!
[. ].
Catch them!
Primates should dispose men.
We must take revenge.
Fight for Caesar.
Females and young remain.
We go to the city.
We will avenge the death of your
father!
Ellie, there!
Attempt to communicate
san-francisco.
Please log in, if you get us.
Your location.
Over.
If you receive give us your
situation.
Over.
I repeat, attempted communication.
If you receive us, please give.
Primates attacking armory.
Sound the alarm!
Keep the doors closed!
It's okay.
- Yes I am.
[. ].
We are survivors!
They managed to grab some guns, it
does not make them men.
They are animals that will push.
Return.
They do not pass these doors!
On the streets of California!
Come help we attacked.
Allo?
Capture the men, they escape.
It should not be far.
It is here.
Dad!
Malcolm!
These are not the men who have hurt
me.
[. ].
I do not know.
Do not talk, you must rest.
Hold fast.
He lost so much blood.
- It will come out?
I do not understand.
Koba would take guns.
Why would he do that?
Is primates who did this!
Riding in the truck.
We followed them here, they lurk
everywhere.
Catch them all!
Kill him.
- No, no!
C'mon, ash!
Men get paid!
Caesar would not it.
Caesar died.
Koba follow you now.
I need regular.
He must find a safe place to operate
caesar).
I need regular.
: We will find.
Calm, Caesar!
I need regular.
: Faster it loses a lot of blood.
: It is here.
Malcolm, fast!
I need regular.
: Here.
: This place is safe?
I need regular.
: This is where I lived before
events.
I need regular.
: Make us the place, alex.
Here.
Ok.
Look!
.
I have to make but I have nothing.
I have material to the city but.
- I go.
It's dangerous.
- It is the only one who can stop
all.
Men!
You.
Prisoners. Primates. Right now.
Live. Cage.
There are still other men go
looking.
Maurice!
Koba said.
It is too devoted to your father.
Protect yourself!
I do not!
Expect.
Your father.
He is alive!
I have what it takes as he goes?
Your.
Mother?
Your mother?
Okay?
For the time being.
I do not!
Not men!
Is Koba!
Caesar must now operate.
My son!
How it goes?
We'll see.
It is very strong.
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
For all.
I do not.
This is my fault.
Koba betrayed you.
I wanted to trust him.
Because it is primate.
I always thought that primates were
better than men.
Now I see.
How much we resemble their.
Koba is where now?
The tower of men.
He is surrounded by his followers.
Those who do not follow?
Prisoners.
Maurice.
Rocket.
Koba killed ash.
Fear makes them loyal.
But when they make you alive.
They turn away from Koba.
They are weak.
Primates always looking for a strong
leader.
We must do something to stop.
Father.
Let me help you.
An apple.
Okay.
House.
Yes I am.
Is your home.
It is home.
Here, though.
Very well.
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
It's been three days.
Your son is not back yet.
Is that.
The video?
A good man.
Like you.
Take him to the tower discreetly by
metro.
Koba fetched females and young.
They arrive.
Mother too.
We go right away.
It goes well?
Who goes there?
Do you human?
It's me, malcolm, do not shoot.
Take the stairs we find ourselves in
the street, go!
I trust you.
I do, do not shoot.
Finally you are!
I was wondering if you were alive.
Do not worry, we will encircle.
What?
Primates took refuge in the tower,
they lost the city.
Look what we have here.
C4, explosives, plastic.
[Here, san-francisco, do you read
me?
].
We just put it down, all the while
going to jump.
It makes them all jump.
We need you.
Here, san-francisco.
If you get me, please.
Go!
Here, san-francisco.
It's okay?
- It's okay? .
Dreyfus!
Werner!
Sorry, I can not let you do.
Must leave them a chance.
It takes time.
It's up there right now.
What you doing?
Caesar.
Has nothing to do here.
Primates following Koba now.
Koba after the war.
Primates can fight together they are
strong.
Caesar is weak.
Koba is lower.
Primates.
You're crazy!
I know what they are capable.
All they want is to survive.
- They are animals.
Because they believed that the first
attack.
Sitting finney!
Sitting!
I considered him a brother you.
Caesar is the brother of men.
Koba fights for free primates.
Koba Koba fights for.
Koba is no longer cage.
I know you do not understand.
- You do not realize you.
You're just delaying things, they
come.
It is in contact with a military
base north.
They are numerous, they come.
He's right.
Dreyfus, what are you doing?
I save the human race.
- I do not.
Primates do not kill primates.
You, you're not.
A primate.
Free-lez.
It is not safe here.
They called the army.
Leaving all now.
Caesar, if you do not go.
It will be total war.
The war has already.
Started.
They started the war.
Men.
Never forgive.
You have to leave.
Before the fights begin.
Sorry.
My friend.
They gave you your chance.
I too have given you.