The subs included in mkv where out ouf sync...
So here are properly synced ones.
Adjusted and synced by B[r]3 to fit:
Eternal.Sunshine.of.the.Spotless.Mind.2004.720p.BluRay.DTS.x264-CtrlHD
"Random thoughts
for Valentine's Day, 2004.
"Today is a holiday invented
by greeting-card companies
"to make people
feel like crap.
"I ditched work today.
"Took a train out to Montauk.
"I don't know why.
"I'm not an impulsive person.
"I guess I just woke up
in a funk this morning.
"I gotta get my car fixed."
Hi, Cindy. It's Joel.
Listen, I don't feel
very well today.
No, food poisoning,
I think.
"It's goddamn freezing
on this beach.
"Montauk in February.
Brilliant, Joel.
"Pages ripped out.
Don't remember doing that.
"It appears this is
my first entry in two years.
"Sand is overrated.
"It's just tiny little rocks.
"If only I could
meet someone new.
"I guess my chances
of that happening
"are somewhat diminished,
"since I'm incapable
of making eye contact
with a woman I don't know.
"Maybe I should
get back together with Naomi.
She was nice.
"Nice is good.
"She loved me.
"Why do I fall in love
with every woman I see
"who shows me
the least bit of attention?"
Hi.
I'm sorry?
I just said hi.
Hi, hello.
Okay if I sit closer?
How far are you going?
Rockville Center.
Get out. Me, too.
Really?
What are the odds?
Listen, do I know you?
Do you ever shop
at Barnes and Noble?
Sure.
That's it!
Yeah?
I've seen you, man.
Book slave there
for five years now.
Jesus!
I would have thought
I would remember you.
It might be the hair.
What might?
It changes a lot,
the color.
That's why you might
not recognize me.
It's called Blue Ruin.
Right.
The color.
Snappy name, huh?
I like it.
This company makes
a whole line of colors
with equally snappy names.
You've got Red Menace,
Yellow Fever,
Green Revolution.
That would be a job,
coming up with those names.
You think there could
possibly be a job like that?
I mean, how many hair colors
could there be? 15 maybe?
Someone's got that job.
Agent Orange.
I came up with that one.
I apply my personality
in a paste.
I doubt that very much.
Well, you don't know me,
so you don't know, do you?
I'm sorry.
I was just trying to be nice.
Yeah. I got it.
My name's Clementine,
by the way.
I'm Joel.
Hi, Joel.
No jokes about my name.
Oh, no.
You wouldn't do that.
You're trying to be nice.
I don't know any jokes
about your name.
Huckleberry Hound.
I don't know
what that means.
Huckleberry Hound?
What are you, nuts?
It's been suggested.
O£, my darling, o£, my darling
O£, my darling Clementine
You are lost and gone forever
Dreadful sorry, Clementine
No?
I'm sorry.
It's a pretty name, though.
It really is nice.
It means merciful, right?
Clemency?
Although it hardly fits.
I'm a vindictive little bitch,
truth be told.
I wouldn't think that
about you.
Why wouldn't you think that
about me?
I don't know.
You seem nice.
Now I'm nice?
Oh, God, don't you know
any other adjectives?
I don't need nice.
I don't need myself to be it
and I don't need anybody
to be it at me.
Okay.
It's Joel, right?
Yes.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I'm a little
out of sorts today.
My embarrassing admission
is I really like
that you're nice right now.
I can't tell
from one moment to the next
what I'm going to like,
but right now
I'm glad you are.
I have some stuff
that I probably should...
I'm writing...
I'm sorry. Okay.
No.
Sure. That's okay.
Take care, then.
Jesus.
I could give you a ride
if you need.
It's cold.
Yeah! Okay. It is frosty.
You're not a stalker
or anything, right?
I'm not a stalker.
You're the one
that talked to me, remember?
That is the oldest trick
in the stalker book.
Really?
There's a stalker book?
I've got to read that one.
Look, I'm sorry
if I came off sort of nutso.
I'm not really.
That's okay.
I didn't think you were.
Do you want
to have a drink?
I have lots of drinks,
and I could...
Never mind.
Sorry, that was stupid.
I'm embarrassed now.
Good night, Joel.
Two Blue Ruins.
Thank you.
Drink up, young man.
It'll make
the whole seduction part
less repugnant.
I'm just kidding!
Come on.
You're kind of close-mouthed,
aren't you?
I'm sorry.
You know, my life isn't
that interesting.
I go to work, I come home.
I don't know what to say.
You should read my journal.
I mean, it's just blank.
Really? Does that
make you sad or anxious?
I'm always anxious,
thinking I'm not living
my life to the fullest.
Taking advantage
of every possibility
and making sure
I'm not wasting one second
of the little time I have.
I think about that.
Yeah?
You're really nice.
God, I have to stop
saying that.
I'm gonna marry you.
I know it.
Okay.
Joel, you should
come up to the Charles
with me sometime.
It gets frozen
this time of year.
That sounds scary.
Exactly.
I'll pack a picnic,
a night picnic.
Night picnics are different.
That sounds good.
But I should go now.
You should stay.
No, I really have...
I have to get up
so early and...
I would like you
to call me.
Would you do that?
I'd like it.
Yes.
Wish me
a happy Valentine's Day
when you call.
That'd be nice.
What took you so long?
I just walked in.
You miss me?
Oddly enough, I do.
You said "I do."
I guess that means
we're married.
I guess so.
Tomorrow night?
Honeymoon on ice?
It's really solid
this time of year.
I don't know.
Come on.
It's so beautiful.
Isn't it?
Don't go too far.
Are you okay?
Oh, my ass!
I think I should go back.
Come on!
But what if it breaks?
"What if?"
Do you really care
right now?
Come here, please.
Slidey-slidey.
This looks good.
Let me show you
this one thing.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Think I heard a crack.
It's not going to crack.
Or break.
It's so thick.
Show me
which constellations
you know.
I don't know any.
Show me which ones
you know.
Okay.
There's Osidius.
Where?
Right there. See?
A sort of a swoop
and a cross.
Osidius the Emphatic.
You're full of shit, right?
No. Osidius, right there.
Swoop and a cross.
Shut the fuck up!
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
Sorry to wake you,
but we're here.
Can I come over
to your house,
to sleep? I'm so tired.
Okay. Yeah, sure.
Let me get my toothbrush.
Yes?
Can I help you?
What do you mean?
Can I help you
with something?
No.
What are you doing here?
I'm not really sure
what you're asking me.
Thanks.
We're looking for 150.
What number is that?
I don't know
what number that is.
Jesus Christ.
You'd think they'd
light the number
or at least put
a number on...
Is that him?
I think so.
Yeah, that's him.
That's him.
Hey, Joel.
Frank.
Shit.
Jesus. The only
Valentine's Day cards I get
are from my mother.
How pathetic is that?
You're lucky
you have Clementine.
She is way cool.
You got any
big Valentine's Day plans
with her?
No.
It's only a day away.
Better make some
reservations or something.
Don't want to end up
at Mickey D's, right?
McRomance!
You want some fries
with that shake?
I have to go to sleep now,
Frank.
It's 8:30.
Patrick, stop it.
Okay.
Showtime at the Apollo.
Quiet.
Get it off your head.
Hey, Joel.
What's up?
Hi, Frank.
I only get Valentine's Day
cards from my mom.
How pathetic is that?
You're lucky
you have Clementine, Joel.
You got any
big Valentine's Day plans
with her?
No.
It's only a day away.
Better make
a reservation somewhere.
Don't want to end up
at Mickey D's.
Oh, no.
Yes.
Valentine's Day
is three days away.
I want it resolved.
I'm willing to be the one
to resolve it.
So I call her,
and she's changed
her number.
So I walked over
to Antic Attic
to get her something.
I thought I'd go over to work,
give her an early Valentine.
And you won't believe it.
She's there with this guy,
this really young guy.
And she looks at me like
she doesn't even know
who I am.
Excuse me?
Can I help you
find something, sir?
Hey, Clem-ato.
Patrick! Baby boy!
What are you doing here,
baby?
Just came to surprise you.
Let me know
if you need something, sir.
How are you?
Pretty good, pretty bored,
pretty tired.
I so want
what's in your suit.
Good.
Why would she
do that to me?
Does anybody want a joint?
God, Rob, give it a rest.
God, she's punishing me.
I know.
For being honest.
It's horrible.
I should just go
to her house.
No.
You don't want to go there,
man.
Get off me. It's too...
Right.
Yeah.
I don't want to
seem desperate.
Joel, why don't you
just see this as a sign?
Make a clean break. Right?
All right, Joel.
Look, man, seriously,
here's the deal.
Don't do that.
Rob, what are you doing?
What's your
fucking suggestion?
What's your brilliant,
reasoned solution?
You're making this
about our shit now?
This isn't about us.
I agree.
It's not about us.
It's about Joel,
who's an adult, okay?
Not Mama Carrie's kid.
Why don't you go
do your laundry?
That's great.
That's good.
Okay.
What is it?
I don't know.
It's some place
that does a thing.
Good morning. Lacuna.
No, I'm sorry.
That offer expired
after the New Year.
Yeah, sure.
We can fit you in...
How about on the 5th?
That's a Wednesday.
All right, great.
Could you spell that, please?
Okay, and we'll need
a daytime phone number.
Great. Have a nice day.
See you then.
May I help you?
I'm Joel Barish.
Excuse me?
I have an appointment
with Doctor...
Mierzwiak.
Here, can you please
fill this out?
I just want to talk to him.
You still need to
fill the form out, sir.
All right.
Thank you.
I don't have a pen.
There's a pen right there.
Good morning. Lacuna.
Yeah, that offer,
that's done now.
That expired
after the New Year.
Mr. Barish?
How are we today?
Not too good, actually.
Oh, my God! Stan!
Sorry, I was just...
I'm working.
Here, Doctor.
Thank you.
You should not have seen this.
I apologize.
This is a hoax, right?
I mean, this is Clem's...
I assure you, no.
No.
There's no such thing as this.
Look, our files are
confidential, Mr. Barish,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say
that Miss Kruczynski
was not happy
and she wanted to move on.
We provide that possibility.
"Miss Kruczynski was not happy
and wanted to move on.
"We provide that possibility."
What the hell is that?
I'm the nicest guy
she ever went out with.
Fuck!
Rob, give it a rest!
It's okay.
It's all right.
Carrie,
I am making a birdhouse.
What can I say? You know,
Clementine's just like that.
She's impulsive.
She decided to
erase you almost as a lark.
A lark?
Why did you do that?
Don't. Wait.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
he just barged right in here.
Okay. I want it done.
I told him pre-Valentine's Day
is our busy time...
That's okay, Mary.
But there are
people waiting.
Mr. Barish,
if you'd like to come inside.
If you'd
take care of Mrs. Woo.
Yes, of course.
Goodbye, Mrs. Woo.
The first thing we need
you to do, Mr. Barish,
is to go home and collect
everything you own
that has some association
with Clementine.
Anything.
We'll use these items
to create a map of Clementine
in your brain, okay?
We'll need photos,
clothing, gifts,
books she may have bought you,
CDs you may have bought
together, journal entries.
We want to empty your home,
we want to empty your life
of Clementine.
And after the mapping is done,
our technicians
will do the erasing
in your home tonight.
That way,
when you awake in the morning,
you'll find yourself
in your own bed
as if nothing had happened,
a new life awaiting you.
Wake up, buddy!
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sobel.
You can't have the procedure
done three times in one month.
It's just not
our policy here.
How are you today,
Mr. Barish?
Hello, I'm right here.
I know it's an emergency.
We'll do everything we can.
We can fit you in
on March 1.
Maybe you could
talk to the doctor and...
All right,
so let's make
an appointment.
What day would you like
to come in this week?
Mr. Barish.
He's really busy
this afternoon.
Maybe tomorrow
would be better,
around 12:15.
Can you do that?
February is very busy for us
because of Valentine's Day.
This is Stan Fink, one
of our most experienced
and skilled technicians.
He'll be handling
your case tonight.
Great to meet you, Mr. Barish.
My name is Joel Barish,
and I'm here to erase
Clementine Kruczynski.
Very good.
Now tell me about Clementine.
I was living with this woman,
Naomi,
a couple years ago.
And my friends,
Rob and Carrie,
invited us
to this party at the beach.
I don't like parties.
Naomi couldn't go,
but I went
and I met Clementine.
I'm sorry.
We'll start with
your most recent memories
and work backwards from there,
more or less.
There's an emotional core
to each of our memories,
and when you eradicate
that core,
it starts
its degradation process.
By the time you wake up
in the morning,
all the memories
we've targeted will have
withered and disappeared.
As in a dream upon waking.
Is there any risk
of brain damage?
Technically speaking,
the procedure is brain damage.
But it's on a par with
a night of heavy drinking.
Nothing you'll miss.
Comfortable?
What we're doing here,
Mr. Barish,
is actually creating a map
of your brain.
Okay, let's get started.
If we want to
get this procedure
underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
I want you to react
to these objects, Mr. Barish,
if you will.
There's a good story
behind that...
Actually, Mr. Barish, I'll get
a much better emotional
read-out
if you refrain from
any sort of verbal description
of the items.
Just please try to
focus on the memories.
I'm sorry.
Healthy activity
up there again.
Healthy read-outs.
Very good.
Here's another object.
Next item.
Potato head.
Just focus
on the memories.
Patrick, do me a favor.
Patrick,
do me a favor, will you?
Can you check
the voltage regulator?
What have we got there?
Voltage looks fine.
Really?
I'm not wiping
as clean as I like here.
Technically,
the procedure is brain damage.
But it's on a par with
a night of heavy drinking.
Check the connections, please.
There you are.
What am I...
I don't understand
what I'm looking at.
Why am I standing here...
Oh, my God, deja vu.
This is so...
We should get started.
If we want to
get the procedure
underway tonight,
we have some work to do.
I'm in my head already,
aren't I?
I suppose so.
This is about right.
This is
what it would look like.
Very good.
We'll dispose
of these mementos
when we're done here.
That way you won't
be confused later
by their
unexplainable presence
in your home.
There we go. Patrick?
Patrick?
Why are there
so many wires?
Because we have
a lot of equipment.
Does that help?
Are you sure you set
that thing up properly?
How's that?
How are you today, Mr. Barish?
There we are, Mr. Barish.
All right,
that's better.
I don't know if I like this.
I think I might
try this then.
We're almost done now.
Yourjournal.
That'll be invaluable.
"I met someone tonight.
I don't know what to do.
"Her name is Clementine
and she's amazing."
Jesus!
What?
Come on, careful!
Step back!
Just take it easy.
It's fine.
Let's not roach the guy.
All right.
We got that one.
This place is sort of a dump,
don't you think?
It's an apartment, Patrick.
Well,
not a dump then,
but sort of plain.
Uninspired.
And there's sort
of a stale smell.
Can we just please
get through this?
We've got
a long night ahead of us.
This is the last time
I saw you.
It's 3:00.
I kind of,
sort of wrecked your car.
Driving drunk.
It's pathetic.
I was a little tipsy.
Don't call me pathetic!
It is pathetic.
It's fucking irresponsible.
You could have
killed somebody.
Maybe you did kill somebody.
Should we turn on the news
and see?
Should I check the grille
to see if there's
children or small animals?
It's just a fucking dent.
You're like an old lady
or something.
What are you like?
A wino?
A "wino"? Jesus.
Are you from the '50s
or something? A "wino"?
Face it, Joely.
You're freaked out because
I was out late without you.
And in your little,
wormy brain,
you're trying to figure out,
"Did she fuck
someone tonight?"
Now, see, Clem, I assume
you fucked someone tonight.
Isn't that how
you get people
to like you?
I'm sorry, okay?
Clem, I didn't mean it,
all right?
Your keys.
I won't need them anymore.
I was just angry or annoyed
or something. I don't know.
Got it.
Mary's coming over tonight.
Just thought
you'd want to know.
I like Mary.
I like when she comes
to visit. I don't think
she likes me.
She likes you okay.
So maybe I should invite
my girlfriend over.
I have a girlfriend now.
Do whatever you want.
Did I tell you...
Did I tell you
I have a new girlfriend?
We gotta focus here,
Patrick.
The thing is,
my situation is
a little weird.
My girlfriend situation.
I'm sure it is.
You've got to be...
Clem, let me drive you home.
Get out of my face, faggot!
Look at it out here!
It's all falling apart!
I'm erasing you,
and I'm happy!
You did it to me first!
I can't believe
you did this to me!
God damn it!
Did you hear me?
By morning you'll be gone!
The perfect ending
to this piece-of-shit story!
Is there
something wrong with a girl
being attracted to me?
Is that a problem?
No, I think it's funny.
Who do you think's
better-looking,
me or this guy?
Patrick, let's focus, buddy.
Remember that girl
we did last week?
The one with the potatoes?
That girl?
Yeah, that's this guy's girl.
Right, was.
We took care of that.
I kind of fell in love
with her that night.
What? You little fuck.
What?
She was unconscious, man.
She was beautiful.
I stole a pair of her panties,
as well.
Jesus!
What? It's not like...
I mean, they were
clean and all.
Don't tell me this.
I don't want to hear
this shit.
They were clean.
What? Don't. Stop.
Okay, all right.
We've got work to do.
Hold my papers.
There's more.
After we did her,
I kind of asked her out.
What?
Jesus.
...how unethical...
It's not really that bad.
Get that look off your face.
What's wrong?
Patrick,
you stole a girl's panties.
There's someone here.
He stole your underwear.
I don't see anyone.
Joel, where are my boots?
Now, why are you
showing me poisons?
Can't you understand English?
Potions, I said. Potions.
£ove potion, please.
I'm fucking
crawling out of my skin!
I should have left you
at the flea market.
Want to go?
I want to have a baby.
Let's talk about it later.
No. I want to have a baby.
I don't think we're ready.
You're not ready.
Clem, do you really think
you could take care of a kid?
What?
I don't want to
talk about it here.
I can't hear you.
I can
never the fuck understand
what you're saying.
I said I don't want to
talk about this!
We're fucking gonna
talk about it!
You can't just say that
and say you don't wanna
talk about it.
I'm sorry.
I'd make
a fucking good mother.
I love children.
I'm creative,
I'm smart, and I'd make
a fucking great mother!
It's you, Joel.
It's you who can't
commit to anything.
It's going.
You've no idea
how lucky you are
I'm interested in you.
I don't even know why I am.
Maybe I should
end it right here!
Leave you at the flea market
with the stupid
costume jewelry!
Maybe you can find a nice
antique rocking chair
to die in!
Hi, Patrick.
Hi, Mary, how's it going?
Hey, you.
It's freezing outside.
Did you find us okay?
Yeah.
Hot.
Poor guy.
Don't you have
anything real to drink?
We haven't checked yet.
Let me do the honors.
Mary hates me.
Never really had
much luck with the ladies.
Maybe if you stopped
stealing their panties.
There's more.
No.
Yes.
You didn't want any,
did you, Patrick?
No, I don't know.
That's okay.
Wait.
"Blessed are the forgetful,
"for they get the better
even of their blunders."
That's Nietzsche.
Beyond Good and Evil.
I found it in my Bartlett's.
What's your Bartlett's?
It's a quote book, Patrick.
It's a book of quotations.
I think Howard will be
in Bartlett's one day.
Definitely.
Howard is pure Bartlett's.
Can you wake him up?
You can't wake him up.
You don't tell me things,
Joel.
I'm an open book.
I tell you everything.
Every damn embarrassing thing.
You don't trust me.
Constantly talking isn't
necessarily communicating.
I don't do that.
I want to know you.
I don't constantly talk.
Jesus.
People have to share things,
Joel.
That's what intimacy is.
I'm really pissed
that you said that to me.
I'm sorry.
My life just isn't
that interesting.
I wanna read
some of those journals you're
constantly scribbling in.
What do you write
if you don't have any thoughts
or passions or love?
"November 19, 2003.
"Dinner at Kang's again.
"Are we like
those poor couples
"you feel sorry for
in restaurants?
"Are we the dining dead?"
I can't stand the idea
of us being a couple
people think that about.
I like that.
How's the chicken?
Good.
More?
No, thank you.
She's going to be drunk
and stupid now.
Would you do me a favor
and clean the goddamn hair
off the soap
when you're done
in the shower?
It's really...
Yeah.
It's gross.
Gross.
I think it's just...
Repulsive.
It's repulsive.
Patrick,
can we get through this?
Hey, Tangerine.
Patrick, it's you.
I'm so miserable right now.
Why? What's wrong?
I don't know. I'm just
confused about everything.
Confused?
What are you confused about?
Everything's fine.
Do you love me?
Of course I do.
Where's
the self-help section?
Do you think I'm ugly?
No. You're beautiful.
Maybe I should come over.
No. I don't know.
I'm a mess, Patrick.
Just let me come over.
I'll cheer you up.
Okay.
Can I leave for a while?
My girlfriend's really upset.
We're right in the middle
of erasing this poor man's...
Let him go, Stan.
I'll help.
See?
How hard can it be?
She hates me.
She wants me to go.
Go.
All right.
I'll be right over,
Tangerine.
You like?
I matched
my sweatshirt exactly.
I like it.
You do?
You look like a tangerine.
Clementine the tangerine.
Juicy and seedless.
I like that.
I like tangerines.
Can you see me
doing ducks?
Tangerine.
How does he know
to call you that?
How did who know?
Oh, my God. Clem?
This is pretty cool.
That's what
they called themselves.
The Clash,
the only band that mattered.
And they called themselves
that for a reason.
It's amazing, isn't it?
Like social justice.
Yeah,
it's totally incredible.
What Howard
gives to the world.
Yeah.
To let people begin again.
It's beautiful.
You look at a baby,
and it's so pure and so free
and so clean.
Adults are this
mess of sadness
and phobias.
And Howard
just makes it all go away.
Baby, what's going on?
I don't know.
I'm lost, I'm scared,
I feel like I'm disappearing.
My skin's coming off!
I'm getting old!
Nothing makes
any sense to me!
You're not getting old.
Nothing makes any sense.
Tangerine.
It's okay.
Let's go out dancing.
You want to go out
to Montauk with me?
Montauk?
No, come up
to Boston with me.
Sure. We can go next weekend.
No, now. I have to go now.
I have to see
the frozen Charles now.
Hi, it's Joel.
£eave a message after the beep
and I'll get back to you.
Pick up.
Hello? What's up?
I got into a little situation
with the old lady.
Can you handle things tonight
alone? I'm really sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I've got it under control.
He's pretty much
on auto-pilot now, anyway.
Thanks.
I owe you big-time.
Dude, I got to go.
"Look. You and me
on the Charles River.
"I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just happy.
"I've never felt that before.
I'm exactly where I want..."
I'm so excited.
I'm excited, too.
Cool.
I got you this thing.
Happy early Valentine's Day.
Thank you.
What is it?
I don't know. Open it up.
It's gorgeous.
You like it?
It's just my taste, really.
God, I've never gone out
with a guy who bought
me jewelry I liked.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Okay.
Joely?
Yeah, Tangerine?
Am I ugly?
When I was a kid,
I thought I was.
Can't believe
I'm crying already.
Sometimes I think
people don't understand
how lonely it is to be a kid.
Like you don't matter.
So, I'm eight,
and I have these toys,
these dolls.
My favorite
is this ugly girl doll
who I call Clementine.
And I keep yelling at her,
"You can't be ugly.
Be pretty."
It's weird.
Like if I can transform her,
I would magically
change, too.
You're pretty.
Don't ever leave me.
Mierzwiak, please
let me keep this memory.
Just this one.
I don't want
to hold your hand. Come on.
Stop it!
I could die right now.
I'm just so happy.
I've never felt
that before.
I'm just exactly
where I want to be.
I want to call it off.
I'll give you a sign.
Can you hear me?
I don't want this anymore!
I want to call it off!
Is anybody there?
What?
We've got to go.
Where?
I have an idea
of how to stop this.
Stop what?
Don't tickle me. No.
Smell my pits!
Concentrate, Clem.
We have to get back
to the office.
Halloween.
There was a tape recorder.
No, not the picture.
Back here. Come on.
Look at me.
I want to go there.
Our files are confidential,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say
that Miss Kruczynski
was not happy
and she wanted to move on.
Tell me about...
Tell me
everything you remember.
That's what he said.
What did we
see that day?
We're going to see
my grandma.
Shit!
Joel, why...
No. We're not
going on a train.
Joel, please.
Don't make me run anymore.
Come on.
Mierzwiak!
Do we always have to run?
Please?
Why don't we begin by
you telling me everything
you can remember...
Mierzwiak,
wake me up!
I'm sorry, Mr. Barish,
I thought you understood
what was going on.
You're erasing her from me.
You're erasing me from her.
You got this thing.
I'm in my bed. I know it.
I'm in my brain.
I'm part of
your imagination, too.
How can I help
you from there?
I'm inside your head, too.
I'm you.
Sorry.
Look, who's that?
He works for us.
That's Patrick,
baby boy.
He's stealing my identity.
He stole my stuff.
He's seducing my girlfriend
with my words and my things.
He stole her underwear.
Jesus Christ.
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just happy.
I've never felt that before.
I'm exactly
where I want to be.
I want to go home.
What?
Wait, Clem.
Clem, they're erasing you.
Over here!
Clem, focus.
I hired them, okay?
I'm sorry. I'm so stupid.
Sweetie, calm down.
Enjoy the scenery.
I need it to stop
before I wake up
and don't know you anymore.
Just tell them
to cancel it then.
What the hell are you
talking about?
I can't just cancel it.
I'm asleep.
Wake yourself up!
Okay, you want me to wake up?
All right.
Okay, here we go.
Will it make you happy
if I try?
Yeah.
I'll try really hard.
Here we go.
That was a great idea.
That's working
like gangbusters.
Don't!
That tickles me!
What the hell is that?
It's a birthmark!
It did work, for a second.
But I couldn't...
See?
I couldn't move.
Isn't that just another one
of Joel's self-fulfilling
prophecies?
It's more important
to prove me wrong
than to actually...
I don't want to discuss this
right now, okay?
Fine.
Then what? I'm listening.
I don't know.
You erased me.
That's why I'm here
and doing this.
I'm sorry.
You know me, I'm impulsive.
That's what I love about you.
I have another idea
for this problem.
This is a memory of me.
The way you wanted
to have sex on the couch
after you look down
at my crotch.
The eraser guys are coming,
so what if you take me
somewhere else,
somewhere where
I don't belong,
and we hide there
till morning?
I can't remember anything
without you.
That's very sweet,
but try, okay?
Okay.
Row, row, row your boat
Gently down the stream
Merrily, merrily,
merrily, merrily
Life is but a dream
It's working.
I'm a genius.
Where did you go?
I'm supposed to come, too!
I'm just gonna go
get a salad bowl.
Can you stir the soup
and keep an eye on Joel?
He likes to be near me.
Absolutely.
It worked.
My God, look at this.
It worked!
Look at this dress, man.
I wish I could
take it with me.
Who am I?
Mrs. Hamlyn.
Right. Mrs. Hamlyn.
I must be about four.
Oh, my gosh.
Found the salad bowl.
I'm serving salad
and string beans.
Is he okay under there?
Honey, are you all right?
I feel like
I could clean up all day.
Would you hate me
if I asked you to clean
some string beans?
No, not at all.
God, I love this kitchen.
Thank you so much.
She's not looking at me.
She's busy.
No one ever looks at me.
I want my mommy.
Oh, baby Joel.
Is every little peanut
under there okay?
He's fine.
Do you have
something to drink?
How about a cocktail?
I know it's not 5:00...
I would die for a vodka.
Let me check
if I have that.
Okay, I'm just going
to wait right here.
No, sweetie. Joely?
Your mother
wants me to mind you.
Get back under the table.
Ice cream.
No, not until
after you've had your dinner.
Come on! Grow up.
Don't leave me, Clem.
Oh, my God.
No, I'm right here.
This is sort of warped.
I'm scared.
I want my mommy.
Don't cry, baby Joel.
It's okay.
Joel, stop it!
I think it's working.
We're hidden, Joel. Look!
Honey, look.
Wait there.
My crotch is still here,
just as you remembered it.
Yuck.
It stopped.
What?
It stopped erasing.
Oh, shit!
This is terrible.
He's off the map.
Where?
I don't know where.
This is very bad news.
Where are my glasses?
Crap! What did we do?
What do I do?
What shall we do?
I don't know what to do.
I just said, I don't know.
I'm sorry.
What shall we do?
I don't know. Mellow out.
You're freaking me out.
We have to do something.
He could wake up
all half-baked.
Quiet.
You're freaking me out.
All gooey and half-baked.
That sounds so good.
I'm hungry.
Oh, shit. What?
We should call Howard.
No way. No sir, man.
This is my...
I can handle this.
You can't call Howard.
There's no time
to fuck around.
I've got this under control.
What are you talking about?
Stop fucking around.
Okay. I'll call Howard.
Hello?
Howard, it's Stan.
I'm working on this guy
down here.
We've lost him
for a moment,
and I can't
bring him back up.
Okay, tell me what happened
before he disappeared.
I wasn't sure
because I was away
from the monitor for a minute,
and I had it on auto-pilot
because I had to pee.
Where was Patrick?
He had to go home sick.
What's the address?
I know,
I'm so sorry.
That's okay. Come on.
We're at 159 South Village.
Apartment 1-E.
Rockville Center.
Mary, he's coming right now.
I'm staying.
Get your stuff, Mary.
I think you should go.
No.
I am so stoned.
Please, Mary,
you have to go.
Stop being stoned.
I don't want him
to see me stoned.
You have no idea
how much trouble I'll get into
if Howard comes...
Joel, stop. Look.
I want her to pick me up.
Weird how strong
that desire is.
Joel, look at me.
You'll remember me
in the morning,
you'll come to me,
you'll tell me about us,
and we'll start over.
Pat? I thought we could
have a little cocktail.
That Patrick guy,
he's copying me.
What Patrick guy?
That guy.
What?
He's here, in my apartment.
One of the eraser guys.
He fell for you
when they were doing you,
and now
he's introduced himself
like he doesn't even know you,
and you guys are dating.
Really?
Is he cute?
There's nothing wrong
with you.
You're the most wonderful
person I've ever met.
You're kind, beautiful,
smart, funny, and nice.
What?
Okay, all right.
Move. Come on,
let's go.
Careful.
I'm still stoned.
Those eye drops
you gave me didn't do shit.
Be cool.
Hello, Mary,
what are you doing here?
Hi, Howard.
She was just here
to help out.
I wanted to understand
as much about the procedure
as possible.
I think it's important
for my job to understand
the inner workings
of the work that we do.
Not that I do,
but the work that is done
by people where I also work.
The work of my colleagues.
Let's see if we can
get to the bottom of this,
shall we?
That's odd.
I already tried that.
You tried going through
the C-gate?
Of course.
I mean, yes.
All right.
You want to get linked up?
Yeah.
I ran the utility programs,
and I had nothing there,
so I checked all the memories
against the printed logs.
Here, Howard,
I got you a chair.
Thank you.
There you go.
You're welcome.
All right.
I've got it.
I'll go through
the entire memory,
see if something
comes up.
I love being bathed
in the sink.
Such a feeling of security.
I've never seen you happier,
baby Joel.
There it is.
I don't understand
why it's off the map
like that.
What the heck
was he doing there?
His eyes are open.
Has this happened before
with him?
No.
This is not good.
I'm going to have
to give him this.
Can't you see
I love you, Antoine?
Okay, we're back in.
That was beautiful to watch,
Howard, like a surgeon
or a concert pianist.
Thank you, Mary.
Howard, you should
get some sleep.
I think I'll be fine now.
Can't you see I love you,
Antoine?
Lucky me. Lay one on me.
Don't call me Antoine.
My name is Wally.
Yes, I know, but how can
a woman love a man
with a name like Wally?
What was that?
My God, there's people
coming out of your butt.
There is?
Got it.
Tangerine! Come on.
We've got to go.
Go on. Please go.
You can run,
but you can't hide.
Clem, come on!
There I am.
That truck.
Doc? Please!
Let's begin by
you telling me everything
you remember...
That's strange.
He's in a memory
that we've already erased.
At least we know where he is.
He's back on track, right?
Come on, Clem.
He's developed
some sort of resistance
to the procedure.
I don't want to run anymore.
Shit.
Come on.
Hide me somewhere deeper,
somewhere really buried.
Where?
Hide me in your humiliation.
Humiliation.
Come on, you big baby.
No!
Bye, Howard.
Wait.
He's disappeared again.
Oh, dear.
I'm so sorry, Howard.
Humiliation.
I don't like it, either.
I'm trying to find
horrible secret places to...
Honey, I have a surprise.
You know what?
I'll just ask you
in the morning.
Good night.
I'm sorry.
Shut up.
Look.
Joel, look where we are.
This isn't good.
Then hide me somewhere
really buried.
Hit it, Joel!
I can't,
I've got to go home.
I'll do it later!
He has a girlfriend.
Wait, what am I doing?
Freddy, you don't
scare me anymore.
Joely, get up.
Come on, it's not worth it.
They're not worth it, Joel.
He's not listening!
Come on.
Stupid!
I'm so ashamed.
It's okay.
You were a little kid.
Come on.
That's where I live, lived.
I wish I knew you
when I was a kid.
Do you like my pink hat?
Here, look, feel better.
You can really kill me
this time. It's my turn. Go.
You're really going to die,
though, okay?
One, two, three.
You're dead.
My mom.
It's okay, we're playing.
It's not real.
He's killing me.
Are you dead yet?
You're dead!
I think
I got the hang of this.
I still don't understand it,
but I'm finding him
quickly enough.
Are you okay?
Oh, my God, that was terrible.
Almost three seconds.
Let's do it one more time.
One more
and then I get to go.
This is so cool!
Look out!
It's fluff.
Our house.
Wait, we've got to go.
Come on.
This is a really bad time
for this.
I don't even know
where we're going.
It's going to be fun.
It's the best place.
No, this way.
This way. Come on.
You're no help at all.
Come on.
Let go of me, Joel.
I like watching you work,
Howard.
I guess I'll go out
for some air,
if nobody minds.
It looks like
you have everything
under control here.
Yeah, that's fine.
Do you like quotes, Howard?
What do you mean?
Like famous quotes.
I find reading them
inspirational,
and in my reading,
I've come across some
I thought you might like, too.
I'd love to hear some.
There's one that goes,
"Blessed are the forgetful,
"for they get the better
even of their blunders."
That's Nietzsche, right?
Yeah.
I thought I could tell you
something you didn't know.
No, it's a good quote.
I'm happy we both know it.
There's this
other one I like.
It's by Pope Alexander
and it goes...
Alexander Pope?
Oh, yeah. Shit.
It's just that I told myself
not to say "Pope Alexander"
and sound like a dope,
and then I go ahead
and say it.
It's no big deal.
You're such a sweetheart.
The quote goes, "How happy
is the blameless vestal's lot!
"The world forgetting
by the world forgot
"Eternal sunshine
of the spotless mind!
"Each pray'r accepted
and each wish resign'd"
I want to be a great,
big, huge elephant.
With a huge trunk like that.
I haven't heard that one.
It's lovely.
I just thought
it would be appropriate,
maybe.
I really admire
the work you do.
I don't mean to be
so familiar...
It's fine.
I'm happy to hear...
I'm sorry.
I've loved you
for a very long time.
I shouldn't have said that.
Mary, you're
a wonderful girl.
But, you know,
I have a wife and kids.
Mary, we can't do this.
Good morning,
Mrs. Mierzwiak.
What? Who is it?
Oh, my God.
Thank you, Stan.
Thanks a lot.
Hollis!
Wait.
I knew it, Howard.
It didn't start out like this.
I came here to work.
This is a one-time mistake.
I'm a stupid girl
with a crush.
I basically
forced him into it.
Don't be a monster.
Tell the girl.
Tell me what?
Oh, you poor kid.
You can have him.
You did.
What?
We have a history.
I'm sorry.
You wanted the procedure.
You wanted it done
so you could get past...
I have to
finish the work in there.
It's almost morning.
We'll talk later, okay?
Let me give you a lift home.
Didn't figure you'd show
your face around me again.
I thought you were humiliated.
You did run away,
after all.
I just needed to see you.
Yeah?
I'd like to
take you out or something.
You're married.
Not yet. Not married.
No, I'm not married.
Look, I'm telling you
right off the bat,
I'm high maintenance,
so I'm not gonna tiptoe
around your marriage
or whatever it is
you've got going there.
If you want to be with me,
you're with me.
Okay.
Too many guys think
I'm a concept,
or I complete them
or I'm gonna make them alive.
I'm just a fucked-up girl
who's looking for
my own peace of mind.
Don't assign me yours.
I remember that speech
really well.
I had you pegged,
didn't I?
Had the whole human race
pegged.
Probably.
I still thought
you were going
to save my life.
Even after that.
I know.
It would be different,
if we could just
give it another go-round.
Remember me.
Try your best.
Maybe we can.
Just tell me
what you remember,
and we'll take it
from there.
I liked you immediately.
You didn't come on to me
at all. I liked that.
I was so tongue-tied
around you at first,
but I wanted you to think
I was smart.
I couldn't wait
to come to work.
I had these fantasies
of us being married
and having kids...
Howie, I can't do this.
We agreed
it's for the best, Mary.
Yeah, I know.
O£, God!
I'll take the bottom
and you...
No, Joel,
help me with that.
Will you get the cooler?
Honey, the cooler's pretty...
She can get it.
Let me get that.
No, no, no.
Don't take anything.
I can take the plane.
Put the gate back up.
This is the day we met.
You were by the surf.
I could just make you out
in the distance.
I remember being drawn to you,
even then.
I thought,
"Wow, how odd!
"I'm drawn to someone's back."
You were
in that orange sweatshirt
that I would
come to know so well,
and even hate, eventually.
But at the time I thought,
"How cool,
an orange sweatshirt."
Hi, there.
Hi.
I saw you sitting over here
by yourself,
and I thought,
"Thank God,
"someone normal who
doesn't know how to interact
at these things."
I don't ever know
what to say.
I'm Clementine.
Can I borrow
a piece of your chicken?
And then you just took it,
without waiting for an answer.
It was so intimate,
like we were already lovers.
I'm Joel.
Hi, Joel.
So, no jokes about my name.
You mean, like
"Oh, my darlin', Clementine?"
Huckleberry Hound?
That sort of thing?
Yeah, like that.
No, no jokes.
One of my favorite things
when I was a kid
was my Huckleberry Hound doll.
I think your name is magical.
This is it, Joel.
It's gonna be gone soon.
I know.
What do we do?
Enjoy it.
You married?
No.
Let's move into
this neighborhood!
I do sort of live
with someone, though.
Male or female?
What? Female.
At least I'm not barking up
the wrong tree.
Do you know these people?
No, of course not.
Come on.
They might have a dog.
There's no dog.
What are you doing?
It's freezing out.
I don't believe this.
Come on, man.
The water's fine.
Nobody's coming here tonight,
believe me.
So, what's
your girlfriend's name?
Naomi,
but we're not really...
Whatever.
So this is great.
Now I can look
for candles, matches,
and the liquor cabinet.
Oh, God.
I think we should go.
There's no phone line.
What?
I think we should go.
Why? It's our house.
Just for tonight.
We are
David and Ruth Laskin.
Which one do you want to be?
I prefer to be Ruth,
but I can be flexible.
What do you need?
Alcohol.
So, are you okay with wine?
I don't know.
Well, you choose the wine.
I'll go find the bedroom
and slip into
something more Ruth.
I'm Ruth-less at the moment.
We really should go.
I've got to catch my ride.
So go.
I did. I thought
maybe you were a nut.
But you were exciting.
I wish you'd stayed.
I wish I'd stayed, too.
Now I wish I'd stayed.
I wish I'd done
a lot of things.
I wish I'd stayed. I do.
I came back downstairs
and you were gone.
I walked out the door.
Why?
I don't know. I felt
like a scared little kid.
It was above my head.
You were scared?
Yeah.
I thought
you knew that about me.
I ran back
to the bonfire, trying
to outrun my humiliation.
Was it something I said?
Yeah.
You said "So go"
with such disdain.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
What if you stayed this time?
I walked out the door.
There's no memory left.
Come back
and make up a goodbye.
Let's pretend
we had one.
Bye, Joel.
I love you.
Meet me in Montauk.
I didn't crash the plane.
The plane crashed.
You were operating
the plane with the remote
control, and it crashed.
It was fucking windy.
Come on.
You're stoned
and you're driving.
The pot balances it out
and brings you back up.
That's why I smoke it.
If I'm going to be drinking,
then I'll smoke it.
It does. A medical test
was done. It's proven
on the Science Network.
Honey, just watch the road.
I can't see shit.
I saw you talking
to a pretty girl.
She was nice.
Yeah, man, who was it?
She was just a girl.
Okay.
So I've got to
drop the van off.
Thanks, Stan. We'll talk.
You've got all your stuff,
I see.
That's right.
I take it
you're not coming back.
I wouldn't come back
if I was you.
Do you swear you didn't know?
I swear.
So you didn't do
the erasing?
Of course not. God, no.
And you never even suspected
we were together?
Once, maybe.
I was coming back from a job,
and you were at his car,
and I saw you two talking.
So I waved to you,
and you giggled.
How did I look?
You looked happy.
Happy with a secret.
And after that?
I never saw you two together
again like that,
so I just figured
I was imagining things.
I really like you, Mary Svevo.
You know that?
Thanks.
Let me get my toothbrush.
Where are you, Clem?
I'm worried.
I feel like you're mad at me
and I don't know what I did.
What did I do?
I love you so much.
I'll do anything
to make you happy.
Just tell me what you want
me to do, and I'll do it.
I'm going to stop by
this morning,
just to make sure you're okay.
Let's go, mister.
I had a really nice time
last night.
Nice?
I had the best fucking night
of my entire fucking life
last night.
That's better.
This is weird.
"To all patients
of Dr. Howard Mierzwiak.
"My name is Mary Svevo.
"We've met,
but you don't remember me.
"I worked for a company
you hired to have
part of your memory erased.
"I've since decided
that this is a horrible...
"To correct this, I'm sending
everyone's file back to them."
My name
is Clementine Kruczynski.
I'm here to erase
Joel Barish.
What is this?
I don't know.
He's boring.
Is that enough reason
to erase someone?
I've been thinking how I was
before and how I am now,
and he changed me.
I feel like
I'm always pissy now.
I don't like myself
when I'm with him.
I don't like myself anymore.
I can't stand
to even look at him.
That pathetic, wimpy,
apologetic smile.
That sort of
wounded puppy shit.
What are you doing?
I'm not doing anything.
The bloom is certainly
off the rose at this point.
Are you screwing with me?
No!
You are screwing with me.
Joel, I'm not!
You clearly are!
Let's just take a minute
and...
Patrick,
get the fuck away from me!
Can we talk about it?
No, get the fuck away!
Hey, Clementine.
Nice to see you.
I mean,
she's smart, I think,
but not educated.
I couldn't talk to her
about books.
She's more of
a magazine-reading girl.
Her vocabulary leaves
something to be desired.
The truth is,
I was embarrassed in public,
Hi.
Because she would pronounce
"library," "li-berry."
Look what I found.
I think if there's
a truly seductive quality
about Clementine,
it's that her personality
promises to take you
out of the mundane.
Made me look skinny.
An amazing, burning meteorite
will carry you
to another world
where things are exciting.
But what you quickly learn
is that it's really
an elaborate ruse.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
It's okay.
I really like you.
I hate that I said
mean things about you.
Let me turn this off, okay?
That's only fair.
The whole thing
with the hair,
it's all bullshit.
I really like your hair.
Thank you.
I do.
You want a drink or something?
Do you have any whiskey?
I didn't think
her sex was motivated.
I saw it clearly
the last night we were
together. It wasn't sexy.
It was just sad.
Sorry,
I thought there was more.
The only way Clem thinks
she can get people to like her
is to fuck them.
Or at least dangle
the possibility of getting
fucked in front of them.
I think she's
so desperate and insecure
that she'll sooner or later
go around fucking everybody.
I don't do that.
I wouldn't
think that about you.
Because I don't.
I know.
It hurts me
that you said that,
because I don't do that.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry about all this.
I'm going to go.
I'm a little confused.
I don't really think
I can be here.
Bye.
I really thought
I knew her so well.
It was nice meeting you
and all.
What a loss to spend
that much time with someone,
only to find out
that she's a stranger.
Wait.
What?
I don't know. Just wait.
What do you want, Joel?
I want you to wait
for a while.
Okay.
Really?
I'm not a concept,
just a fucked-up girl
looking for my peace of mind.
I'm not perfect.
I can't see anything
that I don't like about you.
But you will.
Right now I can't.
You will think of things.
And I'll get bored with you
and feel trapped,
because that's what happens
with me.
Okay.