Euro Trip
Congratulations,
Hudson High Class of 2004.
There she is. Fiona!
Bye.
- Hey.
- Hey!
- Hey, you.
- Congratulations, graduate.
- Thanks, baby.
And congratulations to you, Cooper.
Aww. Thanks, baby!
- Nice try.
- All right. - See you at Wade's party tonight?
- See you then.
Alright
So, it's just you and me
for the entire summer.
Next year you graduate, join me
at college.
Just like we planned.
- Scott, we need to talk.
- Yeah? About what?
About me dumping you.
Huh?
There he is!
The graduate
and his beautiful girlfriend. OK?
Smile, you two!
- Action!
- Dad, Mom, Grandma...
Uncle Moke... uh...
I'm gonna need a minute here, OK?
What do you mean,
you're dumping me?
I just can't take all the
lying
and cheating on each other anymore.
What are you talking about?
Sweetie, I never cheated on you.
I know. That's what makes this so hard.
You're looking good, you guys.
Scotty, it's not you.
It's me.
There I go, lying again.
No, it was you.
You're just so...
...predictable.
- Smile!
So, that's it.
Here's your letter jacket back.
Goodbye.
This isn't mine.
She's a keeper, huh?
Oh, wow.
Oh, my God.
Fiona!
Let's see that again.
- This is just so brutal.
And yet I can't look away.
Bert, play it again. Come on.
- Fiona!
- Bert, get out of here.
OK.See you.
All right. Stay black, Bert.
"Fiona!"
Mail, motherfucker!
Hey, I got one from Mieke.
"Happy Herzlichen."
Still writing that guy?
I thought that was for German class.
Yeah at first, but we're
actually becoming good friends.
He's a really cool guy.
"Dear Mieke, greetings
from your American pen pal."
Scotty, Girl Scouts have pen pals.
Listen to yourself, all right?
You met a "cool guy" on the "internet."
This is how these sexual predators work.
Next thing you know,
he'll want to "arrange a meeting"
where he will gas you,
stuff you in the back of his van,
and make a wind chime
out of your genitals.
Come on, let's go to Wade's.
All right.
Screw it. Let's go.
I'm not gonna let Fiona
ruin my graduation night.
Auf wiedersehen, Mieke.
- What's up, losers?
- What's up, Jenny?
What's up, dude?
Sorry to hear about Fiona.
She's a whore.
That's very sweet of you.
Thanks.
Enough Fiona talk.
Look around.
There's gotta be 100 drunk girls.
We should try to have sex
with every one of 'em.
Hello? Mixed company?
What?
- I'm a girl!
- No, you're not.
- You're just a cool guy with long hair.
- So, where's your evil twin brother?
Jenny!
There he is.
Hey, Jamie.
In fine form, I see.
Why'd you get me
gin and tonic?
- I hate gin.
- You do?
You guys are the worst twins ever!
Chug! Chug!
- When are you guys taking off?
- Tomorrow morning.
Hey, Wade!
Great party, buddy.
Man, I am so excited!
A whole summer,
backpacking around Europe.
You should've come with us
instead of
working for Dr. Dad, Scotty!
It's gonna be so awesome!
Yeah. I planned every detail of the trip
to maximize the fun!
You brought a guidebook to a party?
- Do you wanna see my itinerary?
- Do you wanna see my balls?
You guys decide where
you're gonna go first?
Paris! I can't wait.
Two years ago Nicky Jager's sister,
Debbie
met a wealthy French guy,
and spent a month sailing
the Mediterranean on his yacht.
Isn't that the most romantic
thing you've ever heard?
Stuck on a boat with a weird French guy?
That sounds a little gay.
It's not gay. I'm a girl.
- Kinda gay.
- A little gay.
I gotta piss like a pregnant woman.
Hey, listen up, everybody.
Gotta a little special thing
I'd like to do tonight.
Going to play
a little song for you
about the nastiest, freakiest
little sex puppet I know...
Fiona.
This one's for you, baby.
Happy anniversary.
" Scotty doesn't know
That Fiona and me
" Do it in my van every Sunday
" She tells him she's in church
But she doesn't go
" Still she's on her knees
And Scotty doesn't know
" Oh, Scotty doesn't know
" So don't tell Scotty
Scotty doesn't know
" Scotty doesn't know "
I hope we're just as popular
in college
as we were in high school.
- We will be.
- I know.
Who needs more Chablis?
- Candy, wanna come with?
- No, I'll stay here.
Hello Candy!
- Whoops!
Holy cow!
Oh, this isn't where
I parked my car!
" I can't believe
He's so trusting
" While I'm right behind you thrusting
" 'Cause Scotty doesn't know
Scotty doesn't know "
Cooper Harris, you're a pig!
Uh... Candy, before you go
you might wanna clean that off
Clean what off?
It's like a dirt or something...
just go like this...
No... It's kind of under...
and to the side
under
Is this off?
I think that your top is getting in the way
Really?
Trust me
That's better...
Keep rubbing it
" I did it with her on his birthday
" Scotty doesn't know
Scotty doesn't know
" Don't tell Scotty
Scotty doesn't know "
Mmm-hmm... mmm-hmm...
No, it's just not coming off.
What is it?
- Fine, I'll do it.
Come here.
Oh, my God! Candy!
Cooper!
Hey...
This isn't where I parked my car.
" Scotty doesn't know
Scotty doesn't know!
Hey
This band rocks!
- Yeah!
Mail, motherfucker!
Hey, Mieke.
"I was very sad
to hear about
your lady woman Fiona dumping you.
"Since you no longer have a girlfriend,
maybe I could come to America
"and we could get to know each
other better.
Perhaps we could...
"Zussamen."
What the fuck is "zussamen"?
"Arrange a meeting."
No, no, no! Come on!
Cooper was right.
This guy wants to have sex with me
"Listen, Mieke...
"I don't want to arrange
any meetings with you,
"you sick, German freak.
"So please keep your hands
off my genitals,
"and never write to me again,
and don't come to America."
"Goodbye."
Oww.
I'm never drinking again.
Oh, that's nice.
Bert, what are you doing?
Reading your email.
Don't do that.
Why are you wearing my bathrobe?
Oh, I'm sorry...
but somebody pissed
all over mine last night.
Wow. I can't believe this German chick
wants to come here and hook up with you.
I don't think so, buddy.
Mieke's a guy.
No, it says right here,
"Trauriges m dchen."
"I was a sad girl to hear about Fiona."
I'm taking "Intro to German,"
and even I know that.
Come here.
He sent me a picture, retardo.
See? That's a picture of Mieke
and his cute cousin, Jan.
No, retardo.
That's Jan, a man's name,
and that's not "Mike,"
it's "Mieke," a common
German girl's name,
similar to our Michelle.
I hope you wrote her back
and told her to come visit.
You didn't?
You thought she was a guy!
I'm getting the video camera! Ha!
What an asshole!
No.
"Address blocked"?
"Email not delivered."
No... come on!!
Hey, Mom made waffles.
- What's going on?
- I'm in love with my penpal.
I'm in love with Mieke.
OK... OK.
You know what?
I was actually expecting this.
And frankly.. No listen...
I'm flattered that
you picked me to come out to first.
And don't worry about
telling your folks, 'cause...
- I think they already know.
- No, you idiot. Mike is a girl.
No, no, I get it. Yeah.
He's the girl, and you're the girl,
and sometimes you're both the girl.
Right?
Right? That's hot.
But you know... whatever works for you.
I'm not gonna judge it.
Will you stop? Look, come here.
Look at this picture.
Wow. Who's the hot chick?
That's "Mike." I mean, Mieke.
That's Mieke? That's who you've been writing to
all this time?
No! Until last night,
when I took your advice
and told her to keep her
"hands off my genitals."
Given what we know now, that seems like
the exact opposite of what you want.
This is a total disaster.
Oh, come on. It's not that bad.
Though she is really hot.
You're not listening.
I don't even care what she looks like.
Mieke and I had this incredible bond.
I told her things
I couldn't even tell you.
Like what?
- Nothing. It's a figure of speech.
- No, seriously. What?
- Nothing. The point...
- You like me better, right?
Would ya stop.. listen
This girl is not only smart and funny,
and stunningly beautiful,
but
until I screwed up, she actually wanted to
to come all the way to America just to be with me.
- So do something about it.
- What can I do?
She blocked her email account,
her phone number's not listed.
The only thing I know
is she lives in Berlin.
So go to Berlin.
I can't just go to Berlin, Coop.
- Why not?
- Because...
I just can't, OK?
I'm supposed
to work for my dad this summer.
It looks good on
my med school application.
Oh, Jesus, Scotty!
Man, Fiona was right.
You're so predictable.
- I'm going to Germany.
- No...
We're going to Germany.
How are we going
to get to Germany?
Don't worry. I've got it covered.
- We're going to be couriers?
- Best way to get a cheap flight.
All we have to carry their packages,
then
drop them off when we get there.
- My cousin did it going to India.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Of course, he ended up using
a public restroom in New Delhi
and they had to cut off his leg.
You know...
but he got there cheap,
is what I'm saying.
OK, I don't have anything
to Germany for a week.
But I can get you both
to London today for $118.
Anything else?
Europe is the size of the Eastwood Mall.
We can walk to Berlin from there.
- Cooper, England's an island.
- OK, swim. Whatever.
We'll take it.
Hey.
Thanks for coming with me.
I know you had that internship
at the law firm this summer.
Well, forget about the law firm.
And don't thank me.
I should be thanking you.
This trip is
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity for me
to broaden my sexual horizons.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about crazy European sex.
Ah.
You know America was founded by prudes.
b?i nh?ng ngu?i dàn bà doan trang.
Prudes who left Europe,
because they hated
it all the kinky, steamy
European sex that was going on.
And now I, Cooper Harris,
will return to the land
of my perverted forefathers
and claim my birthright,
which is a
series of erotic and sexually
challenging adventures.
You've really thought a lot
about this, haven't you?
It's my passion.
Come on, come on!
- The adventure begins.
- Welcome to jolly old England.
Yeah, breathe that sweet,
sexy, European air.
- Oh.
- What is that?
It's the phone they gave me
at the law firm.
Yeah, it's pretty neat, huh?
- Works anywhere.
- Yeah?
Excuse me.
Cooper here.
Hello, Mr. Walters.
Yes, sir, I'm down in file storage.
Um, hang on one second.
No, sir, I can't find
the Gutterman file anywhere.
Yes, sir, I'll keep looking.
I don't rest until I find it.
Didn't tell your boss
you were leaving the country?
They would've stopped paying me.
It seemed easier.
- So, where to?
- I don't know.
First bus to Berlin doesn't leave
till tomorrow.
What do you wanna do?
Got the Tower of London...
there's Buckingham Palace.
- Uh...
- There's no drinking age.
Ði thôi!
Kh?n truong nào.
- Hey!"The Fiesty Goat."
All right!
What do you wanna...
Soccer hooligans.
Hey, this isn't where
I parked my car!
Oy!
Who the bloody hell are you?
This is a private members bar,
exclusively for the supporters
of the greatest
football team in the world...
Manchester United.
Now please, enlighten me.
Who the fuck are you?!
That is a good question,
and... Scotty?
Huh?
We're the Manchester United fan club...
from Ohio.
If you're Manchester United
supporters...
sing the Manchester United song.
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
I'm not much of a singer...
- Sing!!
" My baby takes
? " The morning train ?
? " He works from 9 to 5 and then he ?
? " takes another home again ?
? " To find me... ?
? " watching the Manchester United
football team! " ?
Eh?
The best freakin' team
in all the land! Whoo-hoo!
Pretty good.
- Pretty dang good, lads!
- Yeah!
? " My baby takes the morning train ?
? " He works from 9 to 5 and then ?
? " He takes another home again ?
? " To find me waiting for him ?
? " He's always
on that morning train " ?
I've unblocked
your email address,
but this Scott is not responding.
He was the one.
I was going to give myself to him.
Perhaps you should give
yourself to someone else...
Frulein.
I'm never drinking again.
Coop, wake up.
Oh, man, that was a wild night.
You think?
Scotty, where the hell are we going?
Don't worry. If anything
bad happens
my parents will find us.
Honey, where's Scotty?
- Cooper said they were going camping.
- Oh, that's nice.
And where's Bert?
Fuck if I know.
Hey!
How are you, you scalawag!
Look, given the current
geopolitical climate,
all European countries should
have a seat at the table.
- Right.
- Except those fucking Ities.
I hate them Italian bastards.
- You know what I mean?
-
Hello, boyo!
- What the hell happened last night?
- You got steamed up, pissed as a fart.
.
Too much sauce, son.
Don't worry.
We come and got ya,
so you wouldn't miss the trip.
What trip?
- Where are we going?
- What do you mean, where are we going?
We're going to see the Mighty
Reds do the frogs in Paris.
Aren't we, boys?
Yeah!
Why are you yelling at me?
So I tell the swamp donkey
to sock it
before I give her a trunky
in the tradesman's entrance
and have her lick me yardballs!
Wow.
You guys are on a completely
different level of swearing over here.
Coop? Cooper,
we're going to Paris.
I know. Cecil told me.
Mieke's in Berlin.
We're not going to Berlin.
What are we gonna do?
We need a plan.
See what I'm talking about?
This is predictable Scotty talking.
Relax. Paris is practically a suburb
of Berlin.
It's a nothing commute.
That's why France and Germany
have always been allies.
Allies
The twins.
The twins are in Paris, right?
We give 'em a call. They could help us out.
Let me see your phone. I'll give 'em a call
Alright, but I'm only supposed
to use this for business calls.
Hey, don't...
You're on the wrong side of the road,
you snail-eating puffs.
Fuck off! Go on, you Gaelic
fucking garlic-breath tossers!
Piss off!
Get in here and say that,
you froggy Itie shities!
- Fucking beep!
We'll beep, you bastard,
all over your fucking nose!
Get out of the way! Piss off!
Hey, lads!
That wanker's got
a frog football shirt on!
Let's give this nancy
a fucking good kicking!
Come on, lads, he's going off!
All right. Twins said
they'd meet us here.
Look at that!
There they are. Come on. Jenny!
- Jamie!
- Hey!
Come here!
No, no. No, no, no!
- Scott, bienvenu a Paris.
- Thank you.
- What is that? A new camera?
- It isn't just a camera,
This is a Leica M7.
Uber-sensitive exposure settings,
legendary cloth shutter system.
- Let me see that thing.
- No can do.
I spent four years tutoring
lacrosse players to pay for it,
so nobody touches my camera but me.
- It's like your wiener.
- No, it's not...
- Jenny...
- Cooper, leave him alone.
Wow, I can't believe you came
all the way to Europe for a girl.
Wait, not just any girl.
Show her the picture, Scotty.
She makes girls in our high school
look like walruses.
I'm a girl from your high school.
No, I mean "girl" girls.
Guys, we're wasting the whole day here.
We're in Paris!
Hãy t?i Vi?n b?o tàng Louvre!
To the Louvre!
So, you guys wanna stay here,
should we check out
the huge line at the Eiffel Tower?
Here's a fun fact.  Voltaire
contracted
syphilis two blocks from here.
- Should we go?
- Can we please get out of here?
- This guy's really creeping me out.
- Who, robot man?
He's just trying to feed
his robot family.
- I really don't like him.
- Why?
Because he's doing this?
OK, seriously, don't do that.
Cooper.
Do not hate me.
I am familiar with
over 600 dance moves
and I am programmed to get...
freaky.
You're just upset because
people like me better.
It's okay.
Oh!
Fight! Fight!
Break the leg shot!
Ha! Ha! Ha!
Don't look in his eyes, Scotty.
- Ohhh!
- That was not cool.
Ha! Ha! Ha!
Arghhhhh!
Oh!
Guys, let's go. Come on.
Error! Error! Error!
How cool is this?
It's a shame we only get
to spend one day together.
Why don't you come to Berlin?
- Umm, no.
Jamie, come on. In a few months,
we go to different colleges.
This could be the last chance the four
of us are together like this.
Plus, we're in Europe. Huh?
This should be the trip of a lifetime.
There's no way we should split up.
All right, this table
is now Europe, OK?
Excuse me.
We are right here, in Paris,
and I have got to get to Mieke,
who is over here, in Berlin.
And Jamie...If you come with us,
I'm sure there's a
ton of great stuffs that you could see along the way.
- We can go to Denmark.
- I love Denmark.
- We gotta hit Amsterdam.
- Definitely.
And the cathedral at Cameret!
- Yeah...
- Maybe. We'll see.
- Whatever.
- If there's time.
Come on! I really want you
to be there when I meet Mieke.
Fine.
- Excellent!
- All right!
- A toast!
- Yes!
- To Mieke!
- To Europe!
To Europe!
Merci.
- Berlin, here we come!
- All right.
you better let me hold onto those.
- What the hell is that?
- It's a traveler's money belt.
Frommer's says
if you have one of these,
no one can rob you of anything.
Except your dignity.
No, you just put that in your...
wait, what?
Come on, guidebook. Let's go.
Check it out.
European ass.
What's up?
Jesus, Jenny.
I thought you were some...
girl. Come on. Platform 4.
Thanks.
Damn!
I believe this is yours.
Pleased to meet you.
My name is Christoph.
- Jenny, let's go!
- Move it!
Those are my friends.
We're supposed to go to Berlin...
- Jenny!
- I'm coming!!
So, it was really nice
to meet you.
The pleasure was all mine...
Jennifer.
" Scotty doesn't know
That Fiona and me "
" Do it in my van on Sundays "
" Tells him she's... "
What?
You gotta admit,
it's a really catchy tune.
" Tells him she's in church
But she doesn't go "
" Still she's on her knees
And Scotty doesn't know "
" Scotty doesn't know "
- " Scotty doesn't... "
- Buongiorno.
Buongiorno.
You know, there are a lot
of other empty compartments.
Huh?
Ah! Si...
Si.
Pardon me.
Eh?
Ohhh...
Scusi.
Mi scusi.
Hi.
Buongiorno.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Mi scusi, mi scusi.
No! No, no, no!
- Uh-oh.
- What?
Big tunnel.
Who's touching me?
Scotty, is that you?
Ai s? mó tao th??!
Scotty!
Oh!
Mi Scusi.
Crans Sur Mer.
We change trains here.
Well, we got a couple
of hours to kill.
What's there to see in this town?
Hello? The Monument des Poissonieres.
It's a monument to all the local
fishermen who were lost at sea.
Frommer's says it's supposed
to be..."quite moving."
What the hell is wrong with you, C-3PO?
We're here to see Europe,
not some crappy statue.
I'm taking a nap.
Wake me up when the train gets here.
Hmm. Says here this town
has a famous nude beach.
All right, we can't all
just lie around all day.
We gotta get out there and experience
the culture firsthand.
Let's go exploring!
So, what's the etiquette on boners?
Do I roll over and dig out
a hole for it,
or is it cool to just let my flag fly?
Wait, wait.
Does "nude beach" mean
we have to get naked, too?
Of course.
Do you think you can go an hour
without your currency colostomy bag?
Hey! Hey! As long as this thing has
our money and passports in it,
it's not coming off, and
my trunks won't come off, either.
Come on, Jamie
You came all the way to Europe.
Can't wimp out now.
OK.
All right, on the count of three.
Here we go.
3,2,1...
Look at Jamie's penis!
Very funny. Very funny.
All right.
Let the crazy European
sex odyssey begin.
- Here we go.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hello, ladies!
- Ladies?
- Bitches?
Eww! What a rip!
There's no nude girls here,
Just guys like us
looking for nude girls.
I don't understand.
"Crans Sur Mer has one of the best
nude beaches on the continent.
"However...
"during the summer,
the European women
"are chased away
by gawking male tourists,
"so Europe's most nubile exhibitionists
head to the deserted beach
" right next to the Monument des Poissonieres."
There's so many penises.
Frommer's tried to tell you,
but you just didn't listen.
This is the biggest
sausage fest on earth.
It's the international house of sausage.
Hey!
- Thanks for waiting.
- You're not missing anything.
It's all guys.
At least the sun's out.
?  Dreams come true  ?
?  I made my dreams come true  ?
?  My dreams come true  ?
Holy crap!
What? I thought this was a nude beach.
No!!!
- Huh? No.
- What? What are you doing?
- Jenny, you gotta cover up.
Girl?
Girl!
Ooh, girl.
Girl... girl.
Girl... girl...
Run!
- I'm not gonna make it.
- Go on without me.
- All right. See ya.
Chica! Chica!
Reading Mieke's old emails again?
Yeah.
I have no idea what I'm going
to say to that girl when I see her.
You know, she said
I might be the one?
That's huge.
I've never been "the one" before.
Thought I was "the one" with Fiona,
but turns out I was, what, 101?
- 200.
- 200!
Look, you got nothing to worry about.
You'll show up and sweep her
off her German feet.
Thanks.
Yeah.
I will, won't I?
I'm so sad and lonely.
I just wish someone
would show up
and sweep me off
my German feet.
Mieke! I'm here.
Scotty!
About that last email.
I'm so sorry...
The past is the past.
You're here now.
I've been saving myself for you.
Let us make love
for one whole month.
Touch me, Scotty.
OK.
Oh, Scott...
- Honey
Mi scusi.
Mi scusi!
? " Hot stuff baby this evening " ?
? " Gotta have some hot stuff " ?
? " Gotta have some love tonight " ?
? " Hot stuff " ?
Guys, our train
doesn't leave till morning.
- Are we gonna sleep tonight?
- What do you mean, sleep?
We can sleep on the train tomorrow.
This is the best that could've happened.
We're in Amsterdam!
This is the drug and
sex capital of Europe!
Take a look at this.
"Club Vandersexxx."
"The red light district's
hottest sex club."
We have to check it out.
Who's with me?
I'll go.
Fine. Since no one else
is willing to go,
I'll just go myself.
? " I see " ?
? " You're waiting for me " ?
This is definitely
where I parked my car.
Hello there.
Welcome to Club Vandersexxx...
Amsterdam's most erotic club,
where your every fantasy
will be fulfilled.
Also says I get
a free T-shirt with flyer.
He's American.
How sad for you to grow up
in a country founded by prudes.
A country overrun
with crime and illiteracy.
A country where a man
is forced to make sex
to only one woman at a time,
and one must learn
the woman's name beforehand.
- It was horrible.
- I know.
But you can come with me...
and let the Vandersexxx begin.
? " Marijuana in my soul " ?
? " Your iguana in my hall " ?
I can't believe
we're doing this.
Don't worry.
Hash brownies are totally legal here.
You're gonna enjoy these, man.
These are magical.
" I like to smoke marijuana "
- You wanna do this?
- Yeah.
- Hi.
I need a new battery for my camera,
and while you're at it,
it could use a cleaning.
Wow.
Is that a Leica M6?
Actually, it's an M7.
It's got the built-in light meter.
It's so beautiful.
So sleek, so powerful.
How's the new lens system?
Makes the Nikon
look like a disposable.
You really know your cameras.
And you're very cute.
Me? Really?
I'm going on break.
I was going to step out back
and have a cigarette.
Would you like to join me?
I don't smoke.
Neither do I.
Hold on, hold on.
What is it?
This is great!
You're so innocent.
Let's change that... shall we?
What would you like me to do?
Well... I don't really know...
I guess I really
haven't done that much.
I haven't really found the time,
with all my extracurriculars,
and model U.N., advanced placement
classes, after-school tutor...
...ing! Ah!
Gosh, you really like cameras!
Sometimes, we find our clients are
so overwhelmed with the pleasure,
that they sometimes scream out,"no,"
when really they mean,"yes."
And this is why we have the safe word.
The "safe word"?
If at any time the ecstasy
gets too great,
you just use the safe word.
Until we hear the safe word,
we will not stop.
Yeah, right. Stop.
All right.
We're going to start slowly,
teasing you with a little
light erotic foreplay.
Whee!
Oh, yes, ladies!
On, on, vandersexxx!
Hans! Gruber!
Hi.
So, are the girls coming back?
Administer the testicle clamps!
- Huh? What? Hey!
Safe word!
What is that?!
That's not a word, it's a...
"Fluggen-kliggin-kien?"
Fluggen!!!
OK, mister, don't move.
- Excuse me?
Shut the hell up!
Oh, brother! Please don't hurt me.
Oh, no... you're fine.
That's good. You're fine.
Give me cash? You got cash?
Take it all, you dirty girl.
What?
Your wallet! Focus!
- Give it to me.
- Oh!
Oh, I love you!
I love you!
I love you! I looove you!
What's so funny?
I'm really hungry.
I think I've got the munchies.
- Excuse me.
- Huh?
It's hot in here. You hot?
'Cause I'm really hot.
- So good.
- OK, I can't breathe! God!
Tao diên lên dây!
I think we got
a bad batch 'cause I'm freaking out.
I can't... I can't do this.
I saw a gay porno once.
I didn't know until halfway in.
The girls never came.
The girls never came!
I am freaking out!!
- Everything all right with you?
- No, nothing's all right.
You sold us a bad batch
of ash brownies.
You're a bad Rastafarian.
These are not ash brownies.
Hmm?
- What was that?
- We do not sell hash brownies.
We're a simple Dutch bakery!
Now put your clothes back on, white boy!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
"Fluggengegeholen!"
Did you say fluggegecheimen?
Yes! Yes!
For the love of god,
fluggengecheimen!
Are you sure?
Yes, please.
As you wish.
Bring on
the fluggegecheimen!
Wait... what?
Uh-oh.
No, no, no!
I didn't say fluggegecheimen,
I said, uh...
What'd you do last night?
I don't want to talk about it.
What did you guys do?
Don't want to talk about it.
- What is that?
- Free T-shirt.
Hey, guys.
What happened to you?
I got robbed.
It was awesome!
Our money, passports, tickets...
Everything, gone!
How the hell could this happen?
We all go to Amsterdam, and
Jamie's the one who hooks up!
For shame!
Oh, that's me.
Coop here. Sorry.
Hello, Mr. Walters..
You never got the Gutterman file?
I told Humphrey to give it to you.
That's hogwash. I handed it
to him myself yesterday.
I'll tell Humphrey to report
to your office immediately.
Bye.
This job's killing me.
- Uh...
- Let me handle this.
I speak bad German.
- What did he say?
- He said he's driving.
- Oh.
- Something.
Jah.
Berlin?
Berlin!
- He's going to Berlin!
- Awesome!
- All right! Berlin!
- Come on, let's go!
Next stop, Berlin!
Beautiful!
We made it to Berlin.
Jah. Berlin!
- Bratislava?
- Yeah.
Bratislava!
Dear sweet mother of God.
We're in Eastern Europe.
Eww!
Excuse me.
Do you speak any English?
You are Americans?
Yeah.
I love America.
We just get "Miami Vice" on television.
Amen!
"Miami Vice" is number one new show.
Yeah.
Listen, we're trying
to get to Berlin, Germany.
Do you know if there's
a train coming anytime soon?
Oh, yes, very soon.
They are building it now.
Stop! Hammer time!
Enjoy Bratislava!
It's good you came in summer.
In winter, it can get very depressing.
We gotta figure something out.
How much money do we have?
Frommer's travel tip.
I don't have anything.
What? I got noth... fine.
$1.83 American.
What are we gonna get with that?
Gotta love that exchange rate!
Ta.
Dinner is served
Would the masters care
for anything else?
Think we're good. Thanks.
Ah! A nickel!
You see this?
- I quit!
I open my own hotel!
So, we got 27 cents left.
What is there to do in this town?
? - " My Scotty "
- " Scotty, Scotty " ?
? " Scotty doesn't know " ?
? " Don't tell Scotty " ?
? - " Scotty doesn't know " ?
This song sounds familiar.
Jenny, lemme check your coat.
- Hey!
- Jenny!
That outfit is horrible!
Just take it off... now!
No, but I will let you
buy me a drink.
Excuse me!
You are the woman from the Paris
train station, aren't you?
- My name is...
- Christoph.
Yes.
What are you doing here?
This is my place. My family owns
many nightclubs in Europe.
I'd be honored if you'd join me
in my V.I.P.Room for a drink.
Mmm-kay.
Bye, Cooper.
- What's that?
- It's absinthe.
Frommer's says it's
illegal in the States
because it makes you
hallucinate and go crazy.
They call it "the green fairy."
My family has a yacht in the Aegean.
Come with me, Jennifer.
We will sail away together.
Oh, my God!
We will swim with dolphins,
and sip champagne by moonlight.
Oh, my God!
We will spend the day
sunbathing, drinking wine.
My wife makes the best sangria.
Wait... what?
Sangria.
You take a good Spanish Rioja,
and you put in slices of orange, and...
No, wait.
You said you were married?
You go around Europe
sleeping with every woman you meet?
No, please, Jennifer.
It is not like that.
I also sleep with men.
I gotta say, I'm not feeling anything.
Me neither.
Sober as a judge.
How 'bout you?
Tôi ch?ng c?m th?y chó gì.
This absinthe is bullshit!
I hear you, my brother.
I'm outta here.
Excuse me.
- Hey, so where's Christoph?
- Shut up.
- Europe!
- Whoo!
So, tomorrow, Berlin.
Tomorrow, Mieke!
Check it out.
No way!
Jamie's hooking up with another girl?
Goddamn it!
It's just so unfair.
I've been all over,
looking for crazy European sex,
and he's the one who ends up getting...
- Oh, my God!
That is some pretty fucked-up shit.
They really are the worst twins ever.
(Both screaming)
That was a pretty wild night, eh?
Yep. Pretty wild, pretty wild.
I know I was out of control.
How about you guys?
Did you...?
All right, look.
We were really drunk,
và làm vài vi?c diên r?,
và Jamie...
kissed me.
Let's just forget about it, 'kay?
OK, fine. I'll give it a rest.
Jamie, could I borrow your Frommer's?
Oh, here it is. Bratislava.
Hmm. Capital of Slovakia.
Oh, here's a fun fact.
You made out with your sister, man!
- Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
- Like two dogs in heat.
My friends, where is the beef?
You go to Berlin?
I'm your ride.
Hop in.
" "99 Red Balloons"
Okay. This is Mieke's
apartment building.
Wish me all sorts of luck, guys.
You'll do great, Scotty.
Thanks.
I came all this way.
I'm not gonna miss this.
- Dude, Mieke's hideous! Run!
- Stop.
Hi, my name is Scott Thomas.
I'm from America,
and I'm here to see Mieke.
I'm sorry, but Mieke's not here.
Do you know where she is?
She's gone for the summer.
My daughter had intended
to spend the summer in America,
looking at colleges
visiting some friends.
But several days ago,
she suddenly changed her mind.
She would not tell me why.
I think I know why.
This is Heinrich.
He's Mieke's stepbrother.
As I was saying,
she packed up her bag and left.
- It was all very sudden.
- Do you know where she is now?
As you know she's always been
very interested in the classics,
Greek and Roman literature, history,
and she's always enjoyed the ocean,
so she found a program that
combines all her interests.
Do you know where she is?
She enrolled in a summer at sea
program, based in Rome.
Rome.
OK, then I guess we'll go to Rome, then.
Well hold on. Unfortunately, Mieke's only
in Rome for orientation.
Tomorrow her group boards a boat
and she'll be gone for the summer.
And she'll be quite unreachable.
Unreachable.
Mieke's tour group goes
to the Vatican tomorrow,
then she gets on that boat
and she's gone.
So, it's over?
Hey! Thanks for sticking with me
through this, guys, but...
you should probably call your parents,
have them wire you
some money and go home.
What are you gonna do?
I'm going to Rome.
I'll walk, I'll hitchhike,
I'll swim if I have to,
but I'll get to Mieke somehow.
Maybe that'll help.
Where'd you get all that?
Wait. Where's your Leica?
Sold it.
What?
You sold your Leica?
But you loved that thing.
What about your photo tour of Europe?
What about the chateaus?
Chateaus have been there
for 300 years.
Mieke's gone in 12 hours.
Come on let's go! Frommer's says you're supposed to
check in three
hours before international flights.
Come here, guidebook!
Whoo! We're going to Rome.
We're going to Rome!
? " Be my girl " ?
? " Are you gonna be my " ?
? " Girl, yeah " ?
? " Be my girl " ?
? " Are you gonna be my girl " ?
All right, summer at sea group.
Our tour begins in the Vatican museum.
This way, please.
There it is.
This entrance is
for private tour groups only.
Oh... but we are
a private tour group.
We've come all the way from America.
That guy in the orange jacket
is mentally retarded.
Si, I can tell.
How very, very sad.
Yes, it is.
But if you are a tour,
where is your guide?
We've got a fantastic tour guide.
- Right here.
- What? No...
The Vatican has been used
as a papal residence
ever since the time
of Constantine the Great
the Great in the 5th century A.D.!
Let them in
OK... um... if you'll
all follow me, please.
Have a very special day
for a very special little man.
OK.
I can't believe that guy let us in.
What a retard!
- Okay. Let's find Mieke.
- Scusate.
One of our English-speaking
tour guides has called in sick.
Could you please take
these peoples also?
- How big is Vatican City?
- 0.5 square kilometers.
- Who built the colonnades?
- Gianlorenzo Bernini, 1656.
- Where are the bathrooms?
- Floors 2,6 and 7.
Next I'll take you to where the
College of Cardinals elects a new pope.
When this happens, white smoke
is sent up from the Vatican.
- Here's a fun fact...
- Mieke must be around here somewhere.
Ði nào.
Behind me is the appartamento papale,
or "papal apartment."
We're obviously not permitted.
Excuse me, miss. What is this?
That is the bell of San Marco.
When the pope dies,
the Cardinal Vicar of Rome
rings this bell to notify
the people of Rome.
Next we will view the Sistine Chapel.
Follow me, please.
Come on. I think I hear them.
Which way did they go?
That way. I'd stake
my reputation on it.
Good enough for me.
Hey, check it out!
I wonder what this does.
It doesn't do anything,
it's a rope. Come on, let's go.
They got a lot
of old stuff here.
Dio mio!
The bell of San Marco!
The pope is dead!
Whoa.
She's not in here.
Ði thôi. Chúng ta không th? ? dây lâu.
Hey, check this out!
- I'm the pope!
- Cooper...
take off the pope hat.
- Oh, no. It's OK.I'm catholic.
- Take it off, goddamnit!
Oh, you took
the Lord's name in vain!
Only I can forgive
you now, my son.
Take that fudging thing off!
The pope breaks an open-field tackle.
It's a Hail Mary,
he catches at the 40...
th? 30, th? 20, th? 10...
S? th? di!
The pope makes a two-point conversion.
oh, my Lord!
It's the Pope, eight,
and the heathens, nothing!
nothing!
How's you, sucka?
Cooper, the hat! The hat!
The hat is on fire!
" We don't need no water
let the m... "
I'm not kidding! Look!
Oh, holy shit!
I don't want this!
Fireplace! Fireplace!
Go, go!
Whoa!
White smoke!
They've elected the new pope!
I'm coming to you live
from Vatican Square
where the College of Cardinals,
in a surprise move,
has just elected a new pope.
The crowd is very excited.
This is so strange.
Usually they wait 15 days
to elect a new pope.
We could be seeing
history in the making!
We could be seeing an arrest
in the making.
There she is. Mieke!
Hey! Stupid curtain!
Let me out!
Mieke!
It's the new pope!
What the hell...?
Mieke!
Hold on!
This is one crazy pope.
You!
Ferma! Stop! You!
You... and your retarded friend,
you're in big, big trouble.
Oy!
Take your mitts off them boys!
They're with me!
I've just about had enough
of you fuckin' ities!
But I am Swiss!
Them, too!
Now, bud...
you get in there, and you
say what you got to say.
Mieke. I'm here.
I made it.
Who are you?
What a fucking loser!
I'm gonna videotape this.
I'm Scott.
From Ohio?
Scott? Scott Thomas?
- Yes.
- From Ohio?
- What are you doing in Rome?
- I came here to be with you.
Listen, I just traveled
all the way across Europe.
I got chased by naked men.
I ate brownies with absolutely
no drugs in them.
I watched a brother
and sister make out.
I kicked a robot in the balls,
but I did it all so that...
so I could tell you one thing.
I love you, Mieke.
Aww...
We're perfect for each other.
What do you think?
I think...
Oh, Mike... Mieke!
Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
I have cheated on my husband.
Do you think God will ever forgive me?
Oh, yes!
- Father?
This sucks.
I can't believe I'm the only one
who didn't hook up while we were here.
Europe is officially
the worst country on Earth.
I know.
I thought I'd at least get to
have some crazy European sex.
What?
- Scott, I have to go.
- OK.
My boat is leaving.
I still can't believe
you came all the way here,
just for me.
What can I say?
I'm very unpredictable.
Keep writing to me, Scott, OK?
Yeah, I will.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, guys, I'm so glad we got
to take this trip together.
This was the best time of my life.
Excuse me.
You're the young man who gave me
that tour of the Vatican, aren't you?
- Listen, I'm very sorry...
- I just wanted to thank you.
You were the most knowledgeable,
albeit idiosyncratic,
tour guide I've ever had.
Thanks.
But I'm not actually a tour guide.
I've just read Frommer's
enough to have it memorized.
Although I threw in a few things
Frommer's didn't know about.
How would you like to add them?
Excuse me?
That's my guidebook.
I'm Arthur Frommer.
Ng?c nhiên chua!
Frommer's is going to pay me to see
every museum and cathedral in Europe.
tu?ng dài ? châu Âu.
- That sounds so exciting...
for you.
I figured, since you're
going to be staying,
you might need this.
- A disposable camera.
- That's right.
Thanks, Scotty.
That's from both of us.
Scotty doesn't know
Hello, Mr. Walters.
I see.
Fired? Well, I...
Well, if that's what you want,
I understand. I just...
goodbye, sir.
They had to catch you
eventually, right?
- No, they fired Humphrey.
- Shut up!
I got his office and a raise.
- No!
Flight 341
from Rome to Cleveland...
That's you guys.
- Have a good flight, everybody.
- Come here.
Be good.
- Oh! OK...
- Cooper, have a good flight.
- Be good.
Thanks.
I'm on it.
This still
counts as Europe, right?
"Dear Mieke,
"Greece sounds incredible.
"I just moved into my dorm room today,
"but I can't wait to see you
over Christmas break.
"This time I think
I'll fly to Berlin direct."
- Hello?
- Hey, buddy, how's college?
I just got here. My roommate
hasn't even showed up yet.
Do they room all you
pre-med geeks together?
I'm not sure I'm going pre-med.
I'm thinking about majoring in German.
German? I've got a better idea.
Why don't you major
in not being such a woman?
So, how's Jenny?
Jenny... Jenny who?
I know a lot of ladies
named Jenny, they're all...
Ow!
Hey, Scotty, what's up?
Hi, Jenny!
Have you heard from Jamie?
How's he doing with Frommer?
Oh, no.
Hold on.
Come here, robot!
Cooper, not again!
Hold on, this could be
my new roommate.
What's the freak look like?
Is he a dork or is he cool?
Better not be cooler than me.
Is he bigger than me?
I just got your last email.
What are you doing here?
Going to college.
You're going to college here?
- What dorm?
- This one.
Room 214.
How is this possible?
I guess they thought I was a guy.
Now who would be dumb enough
to make a mistake like that?
Do I hear kissing?
Are you making out with
your new roommate, Scotty?
Scotty?
Scotty? Scotty!
" Scotty doesn't know
that Fiona and me "
This happy ending is bullshit.
When does the fairy get laid?
I'm outta here.
" Still she's on her knees
And Scotty doesn't know "
" Oh, Scotty doesn't know "
- Catchy tune.
- Fuckin'-a, man.
" Fiona says she's out shopping "
" But she's under me
And I'm not stopping "
Scotty doesn't know!
Hello
and welcome to Amsterdam's finest and most
luxurious youth hostel.
Sounds great.
There is no bathroom,
nor is there one nearby.
" I can't believe
He's so trusting "
" While I'm right behind you thrusting "
- Get it?
- She got it.
If you do not wish to have
your valuables stolen,
I suggest destroying them
or discarding them right now.
You can also try hiding
your valuables...
in your anus.
Drink?
I'm gonna rip away his pants
and look at his dick, OK?
- Ready? Quit. Shut up.
Sorry. I know I fucked it up.
Yes! You take her hair...
and one strand at a time,
pull it out!
Use her like a humping post!
Jenny, this is Europe.
They have orange juice ads
with lesbians and dildos.
"Happy juice."
You gotta show them something they haven't seen.
? " Fiona's got him on the phone " ?
? " And she's trying not to moan " ?
? " It's a three Way call
And he knows nothing " ?
? " Nothing, Scotty doesn't know " ?
? " Scotty doesn't know
Scotty doesn't know " ?
? Should a fire occur,
due to our faulty wiring, ?
? or the fireworks factory upstairs,
you will be incinerated, ?
? along with the valuables
you have hidden in your anus. ?
? " So don't tell Scotty
Scotty doesn't know " ?
? " Really want to go " ?
? " Scotty doesn't know
Scotty doesn't know " ?
? " Scotty doesn't know " ?
? " The parking lot, why not? " ?
? " It's so cool when you're on top " ?
" Life is so hard
'Cause Scotty doesn't know "
" Scotty doesn't know "
Fuck off! Get out of it, you wankers!
Go on, you gaelic fucking
garlic-breath tossers!
Piss off! Get in here
and say that, mate!
Come on! Fucking come and have it!
You fucking beep?!
We'll beep, you bastard,
all over your fucking nose!
Fuck off!
Go on, you French bastards!
Get on the other side
of the road, you pricks!
Go on out of it!
Fuck off!
I'm nackered.
League supporters.
" Scotty doesn't know
Scotty doesn't know "
- No, wait...
Hey! Check these out!
I'm 18 years old.
? " Gonna tell Scotty
Gonna tell myself " ?
? " Scotty has to know
Scotty has to know " ?
? " Scotty has to
Scotty has to go " ?
? " Scotty doesn't know
Scotty doesn't know " ?
? " Scotty doesn't Scotty doesn't Scotty doesn't..." ?
? Scotty doesn't know!
Scotty doesn't know! ?
? Scotty's gotta go! ?
Is it off yet?
No. Keep rubbing it.