Oh, this is great.
Wow!
That's incredible.
There's got to be
7 or 8 feet up there.
And 80 years of dust.
Look at all this height.
With our bedroom upstairs,
we'd have all this space.
For what?
Just space.
1 ...
2...
3!
And 4?
And 5?
Watch it. Watch it.
God, this place
is huge.
Wow.
It's beautiful.
God!
You guys, it's
absolutely incredible.
Incredible.
A little paint,
you could sell this tomorrow
and double your money.
Carl, you're obsessed.
A little bit.
Whoa, look!
Hey, it's
an Indian head penny.
1 898.
It's a good omen.
You're the good omen.
Oh, it's so great.
I had Rose
move your 3:00 to 4:00.
Gary Allen called
late yesterday.
He has to see you
about the final painting bids
for the loft.
3:00 is the only time
he can make it.
[Mumbling
In Japanese]
Sam?
Huh? Oh, I'm sorry.
Relax. This isn't brain surgery
you're going into.
Pitching these Japanese guys
makes me so nervous.
Sam...
you're going
to be great, OK?
What am I
supposed to say?
I can't tell them
my Swedish pompom girl joke,
you know.
Those are great.
Where'd you get those?
Nice, huh? Molly.
What do you think?
Are they me?
Man, look at that.
A Testarossa.
Whoa.
Ouch.
Pay off
your Mustang first.
[Coughs]
How are you feeling?
What did
the doctor say?
He said
it was contagious,
that it was really...
No.
He said I shouldn't
be coming in today.
What about the rash?
The rash?
Mm-hmm.
The rash is, um...
also incredibly
contagious.
He said they've
both been spreading.
No.
On your genitals
again?
Yeah.
Yeah, right on
the genitals.
Basically everywhere.
He said that I
shouldn't touch anyone.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
You're sick.
I know.
Morning, Paul.
Morning,
Carl, Sam.
Hey, Paul.
Morning, Mr. Wheat.
Morning, Susan.
You're looking good.
Sam?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Here it is.
Thanks.
Morning, Sam.
Morning. Listen,
the Kobiashi people--
They're already here.
They're early.
I know.
Come here. How long
have they been here?
About 1 0 minutes.
Andy Dillon called
and says he needs $900,000
transferred to Albany by 1 0:00.
By 1 0:00?
Yes.
Carl?
Yeah?
Dillon needs 900,000
in Albany by 1 0:00.
Can you transfer it
to his payroll account?
I'll need your Mac code.
OK.
Discretion, right?
Got it.
You bet.
I'll do it right now.
Bill, I'll call you back.
OK, OK, that's fine.
That's fine.
That's fine!
Aw, man,
it's too far out.
Can you
get this, man?
Where
are you guys from,
the New York City Ballet?
Almost.
Oh!
Saved your life!
You shit.
You scared me to death.
Why'd you do that?
It's better than seeing
this gorgeous body
splattered
all over the place.
Look out.
Sam? Molly?
You guys home?
Did you invite Carl?
Slave labor.
-Carl?
-What?
Hurry. Help.
Oh, my God.
Grab the bottom.
Want this down here?
Right here?
Watch your toes.
Where do you want this?
Uh, in the bedroom.
God, this place
looks great.
Yeah.
You like it, huh?
Like is hardly
the word.
I didn't know it would be
this beautiful.
Molly, what about her?
Leave her there
until we get the rest in.
What are these?
Oh, let me show you.
Help me
lift this up.
Here?
Voila!
Wow.
What do you think?
It's fantastic.
I love it.
Sam, what's
this chair doing here?
What do you mean?
I love that chair.
I know, but we
discussed this...
I've had it forever.
When I watch TV,
I sit in it.
This chair is ugly.
So?
And it doesn't go
with anything.
It goes with me.
You're right.
It does.
We'll paint it.
We'll what?
[Cat Meows]
Are you OK?
Mm-hmm. I'm fine.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
You worried
about the promotion?
No, not really.
Then what?
Is it moving in
together?
No.
I don't know.
It's...
a lot of things.
I just don't want
the bubble to burst.
Seems like, uh...
whenever anything good
in my life happens,
I'm just afraid
I'm going to lose it.
I love you.
I really love you.
Ditto.
The pilot
first reported trouble
when the number two
engine blew,
the one in the tail
of the plane...
Oh,Jesus,
another one?
Oh, don't watch that.
I should cancel
my L.A. trip.
These things always
happen in threes.
Sam, get serious.
Besides, you lead
a charmed life.
Oh, yeah?
So did they.
It's amazing.
Just like that.
Blackout.
Oh
My love
My darlin'
I've hungered for...
What are you doing?
I couldn't sleep.
A long
Lonely time
I must
have passed out.
What time is it?
It's 2 a.m.
And time
Goes by
So slowly
And time
Can do so much
Are you
Still mine
Oh, no.
I hope it wasn't
a masterpiece.
It's not now.
Can I help?
Yeah.
Put your hands here
and get them wet.
Just let the clay
slide between your fingers.
Godspeed your love
To me
Lonely rivers flow
To the sea
To the open arms
Of the sea
Yeah
Lonely rivers sigh
Wait for me
I'll be comin'home
Oh
My love
My darlin'
I've hungered
Hungered for your touch
A long
Lonely time
And time
Goes by
So slowly
And time
Can do so much
Are you
Still mine
I need
Your love
I
I need your love
Godspeed your love
To me 렁
Oh, no.
What's the matter?
A glitch.
What's up?
The Greenberg and White accounts--
I can't get in.
The Mac code
isn't working.
Oh, I changed it.
Why?
Nothing. I want to
nose around a bit.
Is something wrong?
Can you keep a secret?
Yeah, sure.
What's up?
There's too much money
in these accounts.
Too much money?
That's impossible.
Sam, this is going
to take you hours.
Let me do this.
It's already
taken me hours.
Let me figure it out.
No, that's OK.
It's like
a vendetta now.
Thanks, though.
I appreciate it.
OK.
If you start to go blind,
give a shout.
OK. Adios.
Listen, what are you
and Moll doing tonight?
We're going to the theater
to see Macbeth.
She likes
the guys in tights.
You want to go?
No, thanks.
I want a full
report, though.
Later.
Yeah.
Well, I loved it.
I was spellbound
the whole time.
I could tell.
So could
everyone else
with that resonating
snore of yours.
Did I tell you
what Melissa said?
Yeah, about six times.
It wasn't six times.
Quit being
so blase about this.
This is really
important.
I'll have two pieces
in her gallery.
The New York Times
reviews her gallery all the time.
Molly,
The New York Times
is just some
frustrated little critic
with pimples on his ass
who flunked art school.
Who cares what they think?
About eight million
readers, that's who.
Nah, they're just
reading the sports page.
Your work
is really beautiful.
It really is.
Thanks.
It shouldn't matter
what anyone else thinks,
just what I think.
I want
to marry you, Sam.
What?
Yep.
I've been
thinking about it.
I've been thinking
about it a lot,
and I think we
should just do it.
You're serious.
Yeah.
What's that look for?
You never wanted
to talk about it.
Do you love me, Sam?
Well, what do you think?
Why don't you
ever say it?
What do you mean?
I say it all the time.
No, you say ''ditto,''
and that's
not the same.
People say I love you
all the time,
and it doesn't
mean anything.
You know, sometimes
you need to hear it.
I need to hear it.
Let's go.
What should we do?
Let me handle it.
What do you want?
Your wallet--
give it to me!
Sam, just give it to him.
OK, just take the money.
Just leave--
No, Sam--
You son of a bitch!
Sam, don't!
Somebody help us!
Jesus Christ, Sam!
Just get off him.
Somebody!
Somebody help us!
Sam, just let...
Sam, stop it.
Stop it, Sam!
[Gunshot]
Molly?
Molly, he got--
Sam...
Baby, hold on.
You're going
to be OK.
Somebody?
Somebody help us!
Oh, Sam.
Oh, my God.
Oh, Sam, come on.
Hold on, baby.
Someone's going to come.
You're going to be OK.
Somebody!
Somebody help me!
Please, anybody!
Help me. Please help me.
Take it easy, all right?
We'll help you, OK?
Molly? Molly?
Molly?
OK.
All right.
Molly?
What should we do?
Aah!
What's happening?
What's...
Is he breathing?
I don't know
if he's breathing.
Don't die, Sam.
Hold on.
Hold on, baby.
Oh, my God.
Come on, man.
All right.
Here we go.
1 ...
Come on, baby.
Sam, don't you leave me.
Sam, hold on!
Sam...
Oh, Sam...
Jesus...
Miss Jensen, if you'll just step
this way, please.
So, what happened
to you?
What?
You're new, huh?
I could tell.
Are you talking to me?
Relax. It ain't
like before.
It's a whole new
ball of wax.
Who are you?
I'm waiting
for my wife.
She's in the cardiac wing.
She's fighting it.
Shot, huh?
That'll do it every time.
Poor bastard.
You may as well
get used to it.
You could be here
for a long while.
Come here.
I'll tell you a secret.
Doors ain't so bad.
Zip, zap--
they ain't nothing.
You'll see.
You'll catch on.
This patient's fibrillating.
Let's move it.
Give me
the paddles.
He ain't
going to make it.
I've seen it
a million times.
He's a goner.
He's still
fibrillating.
Clear.
You see?
Here they come.
Lucky bastard.
It could have been
the other ones.
You never know.
Who are--
No!
Aah!
God help me.
Oh, God...
help me.
''I am sunk
in the abysmal swamp
where there is no foothold.
I have reached
the watery depths.
The flood overwhelms me.
I am wearied with calling.''
As we say farewell
to our friend Sam Wheat,
we are reminded
of his kindness...
his generosity,
his buoyancy of spirit.
All that we treasure--
our loved ones,
our friends,
our body,
our mind--
are but on loan to us.
We must
surrender them all.
We are all travelers
on the same road,
which leads
to the same end.
As our loved one
enters eternal life,
let us remember
that love, too, is eternal.
That although
we will miss him,
our love
will light the void
and dispel the darkness.
I picked up
your shirts today.
I don't know why.
Mr. Reynolds told me
to tell you hello.
I broke into tears.
It's like I think
about you every minute.
It's like
I can still feel you.
I'm here, Moll.
[Hisses]
[Meowwr]
Floyd, what's
the matter, kitty?
What's the matter?
Crazy cat.
Sam?
That's really
stupid.
I love this picture.
It's great.
Office.
Let me see that.
It's, um...
Sam's address book.
Right.
Dave Brubeck.
Newport, '88.
Should I toss
them?
No.
No? Molly, we hated
that concert.
Hey.
Oh. You wanted
to save those?
Rolaids?
Molly, what
are you doing?
I just miss him,
Carl.
Me, too.
Carl?
Yeah?
Wait a minute.
Wait.
What?
Not that one.
Which? Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to put
that on there.
That's OK.
Hey, Moll,
why don't you come?
It's like summer
outside.
No, I'm really
not up for it.
Just for a walk.
I don't want to.
You can't stay in
all day.
It's not healthy.
Carl, I can't do it!
Molly, you're not
the one who died.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
Shit.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe
just a short one.
That a girl.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Molly!
What are you
doing here?
You bastard.
You son of a bitch!
What do you want?
-[Door Opening]
-Molly?
Molly, get out!
Oh, my God.
No, Molly! Look,
no, no, please!
Molly!
Molly,
he's got a gun!
[Meow]
Hi, kitty. Hi.
You hurt her--
Aah!
Shit!
Is somebody there?
Hello?
Oh, my God!
Let go!
What are you doing?
[Subway Horn
Blows]
Aah!
Like trains?
Stay out! This is mine!
[Horn Blows]
Shit.
[Dialing Telephone]
It's me.
I couldn't get it.
She came home.
Give me a couple
of days, man.
I'll go back.
Relax.
I'll get it.
Get what?
Who are you?
What do you
want from us?
No.
You stay away
from her.
Do you hear me?
Stay away from her!
[Gospel Music Playing]
And...
teddy bear, teddy bear,
turn around,
teddy bear,
touch
the ground.
Rosa Santiago?
Please
be seated.
Our sister will be
with us soon.
Sister Oda Mae,
grant us the gift of
your all-seeing presence.
Appear before us
now.
Mrs. Santiago?
Buenos dias.
I'm Oda Mae Brown.
I understand you wish
to contact your husband.
Si.
I believe
he'll be with us today.
Thank you.
But you know,
Mrs. Santiago,
there's no telling
about that other world,
so you've got to be
a believer, Mrs. Santiago.
Are you a believer?
Si. Si, I believe.
I believe.
Then let us begin.
[Grunting]
I can't.
It's too difficult.
I can't make contact.
I don't feel his vi--
No, wait!
I'm feeling something.
Did he know someone
by the name of Anna?
Consuelo?
Lucita?
Julietta?
Josefina? Linda?
Maria?
iSi! His mama!
She is Maria!
Yes! Praise God, I knew
he was with his mama.
Oh, my God.
It's too difficult.
It's two of them.
I'm not sure
I can do that.
It's so trying.
Oh, I pay more.
How much?
$20.
Way to go. Milk her
for every penny.
Huh. Yes, I...I believe
we can start again.
- Praise the Lord.
- Thank you,Jesus.
Welcome, Mrs. Santiago.
You're fortunate today.
The spirits are churning.
My husband?
Have mercy!
Oh, yeah? Where?
Julio?
Yes!
I feel his vibration.
Ooh!
I see him!
How is he?
How does he look?
Oh, he's a handsome man.
Handsome?
Mrs. Santiago,
in Our Father's kingdom,
we're all handsome.
Oh,Julio.
Julio's
coming towards us.
I see him! He's coming!
He's there!
He's dressed
in a black suit.
Black suit?
It could be blue.
What a crock of shit.
Who is that?
Julio! Where are you?
Julio? Julio?
Did you hear it?
Damn!
Where are you?
Julio?
Who are you?
Whoa!
You can hear me?
Don't you hear him?
I don't believe this.
Hey, you,
my name's Sam Wheat.
Can you hear me?
Sam Wheat. Say my name.
Leave me alone!
Say it! Sam Wheat!
Talk to me, Oda Mae.
Say something!
Sam Wheat!
Jesus.
- Sam Wheat?
I swear,
no more cheating.
I'll do anything.
I'll do penance,
but make that guy
go away!
No way.
Aah!
It's OK.
All right, sister.
Thank you.
Yeah, you're
all right.
My mother
and my mother's mother
both had the gift.
They always said I had it,
but I never did.
I never had it.
They told me
all about it.
But now that I got it,
I don't think I want it.
Go away.
Find somebody else.
Somebody else?
You're out of your mind.
I'm getting there fast.
She hit her head
harder than we think.
She was talking to nobody
before she hit her head.
Sister can do that.
Where exactly are you?
Standing
right beside you.
Well, honey,
we're right here.
Are you white?
What?
White?
You're white,
aren't you?
Know what I think?
I'll call the doctor
right now.
I knew it.
A white guy. Why me?
Listen, damn it.
You're going to help me.
There's a woman
named Molly Jensen.
She's in terrible danger.
The man who killed me
broke into our apartment,
and he's going
to go back.
You've got
to warn her.
What makes you think
she'll listen to me?
It's just a phone call.
Look...
you're all I've got.
Now, I'm not leaving
until you help me.
I don't care
how long it takes,
'cause I can talk
forever.
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
Hello?
Uh, hi. Is this
Molly Jensen?
Yes.
My name's
Oda Mae Brown.
I'm a spiritual reader
and advisor.
A friend of yours gave me
a message for you.
I know this sounds crazy,
but it's not.
You got to believe me.
Just don't be afraid.
Who is this?
I got a message
from Sam.
What?
Sam Wheat?
He asked me to call.
[Click]
I told you.
Go there.
Forget it.
I'm not going anywhere.
I don't care
what you do.
Second verse
Same as the first
I'm 'En-er-y the Eighth
I am
'En-er-y the Eighth
I am, I am
I got married
to the widow next door
She's been married
seven times before
And ev'ry one
was an 'En-er-y
'En-er-y
Wouldn't have
a Willy or a Sam
No, sir
I'm her eighth old man
I'm 'En-er-y
'En-er-y the Eighth
I am, I am
I am
Second verse
Same as the first
I'm 'En-er-y the Eighth
I am
'En-er-y the Eighth
I am, I am
I got married
to the widow next door-- 렁
All right! All right!
Stop singing!
I'll go anywhere
you want to,
just don't sing anymore.
I can't believe this.
I can't believe
I'm doing this.
What am I doing
down here?
I never come downtown.
I hate downtown.
She's probably
not even there.
Where are you?
Oh.
Woof.
Which building is it?
Uh, push 3.
[Buzzer Beeps]
See? Nobody's there.
She's there.
Just wait.
I did everything
I said I'd do.
I pressed
the button.
She's not there.
I'm going.
99 bottles of beer
on the wall
Take one down
Pass it around-- 렁
Don't sing, all right?
[Molly]
Hello?
Molly--
Shh! She can't hear you.
Hi, I'm Oda Mae.
I called you about
your friend Sam Wheat?
[Click]
I told you.
Hey, Molly!
Molly Jensen.
I know you're up there.
I know you hear me.
I'm down here.
Sam wants to talk to you.
This is for real.
Remember the starfish
in Montego Bay?
How would I know that
if he wasn't here?
Hey, Molly, I know
about the green underwear
that you wrote
your name on.
I'd never get over that,
I tell you that.
I know about
the picture in Reno.
Hey, Molly!
Ask her about the sweater
she knitted in the closet
that's too big.
He asked me to remind you
of the sweater in the closet
that you knitted
that's too big.
Four sizes.
Hey, you hear me
talking to you?
I hear you.
Shut up. Nobody's
talking to you.
Ever hear of a phone?
Want to kiss my butt?
I'm not staying
down here all day.
Thank God.
Aw, man, shut up.
Molly! I'm going
to count to 3,
and I'm out of here.
1 , 2, 3.
No, Oda, wait.
No.
It's Molly.
Molly?
I'm Oda Mae Brown.
I don't know you or Sam,
but let me tell you
what he did.
He kept me up all night
singing I'm Henry
The Eighth, I Am.
That's how he got me
to go out with him.
Look, I'm sorry.
I just--
I just don't believe
in this life
after death stuff.
Well, tell her
she's wrong.
He says
you're wrong.
You're talking to him
right now?
He just asked me to tell you
that you're wrong.
So where is he?
I can't see him.
I can only hear him.
I'm right here.
That doesn't help,
Sam.
I'm holding
her hand.
He says he's
holding your hand.
What are you doing?
What do you think
you're doing to me?
If you think I'm here for
my health, you're crazy.
Sam's dead, OK?
He's dead.
Tell her
I love her.
He says
he loves you.
Sam would
never say that.
Say ditto.
What the hell
is ditto?
Ditto!
To tell you
the truth,
I don't know how
I'm doing this.
Confidentially,
nothing like this
has ever happened
to me before.
I mean, nothing.
Now I can't
turn it off.
Is this him?
Is this you?
- Yeah.
Huh. Cute.
White,
but cute.
What I don't
understand is,
why did he come back?
I don't know.
Why is he
still here?
He's stuck,
that's what it is.
He's in between
worlds.
You know,
it happens sometimes
that the spirit gets
yanked out so quick
that the essence
still feels
it has work to do.
Would you stop rambling?
I'm just answering
her question.
He's got
an attitude now.
I don't have an attitude.
Yes, you do
have an attitude.
We're having
a little discussion.
If you didn't have
a attitude,
you wouldn't have
raised your voice.
God damn it,
Oda Mae--
Don't you god damn me.
Don't you take
the Lord's name in vain.
Would you relax?
You relax.
You're the dead guy.
Want me to help?
You apologize.
Jesus Christ!
I'm leaving.
Nobody talks to me like that,
you understand?
Now, you better
apologize.
I'm sorry.
I apologize.
OK?
Now, would you
sit down?
Please?
He's apologized.
I need you to tell
Molly what I'm saying,
but you have to tell her
word for word.
Yes. He wants me to tell you
what he's saying
word for word.
Molly, you're in danger.
You can't just
blurt it out like that.
And quit moving around,
will you?
You're making me dizzy.
I'll just tell her
in my own way.
Molly, you in danger,
girl.
What are you
talking about?
I know the man
who killed me.
He knows
who killed him.
His name's Willy Lopez.
I know where he lives.
He's a Puerto Rican,
Willy Lopez.
He knows
where he lives.
Write it down.
You write it down.
I ain't no
damn secretary.
Just do it!
Argh!
He's so testy.
What is it you
want me to write?
It's 303 Prospect Place,
apartment 4-D.
303 Prospect Place?
Yeah.
That's my
neighborhood.
Molly, he's got
my wallet,
he's got my key,
and he was
in here.
He's got his wallet
and key and was here.
Yesterday after your
walk with Carl,
you talked to Floyd,
took off your clothes--
All right,
all right.
When you came in
after your walk with Carl,
he saw
everything.
Go to the police.
It was a setup.
I was murdered.
He says go to the police.
He was murdered.
There's somebody
else involved--
I don't want no more
to do with this.
Where are you going?
I'm leaving, I did everything
I said I'd do.
And don't be
following me.
I'm finished.
I mean it.
Have a nice life.
Have a nice death.
Goodbye.
Molly, there is no one
on earth besides you
who wants this
to be true more than me,
but you got to be
rational about this.
Sam is no more
in this room than--
Look, I understand the
need to hang on to him,
I really do,
but this is absurd.
I know this seems absurd,
but it had to be real.
You believed some
fortune-teller from Brooklyn
who shows up
at your door?
I watched her have
a conversation with him.
I don't buy it, Moll,
not for a minute.
What about the things
she knew?
What things?
The photo Sam took of me
on our trip to Reno.
Carl, we were alone.
And the green underwear
that I wrote my name in.
She said Sam knew
who killed him.
Yeah, that he
was set up.
This is getting
deranged.
We're off
the deep end.
She had a name
and an address--
Willy Lopez.
303 Prospect Place,
apartment 4-D.
This is sick.
Oh, Carl.
This is really sick.
Oh, God.
Molly, I don't
understand
how you could--
you could...
swallow this crap.
I mean...
this guy
may not even exist.
Maybe she's just
trying to use you
to set someone up.
You're right.
You're absolutely right.
That's what
I got to find out.
What do you mean,
find out?
She said Sam wants me
to go to the police.
Sam wants you to
go to the police?
Jesus, Moll. Are you
out of your mind?
What are you going
to tell the police?
That some
storefront psychic
has been communing
with the dead?
Do you know what
that sounds like?
You're talking ghosts here,
for Christ's sake.
I'm sorry.
This stuff just really
gets to me,
you know?
It's OK if you
don't believe me.
I'm trying to, Molly.
Look...
if it'll make you
feel any better,
I'll go check
this out, OK?
I want you to try
and get some sleep.
OK?
All right.
I'll call you
in the morning.
OK.
Be careful.
[Knock Knock]
Carl.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Who you been
talking to, Willy?
''Talking to''?
What the hell do you mean?
Some woman knows
all about you, everything.
Where's she
getting it from?
I haven't said
a word to anybody.
She knows your name
and where you live.
A lot of women
know where I live.
This is not a joke.
She knows
about the murder.
I want you
to find this bitch,
whoever she is,
and I want you to--
Just get rid
of her, OK?
I've got $4 million stuck
in a god damn computer.
If I don't get
those codes,
if that money is not
transferred soon...
I'm...
dead.
We're both dead.
Why not tell them
you only launder money
the first of the month?
What the hell
is wrong with you?
Is everything a joke?
You killed a man.
You were supposed
to steal his wallet.
-Was that a joke?
-I did you a favor.
That was a freebie.
Look, these are
drug dealers, OK?
Just don't blow this
for me.
I've risked my job.
I could go to jail.
$80,000 of that money
is mine.
Look, just...
let me have the key
to Sam's apartment.
I'll get the address book
myself, OK?
You god damn bastard!
Why?
Why? You were
my friend!
I had a life,
god damn you.
I had a life!
Look, I don't even believe
in this stuff myself.
But she was real.
You think I'd come down here
if it wasn't real?
You know,
you told me if I had
any new information
that I should come.
So here I am.
I know
how this sounds.
I hear myself
saying it,
and I want
to cringe.
But this woman knew things
she couldn't have known.
Things Sam
only said to me.
OK, according to this
psychic lady,
there are ghosts and spirits
all over the place
watching us
all the time?
Huh?
Hell, I'm never going
to get undressed again.
Excuse me.
I got more
important things to do.
The guy's name
is Willy Lopez.
All I'm asking you to do
is check it out.
OK. Wait here.
Let me see if the guy's
got a record, all right?
Great.
What are you doing?
Where's the file
on Willy Lopez?
There isn't one.
He was probably
some old boyfriend
she was trying
to get even with.
This psychic woman's
got a record
that goes back
a long way.
1 967,
Shreveport,
forgery...
selling false I.D.
Served one year, 1 9 7 1 .
Baton Rouge,
arrested for fraud.
Numbers racketeering,
served 1 0 months, 1 9 7 4.
Look,
this is impossible.
It goes on and on.
She knew things,
private things.
Now, how could she
have known all that?
A lot of times
they read the obits.
She just had to see
the word ''banker''--boom.
Hell, they even go
through your...garbage
to find things
they can use--
letters, old papers.
It doesn't take much.
No.
It was real.
She knew about a...
a sweater I knitted.
And songs we sang.
Our trip
to Montego Bay.
I'm sorry.
I know this is hard.
People want so much
to believe.
They're grieving,
they're vulnerable...
and they will
give anything
for one last moment.
Believe me.
These people know
what they're doing.
I know
how you must feel,
but you know
you can press charges.
No.
Thank you.
Oh, God,
let this be it.
Yes.
[Ring]
Hello.
Eddie? It's Carl Bruner.
What's up?
Everything's fine.
Just, we're all set.
Let me know what
you want me to do.
Want you to
transfer the money
from the 1 2
separate accounts
into a single account
under the name Rita Miller.
OK.
Tomorrow at five minutes
before closing,
3:55 p.m.,
transfer the full account to
the First Island Bank of Nassau,
registry number
486-9580.
Call us when it's done.
OK. I've got it.
Just tell Mr. Balistrari
that there won't be
any more problems, OK?
Yeah. I'll do that.
Thank you.
Good work, Carl.
Molly, why
can't you hear me?
I need you.
[Knock On Door]
[Knock Knock Knock]
Who is it?
It's Carl, Molly.
No.
Don't open it,
Molly.
He's a murderer.
Hi.
Hey.
I know it's late.
I'm sorry
to disturb you.
I've been thinking
about you all day,
and I feel really lousy
about what happened last night.
This supernatural
thing just--
Don't worry about it.
It's OK.
No, it's not.
You needed me to hear you,
and I didn't.
I wasn't there for you,
and that was...
that was wrong.
It's just, I...
I just--
I want you to know
that I'm your friend.
Thanks, Carl.
You were never
our friend.
That really means
a lot to me.
Me, too. I brought you
some Japanese apple pears.
I know you like them.
Thanks.
That's very sweet.
Could I come in
for a second?
It's just been
one of those days.
Maybe some coffee?
Yeah. Come on in.
No, Molly.
You seem a little tense.
Are you OK?
No. I'm fine.
It's just--
What can I tell you?
It's been tough.
It just still hurts
so much.
You lying snake.
And on top of it,
it's stuff at work.
They've given me
my own accounts,
which is good,
but I just haven't really
had time to adjust,
kind of absorb
everything.
It's no big deal.
Yeah.
Can I have just
a little more cream?
Yeah.
Oh, shit.
Jesus. I can't believe
I did that.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Oh, God.
Let me throw that
in the washer.
Don't worry about it.
It's OK. It's just...
You want
another shirt?
No. It'll dry.
It'll just take a minute.
There you go.
Where were you today?
I thought you were going
to come into the bank
and sign those papers?
I was supposed to,
but I didn't have time.
I went to the police.
You did?
Wow. What
did you tell them?
What did they say?
It was awful.
I felt really stupid.
They brought out a file
on this woman and--
At least
1 0 inches thick.
A ripoff artist, huh?
No, Molly.
You know,
the sad thing...
is that
I believed her.
Molly...
sometimes
we need to believe.
Why? What's the point?
Molly, it's not easy to face
the realities of life sometimes.
You got to
give yourself that.
What you've got to remember
is the love that you guys felt.
You got to remember
how good Sam was.
You were everything
to him, Molly.
You were his life.
I feel so alone.
You're not alone.
OK?
You got your work.
You're incredibly talented.
You're young.
You're fantastically
gorgeous.
I don't know
what's real anymore.
what to think.
Just think about Sam.
Think about the time
you guys had together.
How wonderful that was.
Yeah.
Let your feelings out,
Moll. It's OK.
Life turns on a dime.
You know?
I mean...
people think that...
they're there forever, that there's
always going to be tomorrow,
but that's bullshit.
Sam taught us that.
You have to
live for now.
For today.
I can't.
I'm sorry.
It's OK.
I--I--I can't.
It's just too soon.
It's OK.
You've been great,
Carl.
But I need you
to leave.
I understand totally.
Please.
Could we just have dinner
tomorrow night? Just talk?
Can I interest you
in that?
Yeah.
Sure.
Great.
Hey.
Get off my train!
No.
Get off!
Get out of here!
No.
Show me
how you do that.
I'm not leaving
till you teach me.
Get off!
No.
You stubborn asshole.
Ha ha ha.
What are you doing?
What the hell
are you doing?
What am I doing?
You're trying to move it
with your finger.
You can't push it.
You're dead.
It's all in your mind.
The problem with you
is you still think you're real.
You think you're
wearing those clothes?
You think you're crouched
on that floor?
Bullshit!
You ain't got a body
no more, son!
It's all up here!
You want
to move something,
you got to move it
with your mind!
You got to focus!
How? How do you focus?
I don't know
how you focus.
You just focus.
How did you do that?
You got to take
all your emotions,
all your anger, all your love,
all your hate,
and push it way down
into the pit
of your stomach
and let it explode
like a reactor. Pow!
OK.
Don't laugh.
Way to go, kid.
I did it.
Way to go.
From your gut,
like I told you.
Give it time.
What else have you got?
How long
have you been here?
Since they pushed me.
Someone pushed you?
Yeah, someone pushed me.
Who?
You don't believe me?
You think I fell?
You think I jumped?
Well, fuck you!
It wasn't my time!
I wasn't supposed to go!
I'm not supposed
to be here!
Oh.
Oh, I'd give anything
for a drag.
Just one drag.
Are you all right?
Who are you?
Why are you hounding me?
Who sent you?
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone!
Yes!
You need
to concentrate,
'cause if
you concentrate,
you'll probably
rouse him.
What's his name
again?
Orlando.
Orlando. Orlando.
Is there an Orlando here?
I'm here.
He's here.
Oda Mae, I--
Sam.
Excuse me.
I'm Orlando.
The line's
over there.
Where did these ghosts
come from?
You can hear them, too?
I hear them in the morning
and the evening.
They're coming
into the shower.
Did you tell every spook
you met about me?
I got spooks from Jersey
coming in here.
There's stuff going on
you wouldn't believe.
It's amazing.
You're really doing it.
I know.
Can you
hurry this up?
Oh, chill out.
Chill out.
I need your help.
There's something
we need to do.
I'm not doing anything
else with you, Sam.
You're holding on
to a life
that doesn't
want you anymore.
It doesn't want you.
Give up the ghost.
Are you speaking
to me?
Does it look like it?
You're supposed to be
concentrating, aren't you?
You going to try it?
Thank you very much.
Sam, are you going
to get out of here?
Uh-uh.
Fine, then stay there.
Excuse me.
You ready now?
Let's do it.
I got to talk
to you now.
I've got a plan.
All we got to do
is we can...
Oda Mae?
Oda Mae.
Ortisha?
Orlando. Is that you?
Ortisha, where you at?
I can't hardly see.
Here.
Sh-She's here.
In front of you.
I'm right here.
Damn, baby, what did
you do to your hair?
Orlando, you like it?
It's autumn sunrise.
Get out of me,
you son of a bitch.
Don't you ever do that
to me again.
Orlando?
Ugh!
I can barely move.
You should know
better than that.
Jumping into bodies
wipes you out.
Everybody out.
What happened
to Orlando?
Where's
the insurance policy?
Are you deaf?
I said everybody out!
Everybody out!
Get out! Get out!
Everybody get out!
Get out.
You the fortune-teller?
Who are you?
That's an interesting
question.
Why don't you tell me?
Willy.
Willy?
Prospect Place Willy?
Get out of here fast.
Oda Mae!
Sister! Sister!
I'm all right.
We're in trouble,
so you got to help.
What do you mean we?
You're already dead.
These people
are trying to kill me.
And they'll be back.
Why don't you just find
a house to haunt?
Get some chains and
rattle them or something.
I have a plan,
and it will work,
but get some
of your fake I.D.s.
Forget it.
If you do this, they'll
never bother you again.
Scout's honor.
All right.
What do I have to do?
What exactly
do I have to do?
You got a nice dress?
I don't see what's wrong
with what I'm wearing.
Sorry. I made a joke.
I love your shoes.
I don't know anything
about banking.
Oda Mae, would
you just relax?
Listen, I'm nervous.
I'll get you
through it.
Your fake driver's
license is great.
Oh, Sam. I don't think
I should do this.
Straight ahead.
A stairway that says new accounts.
I ain't giving
them money.
Do what I say.
Don't talk.
Tell her you're here
to fill out a signature
card for a new account.
I'm here to fill out
a signature card for a new account.
Do you know
your account number?
926-31 043.
926...
31 043.
Rita Miller.
Who?
Didn't you sign a card
when you opened
the account?
Carl Bruner opened it
for you by phone
and asked you
to come in today.
Carl Bruner opened it
for me by phone.
Now he's asked me
to come in today.
Is that right?
Yeah.
All right.Just sign this
card on the bottom line, please.
May I use your pen?
Thank you so much.
No, no, no!
Rita Miller.
I'm so sorry.
You know, I...
I need another one.
I signed the wrong name.
Make sure it goes up to
the third floor file
because you have
a transaction to make.
Make sure this goes
to the third floor file.
I have a transfusion
to make.
A what?
Let's go.
You know what I mean.
Can I keep this pen?
Uh...uh,
yes, sure.
Thank you so much.
Bye-bye. I just
love these pens.
What do you want to
keep the pen for?
[Ring]
Carl Bruner speaking.
Hi, Carl.
Mr. Balistrari.
Balistrari? Carl,
it's me,John.
John.John, sorry, um,
what--what-- what--what's up?
I've got the info
on the Bradley portfolio.
Oh, right.
I'll pick it up
later, all right?
I'll be here
till 6:00.
I don't suppose I can
talk you into losing the hat.
You keep
messing with me,
you'll be here
by yourself.
Shh. Now tell the guard
you're here to see Lyle Ferguson.
Hi. I'm here to see
Lyle Ferguson, please.
Do you have
an appointment?
No, I'm here
for my health.
Tell him Rita
Miller's here.
You--You just tell him
Rita Miller's here.
One moment.
Don't embellish.
Jawohl.
Excuse me?
Now, listen.
This guy Ferguson's a real jerk.
I've known him
for five years,
and he still
thinks my name's--
Why are you
whispering?
Just be quiet
and listen.
He's a social moron.
Just tell the guard
Ferguson knows you.
You spent time with him
and his wife Shirley
at the Brewsters' Christmas
party last year. Got it?
What is this
in regards to?
What? He doesn't
remember me?
Oh, we spent
all that time
at the Brewsters' Christmas
party last year.
It was beautiful.
A big old tree and thousands
of presents everywhere.
It--
Gas.
I get a little gas
from time to time.
That's all. Gas.
Quit poking me!
Well,
don't overdo it.
Now, listen.
This'll be easy.
Ferguson was so drunk,
he could've had a conversation
with Tina Turner
and not remember.
I don't know, Sam.
Here we go.
Hello. Hello.
Uh, yes.
Of course, yes.
Well, uh, it's been
a...a long time.
Long time.
Ask how Bobby
and Snooky are doing.
How are Bobby
and Snooky doing?
Fine. Fine.
Thank you.
Thank you
for asking.
Uh, and how is
your, uh, family?
Oh, couldn't
be better.
Well...wonderful.
Tell him you've
been wondering
how they did on the
Gibraltar securities.
I was just wondering,
how did you do on
the Gibraltar securities?
The Gibraltar
securities?
Well, it looks like we topped out
on that one, huh?
Sure did.
That was
a useful tip.
Good old Randy.
Good old Randy. Got a
good old head on his shoulders.
Her shoulders.
Randy.
So, what, um...
what brings you
here today?
You're closing
an account.
I'm closing an account.
Do you have
your account number?
Yes?
Yes.
926-31 043.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Good.
Well, Rita, it looks like
you'll be withdrawing
$4 million
from us today.
$4 million!
Say yes. Say yes!
Is that correct?
Yes.
Yes, uh, yes!
Yes, that's correct.
Easy, easy.
Yes. Well, how
would you like that?
1 0s and 20s.
Pardon?
Tell him
a cashier's check.
I think better
A cashier's check.
Fine.
Well, of course,
uh, you know,
we require identification
from everyone.
Oh, I see.
It's just
procedural.
Yes. I...
Thank you.
Well, I'll, uh,
I'll be right back.
$4 million!
Shh!
Yeah, get me the
First Island Bank of Nassau.
It's on the Rolodex.
Well, we have some, uh,
things for you to sign here.
This officially
closes the account.
And, uh,
here you are.
Now sign Rita Miller.
Mm-hmm.
Rita Miller.
That's my name.
My name. Rita Miller.
My name.
That's my name.
Molly, hi.
Hi.
Oda Mae,
I'll be right back.
Just anywhere?
Right here.
Right.
Fine.
The, uh, check.
This, uh--
Here you are.
The person you need
is right down on the end.
Mama took the money that
she made in the oil wells,
and she sunk it
into gas pumps.
You know, how they have
at the gas station?
It's very,
very lucrative.
Oda Mae...
it really adds up.
Say goodbye.
It's been a pleasure
doing business with you.
Now, may I keep the pen?
Say good night to Bobby
and Snooky for me.
Bye-bye.
Why are you
rushing me?
What is wrong?
Oh.
Excuse me. Lyle?
Oh, yes. Uh...
Molly.
Jensen. The woman you were
just doing business with...
Yeah?
What did she want?
Did it have anything
to do with Sam?
Sam? Why, no. No.
That was Oda Mae Brown,
right?
No. Her name
was Rita Miller.
She was closing
an account.
Is there a problem?
No, I guess not.
Thank you.
Carl,
is something wrong?
Is somebody playing
with the computers?
What?
One of my accounts
is closed.
Which account?
What's wrong?
You want me
to call someone?
No, it's OK.
I can do it.
I got it.
$4 million!
What am I going to
do with this money?
I'm going
to buy the block.
I'm going to make my sister
go to a fat farm.
I'm going to
buy the building.
I've got an idea.
Please donate.
Take the check
out of your purse.
Right. I should put it
where nobody can get it.
No. No. Endorse it.
If I endorse it,
then if I drop it,
somebody will get it.
I never said you were
going to get the money.
It's blood money.
I was killed for this money.
Now,
endorse the check.
What are you going
to do with it?
Look over there.
To your left.
You don't think
I'm giving this $4 million
to a bunch of nuns.
If you don't,
they'll track you down.
Get rid of it.
Sam,
you're killing me!
It's $4 million!
You'll go to heaven.
I don't want
to go to heaven.
I want to
cash the check.
Hello.
You'll thank me
later.
How are you
doing?
Now, endorse it
''Rita Miller.''
I know.
Make it out
to St.Joseph's shelter.
I can't believe
you're making me do this.
Now give it to her.
I want to feel it
one more time.
Give the lady
the check.
I will!
Hand her the check.
You can do it.
Give her the check.
I will!
Bless you, child.
Bless you.
Give it to her.
Let go. Let go!
Shit.
I'm proud of you,
Oda Mae.
I don't care. Stay away
from me from now on.
What is that nun going
to do with it?
Leave me alone.
Never talk to me again.
I think you're
wonderful, Oda Mae.
[Blows Raspberry]
Go ahead, search.
You'll never find it.
They're going
to kill you, Carl.
You and Willy.
You're going
to be fertilizer.
They're going to bury you
right next to Jimmy Hoffa.
Yoo-hoo!
[Beep]
Who's doing that?
[Knock On Door]
Hey.
Hi.
I thought we were
having dinner.
I know, Moll.
I'm sorry.
I just forgot.
Had trouble
at the bank.
Forgot?
I wish you'd called.
I've been
really worried.
Listen, Molly.
I got to ask you about something.
Yeah. He needs
to borrow $4 million.
When you said that you
thought Sam was here,
that he was
talking to you,
what did he
say to you?
What does that have to do
with anything?
Just listen to me.
This psychic lady, I want
to know what she told you.
Stop this.
It doesn't matter.
It wasn't real.
What the hell happened
to you tonight?
Does this have
anything to do
with her being
at the bank today?
The bank?
Yeah. Ferguson said
she closed an account.
Her name isn't even
Oda Mae Brown.
It's Rita Miller
or something.
Carl, are you all right?
It's just
my stomach. It's...
um...
Jesus.
Do you have any, like, some
Pepto-Bismol or something?
Cyanide...
Uh, yeah.
It's upstairs.
Sit down.
I'll get it.
What's wrong?
Does little Carl
have a tummy ache?
What are you doing?
Now do you
believe in ghosts?
I'll set the place
on fire,
I swear to God.
I'll cut her throat.
Carl.
I swear to God.
I'll cut her throat.
I need that money,
and I want it
tonight at 1 1 :00.
If that psychic does
not bring it here,
Molly is dead. OK?
Carl, who are
you talking to?
Nothing. Now, Molly,
listen to me.
I can't explain this now,
but there's a problem, OK?
Something
at the bank.
Carl, you're
scaring me.
I'll come back
about 1 1 :00.
Why? Why not now?
Molly, look,
I'll come back.
Like 1 1 :00, OK?
I'm sorry to do
this to you, Molly,
but it's important.
Got to go.
Oda Mae!
Ahh!
I'm Arsenio Hall.
Don't try to adjust
your television.
I'm black.
I want to watch
Love Connection.
I love
I love that man
on there.
That's Arsenio.
So?
You love
Love Connection,
send your picture
in there.
She did.
They just haven't
answered yet.
Oda Mae?
Sam?
Not again.
They want the check,
and they're coming for you.
The check you said they
would never know about?
Oda Mae,
what's happening?
Sam?
Get out of here!
Now! Go!
Put the damn remote down.
Come on.
Knock on the doors.
Help! Help!
It's an emergency.
Let us in.
Who are you
kidding?
Open up!
You can't come in.
The cat don't
like visitors.
She'll pee all over.
They're going
to get us.
Where's Sam?
The bitch just left.
I'll check
downstairs.
[Doorbell Rings]
Carl?
Aah!
Willy!
Hey, man. You got
a serious problem, man.
Help me!
Help!
Willy!
I heard the car.
I was standing right there.
You could hear it
across town.
Sure, they snuffed him.
Yeah, yeah.
That dude is dead.
You're dead, Willy.
[Groaning]
Aah! Aah!
No! No! No!
Aah!
Help me!
Tell the driver
to hurry.
Yo, man, you want
to step on it, please?
Lady, I'm driving
as fast as I can.
[Honking]
Problems?
[Knock Knock Knock]
Carl, is that you?
No. It's me, Oda Mae.
Listen.
Molly, I know what you
think of me,
but you are in
serious danger.
I got Sam here.
We got to talk.
Get the hell
out of here.
I'm calling
the police.
Tell her to do it.
Fine. We want you
to call the police.
Let us in.
No.
Look, don't
you get it?
Sam wasn't just accidentally killed.
He was murdered.
He found out Carl was
laundering money at the bank.
This guy Carl
is dangerous.
He tried to kill me.
He's going to try
to kill you, too.
You're in
deep trouble.
Why are you
doing this to me?
I can't...
I just can't...
Oda Mae. Oda Mae,
tell her...
tell her she's wearing the shirt
that I spilled the margarita on
and the earrings
I gave her for Christmas.
Sam says you're wearing the shirt
he spilled the margarita on
and the earrings he
gave you for Christmas.
Don't you see?
I'm not a fake.
Not about this.
Give me a penny.
What?
Push a penny
under the door.
under the door?
Do it.
Tell her it's for luck.
Sam says
it's for luck.
We're between Green
and Mercer on Prince.
The gray building across
from the post office.
Thanks, Sergeant.
Please hurry.
We'll be waiting.
All right. They're
on their way.
Good.
So, what do we
do now?
Just wait.
Is Sam here?
Sam?
I'm sitting
beside her.
He's sitting
right beside you.
Sam, can you feel me?
With all my heart.
Says with all his heart.
I'd give anything
if I could just
touch you once more.
He says he wishes
he was alive again
so he could
touch you.
Me, too.
OK. OK. Look.
You can use me.
Use you?
You can use
my body.
Use your body?
Just do it quick
before I change my mind.
Oh, my love
My darlin'
I've hungered
for your touch
A long, lonely time
And time goes by
So slowly
And time can do
so much
Are you still mine
I
Need your love
Godspeed your love
To me
Lonely rivers flow
To the sea
To the open arms
Of the sea
Yeah
Oh, my love
My darlin'
I've hungered
Hungered for your... 렁
Molly!
Molly,
are you home?
It's Carl.
Molly!
Fire escape.
What's happening to me?
Molly?
[Metal Clanks]
Molly!
Son of a bitch!
Come on.
Oh. Look. Look.
Oh. Let's go.
Let's go.
All right.
Molly!
Just get away
from us, Carl.
Molly!
You're just a liar.
Listen to me.
This woman's a thief.
She's a con artist.
Why are you
doing this?
Don't listen to her.
Stop!
Just get away
from us, Carl.
I've called
the police.
Oh!
Shit.
Unh! Oh!
Why are you
doing this?
Don't interfere!
She's a thief!
All right.
Give me the check.
Carl, no!
Out of this, Molly!
Keep out of this,
Molly!
Give me the check!
Get off of me!
Where is it?
Where is it,
god damn it?
I gave it away.
You're lying.
Don't...lie to me,
god damn it!
[Click]
The check.
Watch out, Sam!
I swear to God
I'll kill her!
Now, just...
look.
Just give me
the check, Sam, OK?
I promise you
I'll let her go
if you just
give it to me. OK?
Sam?
Aah!
Oh, Carl.
What?
[Groaning]
Aah!
Ooh! Help!
Are you two all right?
Sam?
Molly?
I can hear you.
Oh, God.
Sam?
They're waiting
for you, Sam.
I'll miss you.
Your mother
would be proud.
I'm going to miss
you, too, Sam.
You're all right.
Bye, Oda Mae.
Bye, Sam.
I love you, Molly.
I've always
loved you.
Ditto.
It's amazing, Molly.
The love inside...
you take it
with you.
See ya.
Bye.
Subtitles by  Ajeesh vijayan