Movie & Captioning Conformed By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You'll Like & Enjoy The Movie !!! "
Damn! How do you say "permit"?
I have a permit.
- Dr. Niko Tapopopolis?
- It's Tatopoulos.
Kyle Terrington.
I'm with the U.S. State Department.
- What are they doing?
- You're being reassigned.
- But my work here isn't finished.
- It is now.
There's pressure
from the Americans.
What have you told them?
Nothing yet.
Are there any survivors?
Only one, sir. He was lucky.
Get them out.
Ask him what happened.
What did you see, old man?
That's affirmative.
Hey, where are you going
with my stuff?
Hello. Hello.
That's very delicate.
Thank you.
- Dr. Niko Topodopeless?
- Tatopoulos.
Whatever. Come on,
get these people off of the pier!
- Sir, what am I doing here?
- Watch your step. Don't talk to anybody.
Come on, get them off the damn pier!
- What is all this, some kind of spill?
- Something like that.
Look, I work for the
Nuclear Regulatory Commission...
...but accidents
and spills aren't my field.
We know.
You know you've interrupted a 3-year
study of the Chernobyl earthworm?
Yeah, you're the worm guy, right?
The radioactive contamination in that
area has mutated the earthworm's DNA.
- You know what that means?
- I got a feeling I'm about to find out.
It means, because of a
man-made accident...
...the Chernobyl earthworms are now
17% larger than they were before.
- Seventeen percent? Sounds pretty big.
- They're enormous.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm a biologist.
I take radioactive samples
and I study them.
- Great. Here's your sample. Study it.
- What sample?
- You're standing in it.
- I don't see it.
Where is it?
I don't see it.
Colonel! Colonel!
That was a footprint!
I was standing inside of a footprint!
That's right.
But there's no animal in the world that
makes footprints like that, is there?
I told them this is not your field,
but they never listen to genius.
This is Elsie Chapman, of the
National Institute of Palaeontology.
She's your boss.
- Those were footprints, right?
- Yes, they were.
Did anybody see what made them?
Actually, no such luck.
It happened so fast, nobody knew
what hit them until it was over.
- Elsie.
- Yeah?
The tape's in.
The French finally released it.
This is a Japanese cannery ship...
...that was attacked and sunk
near French Polynesia.
We believe it's connected. Dr. Craven,
have you met the worm guy?
Sorry. Summer cold.
- Come on, all right?
- Have a nice day.
Wait, wait, wait!
- They say it'll rain all week.
- What's with the bags?
- Caiman's groceries.
- Oh, girl.
- Speak of the devil.
- What?
This is the midget version.
This makes me look like a professional.
Can we put this on the 5, please?
- You think I should ask him?
- No.
- I'm gonna ask him.
- No!
- I will.
- Audrey.
- Did you talk with Humphries?
- This is not the place.
- Just tell me. Did you talk with him?
- It's between you and Rodriguez.
You serious? He's gonna consider me
for the job? What else did he say?
Why don't we talk about it
over dinner tonight? Your place.
- Mr. Caiman, you're married.
- Yes, and you're very beautiful.
- Have I ever told you that before?
- Mr. Caiman!
I've been doing research for you...
...after hours and weekends
for over three years.
This is a very important job to me.
I'm too old to be
your assistant anymore.
I need to know this job
is going someplace.
So have dinner with me tonight.
I can't.
It's your choice.
- Okay, let's go.
- Charlie.
Say hello to your new co-anchor,
Ms. Desireé Pon.
Hello, Desireé, welcome aboard.
Mark, can I have a pillow,
phone book, something?
- Three, two...
Hello, New York. Today at 5 we'll
ask Fat Pat when the rain will end.
So three years digging up worms
in Chernobyl?
- How did Mrs. Tatapolis handle it?
- Tatopoulos. I'm actually not married.
- Really? A girlfriend, or...?
- No. Perhaps I work too much.
So do you mean to tell me
there's no one...
...who holds a special place
in your heart?
No. Not for a long time now.
Well, you may be the wrong man
for the job, but I think you're cute.
Thank you.
She thinks I'm cute.
Who the hell are they?
- Get those people out of there.
- They're with me.
Is that right? Who are you?
La Rochelle Casualty
and Property Insurance.
We're preparing our report.
- You're pretty damn fast.
- That's our job.
Your people are getting
in the way of my job.
Colonel, what do you think
could have done this?
Listen, Mr. Roach, you get your
people out of here, or I will.
The captain's getting some coffee.
Then he's gonna kick your asses.
Well, I'm in for a buck.
What the hell
is that dope-head doing?
Artie, what the hell's wrong?
Why are we slowing down?
I don't know, she's at full throttle.
Maybe she's heavy in the net.
- How come we stopped? Nets full?
- I don't think so.
We must be caught on something.
Bring in the nets. Bring them up!
Pull them in now.
- What's going on?
- We're bringing them in.
The engines are heating up.
- Should I shut them down?
- No, keep pulling.
I'm trying! I'm trying!
Cut them loose!
Look out!
Cut them loose now!
Hurry! Hurry!
She's going down!
Do you hear that?
Excuse me, sir. We just got a report
of three fishing trawlers going down.
- What makes you think it's related?
- The trawlers were pulled under, sir.
Jesus Christ...
It's only 200 miles off
the Eastern seaboard...
...and we don't even know what it is.
- Theropoda allosaurus.
- What?
A type of enormous reptile...
...that we believed
died out in the Cretaceous Period.
So where's it been hiding
the last 60 million years?
What about the traces of radiation?
The radiation isn't an anomaly.
It's the clue.
This animal is much too big
to be some kind of lost dinosaur.
Don't tell me what it isn't,
tell me what it is.
Well, what do we know?
It was first sighted off of
the French Polynesian Pacific.
That area has been exposed
to dozens of nuclear tests.
- Hence the radiation.
- More than that.
I believe it's a mutated aberration.
A hybrid caused by the fallout
on these islands.
Like your earthworms?
Yes. Yes.
We're looking at a completely
incipient creature.
The dawn of a new species.
The first of its kind.
- My life sucks.
- Oh, please.
- Your life doesn't suck. His life sucks.
- Because I'm married to you.
I cannot believe
he put the moves on me.
After everything I've done for him.
He is scum.
To him, you're just
a pair of breasts that talk.
- Hey, there's an image.
- I'm telling you, he is dirt.
He's a douche-bag, gutter-slime'
dog-crap puke-chunks.
Hey, you don't see I'm eating?
Audrey, you're too damn nice.
That's your problem.
Nice gets you nothing in this town.
It's dog-eat-dog.
You gotta be a killer to get ahead.
I'm sorry, baby, but you just
don't got what it takes.
- Do you think that's true?
- Pretty much. You're a nice person.
Nice guys finish last.
- I can be tough if I want.
- Yeah, sure.
I can. I can.
- No, yeah, no.
- Whatever.
Oh, my God!
Could you turn that up please?
- Sometime in the last 12 hours.
It is not known yet...
- It's Nick.
- Who is he?
He was my college sweetie.
He looks so handsome on TV.
There is tight security
around the crash site...
...possibly due to the sensitive
military cargo on the plane.
You wanna unload this thing?
I'm getting soaked here.
Come on, will you?
Hey, Joe! Gonna catch one of them
little fish in the East River?
I hope so.
But you never know.
I mean, today could be my lucky day.
The only thing you'll catch is a cold.
Hey.
I got a bite.
Boy, do I have a bite!
Don't let up on him, Joe.
You got a big one, baby. Hold on to it.
You want to fight?
Here he is, ladies and gentlemen,
the man you've all been waiting for.
Yours for a safer New York,
your mayor, Mayor Ebert!
Thank you. Thank you.
I want to thank you all for coming out
on this beautiful New York City day.
Four years ago, people didn't think
I would reduce crime.
But I did!
Oh, my God.
Move! Let's get out of here!
I'm grateful we're getting a new set.
I know that represents a
commitment from management.
Here's what I don't understand:
Why we're the only station in town...
...that doesn't have the Korean
grocery holdup as our lead.
- What's our lead? Rain, again!
- Mom?
I know, it impresses the people at the
parties you go to that we're classy.
Sorry, I just don't give
a rat's ass about a war...
...in some country whose name
I can't even pronounce.
- How about a real story?
- Sir?
I think your story
just walked by the window.
What?
Maybe we can get in the Korean
grocer's hospital room.
- So did this Romeo have a name?
- Nick Tatopoulos.
- Jesus. Is that why you dumped him?
- No.
- How long did you go out for anyway?
- Nearly four years.
Girl, I'm surprised he didn't
ask you to marry him.
Well, that's the problem.
He did.
Tell me that's not another parade.
I don't think that's a parade.
Please stand by.
What the hell is that?
Are you all right? Are you cut?
You all right?
Victor! Don't be stupid.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
That is really...
That is large.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
Come on, you bastard. Come on!
Victor, get back here, you retard!
Somebody do something!
Come on! Come on!
Can you tell us what's going on?
Watch it!
- Sergeant O'Neal, sir.
- Any word from the mayor's office?
Yes, sir. They've agreed to evacuate the
city. They've called the National Guard.
Evacuate Manhattan?
That's over 3 million people.
- Has that ever been done before?
- I don't think so.
- Where is he now?
- We lost sight of it, sir.
You wanna run that by me again?
After its initial attack, he...
...disappeared.
Secretary of Defense Burk
is on the line.
I don't understand. How can
something so big just disappear?
- We're not sure, but...
- Yeah, yeah.
- He probably returned to the river.
- I don't think so.
I mean, look at it. It's perfect.
An island, water on all sides.
But like no other island in the world'
it's a place where he can easily hide.
He's in there someplace.
Channel 12 caught it on tape.
Hello, I'm Charles Caiman,
in the WIDF news center.
Ladies and gentlemen, we New Υorkers
like to think we've seen it all...
...but what you're going to see now
will shock you beyond belief.
This is footage we have
that indicates...
...that there is a dinosaur
loose in Manhattan.
WIDF's exclusive footage was shot
barely half an hour ago.
WIDF cameraman, Victor "Animal"
Palotti, surνived unharmed.
You are so great.
Great stuff, Animal.
Weren't you scared?
Yeah, I thought Lucy
was gonna kill me.
- Damn right, you crazy wop.
- Okay, people.
- What were you thinking?
- We have to be completely relocated...
...to the New Jersey station
for the 10:00 broadcast. Animal!
You're riding in the chopper
with Caiman. Now. Let's go, lift off.
- Are you going to be all right?
- Yeah. Audrey's gonna spend the night.
A threesome. That's excellent.
I'm a little tired, but...
Dozens of people are reported killed,
thousands injured.
Civil defense stations are
being set up throughout Manhattan.
But in addition, city, military
and health officials...
...are setting up a command post
on the Jersey shore...
...in anticipation of an evacuation...
- My bag. My bag!
- Mr. Caiman.
Mr. Caiman, wait.
Mr. Caiman, I've got a lead.
I know a guy who's
on the inside with the military.
- Not now.
- I can get great inside information.
Look. This is the moment When
the big boys go to Work, okay?
The bag.
- This is crazy. Come on, let's go.
- Wait up.
Come on.
Wait up.
- Can we get a cab?
- Audrey, what are you thinking?
Move, move!
On the sidewalk, right now!
In what city officials
are describing as...
...the worst act of destruction since
the World Trade Center bombing...
...hundreds of thousands
have jammed the streets...
...in the largest evacuation
in this city's history.
And many people...
Many, many people
are not happy about it.
Among those unhappy citizens
are the managers of the stores...
...along pricey 5th and Madison Ave.
The Warner Bros. And Disney stores
have been cleared out by looters.
The streets are jammed.
Traffic's at a standstill.
Emergency vehicles cannot have access
to emergencies that may develop.
There's a slow but steady stream
out of the city...
...as if Long Island or New Jersey
were any refuge in this time of crisis.
This is great. If I'm wrong
on this evacuation...
...they'll string me up
from the Liberty torch.
Didn't we agreed we weren't gonna have
any sw eets until after the election?
Back off, Gene.
Who the hell are they?
A contingent of building oWners
and business representatives.
- I don't have time for this nonsense.
- Campaign contributors.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I share your concerns.
I want to get this city back in business
as soon as possible. Please.
La Rochelle Insurance. We represent
nearly 13% of the buildings in your city.
You can count on our emotional
and financial support.
Well, thank you. Thank you.
What do you plan to do?
- Coming through.
- Where's your ID?
- What's wrong? Don't you watch TV?
- You gotta have press ID.
I've got ID. I had a badge on my bag.
I don't know if this is a good idea.
What are you talking about?
You stole it.
Finally you got a little chutzpah.
Don't wimp out.
- What if Caiman finds out?
- Look.
How often do you think you'll have
an ex-boyfriend inside a major story?
This is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
If you stick this thing...
Have you got any glue or something?
I'm sorry, I left my forgery kit
back at the office.
- No croissant?
- No, monsieur.
- You call this coffee?
- No, I call this America.
Sorry, Mr. Mayor, that's where
we are at this point.
Now, hold on. Hold on.
You're telling me, in an election month
I evacuated this city for nothing?
Do you realize what this evacuation
will cost the people of this city?
We've been monitoring
all the waters around the island.
As far as we can tell'
this thing has not left the area.
- But you don't know for sure.
- We have reason to believe...
...it may be hiding in
a building in the restricted area.
- But you don't know for sure!
- Mr. Mayor.
We cannot give the all-clear until each
and every building has been checked.
- What is it?
- Excuse me, sir.
That may be more difficult
than we projected.
Terrific. Terrific! More good news!
We've run into a problem.
- Do you believe this?
- I don't know what's going on.
- You never know what's going on.
- Thank you.
- Right here, sir.
- Have them fall in.
Let's go, people, fall in downstairs.
Lieutenant Anderson and his men
found this, this afternoon.
We were checking the building above
and we discovered the floor was gone.
When we discovered that he could
burrow his way through the tunnels...
...we realized he could be
outside the quarantine zone.
Holy Christ.
- How many tunnels lead off the island?
- Only 14. He hasn't used any of them.
- Have them all sealed up.
- Yes, sir.
How? How would we do that, sir?
Fill them with cement, brick them up,
put landmines in them. I don't care!
Make sure the damn thing
doesn't leave the island.
You know, he's not some enemy
trying to evade you.
He's just an animal.
What are you suggesting?
Well, when I had to
catch earthworms...
...I knew the best way to get them
was not to dig them out...
...but to draw them out.
All we need to do is to find out
what he needs, and he'll come to you.
- Where are they now?
- Delta Niner, where is the convoy?
Command, they've just
entered the city.
I have no contact with the convoy.
I'm expecting ground confirmation.
- Sir, convoy ETA is 10 minutes.
- We've got to hurry.
Man your positions. Ten minutes ETΑ.
Go, go, go! All systems go.
Is it good?
Let's go, let's go!
Come on, move it through!
We have picture.
You can leave, Jean Luc.
We have a signal, sir.
You said this was French Roast!
More cream.
Bring them in. Come on,
bring it back!
- I sure hope this plan of yours works.
- I'm kind of hoping that myself.
- Did you approve this?
- They just appropriated it.
Twelve of the city's dump trucks.
Would you like to tell me
what's going on here?
Actually, no, I wouldn't.
And don't touch anything.
- How's O'Neal doing?
- Everything is on schedule, sir.
- Sure you didn't know about this?
- No one told me anything about this.
Why do I even keep you around?
Dump!
No. Very clever.
All right, let's pile it on,
and let's get out of here.
That's a lot of fish.
Come on, you bastard,
it's suppertime.
Look at all that frigging fish.
Is this gonna work?
We gotta get the manholes uncovered.
We want him to smell the bait.
Come on.
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, guys.
- Let's get those lids off. Go, go!
- What the hell is he doing?
- Okay, this way, this way. Come on.
- Let's go!
Come on. Over there!
- This one.
- Yes, sir.
- Give me the crowbar.
- Sir.
Set up here. I've got a shot.
This is Six Alpha Charlie.
We gotta move.
We can't stay put, we gotta move!
Let's go, fall back!
Go, go, go!
We need bigger guns.
- We've lost communications.
- Get us back online. Fire at will!
Sergeant, fire at will!
Fire! Fire! Fire!
O'Neal, you better tell me
what's going on.
He's gone, sir, he's gone.
Echo unit in pursuit.
Follow my lead.
All systems armed. Echo 4 armed.
We're doing 80 knots
and he's pulling away, sir.
I've got him locked on.
- Locked on, sir. Target is locked on.
- Fire the damn missile.
- Echo 1 through 4, fire at will.
- Fire sidewinders.
Damn! That is a negative impact.
I repeat, that is a negative impact.
- Negative impact, sir.
- "Negative impact"?
That's the damn
Chrysler Building we're talking about.
- You told me he had it locked on.
- Echo 1, we had you locked on.
The heat-seekers can't lock. He's
colder than the buildings around him.
Freddie. Freddie! Freddie!
- What? What?
- Let's go before we get caught.
Jimmy. You know
that bad feeling I get...
...when something really bad
is gonna happen?
I'm getting that feeling
right now, man.
- Descend to 300 feet. Lasers on.
- Target, 11 o'clock.
Where'd he go?
Echo flight, get it together, guys.
Prepare to fire.
- Echo 4, ready.
- Echo 2, ready.
Fire!
I think we got him.
We've lost Echo 1 and 2, sir.
Echo 4, where is target?
Jesus! He's right on my tail, sir.
I don't think I can shake him.
I think I lost him.
We've... We've lost Echo 4, sir.
What's the matter with you people?
You've caused more damage
than that goddamn thing did!
- Calm down. Have some candy.
- I don't want any. Leave me alone!
I can't believe it. I mean...
He did all of this,
and we did nothing to him.
That's not true. We fed him.
Here at the command center
in New Jersey...
...there is no new information
to report.
The military has clamped a media
blackout on whatever is going on.
Officials are not saying anything...
...about their attempts to contain or
control this creature, and now I see...
No, the situation is under control.
It's under control,
we have containment.
- Can I help you, young man?
- Yes.
Do you have any
at-home pregnancy tests?
Especially ones that look for
gonadotropic hormones...
...or clomiphene citrate?
I don't know. This...
This...
- This is all we've got.
- I'll take all of them.
Wow, you must have
quite some harem.
Audrey? Oh, my Go... Is that you?
What are you doing here?
Hi. Hello.
- Wow. How much is that?
- $46.
God, you look...
Wow! How have you been?
It's good to see you, Nick.
- So you made it.
- What?
You're a reporter, huh?
No, that's good. That's good.
That's what you always wanted.
I'm happy for you. Really, I am.
You're still mad at me?
Well, you left without a phone call,
a letter, nothing. All this time.
Yeah. Yeah, I guess
I am still a little mad.
That was eight years ago.
Some people change.
Most people don't.
Well, I'm sorry you feel that way.
Audrey.
You're right.
Eight years is a long time.
Can I make you a cup of tea?
Sure, that'd be nice.
I still can't believe it.
How does a guy go
from anti-nuke activist...
...to working for the
Nuclear Regulatory Commission?
When you and I went
to rallies together in college...
...we helped to create awareness.
But now, from the inside,
I'm able to effect real change.
Exactly what changes
are you trying to effect?
I'm preparing a census
for the government.
I'm cataloging new species
that have been created...
...as a direct result
of nuclear contamination.
Is that what you think
created this thing?
Yeah. I found a blood sample
earlier this evening.
- How close did you get to the thing?
- I got pretty close.
- And what else did you find out?
- Well, we know he eats tons of fish.
He's amphibious.
He's a burrower. And...
...he's pregnant.
- He is?
- He's a very unusual he.
I mean, obviously these tests
weren't designed for this...
...but fundamentally they look for
the same hormonal patterns...
...to indicate pregnancy.
I don't get it. If he's the first of his
kind, how can he be pregnant?
Doesn't he need a mate?
Not if he reproduces asexually.
Where's the fun in that?
I kept thinking'
why would he travel so far?
But it makes perfect sense.
Lots of animals travel
great distances for reproduction.
That's what he's doing in New York.
He's nesting.
- Nesting?
- Yes.
Do you realize that a lizard can lay
up to 12 eggs at a time?
- Think of it.
- I didn't know that.
Forgive me, I have to get this to the
lab and see if I can confirm all this.
I'll be right back.
Come on, Joey'
there's nothing down here.
I'm telling you, man, I heard...
I heard something.
You heard nothing. It's a dead end.
Anything?
No. Nothing down here.
Nothing at all.
This is why, in this case, all the king's
horses and all the king's men...
...may not be able to put
the Big Apple together again.
Audrey Timmonds, WIDF News.
Yes!
- You owe me a beer.
- Like it?
- Yeah.
- I should've worn my hair back.
- No, it looks great.
- Good, good.
How did you get ahold of this?
Well, you know. It's like you said,
nice guys finish last.
- Thank you. I love you.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
What...?
Murray. Murray! Come here a second.
Hold on a second, all right?
What is it?
I've got exclusive footage of other
places this thing has attacked.
- You do?
- Yeah.
- Whose story is that?
- Mine.
There's a lot of movement
down there.
Military, police...
- It's my breakfast.
- I'm hungry.
Quiet!
If we can lure him into
a more open area...
...such as this portion of Central Park,
we should be able to take him down.
- Last time you didn't even scratch it.
- That's not true.
My worm guy, I mean...
...Dr. Tatopoulos has found blood.
- Yes, I did.
See, the only thing we need to do
is get him out into open terrain...
...and use weapons that don't rely
on heat-seeking technology...
Excuse me, sir. I think the situation has
become more complicated than that.
The blood I collected revealed that the
creature is either about to lay eggs...
...or already has.
Are you trying to tell us that there's
another of those things out there?
No, no, governor, I don't believe so.
Wait a minute, wait.
Then how can it be pregnant?
What is this, the Virgin Lizard?
No, no, it reproduces asexually.
That's why we have to find the nest
as soon as possible.
Otherwise up to a dozen
will be born...
...each one capable of laying eggs
on its own.
Very quickly we could be
looking at an enormous population.
So after we kill the creature,
then we search for the nest.
No, I think it might be too late
by then.
These eggs are going
to hatch very quickly.
- How could you possibly know that?
- The fish.
The fish that we found
on the subway.
He's not collecting all this food
just for himself.
He's preparing to feed his young.
Do we have something on this guy?
Professor Nick Ta... Tat... Tato...
They call him "the worm guy."
Stay tuned for a special report.
Excuse us, please. Where you been?
- Your spot is up right after this.
- Oh, good.
- Could you turn it up, please?
- Can you turn it up, please? The TV?
If Dr. Tatopoulos is right, we have to act
quickly, before this problem escalates.
You want to divide our efferts based
solely on some wild theory?
Sir, Nick's come through
for us before, and if he feels...
Come through for you?
Your campaign's a disaster.
You weren't even able to
keep this thing out of Manhattan.
Excuse me, gentlemen,
but I think we should see this.
- Methods and motivations of
Manhattan's newest unwanted pest.
"Godzilla."
That's what Japanese sailors called him
in song, a mythological sea dragon...
...who filled their hearts with fear.
- Oh, my God! He stole my report!
- Yeah, I know.
That myth has become reality,
our modern-day terror.
- I don't believe it!
- Who is this Godzilla?
Where did he come from?
Why is he here?
And it's "Gojira, you moron!
A direct path can be traced from
Manhattan to French Polynesia...
...where nuclear tests have been
going on for two decades.
Researcher Dr. Tapadopoulos believes
the creature may be nesting...
...using Manhattan as ground zero
to cultivate the species.
This, despite the fact that the
combined might of the U.S. Military...
...has been unable to subdue...
- You went to the press with this?
- No.
- No, I haven't talked to anyone.
- They mentioned you by name!
Yeah. Yeah.
- You gave them the tape?
- No, I didn't give them the tape.
No, it's in my tent right now.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, she took it.
Pack your stuff, mister. You're
officially off this project, as of now.
What's going on?
We're leaving.
I'm so sorry about all this.
Make sure that Hicks finds that nest
before it's too late.
I'll try.
What do you mean, he's not there?
A second ago you said
he was on the other line.
Please, it's urgent. I really need to
talk to him. Yes. Nick Tatopoulos.
You're leaving? Why?
Is it because of me?
Because of the story?
- What did you think would happen?
- You never said it was off the record.
I shouldn't have to, Audrey.
You were supposed to be my friend.
I trusted you.
Nick, there's something
I have to tell you.
Look, I lied to you. I'm not a reporter.
When we broke up and I first came out
to New York, I was so sure I'd make it.
But I haven't.
That's why
I needed the story so bad.
I just couldn't tell you I'm a failure.
And you thought that made it okay
to steal my tapes?
No. It was a terrible thing to do.
I never should've have done that.
Good luck with your new career.
I really think you have what it takes.
Newark Airport.
I'm sorry.
Hey, yo! Come on, give her a break,
will you?
Excuse me, is this the best way
to the airport?
Sir, where are you going?
Hey, hello!
Okay, stop. Stop the car, right now.
Now let me out of here.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
Hey, I know you, don't I?
- Yeah. You're that insurance guy.
- Agent Philippe Roaché.
Sounds big.
French Secret Service.
I thought you'd like to know
that your American friends...
...have decided not to look
for the creature's nest.
What? Are you sure?
How do you know that?
- We know. Trust me.
- Trust you?
You hijack me
and you expect me to trust you?
- Yes.
- And why should I do that?
Because you are the only one who
wants to find the nest as much as I do.
How did you get all this stuff
into the country?
This is America.
You can buy anything.
But why all the secrecy?
Why aren't you guys
working with the U.S. Military?
I'm not permitted
to speak of such things.
Hey, you said you needed my trust.
Well, then I need yours.
I am a patriot. I love my country.
You understand that?
Sure.
It's my job to protect my country.
Sometimes I must even protect it from
itself. From mistakes we've made.
Mistakes that we don't want
the world to know about.
- The nuclear tests in the Pacific?
- Yes.
This testing done by my country
left a terrible mess.
We're here to clean it up.
They are setting the next fish trap
at 8-something.
We know how to get into the city'
we just don't know where to look.
Here. This is the 23rd Street
subway station.
That's where we first found the fish.
That'd a good place to start looking.
So you're in?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm in.
I always wanted to join
the French Foreign Legion.
- Hello.
- How's it going?
Excuse me. Pardon me. Sorry.
- Honey.
- Hi, sweetie.
- Who the hell are all these people?
- What?
I couldn't just let them
sleep on the street.
- Where's Audrey?
- In the bedroom.
- Crying her eyes out because of you.
- Me?
What did I do?
All that "You gotta be vicious" stuff
you filled her head with.
- Get out of here!
- Go in there and talk to her right now.
Is it being with you?
Excuse me.
Contrary to some frivolous reporting...
...we have absolutely no information
whatsoever to make us believe...
...that there are any eggs
of the creature in the city.
There's no need for panic.
Repeat, there's no reason to panic.
It's all my fault.
What have I done, Animal?
What have I become?
Look at me. This isn't me.
I don't do stuff like this.
You made a mistake. All right?
It happens.
Yeah, well...
...I just totally screwed up with the
only man who will ever care about me.
If I told you you could
make it all up to him, would you?
Of course I would.
Get this. After he left you in the street,
I kind of followed him.
I figured I'd talk some sense
into the guy.
Next thing I know,
he pulls into this warehouse...
...with all these French wackos
in military outfits.
They wanna try to sneak
back into the city tonight.
They're going after the nest.
If he finds it, I think you should be
the one to let the whole world know...
...that he was right all along.
You want me to follow him
into the city?
Yeah, we both will.
- Come on, it'll be fun, it'll be fun.
- I already made a mess of everything.
Yeah, you really did, Audrey.
Listen, I'm going after him.
You can go with me, or not. Okay?
- What are you doing?
- Can't let Lucy know. She'll hurt me.
What's with the chewing gum?
It makes us look more American.
Oh, really?
Just let me do all the talking.
All right?
It's not in gear.
Follow me. This way.
- Are you okay?
- I'm okay.
Come on.
What is this place?
It's a vent that leads down
to the subway tunnels underneath.
It should take us right to
the 23rd Street station in Manhattan.
You gotta be kidding me.
Aren't there rats and stuff down here?
I'm more concerned about lizards.
Big, ugly, nasty, large lizards.
Who are you boys with?
- We're with the 3-2, sir.
- I didn't ask you, soldier.
Well, Sergeant O'Neal
just called down for us.
He wants us to join him right now.
Sir. Thank you.
- Have you got a problem talking?
- Why, no, sir. I'm fine.
Come on, let's go!
- All right. Keep it moving.
- Thank you very much.
Elvis Presley movies.
He was the king.
- Sir, O'Neal on the line.
- O'Neal, do you read me?
- O'Neal.
- How are we doing?
So far, so good.
We're right on schedule.
We're good.
We're... We're good.
- Oh, my God!
- Yeah.
There they are. Kill your light.
Kill your light.
Come on, how do we get down there?
We're gonna lose them.
- How did they get down there?
- I don't know.
You don't think
they climbed down this thing?
Oh, Jesus!
Careful.
- Give me your hand.
- I got you.
- Do you hear that?
- What?
Animal, come on!
I guess we go this way.
We've spotted him in section five.
Combat positions. Here we go!
Target's heading north
to section five.
Do not fire until he has cleared
the buildings and enters the park!
Wait until he enters the park.
Come on.
He's leaving! Damn it! Fire!
Fire at will!
Damn!
Fire!
Fly to evasive maneuvers.
The target is in the clear and headed
towards the West Side Highway.
Don't worry. The Navy has a little
something there waiting for him.
- All stations manned for battle.
- At ordered depth, sir.
We have him on sonar.
Utah closing in.
Make final preparations,
prepare to fire.
- Aye, aye, manned and ready.
- Torpedo room manned and ready.
- Final bearing and shoot.
- Are we locked on?
- Are we locked on? Locked on, captain.
- Number one, stand by.
- Fire.
- Torpedo one left the tube.
Indiana and Anchorage closing in.
- Ensign, what's the status?
- We are locked on and closing in, sir.
Fire number one.
- Sir! The target's heading right at us!
- All back full!
Aye, aye, sir. All back full.
Stand by for impact. In 10 seconds.
Six, five, four...
...three, two, one.
We've lost the Anchorage, sir.
He's shifted course, sir.
- He's headed back towards Manhattan.
- Full ahead. Close in, lock on.
- Prepare tubes three and four, lock on.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Stand by, three. Fire.
- Torpedo three cleared and left the tube.
Impact in eight seconds.
Seven, six...
Three, two, one.
- Direct hit!
- Got him.
- Congratulations, sir.
- Good job.
Yeah, well done.
What's up there?
This is a good smell.
Audrey, look at this.
He trashed the Garden.
Oh, man! Now I'm pissed.
- Is that them?
- Yeah.
Three eggs.
I thought there'd be more.
And you were right.
Oh, my.
There's gotta be
more than 20 eggs here.
Way more.
Start counting.
- Could you help me?
- Yeah, you all right?
There.
We don't have enough explosives.
What the hell are they doing?
Nick, we have a problem.
Oh, my God. My God!
Come on. Let's go!
One second, all right?
One second. This is unbelievable.
Don't you think
we have enough already?
I just want...
Yeah, that's good for me.
That's plenty.
We should...
Just let's not...
...startle it.
We smell like the fish.
- I think we should leave now.
- I think that's a good idea.
Come on!
- Everybody outside! Now!
- Come on. Let's go.
Lock the doors now! We have to keep
them contained inside. Let's go!
- You see that?
- All right. On three.
Three!
This is where the Knicks
get showered and everything.
Great. Now what do we do?
I'm standing just outside the Jersey
entrance to the Lincoln Tunnel.
Thousands of angry refugees are
demanding to be let back into the city.
All major arteries into the city
are clogged with Manhattanites...
...who are jubilant that Godzilla...
Yes, yes, I understand.
- Your office is swamped with calls.
- I know, I know!
Do you have any idea
what's going on out there?
Phones are ringing off the hook.
People are screaming to be let back in.
We're sending divers into the river
for the body.
That thing's dead.
What are you waiting for?
Colonel. Colonel, we've gotta
start a search for the nest.
We've been through this already.
What if Nick is right,
and we blow this whole thing?
This could be the only chance
we have to do something about it.
Captain, organize a search party.
I want a complete sweep of
the entire city and the subway.
You don't have
the authority to do that.
Try and stop me.
Contact the military. Get them to send
a bomber to blow up this building.
- How do I do that?
- 555-7600.
Tell them it's a Code Dragonfly.
That should get you through.
- What are you waiting for?
- 555 what?
- 7600.
- All circuits are busy right now.
- It's busy.
Try again.
What did they say?
I can't get through.
I don't know what's wrong.
We secured the doors
on the upper levels.
Where are Jean-Philippe
and Jean-Pierre?
They didn't make it.
Nick, my men and I will hold them here.
You'll have to go and get help.
You think we could fit up in there?
There's one way to find out.
Boost me up. Boost me up.
This is not good.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Wrong floor.
Why don't we go this way?
- It's me. It's me.
- What happened?
They're loose. They're all over
the place. I couldn't get out.
No one can get out.
- Who the hell are you?
- Audrey?
Here.
- Are you all right?
- I think so.
- No cameras.
- Are you kid...?
Yeah, all right. Very good.
Do you have a radio or walkie-talkie?
Anything to contact the outside?
- What about the phones?
- The circuits are all jammed.
Wait. I know how we can get
a message to the outside.
This way. Come on.
The tape. The tape!
Come on!
Come on. Come on.
- The broadcast booth is over here.
- How do you know that?
Our network covers
the Ranger games.
- It's locked.
- There's a code. There's a code.
Come on. Come on!
I was just about to get it.
The network's on an intranet. It's a
direct feed to our computer system.
Your station won't have any easier
time reaching the military than I did.
When you worked with them,
did they monitor all news broadcasts?
Yeah. Yeah, they did.
All right, we'll go live. Audrey'
we'll broadcast right from in here.
- Hopefully they'll see it.
- I'll try to get a message through.
Let's not forget in our rush
to return to the city...
...that many people have had
their lives changed forever.
No one in the city has been
untouched by the frenzy...
The sick, the displaced,
the injured all need our help...
There's no Ranger game on tonight.
Ed, if you're seeing this, will you
please put us on live? It's urgent!
I know this sounds crazy,
Ed, but you have to do it.
- Please, just trust me.
- I'm not putting you on live.
- I don't think he's gonna do it.
- Yes, he will.
All right, Ed? Come on.
See that, Ed? They're gonna be
all over the city if we don't stop them.
Give me a second, will you?
- Finally it's time to return home.
- Get the diving boats ready.
Our fears have been allayed...
...thanks to the heroic efforts
of our boys in uniform.
Are we on?
- Yeah, good, you're on.
- Are we live?
Yes, yes. You're on. Go!
We're live inside
Madison Square Garden...
...where Niko Dr. Tatopoulos has
discovered the beast's lair.
Doctor, can you please tell us
what's happening here?
- That's you. Yes, go, go.
- Thank you.
Yeah, well, we've discovered
over 200 eggs...
Go get Hicks. Get Hicks!
...which, a few moments ago,
began hatching.
The creatures, though just hatched,
are over 9 feet tall...
...and they've begun feeding.
When their food supply
runs out here...
...they will attempt to hunt down food
of their own outside of this nest.
Oh, my God.
If they get out, they'll multiply, and
very soon a new species will emerge.
One that could replace us as
the dominant species of this planet.
Each one of these amazing reptiles
are born pregnant.
Adaptive and cunning, these 200
could become 40,000 within this year.
If the military is listening
to this broadcast...
...they have to destroy
this building immediately...
...before these creatures
can escape.
So far, they're all trapped
inside this building...
...but I don't think we can
contain them for long.
They're very strong, they're agile,
and they're looking for food.
So I guess your theory
of the creature nesting...
...turned out to be correct after all.
Regardless of what happens to us,
the most important thing...
...is that this building
be destroyed immediately...
...before they can escape
into the city.
Reporting live from
Madison Square Garden...
...this is Audrey Timmonds'
for WIDF News.
Thanks, Audrey.
Sure.
That's affirmative.
Let me spell it out for you.
I want you to blow up
Madison Square Garden.
Well, the good news
is they got that message.
The bad news is we've got less than
six minutes to get out of the building.
Okay, the party's over.
Time to leave.
Anyone care to join me?
- Where did you find this guy?
- He's from France.
Stallion 1-5 is inbound.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Guys, this way. Come on.
Oh, my God. The fish!
Nick, come on!
They've eaten all the fish.
Come on, Nick, this way.
Not this way, back that way!
- The escalators!
- Hurry!
Stallions, check master arms on.
Two, three.
I think I lost them.
Stallion 1-5 showing a good laser track
on top of the Garden. Selecting LGB.
How much time do we have left?
- Less than 30 seconds.
- Oh, God!
Let's go!
Let's go, come on!
Come on! Come on!
Send your Mavericks.
Two away.
Lead has good hits.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Somehow I never thought
your life was this exciting.
You'd be surprised.
I'd like to find out.
- How are you doing? You all right?
- I could use a coffee.
He looks angry.
- What do we do?
- Running would be a good idea.
Let's go!
Come on. Come on!
- Get in, get in.
- What are you doing?
You better step on it, Mr. French.
Take 57th across town
and cut up the West Side.
No, are you crazy? Take the FDR.
- Please! The FDR, in the rain?
- There ought to be a map.
It's getting larger.
Take the Westside Highway.
- I got one.
- No, the West Side's got construction.
This is a subway map!
- Broadway?
- No, no.
Make up your minds!
Broadway! Take Broadway!
Affirmative.
We're traveling down Broadway and...
...make a right on 34th Street.
- That was O'Neal!
- Everybody okay? Everybody all right?
- Turn around. Do it!
- What?
- No.
- What? Why?
Command Center, come in.
Command, this is O'Neal...
O'Neal!
- O'Neal, what's going on?
- He's back, sir. He's back.
Godzilla is still alive.
Lieutenant Rodgers, are those
F-18's still in the air?
- Yes, sir. They're heading back to base.
- Turn them around.
- Here it is. Here it is.
- Sir, what are we looking for?
Every cab company keeps a record
of each of its cabs, radio frequencies.
Bingo.
He's getting closer.
There, there! The tunnel!
Go in the tunnel.
They've got it blocked off.
- Now where would you like to go?
- Turn off the lights.
Nick, are you there? Nick?
O'Neal?
Nice trick with the cab ID.
- Where the hell are you?
- You have to help us.
We're in the...
- Park Avenue Tunnel.
He's got us trapped in here.
- Listen to me.
You guys have got to
lure him out into the open.
So we can get
a clear shot at him. Over.
No problem. Want us to
wash him up for you too?
Where's the nearest
suspension bridge?
Brooklyn. Brooklyn.
- Let's go.
- How would you like us to do that?
Does this thing have high beams?
Now!
Sir, he's headed toward
the Brooklyn Bridge.
Target is heading
toward the Brooklyn Bridge.
Direct the F-18's
to the Brooklyn Bridge.
- He's not following us.
- Really?
Oh, my God!
You gotta be kidding me, man.
We're in his mouth!
You're going the wrong way.
- You're going the wrong way.
- Shut up!
Okay, gun it! Gun it! Go, go, go!
Go, go, go!
Move it, move it, move it!
O'Neal! O'Neal, it worked!
He's caught
in the suspension cables.
- Do it! Now!
- Roger that.
Stallion 1-5, tally one on the bridge.
Lock on and fire at will.
Two away.
Direct hit, but the target
is still moving, sir.
Well, circle around and fire again!
That's my husband!
Oh, my... I'm gonna kill him.
Oh, my. Oh, God. Oh, no.
Wait. We can use this.
- "The mayor who destroyed Godzilla."
- I don't think we should exploit this.
- It could backfire.
- Listen to me, idiot.
I do the thinking here, you idiot.
It's a magnificent idea.
You know what I think about you
and your campaign?
Gene, where you going? I need you.
O'Neal, do you read me?
Yes, sir.
That's one hell of a job, soldier.
That's one hell of a job.
Roger that, sir.
Sorry, folks, I've already promised
my story as an exclusive...
...to another reporter.
We did it! We got the exclusive!
Audrey, you're beautiful.
- We did? I don't think so.
- Remember, you work for me.
Not anymore, Chuck. I quit.
- But you...
- She quits.
Audrey. Audrey.
Did you take the tape
from the camera?
No.
- I mean, I couldn't have just lost it.
- Where's Philippe?
Hello? Hello?
- It's Philippe.
- Where are you?
Tell you friend I'll send the tape...
...after I've removed
a few items from it.
- I understand.
- I just wanted to say au revoir.
Thank you for your help, my friend.
Well, wait... Hello?
Who was that French guy anyway?
Just some insurance guy.
Did he take my...?
Did he say anything about my tape?
Yeah, he said something
about your tape.
- Does he have my tape?
- Yeah, he has your tape.
You'll get it back.
The End
Movie & Captions Conformed By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You've Liked & Enjoyed The Movie !!! "