Come on, you lazy Kaffirs.
Come on.
Keep in line, man. Keep in line.
What are you looking at me
like that for, you fuck?
What are you looking at?
I'll fuck you up!
Move!
You men make sure
that's tied down properly, you hear me?
Careful, man!
- Pa, why is it taking so long?
- Go back to your mother.
Move your feet, move your feet, come on!
I said, go back!
Move!
Sergeant Gregory, Dannie Bosman,
the old skipper for the crossing.
- Your first time to Robben Island?
- I hear the fishing is excellent.
- You'll get bored with that soon enough.
- Ah.
What prison are you from?
Kroonstad Maximum Security.
Well, Robben Island
is a totally different ball game.
All prisoners below deck and secured,
Captain.
Ladies and children, all aboard please!
- Where's your mom?
- Busy putting on her lipstick.
We can board now, sweetie.
- How do I look?
- You look great.
- As long as I don't get seasick.
- It's only an hour.
- Will I be able to get my own bedroom, Pa?
- Of course you will.
I don't want to share with Natasha again.
Who said I want to share with you?
You two stop fighting
and behave yourselves.
Remember, first impressions are everything.
Are all the prisoners
on the island black, Ma?
- All of them.
- But at Kroonstad, they were white.
Now, we don't mix whites and blacks,
not even in the prisons.
These are not just criminals, Brent.
These are terrorists.
But what's the difference?
Terrorists are terrible people.
They want to kill all the whites
and take our land away from us.
Which is why we lock them up on the island.
Sergeant Gregory.
Captain Devett,
the personnel officer on the island.
How do you do, Captain? I'm Gloria...
I have a jeep standing by. This way.
Your furniture will follow.
One, two.
All aboard, Captain.
This is it.
You can stand down for today, Sergeant.
This evening you're expected to attend
an officer's braai at the OC's residence.
Missus included. Full dress uniform.
Gloria, I can't find my step-outs.
Ma is visiting next door, Pa.
Why the toilet outside, Pa?
These houses are old, boet.
They were built during the war.
- What war?
- Second World War.
- But what happens if I need to go at night?
- Then you'll go.
But there are bad people out there.
Boy, the only bad people on this island
are locked up in jail, okay?
Okay, Pa.
James, are you decent?
Yeah, why?
Excuse all the boxes,
but you know how it is.
This is my husband, James.
- How do you do?
- Sannie's kindly offered to baby-sit for us.
- Oh, that's very nice.
Well, Sannie's husband is head chef here.
So, if you ever need anything,
eggs, flour, sugar, you know who to ask.
Just don't say where it came from.
- I can't find my step-outs.
- Under the bed. I polished them.
- And you, James, what's your posting?
- He doesn't know yet.
We'll probably find out this evening.
He must be something special,
'cause the NCOs are never invited
to the Colonel's house.
Not unless they are in deep trouble.
- Serious?
- We don't mix.
Officers here are all bloody snobs.
I've got dinner on the stove. Give me
a shout when you're ready to go, Gloria.
All right. Thanks, Sannie.
Well, I'm starting to get a bit nervous now.
You get in with the officers
and they'll nominate you for a commission.
You have to be a warrant officer first, Gloria.
This is not Worcester, James.
This is not Kroonstad.
This is Robben Island,
the number one prison in the country.
You play your cards right and who knows,
in five years you could be at head office
in Pretoria.
Dream on.
I think I'm going to give you
a quick little haircut before we go.
Christ, woman, you never stop.
- Oh, come on.
- Never.
You don't have to wait
to go to the mainland.
I'm a fully qualified hairdresser.
- Really?
- And I'm good.
Highlights is what you need. A bit of flair,
then you'll see the heads turning.
Well, are we going to keep you busy,
or what?
This is no holiday camp, Sergeant.
You got warders stuck out here
for two weeks at a time.
It's a recipe for alcohol abuse,
for prostitution...
Prostitution?
We've got married NCOs pimping
their wives out to single warders
to supplementing their shitty salaries.
I hope Captain Devett
is not painting too bad a picture of us.
- Welcome to the island, Gregory.
- It's an honor to be here, sir.
I see our wives are already making friends.
Thank you for inviting us, sir.
There's someone who wants to meet you.
Excuse us, Captain.
This is Major Piet Jordaan,
from the Bureau of State Security.
I believe you speak
the Kaffir languages, Sergeant.
- I speak Xhosa, sir.
- Where did you learn the language?
I grew up on a cattle farm in Transkei.
When you've got no brothers to play with,
you end up playing with the Kaffirs, sir.
Shall we take a walk, Sergeant?
So, what do you think of the judgment
handed down in Mandela's trial?
In my opinion,
he should have got the rope, sir.
Oh, then we could have turned him
into a martyr.
Perhaps he's more use to us behind bars.
That's a waste of taxpayers' money,
is what I say. They all are.
All blacks?
Certainly the ones who took up
arms against us. The communists.
Mandela denies he's a communist.
Well, they're all liars, aren't they?
You know, in the 1800s,
this whole island was a leper colony.
Nothing's really changed then.
How do you feel about heading up
the censorship office in B-section?
Excuse my ignorance, sir,
but what is B-section?
That's where we keep Mandela
and all his mates.
I need someone on the inside,
someone who speaks their language.
I want to know what they think,
how they think.
Anything you find odd in their letters
or their visits,
you report directly back to me.
I want you to be my window into their soul,
if they have a soul.
And here I was thinking
I was going to spend my first year
working bloody nightshifts.
- You can if you want.
- No. Please, no, sir.
It would be an honor for me
to run the censorship office.
I won't let you down.
You let me down,
you let your country down.
- I would never do such a thing.
- Of course not.
Well, I don't know about you,
but I'm bloody starving.
Let's go and get something to eat.
- They asleep?
- Finally.
Too much bloody excitement.
The Colonel's wife, Joyce,
is coming over tomorrow for a cut.
She bakes so she'll pay with a cake.
And Hettie,
you know that nice captain's wife?
Her husband dives for crayfish
so that's how she'll pay.
And that woman with the gray hair...
- Gloria.
- What?
They're putting me with Mandela and Sisulu
and them.
No.
They want me in charge
of the censorship office.
My God, James,
why didn't you say something?
Wasn't going to blow my trumpet
in front of all those bloody officers.
This is big, my boy. Mandela.
Never mind that, I report directly to Pretoria.
This is fantastic.
Did they say anything about a promotion?
In due course, I was told.
No more discipline order for me.
From now on, I'm in charge of the worst
terrorist this country's ever seen.
Do you know how many bridges
he's blown up?
Do you know how many police stations
he and his Umkhonto we Sizwe
have bombed?
Didn't I say this was going to be our island
in the sun? Didn't I say that, James?
You sure did, Booky.
Put your backs into it, you lazy Kaffirs!
Get up, you slack bastards!
Three days off rations for insubordination.
Attention!
I'm your new censorship officer!
If you want to post a letter,
you do it through me!
One letter every six months,
no longer than 500 words.
No reference to other prisoners,
no mention of prison conditions.
And no bloody politics.
If you fail to adhere to these regulations,
your letters will not be posted.
If you receive a letter, it comes through me.
Same story. One every six months.
Any mention of politics
and that letter will be censored.
Is that clear?
You fuck with me and I'll make your life
a lot more miserable than it already is.
And I'll enjoy doing so.
Which one is Mandela?
He's in solitary.
Five days for talking in the passage.
Right! Back to work!
Let's see you breaking some rocks!
Last one on the right.
It's nice and damp in there.
Hey, you.
I'm talking to you, man. Look at me!
I'll see you, Mandela
Mrs. Mandela, Sergeant Gregory.
I'll be monitoring your visit.
- How do you do, Sergeant?
- Follow me.
Vosloo, let's call prisoner 466l64 to Booth 3.
Here, please.
You speak only in English.
And only about family matters.
Prisoner ready.
You have 30 minutes, starting now.
- How are you, Madiba?
- Compose yourself.
We don't have much time.
How are our daughters?
They can't sleep at night.
Terrified the security will come
and bash down our door.
That is political, Mrs. Mandela.
It is not. It is about our family.
There is too much harassment
from all sides all the time.
It is upsetting the girls.
George Bizos suggests we send them
to a boarding school in Swaziland.
They'll come home on holidays.
Will you cope being alone?
When I married you,
I knew I was marrying the struggle.
Have you heard from Evelyn?
She has a job at the mines, typing.
Thembi came to visit.
How is my son?
He's a man now.
He has his driver's license and his own car.
Tell him I'm allowed another visit
in six months' time.
He has to put in an application.
I will tell him.
How are our friends in Lusaka?
Oliver has been appointed
President General of the ANC.
English only.
Tell Oliver that all of us in here
agree he should escalate the armed struggle.
The people must make
this country ungovernable.
That's it.
Vosloo, this visit is terminated.
This way, please.
No, please,
we were talking about family matters.
Do you think I'm stupid?
Vosloo, escort the prisoner back to his cell.
Follow me.
On your feet, Mandela, move!
Gregory!
- That was quick.
- They started talking in Xhosa.
About what?
Mandela told her to instruct Oliver Tambo
to escalate the armed struggle.
He said they must make
the country ungovernable.
- Anything else?
- Family stuff.
Kids going off to boarding school,
that sort of thing.
When Winnie gets back to Joburg,
she's going to be detained indefinitely.
It's going to be front-page news.
I'll send you a clipping.
Make sure Mandela gets it.
No problem.
Oh, one small thing.
She mentioned his son Thembi,
the one from his first marriage.
He's got his driver's license.
He even has his own car.
- He probably stole the bloody thing.
- Right.
Highlights really
look fantastic on you.
- Hello, sweetie.
- Ladies.
- How was your day?
- Good. Where are the kids?
Switch on the kettle, won't you?
Make us all a nice cup of tea.
- What do you think, James?
- About what?
Her hair.
Oh, it's nice.
Nice? Please, it's stunning.
Wait till Jan sees it.
You're in for a busy night, my girl.
I believe Mama Africa
paid us a visit today, James.
You girls seem to know everything.
Nothing happens on this island
without me finding out about it.
Usually before it happens.
So what's she like?
She was only there five minutes.
They started talking Xhosa
so I sent her packing.
James speaks fluent Xhosa.
- Really?
- He grew up with them on a farm.
He had a friend called...
What was his name?
Man, who cares?
- No, man, tell us.
- Please tell us, James.
Bafana.
James has got a photo of the two of them.
I'll get it.
Gloria, no. Gloria!
- No, I want to see it.
- Me, too.
Didn't know you were a farm boy, James.
- I'm not a farm boy.
- Here it is. Look.
Oh, cute. Look at the little Kaffir lover.
I'm not a Kaffir lover!
He's even got his arm
around the little nigger.
That's it.
- Looks like a Kaffir-lover to me!
I'm going fishing. Brent, get your rod!
Look, Pa, a starfish.
- That's nice, Natasha.
- Pa, I've got one.
Hey, bring him through the rocks there.
Nice and slow, that's it.
Hey, don't look at me, man.
Don't look at me.
I'm not your bloody mother, man.
- Give me that, Brent. Come here.
- Move it! Bastard!
Natasha, come here, girl.
Stay down. Stay there.
- Pa, what about my fish?
- Never mind your fish.
- Faster, faster, faster!
- Come, come, come!
Are you trying to piss me off?
- Get down, boy!
- But, Pa...
Move it, you lazy bastards.
All right then, we can go back now.
Come on. Okay?
Move it!
But what about my fish?
I'm sorry, boy, but if those warders
had seen you, I'd be in big trouble.
- Why?
- Prisoners aren't allowed to see children.
- Why not?
- Because they are here for punishment.
Okay?
Huh.
This is from Motsadi's wife.
"We have decided to boycott the bus service
as they have increased the fare by 80 cents."
Cut it out.
The following,
please collect your letters.
Sisulu.
Mhlaba.
Kathadra, hurry up.
Do you think I've got all day?
Motsadi! Jonas Motsadi! Where's Motsadi?
The rest of you are dismissed.
Mr. Gregory, I found this in my cell.
According to regulations,
no prisoner may be in possession
of any newspaper or part thereof.
Therefore, I am handing it over to you,
the proper authority.
I am surprised that you did not look
at the article, Mr. Gregory.
- Come on! Come on!
- That's it. Yes, go, Robben Island.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Ah!
- He's really got something, hey, darling?
- Very good.
Gregory, for a postman,
you play a damn good game of rugby.
- Robben Island!
- Robben Island.
I think it's time I had a word with Piet
about James.
He's officer material,
there's no question about it.
Oh, Joyce. I'll do your hair for free
for the rest of your life.
Then I'm definitely going to talk with Piet.
- Off to Cape Town for the weekend?
- Yeah, my mom's been dying to see the kids.
It's been ages.
Then I'm going to give you
a little shopping list
with a good mayonnaise at the top.
I can't stand this prison issue stuff.
- Granny!
Hello, my darlings!
These are for you.
I found them on the beach.
- Oh, they're beautiful.
- Hi, Mom.
- How was the ferry?
- Fine. The sea was flat for a change.
- Oh, good.
- I got you some fresh crayfish, Barbara.
Oh!
Never mind fresh, they're alive!
Well, seeing as you didn't get seasick,
we can go shopping.
- Nelson Mandela. That's awful.
- Yeah, it's a big responsibility.
James gets to check their mail
and monitors all their visits.
That's restricted information, Gloria.
Oh, for goodness sake,
Mom's not going to tell anyone.
Gloria, come help me choose
some salad stuff quickly.
I'll wait outside with the kids. Come here.
The two of you, stand still.
Passport. Where's your passport?
Let me see your passports.
- Where's your passport?
- Your pass.
You have no pass. Come, come, come.
What's going on, Pa?
Passports. Where is your pass?
They are checking for passes.
- Come back here. Where's your pass?
- No! No!
Come back, come back.
Hey, freeze, Kaffir.
I need some help over here.
Get in the van!
Where's your pass?
- I don't have it!
You can't just leave the baby here!
Hey, shut up!
It's none of your business.
I'll take him. He's my daughter's child.
It's all right. It's all right. It's all right.
It's okay.
Maybe you should go talk to her.
Another minute and these'll be done, okay?
Feeling better?
- Dinner's almost ready.
- Why didn't you stop that policeman?
Because that's his job.
To take the mommy away from the baby?
No, but if the mommy doesn't have a pass,
then she's not allowed to be there.
So they had to arrest her.
Do we have a pass?
- We don't need one.
- Why not?
Because we're white.
- But is that fair, Pa?
- That's apartheid.
It's the way we live, Natasha.
Whites on one side, blacks on the other.
It's God's way, darling.
Just like he doesn't
put a sparrow with a swallow.
Or a goose with a duck
or a cow with a buck.
It's just not natural.
And we don't question God.
Hmm?
Switchboard.
Pretoria 39001.
Jordaan.
Gregory here.
A telegram just arrived for Mandela.
I know, the boy smashed head on
into a bridge.
- Was it...
- What?
You know. Is it an accident?
Of course.
You'll tell him personally, won't you?
Yeah.
Let me know his reaction.
What's up?
Mandela's older son
was killed in a car crash.
Good riddance.
Do you have kids?
Dig. Hey, work, you Kaffir!
Who the fuck is Madiba?
- Madiba is Mandela's clan name.
- Clan?
Go tell him.
Mandela, I'm sorry.
Hey, what are you trying to do, man?
Get back to work.
- Vann Niekerk, can I have a word?
- What?
Regulation 16-A of the Prison Act states
that if a prisoner loses a family member
they are entitled to two days off work
on compassionate grounds.
- Compassionate grounds?
- Mandela's a lawyer.
He knows these things. You don't want him
laying a charge against you, do you?
I can escort him back to his cell, if you like.
Earlier today,
South African forces intercepted
a large group of SWAPO insurgents
in South West Africa, killing 12...
- Would you like some more?
- Yes, please.
...and arresting five. There were no reports...
Thank you.
...of casualties on the South African side.
Dr. Christian...
Your food's getting cold.
- What if it was murder?
- Not in front of the children.
James!
They'd never do such a thing.
I called the police in the Transkei.
I spoke to the duty officer.
The more questions I asked,
the more he clammed up.
Eventually he hung up on me.
- That doesn't mean...
- Can I serve the jelly, Ma?
Go ahead, darling.
I was the one who told Jordaan
that Thembi had a license, that he had a car.
You're doing your job.
This country is at war, James.
These people are savages.
They don't want to share
this country with us. They hate us.
If they had their way, they'd drive
every single white person into the sea.
They'd leave us with nothing,
not even the clothes on our back.
Yeah. I know.
Come and have pudding.
All right, you win this time.
There won't be a next time.
I'll come back and visit.
I promise I will, Bafana.
My father says
you are going too far to ever return.
I have to go.
This tail will protect you
the rest of your days.
I will wear this forever.
- I see you, Madiba.
- I see you, Mr. Gregory.
I want you to know that I am very sorry
about the death of your son.
Many times I tried to explain
to my son why I was always away from home,
that I fight for a better world,
for my people and my family.
I'm not sure he ever understood.
Where did you learn to speak Xhosa,
Mr. Gregory?
I grew up
near where you were born.
Then you understand.
I need to bury my son.
- You know they'll never allow it.
- I'm an honorable man.
I give you my word I will not try to escape.
It's not you.
It's your communist friends,
what if they try to rescue you?
What communist friends
are you referring to, Mr. Gregory?
The whole of the bloody
African National Congress.
Obviously, you have not read
the Freedom Charter.
- I have.
- You have not. It is a banned document.
Where would a sergeant
in the Prison Services
get his hands on such a document?
Well, I know about it.
Then you would know
that all we want is equal rights for all,
a world where people like you and I
can live peacefully side by side.
That is what I wanted for my child.
Surely, you want the same for your children.
I wish to be alone now.
- Motsadi, Mandela must eat.
- When our leader is ready to eat, he will eat.
You tell him his son was buried yesterday,
that the boy's mother was at the funeral.
- Have you read the Freedom Charter?
- What?
- The Freedom Charter, have you read it?
- No.
Do you know what it's about?
It's about the extermination of the whites.
- Stuff like that, isn't it?
- How must I know?
Pa, can we go watch Province
play against Natal on Saturday?
- Maybe.
- Yes!
I just need to quickly pop
into Roeland Street Prison.
- But my mom's got lunch waiting for us.
- You go ahead. I'll be on the next train.
But Roeland Street is not...
Go, kids! Go.
Excuse me, I understand there's
a section here containing banned literature.
- Downstairs.
- Thank you.
- Yes?
- I'm with the Prison Services.
I'd like to take a look
at the Freedom Charter.
Wait here.
- You got authorization?
- What?
This is a restricted area.
You need authorization to be here.
Sergeant Gregory.
I'm a warder at Robben Island prison.
So? You need authorization
from the security police
if you want to look at banned material.
Listen here, Major Jordaan
of the Bureau of State Security
personally instructed me
to take a look at the Freedom Charter.
Call him. It's Pretoria 39001.
Give him what he wants.
Sit there.
- You'll find it in there.
- Thank you.
"We, the People of South Africa,
"declare for all our country
and the world to know
"that South Africa belongs to all
who live in it, black and white,
"and that no government
can justly claim authority
"unless it is based on
the will of the people. "
- What are you doing here, James?
- What are you doing here?
I can't believe you did that.
How can you lie to me?
Gloria, I'm working with them.
I need to know how they tick.
I'll tell you how they tick, James.
They tick like a time bomb.
And then they blow up, boom!
Sit up straight.
Afternoon.
Can you imagine what would happen
if Piet found out about this?
You could kiss your promotion goodbye,
that's for sure.
Please, man, what promotion?
- I promised Joyce I wouldn't say anything.
- About what?
Come on, Gloria, you can't keep a secret.
Piet put a recommendation into Pretoria
that you be promoted to warrant officer.
He even told Joyce if you carry on
the way you are,
you'll be lieutenant at the end of the year.
Well, that's very nice.
Not if you throw it all away
by doing something stupid.
I'm not going to do anything stupid.
With the salary you get and the little I make,
we can't even afford to buy the kids
new school shoes.
Come on, Gloria. Come on.
- It's not that bad, Gloria.
- James.
The Prison Service is all we've got.
Christ, they even own the house we live in.
I'm not going to mess things up. Okay?
Look at me. Okay?
Plumstead is up next.
I don't want your mom seeing you like this.
- Hey, man. How was your weekend?
- Good.
- Did you go watch the Province match?
- No, but they nailed them good.
Are you looking at me?
Don't you look at me. Move it!
Come, come, come.
You slack bastards! Move it!
Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up!
- The post will have arrived by now.
- Not with this southeaster blowing.
- That ferry will be an hour late, at least.
- Go check anyway.
"The national wealth of our
country, the heritage of South Africans,
"shall be restored to the people.
"The mineral wealth, the banks,
industry shall be transferred... "
The ferry hasn't even left Cape Town harbor.
- It must be pretty rough out there.
- You can say that again.
Mandela, I have a question for you.
You claim the ANC is not communist,
but the Freedom Charter says
that the mineral wealth,
the banks and industry
shall be transferred to the people.
That is communism,
and don't try to bullshit me otherwise.
It is not. It is in fact true nationalism,
where all the people,
white, black, colored, Indian,
all benefit from the accumulated wealth
of the land.
Our land and your land, Mr. Gregory.
- These are ideals you'd kill for?
- These are ideals I would die for.
It's not justification for murder
and you know it.
You people should never
have taken up arms against us.
You white people were deaf to our pleas,
blind to our suffering.
You left us no choice but to take up arms.
Sergeant!
- Sir!
What are you doing cavorting
with a prisoner?
I was just telling Mandela his lawyer
is coming on Monday for a consultation, sir.
- Get your arse up here.
- On my way, sir.
Raise your arms.
- Sir, I can...
- Raise your bloody arms, Sergeant!
Congratulations, Warrant Officer.
I'll see you in the clubhouse.
Thank you, sir.
For he's a jolly good fellow
And so say all of us
To James!
And may his promotion not go to his head
and cause us a lot of heartache!
Cheers, James.
Officer Gregory, may I have the pleasure
of dancing with you?
Didn't I say this would happen? Didn't I?
You sure did, Booky.
What you going to do about it?
Switchboard.
Pretoria 39001.
Jordaan.
I've got a postcard here for Jonas Motsadi.
Motsadi. Isn't he due for release next week?
Yes. There's a message written inside it
in Xhosa.
What does it say?
It says he must go
to an ANC safe house in Gaborone
and from there, he'll receive instructions.
Is there an address?
36 Moroka Street, Gaborone, Botswana.
Put the message back just how you found it
and make sure that Jonas Motsadi
gets his little postcard.
...of local cricket supporters.
Included in the team
are such esteemed players
as Bob Willis, Tony Greig...
Watch your queen.
...and Trevor Chappell.
In the early hours of this morning,
the South African Defense Force
launched a pre-emptive strike
on a known ANC safe house
in Gaborone, Botswana,
killing four terrorists.
One of the men, Jonas Motsadi,
was recently released
from Robben Island Prison
where he was serving five years
for sabotage.
That's us, Pa. Robben Island.
Did you know him?
The weather forecast
for the Western Cape tomorrow
is cloudy with occasional fog patches,
clearing later with moderate
to fresh westerly winds...
It's your move, Pa.
Go, move it! Yes, yes, yes!
Faster.
Are you sure
my wife is on the ferry?
I called ahead.
It will be Christmas soon.
- My kids are already counting the days.
How are they doing in school here?
My son struggles a bit,
but my daughter is sharp as nails.
You must encourage them
to do well in school
so they can go to university
and make something of their lives.
University is expensive, man.
Although you bloody people
think it should be
"free, compulsory, universal
and equal for all children," isn't it?
That is a direct quote
from the Freedom Charter.
I am most impressed, Mr. Gregory.
Mr. Gregory,
I have a favor to ask.
I have a small Christmas present for Winnie
and I was hoping you could give it to her.
No, man, Mandela.
Now you're going too far.
It's just a small chocolate.
Where the hell
did you get a chocolate from?
That is of no consequence.
I could have you in solitary
right this bloody minute!
I have not seen my wife for two years.
For God's sake, man,
where is your humanity?
Where is it?
Drop it and walk on.
- I'll escort Mrs. Mandela from here.
- My orders are to remain with her...
I am in charge of visits on this island,
and you will remain on this bloody ferry
until it leaves! Please.
I see you, Madiba.
What have they done to you, Namzamu?
They dragged me from our daughters.
They beat me.
English only.
Please, Mrs. Mandela,
you have very little time. Don't waste it.
Mr. Gregory is right.
From Nelson.
He says it's your Christmas present.
Have a safe journey, Mrs. Mandela.
Warrant Officer!
You recognize this?
That's Govan Mbeki's writing.
It was intercepted by Security Branch
at the Soweto post office.
Since when are prisoners allowed
to discuss other prisoners in their letters?
I would never have allowed this through.
Vosloo must have missed it.
You're in charge of the Censor Office,
not Vosloo.
- Make sure this doesn't happen again.
- Yes, sir.
- Nice work with Jonas Motsadi.
- Thank you, sir.
- Warrant Officer Gregory.
- Gregory, get your arse over here!
I'm on my way, sir.
Enter!
What is the meaning of this?
It says here, they sat under a tree,
ate bread and cheese
and finished it up
with a dessert of chocolate.
You know the media,
they always exaggerate.
Are you telling me
there's some truth in this?
Mandela gave me a little chocolate
to give to Winnie.
- That's all that happened, sir.
- A little chocolate?
- That was her Christmas present.
- Are you completely mad?
We are trying to demoralize this terrorist,
trying to isolate him from his family,
and here you are playing Santa Claus.
How do you know there wasn't a message
in that chocolate?
I checked it before I gave it to her.
And if it had been poisoned?
- Nelson would never do such a thing.
- Since when was he "Nelson"?
Next thing,
you'll be wiping his fucking arse!
I apologize, sir. It was my mistake.
Let me tell you how
you are going to pay for this.
For the next four months,
you will spend every off weekend
doing night duty in B-section.
Are you happy with this?
Or would you rather I stripped you
of your rank, Warrant Officer?
- I'm happy with night duty, sir.
- Get out of here!
- Yes?
- Colonel, the Minister of Prisons...
James Gregory, you swine.
Do you know what trouble you've caused?
Sorry?
They should be transferring you
off the island, not us!
What's going on?
Pretoria just called.
They told Piet to pack his bags!
They are transferring us to Barberton.
Do you know how hot it is in Barberton?
I don't understand.
They said that Piet is running
a holiday camp here instead of a prison,
- and all because of you, James Gregory!
- Joyce, don't shout like that at James.
- If you've got something to say come inside.
- Oh, I will not step foot inside that house!
After everything we've done for you.
What on earth was that all about?
- I gave Winnie Mandela a chocolate from...
- James.
I don't know what all the fuss is about.
Well, we can forget about
you making lieutenant now.
Maybe there are more important things
to think about than making lieutenant.
Do you have a home to go to, Sannie?
My name is Stander,
and you will remember my name
until the day you die!
Most of you bastards
joined the prison service
because you were too cowardly
to join the police or the army.
The army that is right now
defending our borders
against the communist masses
trying to infiltrate our beloved fatherland.
And the police,
who are fighting in the townships
so that your wives and mothers
and daughters and sisters
can sleep safely in their beds at night
and not get raped by fucking Kaffirs
while you sit comfortably on your arses
on paradise fucking island.
Well, that all changes as from today,
because this island is now my island.
And the war will be fought on my island
the same way
that it is fought against SWAPO
on the borders
and the ANC and the PAC in the townships.
Your enemy is behind these walls,
and you are at war with them.
Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
Is that fucking clear?
- Yes, sir!
Move you, Kaffir dogs! Stand in line!
Come on!
Welcome to hell, you heathen bastards.
We're freedom fighters.
We are not heathens.
Thank you, Boytjie. I don't want that animal
bleeding in my prison.
Chain him to the flag post,
so he remembers forever
what flag flies above this land.
Strip search.
Beer, please.
How you doing, Dannie?
Not bad.
So, they're finally going to
let us have television,
20 years after the rest of the world.
Suit yourself, Dannie.
Yes, two triple brandies, please.
Is this him?
You don't have a chocolate for me, too,
do you?
Very funny.
So, tell us about Mandela.
What does he write in those letters
to his fat, black, bitch wife, huh?
I'm trying to have a quiet drink here.
Go on Gregory, tell us, man.
Vann Niekerk, do you have any idea why
the prisoners call you Mbukane?
I don't speak Kaffir, so how would I know?
Let me tell you. It means one of those great
big green flies that feasts on human shit.
- Really?
- Really.
So, tell me, is it true what they say
about Gloria, your wife?
What?
That at night you take her up to the prison
so your darky friends can snack
on some white pussy.
Fucking Kaffir lover!
That's enough! That's enough!
James, James, go home to Gloria, James.
Here's his coat.
Jesus! What happened to you?
Nothing. I fell off my bike. It's the rain.
I'll get some ice.
Lynette's having a tea party tomorrow
to welcome Colonel Stander's wife
to the island.
That's very nice.
I haven't been invited.
She probably forgot to call you.
According to Anne, Lynette doesn't
want Kaffir-lover wives at the party.
Fuck them! All of them!
Don't swear like that.
What can I say?
Not much, James.
Even the officers' wives have stopped
coming to have their hair done.
I'm sorry, Gloria.
How could you let things
get to this point, James?
I think if you met Mandela,
you'd understand better.
I heard of a really nice,
small prison near East London
called Fort Glamorgan. They say
it's very pretty on the east coast.
You want me to put in for a transfer?
How would you feel about that?
I'd love to get off this island,
the sooner, the bloody better.
I was hoping you would say that.
And I thought you wanted to stay.
So much for our island in the sun, eh?
Your man on the inside,
does he know why we're coming?
Not yet.
I keep him in the dark most of the time.
You think Mandela will go for it?
In my opinion, no.
Then why in God's name are we doing this?
Public relations.
You've got a visitor.
This is Mr. Kruger, Minister of Prisons.
So, how are you enjoying
living on this island, Mandela?
Our cells are damp,
the food is not fit for human consumption,
we are treated worse than
common criminals, and you ask me
how am I enjoying it?
I have a proposition for you
that could change all that.
What? One man, one vote?
Free and fair elections for all?
If you and the African National Congress
agree to discontinue the armed struggle,
you can leave this island.
We will let you and your family go live
in Transkei.
Then I would rather remain here
on this island.
Then you are more stupid
than I even thought you were.
We are finished here, Major.
Major.
I put in for a transfer to Glamorgan, but it
was turned down by someone in Pretoria.
Yeah, I turned it down.
Why?
You got a problem with the job here?
The school here only goes up to standard 5.
My son goes to high school next year.
Well, send him to boarding school.
I was at boarding school, and no son
of mine will ever go to a boarding school.
We need you here, Gregory.
These are difficult times.
You must put your country first.
My family comes first.
I'll put in another application.
If it's rejected again, I'll resign.
You're gonna throw away your pension?
Don't be stupid, man.
I'm telling you now, I will resign.
Nobody wants an ex-prison warder.
If you resign, you will be out on the street.
Then where will your family be?
You think about that.
Hey, darling.
Rejected again.
We'll manage, James.
We can stay with my mom.
I'll find a job at a salon. We'll get by.
It's not just our future that worries me.
Every time I switch on the radio, all I hear
is another riot, another car bomb,
another suspect who's been chucked out
of the window by the police.
Another landmine.
Is this the country our kids
are growing up in, Gloria?
God help us.
Colonel, my letter of resignation.
I'm giving you two weeks' notice.
- I don't have a problem with this.
- I didn't expect you to.
But Pretoria might have a problem with it.
Well, fuck Pretoria.
Gregory! Haven't you forgotten something?
What?
You salute an officer.
What are you going to do, fire me?
Morning, Mrs. Gregory. Is James here?
Wait here.
What are you doing here?
To be honest,
I didn't think you'd call my bluff.
Really?
I got an offer for you.
Let's call it a compromise.
We both want something from each other.
You want to get off the island, and I want
you to keep working with Mandela and them.
You understand them
and you speak their language.
Get to the point.
I can arrange for all the mail from B-section
to be routed through Roeland Street Prison.
You can do everything from there,
without ever setting foot on the island.
- What about visits?
- Vosloo can handle them.
Accommodation?
It so happens that the Prison Service has
a house standing vacant in Plumstead,
quite near to where your mother lives,
Mrs. Gregory.
You've thought of everything.
This is a one-time offer.
I want an answer now.
Yes or no.
Give us a minute.
What do you think?
I think you just won a major battle
for the Gregory family.
Gregory.
You've been rather quiet, lately.
There's been nothing to report.
What, they're finally behaving themselves?
You have time for a beer?
Gloria will be expecting me.
Come on, just a quick one.
So, I believe your son's following
in your footsteps.
Not for long.
He just started his first year at university.
Doing it through correspondence.
Once he gets his degree, he'll be out
of the Prison Services in a flash.
A warder's son at university,
that's a turn up for the books, huh?
He's got Mandela to thank for that.
"Make sure your
children go to university, Mr. Gregory.
"South Africa needs
well-educated young people.
"They will be our future leaders."
- How is he?
- He always asks after you.
Yeah, he's getting on a bit,
but then I suppose we all are.
What do you think of this
Free Mandela campaign?
That's the least of our worries.
Big problem is the international sanctions.
It's crippling us economically.
Yeah, you know something's wrong
when petrol costs more than beer.
Why, do you think we should let him out?
You mad?
With Botha in power, you'll never have him.
Yeah, I suppose you're right there.
- Well, thanks for the beer.
- My pleasure.
I'll see you around, Major.
We clear?
Yeah, I think we can trust Gregory.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
- See you later. Bye.
- Bye.
Hey, sweetie. How was your day?
Same. Yours?
Brent, you should be studying,
not working on that stupid car.
Didn't I send for some plugs, Pa?
Check in the shed for new ones.
- Pa, there's a call for you.
- I'll be right there.
- Hello.
- Brigadier Morkel, James.
We need you at Pollsmoor tonight.
- Tonight?
- Yes, it's very important.
Make sure to be there at 2000.
I understand, Brigadier. I'll be there.
Do I smell curry?
It's just a chicken curry.
- How did the exam go?
- Not bad.
- Mmm! Not bad or good?
- Good.
Would you like a G&T?
Yeah, just a little one.
You go wash your hands before dinner.
Authorities believe that ANC terrorists
were responsible for the blasts.
According to the report,
there were no casualties,
and damage to the facility was superficial.
And now, for a look at tomorrow's weather...
That was Brigadier Morkel.
I have to report at the Pollsmoor
at 2000 hours.
What for?
He wouldn't say.
Is it Mandela?
Can't be, not if it's Pollsmoor.
Good evening.
Turn left, first road.
- Captain.
- Gregory, follow me.
Evening, James.
Sorry to spring this on you
at such short notice, sir.
- This is...
- General Voster.
Of the National Intelligence Service.
Previously known as the
Bureau of State Security.
Things in this country seem to be changing
so quickly, it almost astounds me.
I don't understand.
Tomorrow we'll be transferring you here
to take charge of Mandela
and four of his fellow prisoners.
You will be working with Brigadier Morkel,
directly under my command.
Yes?
They've just passed through the main gate.
We're going to be easing up
restrictions on visits,
mail, study time, newspapers, the lot.
Sir, I have a home in Plumstead. My wife
has a job there, my daughter's busy with...
You have nothing to worry about, James.
We have lots of accommodation for you here
and your family. Everything's sorted.
Why me?
You were the only warden from Robben
Island they never laid a charge against.
Not that that's a recommendation
in my book.
Go that way.
- It's been a long time, Nelson.
- Where are we, Mr. Gregory?
At Pollsmoor Maximum Security.
- You still up?
- Yeah, Villages is on.
What's happening? You want some tea?
I was going to ask you the same question.
Or would you prefer coffee?
- James!
- What?
- What happened at Pollsmoor?
- You won't believe it.
Well, maybe if you tell me, I will.
They've moved Mandela
and four of his comrades there.
I want tea, not coffee.
After 18 years on that bloody island.
So, what did they need you there for?
- They want to transfer me.
- Not again.
You'll be in the bloody car
three hours a day.
They want me on 24-hour notice
at the prison.
They've asked me to head up
the Mandela detail. Brent will be in it.
It'll be a whole new unit
under my command.
You can't decide something like this
without discussing it with me first.
They gave me no option.
Who's they?
General Voster, National Intelligence.
What about Natasha? Did you think of her?
She can take the train.
The train's a great place for her to study.
Gives her lots of time.
- Why did they move him?
- Because they're scared.
Can you imagine what would happen
if he died on that island?
There'd be a bloodbath.
- He could easily die in Pollsmoor.
- I don't know.
Maybe they're ready to start negotiating.
Don't be naive.
They don't negotiate with terrorists.
What? You think this can go on?
The country's going up in flames, man.
They bombed Joburg yesterday.
Next thing they'll blow up parliament,
then they'll start blowing up schools,
the railway stations.
But you think it's all right for Natasha
to catch the train every day?
Jesus, James.
Listen to me.
These last five years have probably been
the most boring of my life.
I go to that little office in Roeland Street,
and I open letters, and I read them,
then I fold them, put them back
and send them off. I need a change.
These could be extraordinary times.
I don't want to look back on my life
and say I stood on the sidelines.
This could be history in the making,
and I want to be a part of it.
It better be a house with a garden.
Thank you.
Chris, where does this lead?
It connects D-section with E.
- Secure it, I want it sealed off.
- I'll see to it.
Why is this man alone?
From now on, we work in pairs.
Two guards on each post.
Yes, sir.
Morning, gentlemen.
Mr. Gregory.
We are still waiting for an explanation.
- Well, I hear rumors.
- Rumors? What rumors?
They say you had too much influence
over the other prisoners on the island.
This is my son, Brent. He'll be assisting me.
- All in order?
- Yes, sir.
Chris.
- How far away is that mountain?
- About two miles.
Is it state owned or private?
I think it belongs to National Parks Board.
Find out.
How's it, Raymond?
- What's all the stuff doing outside?
- I'm putting it in storage.
How are you going to cut hair
without your table?
I've had a sign up outside for a week
and not one person's come.
They go to the mall for that kind of thing.
Besides, this place is too small.
You can hardly move in here.
It's a roof over our heads, Gloria.
You call this a roof?
I can hear the people bonking next door.
Where's Natasha?
She's sick of spending
half the day on the train.
She's going to stay over at my mom's
and visit on weekends.
Help me with the TV. I want it in the corner.
Wait. Mind your back.
Brent met Mandela
for the first time this morning.
And?
Yeah, I know, he said it was
like meeting an old uncle.
...have been deployed in Soweto
to quell widespread violence and unrest
sparked by demonstrators calling for the
unconditional release of Nelson Mandela.
The spokesperson for
the South African police force
said many arrests have been made, and the
situation had been brought under control.
Switch it off.
- For your tomato plants.
- Thank you, Mr. Gregory.
- And how are you, Brent?
- I'm fine, Mr. Mandela.
That's good.
Show me what
you're made of, Mr. Gregory.
Defend yourself for I am a young ox.
You are talking to a bull.
Pa, what are you doing?
Stand back, Brent.
Come on, Warrant Officer.
It seems you know more than
just our language, Mr. Gregory.
Pa, where did you learn that? Pa?
You should put some ice on it.
It's not right.
Most of these people were civilians,
ordinary people going about
their daily business!
That's it, have a good look, man.
Have a good look!
For goodness sake.
Hey man, hey man.
In 1976, when the police opened fire
on Soweto school children,
how many were left dead in the streets?
Thousands and thousands!
Huh, what about those injured?
And now you want to cry about 17 people?
What is that, hey, get lost man!
Wait, you knew me in '76, Raymond.
Did I celebrate the death of those children
with the rest of the warders
at Robben Island? Did I?
I was horrified by it, horrified!
This is also wrong!
You could stop this.
You could put an end to this violence.
How?
Tell your people in Lusaka
to end the armed struggle.
Mr. Gregory,
do you honestly think that
if we laid down arms today,
the apartheid regime would cease
their acts of violence against our people?
It's a vicious circle.
I have waited 20 years for your people
to come and talk to me about peace,
but they are not interested in peace.
They are only interested in power.
So are you.
When those in power deny your freedom,
the only path to freedom is power.
Turn the TV, Pa. Botha's giving a speech.
- Where's your mother?
- She took the car.
She's got an interview at a new salon
opening up in Cape Town.
She said she can't sit around
waiting for her life to restart.
Good for her.
...people who put
pressure on South Africa,
from outside and from within.
I stated in Parliament that if
Mr. Mandela gives a commitment
that he will not make
himself guilty of planning...
The guy can talk a lot of shit, eh, Pa?
They're all the same.
...I will, in principle,
be prepared to consider his release.
The choice is his.
All that is required of him now
is that he should unconditionally
reject violence as a political instrument.
This is, after all, a norm which is expected
in all civilized countries of the world.
The presumption being
that South Africa is civilized.
Here, James. This... No, sit down.
This just came from Pretoria.
Would you believe it?
You know, I think it's just some
public relations gesture.
That won't be necessary.
Where are we going today?
You're meeting your family in the room
where you normally meet your lawyer.
I do not understand.
There'll be no more glass
between you and your visitors.
I will be able to touch?
Yes.
Mr. Gregory,
I have not touched my wife in 21 years.
You'll be fine, Nelson.
My father says,
"What freedom am I being offered
"while the organization of the people
remains banned?
"What freedom am I being offered
"when I may be arrested on a pass offense?
"to live my life as a family
"with my dear wife,
who remains in banishment in Brandfort?
"What freedom am I being offered... "
- She speaks very well, huh?
"...when I must ask for permission
- "to live in an urban area?"
- Not quite your regular terrorist, eh?
"What freedom am I being offered
"when I need a stamp on my pass
to seek work?
"What freedom am I being offered
"when my very South African citizenship
is not respected?
"Only free men can negotiate.
Prisoners cannot enter into contracts. "
My father says,
"I cannot and will not give any undertaking
"at a time when you, the people,
and I are not free.
"Your freedom and mine
cannot be separated.
"I will return."
Power to the people!
Warrant Officer Gregory?
My name is Groenewald.
I'd like you to consider me
for the Mandela detail.
I'll get Personnel to send your file over.
My wife's nephew lost his legs
in the Pretoria car bomb.
It would be my pleasure to
return this kindness to Mandela.
You must be joking.
I'm not joking. I promise you, I'm not joking.
Gloria!
James!
Oh, James, where have you been?
We had to isolate Mandela from the others.
What's wrong?
A man phoned.
He said they were going to kill Brent
and Natasha.
He said we're Kaffir lovers
and we're all going to die.
Do you recognize his voice?
No, he said I was a fucking bitch,
and he said I was dead.
- It's all right. It's okay.
- It's not okay, James!
It's not okay. They want to kill my babies.
Nothing is going to happen to you
or our family, okay?
Brigadier Morkel, now.
Brigadier, listen. Somebody phoned Gloria
and threatened to kill her and the kids.
I want 24-hour protection on my family
or I'm off the job.
We'll take care of it.
- Major.
- Sir.
Gregory's making noises
about resigning again.
Give him what he wants.
Just keep him happy.
It's a joke. Guarding the guard
who's guarding Mandela.
We've got bigger problems.
The international community are crying
for Mandela's release.
They're putting more and more
pressure on us.
- Are we going to bend?
- No.
We're not going to give
power to the blacks ever.
Besides, imagine if a right-wing bullet
takes him out.
There'd be bloodshed like
this country's never seen.
No, we'll have to make it
look like we're negotiating
and give him access to his people.
Maybe if we moved him to someplace
more comfortable, it would look better.
Like where?
The farm prison outside Paarl,
Victor Verster.
It's got mountains, vineyards.
There's a farmhouse on the one side
which is isolated, secure.
Mr. Mandela's expecting you.
Mr. Maharaj is a vegetarian,
so I'm not sure he'll appreciate the lamb.
Well, I've baked a quiche for him.
Don't serve wine to Mr. Ayob.
He's a Muslim.
Christ, it's like the bloody
United Nations in there.
The message from P.W. Botha is simple.
It's power sharing or nothing at all.
We will not enter into any discussions
unless all parties agree to
the principle of free and fair elections.
Sorry to interrupt, sir.
I'm taking the afternoon off.
If you need me, just speak to Chris.
Very good, Mr. Gregory.
Good day to you, gentlemen.
This country's full of surprises.
James, it's beautiful!
What did I tell you? Look at the mountains.
Come, let me show you inside.
How's my girl?
This is so cool, Pa.
Bring in the suitcases, Brent.
- Wait.
- What?
James!
It's got a dishwasher, washing machine,
a spin dryer, the works.
The kids have each got their own bedrooms
with study desks,
and there's an extra TV
in the main bedroom.
No!
You don't believe me, go look for yourself.
I promise you, we will not move from here
unless you decide to.
Gloria, Gloria, you should be happy.
This is a new beginning, a new start.
I'm happy. I'm happy. Thank you.
Jeez, do you guys have to do that
in front of us?
Come.
- What do you think? In about an hour?
- You're not chilly?
Oh, that's sweet.
Damn it, I left my smokes in the car.
You go on. I'll catch you up in a minute.
That's typically Pa.
- Why you following me?
- Please, don't shoot.
- Who are you?
- National Intelligence, top left jacket pocket.
- Why?
- My orders are to look out
for you and your family
whenever you leave the prison.
Tell Jordaan next time send a professional.
Gregory's residence.
Hi, Natasha, it's me. Is Pa there?
No, he just left. How did the exam go?
I cruised it, thanks to Mr. Mandela.
Everything he covered in commercial law
came up. He's amazing.
- No, you must tell Ma.
- No, no, I will.
Brent, drive carefully, okay?
I will, I will. I'll see you later. Cheers, bye.
- What time is it?
- Past 10:00.
I must have drifted off.
- Should I close up?
- Please.
Is your family happy
- with their new accommodation?
- Extremely.
I saw on the television
that President Botha suffered
a minor stroke.
Do you know what hospital he's in?
- I could find out.
- I would like to send him a bowl of fruit.
And a card.
Do you think he'd do the same for you?
That is not relevant.
I'll get Brent to find out.
How is the young man?
He finished his last exam.
He should be driving back
from Cape Town as we speak.
I am sure he will do very well.
Good night, Mr. Gregory.
Good night, Madiba.
This house is too big for one person.
It needs a family, the sound of children.
Hello?
Warrant Officer Gregory?
- Yes.
This is Klapmuts Police Station.
Are you Warrant Officer Gregory?
I just told you I am.
Well, your son is dead.
What? Listen, this is no time for sick jokes.
Was your son driving a Ford
back from Cape Town this evening?
Yes.
Then he's dead. He was killed in a car crash.
What's wrong?
- Brent is dead. He was killed in a car crash.
- What?
What?
It's because of everything I've done, Gloria.
It's because of Thembi Mandela,
Oscar Ngidi, Jonas Motsadi, Diliza Mje,
I sent those men to their deaths,
and now God is paying me back.
- No, James, no. It's not your fault.
- I'm so sorry.
It is. I sent those men to their deaths.
God forgive me! Please forgive me!
We didn't know better, James.
We didn't know better.
- Forgive me, please forgive me.
- It's not your fault, it's not your fault.
Shh.
I was deeply shocked to hear of
the tragic death of your beloved son Brent.
And on behalf of myself and my family,
I send you our sincerest sympathy.
Few things are as painful
as an invisible wound.
But I hope you and your family will be
comforted by the knowledge that Brent
was loved and respected by almost all
those who came in contact with him.
Once again, our deepest condolences.
James, you've got a visitor.
James.
General Voster called on
a number of occasions
to offer his condolences,
but you don't come to the phone.
I tell you, James, if you don't go
back to work, you will wither away.
The results of his final exams.
He passed everything, with distinction.
First person in both our families
to get a university degree.
Life goes on.
It has to.
You heard Botha resigned.
This new man, de Klerk,
he's cut from different cloth.
Please, man.
We've been hearing talk of change for years
and nothing ever happens.
This man is different. He's a listener.
He's going to want
to meet Mandela face to face.
And we're going to need you there, James,
to set it up.
Do you remember once telling me
you didn't want to be on the sidelines,
that you wanted to be part of history?
We need to be strong, James,
for each other,
for Natasha, for whatever the future
holds for us in this bloody country.
It's nice to see you back again, sir.
I've got tea on the stove, if you want.
I'm fine.
Come, my friend.
Let us take a walk in the garden.
Time will heal physical wounds,
but time will not heal invisible wounds.
Sometimes, even now, I think of Thembi.
In some ways, I don't think I have
ever stopped thinking about him.
Madiba...
What is it, Mr. Gregory?
I told the security police
that Thembi had a license to get a car.
I told them.
Because I heard Winnie telling you.
Do you honestly believe that the security
police did not know that before you did?
There are other names, other people that I...
Mr. Gregory,
we all have our jobs to do in this life.
You cannot allow guilt or bitterness
to cloud your way forward.
Come, I have something for you
to give to Gloria, from me.
That was given to him by his mother.
He says winter is coming
and you need to keep warm.
That's very kind of him.
Can you believe that in all these years,
I have never once laid eyes on him?
I don't even know what he looks like.
Merry Christmas.
Happy Christmas, Gloria.
No moping, you two. Please.
Make a toast, Pa.
To a new South Africa.
- To South Africa.
How do I look?
You cannot visit the President with a tie
that looks like a hangman's noose. Here.
You will appreciate
it has been 20 years since I've worn a tie.
You're looking very elegant, Mr. Mandela.
- Thank you.
- Please follow me.
The President is waiting for you.
Stay here, Chris.
Why is it I am not surprised
to see you here?
It's over.
I could have told you that long ago.
They're releasing him on Sunday.
You will be in charge of his personal safety
until he walks out of the gates
of Victor Verster.
You've done a good job, Gregory.
Well done.
Tell me the truth.
Thembi's accident, was it murder?
No, not even I know that.
Take a seat in the lounge, Brigadier.
Mr. Mandela won't be long.
- Is Warrant Officer Gregory here?
- He's helping Mr. Mandela pack, sir.
There is a clear sign of movement
over beyond the higher trees,
the helicopters...
Quite a number of helicopters circling above
the Victor Verster Prison.
Excitement in the crowd, movement...
Good morning, Brigadier.
What brings you out here?
I'm here to officially release you.
Sign here.
Mr. Mandela, I'm giving you
a copy of this release form
in case someone wants to arrest you
for escaping.
Warrant Officer Gregory, your insignia.
Take them off.
What?
Your insignia, off.
Congratulations, Lieutenant Gregory.
Thank you, sir.
I guess I will now have to
show you some respect.
It's a bit late for that, Madiba.
- So how does it feel?
- What?
Being a free man, after 27 years.
It will take some time to sink in.
I understand.
I've been wanting to give you something,
but I couldn't think what.
This was given to me by a friend,
the one who taught me to
stick fight better than you.
Are you challenging me, Mr. Gregory?
Because if you are, we can step outside.
No, no.
It has protected me for many years.
I hope it does the same for you.
Thank you, Mr. Gregory.
You join us
at the Victor Verster Prison,
where the excitement is running high.
The helicopters circling above.
The first cars coming out.
And Mr. Nelson Mandela will,
within seconds... Within seconds appear
and that will be the moment
the world has been waiting for.
Mr. Mandela who has grayed,
a man who has been in prison
for nearly three decades,
would be appearing in public,
for the first time, any moment now.
There's Mr. Mandela, Mr. Nelson Mandela,
a free man, taking his first steps
into a new South Africa.
Mr. Mandela! Mr. Mandela!
Mrs. Winnie Mandela
next to him, waving to the crowds,
hand in hand.
"There shall be peace and friendship.
"Let all who love their people and
their country now say, as we say here,
"these freedoms we will fight for,
side by side,
"throughout our lives,
until we have won our liberty."
That is the man who the world
has been waiting to see,
walking strongly, step by step,
further into freedom.
Goodbye, Bafana.
Subtitles by LeapinLar