Please verify that the P-one ATA removal
on replacement cap part
one and two are complete.
DMA M-one, M-two, M-three and M four
are complete. - Okay. Copy that, Explorer.
Dr. Stone, Houston. Medical is
concerned about your ECG readings.
I'm fine, Houston.
- Well, Medical doesn't agree, Doc.
Are you feeling nauseous?
- Not any more than usual, Houston.
Diagnostics are green.
Link to communications card
ready for data reception.
If this works, when we touch down tomorrow,
I'm buying all you guys a round of drinks.
That's a date, Doctor.
Just remember, Houston's
partial to margaritas.
Booting comms card now.
Please confirm link.
That's a negative,
we're not seeing any data.
Standby, Houston, I'm
gonna reboot the comms card.
Standing by.
Houston, I have a bad feeling
about this mission. - Please expand.
Okay, let me tell you a story.
It was ninety-six. I'd been
up here for forty-two days.
Every time I passed
over Texas, I looked down
knowing that Mrs. Kowalski
was looking up, thinking of me.
Six weeks I'm
blowing kisses at that woman.
Then we land at Edwards and I find out
that she's run off with this lawyer.
So, I packed my car, and
I headed to... - ... Tijuana.
You've told this story, Kowalski.
As Houston recalls, she, uh,
took off in your seventy-four GTO.
Engineering requests fuel
status on the jetpack prototype.
Five hours off the reservation and
I show thirty percent drain.
Give my compliments to Engineering.
Except for a slight malfunction
in the nulling of the roll axis,
this jetpack is one
prime piece of thrust.
Engineering says thank you.
Tell 'em I still prefer my
sixty-seven Corvette, though.
Speaking of which, did I ever tell you...
- We know the Corvette story, Matt.
Even Engineering?
- Especially Engineering.
We're going to miss you, Matt.
Comms card reboot in progress.
- Thank you, Doctor.
Shariff, what's your status?
Nearly there. Replacing battery
module A-one and C.
Ccould you be a little more specific?
Indeterminate estimates
make Houston anxious.
No, Houston. Don't be anxious.
Anxiety's not
good for the heart.
System is ready to reactivate.
Hubble telescope engaged.
Upgrade fully functional.
That applause you hear
is for you, Shariff.
Congratulations. Kick back,
take the rest of the day off.
Matt, do you have a visual on just what
Mission Specialist Shariff is doing up there?
He appears to be doing
some form of the Macarena.
But that would be just a best-guess
scenario on my part.
Dr. Stone, Houston. Medical now have you with
a temperature drop to thirty-five-point-nine
and a heart-rate rise to seventy.
How are you feeling?
- Houston, I'm fine.
It's just keeping your lunch down
in zero-G is harder than it looks.
Dr. Stone, Medical is asking
if you want to return to Explorer.
Negative. We've been here a week,
Houston. Let's just finish this.
Card is up.
- No, that's a negative.
I'm afraid we're getting
nothing on this end, Doctor.
Try again.
- No, still nothing.
Houston, can you please turn
that music off? - Kowalski.
Not a problem.
Thank you, Kowalski.
Now, Houston?
- That's a negative.
Could Houston be
misinterpreting the data?
Well, we're not receiving any data.
Engineering is recommending
a vis-check for component damage.
Let me see what's going on.
What have we got?
Visual examination doesn't
reveal any damaged components.
The problem must be originating
from the comms panel.
Yeah, that seems to be the case.
Engineering admits that you
warned us that this could happen.
That's as close to an apology
as you're going to get from them.
We should have listened to you, Doc.
Get working. - Well, ooks like we're
going to have to improvise.
I'm on it.
- How long do you think it'll take you?
One hour.
- Outstanding.
Installing your system in the
Hubble is the purpose of this mission
and so we appreciate
your patience, Doctor.
Kowalski, we... we know you don't
care about things like this,
but, uh, for your information, this
delay is not gonna be long enough
for you to break Anatoly
Solovyev's spacewalking record.
It seems like you're gonna be left...
- Seventy-five minutes shy?
Never crossed my mind.
Matt... it's been a privilege.
- Right back at you, Houston.
Enjoy your last walk.
Am I a go to assist Dr. Stone in
removing the panel?
Assistance appreciated.
- Permission granted.
Thank you, Houston.
Mind if I join the fun?
- Certainly.
How you feeling?
Like a Chihuahua that's
being tumble-dried.
Well, it's been a rough week.
If it makes you feel any
better, I coughed up everything
but my kidneys on my first ride.
Shit.
Sorry.
I'm used to a basement lab in a hospital
where things fall to the floor. Thank you.
Well, you're the genius up here.
I only drive the bus.
Yeah, well, call me a genius if I can get
this board initialized in the next hour.
Explorer, this is Houston.
- Go ahead, Houston.
NORAD reports a Russian satellite
has incurred a missile strike.
The impact has created a cloud of debris
orbiting at twenty thousand miles per hour.
Current debris orbit does not
overlap with your trajectory.
We'll keep you posted on any
developments. - Copy that, Houston.
Should we... Should we be worried? - No,
let's let the boys down there worry for us.
Explorer, engage arm
and pivot to cargo bay.
Stand by for arm maneuver.
So, doc, now that you work for
NASA, how do you like us?
Kind of like winning
the lottery, huh?
I was just happy that they didn't
cut the funding to my research.
How long was your training?
- Six months.
Including holidays?
- Mm-hm.
So, what is this scanning system?
- Oh, nothing Matt.
It's just a new set of eyes to
scan the edge of the universe.
It's designed for hospital use,
but this one's a prototype.
Stand by for locking.
Listen, they don't bankroll prototypes.
Even for your pretty blue eyes.
Well, my eyes are brown.
Right now, your eyes are
bloodshot.
Kowalski!
Is this great, or
what? Woo-hoo-hoo!
And to think he went to Harvard.
You gotta admit one thing:
Can't beat the view.
So, what do you like
about being up here?
The silence.
I could get used to it.
Terrific.
Houston, from first inspection,
comms panel appears to be dead.
Am I a go to cut link to auxiliary?
You're the expert, doctor.
It's your call.
Houston, I have a bad
feeling about this mission.
Please elaborate.
- It's the same feeling
I had about Mardi Gras in 1987.
That is affirmative.
Surprisingly, Control hasn't heard
the Mardi Gras story. Please proceed.
Well, it's day one, and I'm
bumping my way down Bourbon Street
looking for a sister
of a friend of mine.
Streets are full of people. I'm thinking
there's no way I'm gonna find this girl.
Proceeding to override. - Then all of the
sudden, I look up, and there she is,
and I'm about to yell out,
and I see she's holding hands
with some short, hairy guy in board
shorts and a Margaritaville shirt.
And then I realize that
this guy is not a guy.
That my girl is holding hands with a...
ISS, this is Houston.
- Proceed, Houston.
Explorer, this is Houston.
- Go ahead, Houston.
Mission abort. Repeat. Mission abort.
Initiate emergency
disconnect from Hubble.
Begin reentry procedure. ISS,
initiate emergency evacuation.
Copy all, Houston, and in work.
Matt, immediate return to Explorer.
Repeat, immediate
return to Explorer. - Copy.
Explorer, prep airlock.
- Airlock engaged,
ready to receive.
- Houston, elaborate.
Debris from the missile strike has
caused a chain reaction,
hitting other satellites
and creating new debris.
Traveling faster than a high-speed
bullet up towards your altitude.
All copy?
- Copy all.
Put a bow on it, Dr. Stone.
- I can't.
The board is still initializing.
- I'm not gonna ask you again.
One second.
- Not one second. Now.
Shut it down.
That's an order.
- Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm done. I'm done.
Kowalski, initiate emergency
disconnect from the Hubble.
All right, Shariff, let's do this.
- Roger, Matt.
Houston, update.
- Well, we have a full-on chain reaction.
It's been confirmed that it's
the unintentional side effect
of the Russians striking
one of their own satellites.
They shot down their own satellite?
- Right of disposal.
Most likely a spy sat gone
bad. Now it's shrapnel.
Explorer, ready to disengage HST.
Locks releasing in three... two... one.
- Explorer, new data coming through.
What's the blowback, Houston?
- It's not good.
Most of our systems are gone.
Debris chain reaction is out of
control and rapidly expanding.
Multiple satellites are down, and
they keep on falling.
Define 'multiple satellites. '
- Most of them are gone.
Telecommunication systems are dead.
Expect a communication
blackout at any moment.
Kowalski, visual of debris at nine o'clock.
- Half of North America
just lost their Facebook.
Explorer, repeat, expect a
communication blackout
at any moment.
Copy that, Houston.
- Explorer, this is Kowalski,
confirming visual contact with debris.
Debris is from a BSE sat. - Heads up!
To repeat, I have...
- Dr. Stone requesting faster transport.
We have to go. We have to go, go, go!
Kennedy reports meteorologicalconditions
no-go for re-entry.
Houston, Explorer. Copy. Explorer, Dr. Stone
requesting faster transport to bay area.
Explorer, do you copy?
- Explorer, permission to retrieve Dr. Stone.
You're a go, Kowalski.
Houston, this is Explorer, copy.
All right. - We've lost
Houston. We've lost Houston.
Unstrap. Look, we need to
get the hell out of here. - All right.
Need some help there, Matt?
- No, don't wait for us. - It's stuck!
Man down! Man down!
Houston, this is Explorer, copy. Houston,
this is Explorer, copy. Kowalski, repor...
Explorer's been hit! - Explorer, do
you read? Explorer, over! Explorer!
Astronaut is off structure!
Dr. Stone is off structure!
Dr. Stone, detach! - No!
- You must detach!
If you don't detach, that
arm's gonna carry you too far!
Listen to my voice!
You need to focus!
I'm losing visual of you.
In a few seconds, I won't
be able to track you.
You need to detach!
I can't see you anymore!
Do it now!
- I'm trying! I'm trying! I'm trying!
Houston, I've lost visual of Dr. Stone.
Dr. Stone, do you copy?
Repeat, do you copy?
Yes, yes, yes. I copy! I'm detached!
- Give me your position.
I don't know! I don't know! I'm
spinning! I can't... I can't...
Report your position. - GPS is
down. It's down, I can't...
Give me a visual.
- I told you, nothing. I see nothing!
Do you have a visual of Explorer? - No. No.
- Do you have a visual of ISS? - No.
You need to focus. Anything, use the
sun and the Earth, give me coordinates.
I can't breathe!
Give me coordinates!
Dr. Stone, do you copy?
Repeat, do you copy?
Give me your position!
Report your position.
Do you have a visual of Explorer?
Do you have a visual of ISS?
I need you to focus. Anything.
Use the sun and the
Earth, give me coordinates.
Give me coordinates.
Kowalski? Kowalski, do you copy?
Kowalski... I have... have a vis...
Kowalski, I have a visual.
I have... have a visual of Explorer.
With north at... twelve o'clock
and the shuttle is at
the center of the dial.
I can see... I can see the Chinese station.
No, it's the International Space Station.
ISS is at...
ISS is at seven o'clock.
Lieutenant Kowalski, do you copy?
Explorer, do you... do you copy?
Houston, do you copy?
Houston, this is Mission
Specialist Ryan Stone.
I am off structure and I am drifting.
Do you copy?
Anyone?
Anybody?
Do you copy?
Please copy.
Please.
Dr. Stone, do you copy?
- Yeah, Lieutenant Kowalski, yes.
Yes, Lieutenant Kowalski, I'm
here, I'm here. - Repeat, do you copy?
Yes, yes, I copy, I'm here!
I'm here. - Flash your light.
My light... my light?
- Flash it so I can see you.
Okay. Uh...
I...
Okay, okay. Here, here! I'm here!
There you are. Hang on
tight. Report your status.
I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm all right.
Your status. Give me your readings.
Three... three... three point six PSI.
- Your O2, give me your O2.
Oxygen is going down. It's going down
fast. It's going down fast. Nine...
No. No, eight-eight percent.
Okay, you're breathing too fast.
- Eight three point nine percent.
You're burning oxygen, and
we don't want to do that.
We want to relax. Copy?
- Okay, sorry. Yes, copy, copy.
All right. Nearly there.
- Please hurry.
You can holster that torch, Dr. Stone.
- Sorry. Sorry.
Gotcha. All right, now
I'm gonna tether you to me.
I know, you never realized how
devastatingly good-looking I am.
But I need you to stop staring and
help me with the tether.
Okay?
- Okay, okay.
I got it.
All right, here we go. All right.
Now, to clear you from the jets...
I'm gonna give you a little push.
No, no, no, no. No, no, no.
- Not a push.
No, no.
- A nudge.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no! Damn it, no! No!
See? Where you go, I go.
Better.
Let's get outta here.
Goddamn it.
- I know what you mean.
Damn it.
- You're burning oxygen.
We're going back to the shuttle.
How's that for a plan? Copy?
Fuck!
- Right. Copy that.
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
Dr. Stone and I are gonna
make our way back to base.
Can you get the Explorer to prepare the
airlock for arrival? Copy?
Houston, this is...
Kowalski. How do you copy?
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
They can't hear us.
- We don't know that.
That's why we keep talking.
If somebody is listening,
they might just save your life.
Set your watch for ninety minutes.
- Why ninety?
Well, Houston clocked that debris
at fifty thousand miles an hour.
If you factor in our current orbit,
then I figure we got about ninety minutes
before we get our asses kicked again.
O2 down to six percent.
- Okay.
Pretty scary shit being
untethered up here, isn't it?
Yeah, pretty scary shit.
- Well, you did all right.
Well, you weren't so bad yourself.
Houston, in the blind.
This is Kowalski.
Our current location is approximately
nine hundred meters out from the Explorer.
Dr. Stone and I would like to retrieve
the body of Mission Specialist Shariff
and return it to the shuttle.
Am I a go to retrieve?
Roger that.
- Where is he? Where is he?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Grab him!
- I'm trying, I'm trying!
You're pullin' me away.
- Got... I got him!
Clutch him like he's your Valentine.
- I got him. Okay. I got him.
I can't engage my thrust with you
two yo-yoin' around.
Jesus Christ.
Here's hopin' you have a hell of
an insurance policy, Houston.
The damages to Explorer are catastrophic.
Will commence search for survivors.
O2 down to five percent.
All right, here we go.
Careful of the edges!
Here. Here!
Houston, in the blind. To confirm.
Mission Specialist Dr. Stone and
Mission Commander Matthew Kowalski
are the sole survivors
of the STS-one-five-seven.
I apologize for not complying.
I should've stopped working as
soon as you instructed me to.
We were gonna get hit no matter what.
There was nothing you could
do to change that.
Hey.
- Yes?
All right, we have to make our
way to the Space Station.
Over there.
It's a bit of a hike, but we
need to use their escape pod,
the Soyuz, to get back to Earth.
Agreed?
Dr. Stone, agreed?
Agreed.
- All right. After you.
Oh, God.
Houston, in the blind.
This is Kowalski.
Dr. Stone and I have
determined to proceed to ISS
and use one of their
Soyuz for re-entry.
ISS, if you hear us...
we could sure use a rescue mission.
O2 down to two percent.
- We're getting there.
Beautiful, don't you think?
What?
The sunrise.
That's what I'm gonna miss the most.
So where's home, Dr. Stone?
Ryan, where's home?
Home?
Down there. Mother Earth.
Where do you pitch you tent?
Lake Zurich.
- Where the hell is that?
Illinois.
- Illinois.
Central Time Zone.
That would make it roughly...
eight PM.
What are the good people of Lake
Zurich doing at eight o'clock?
I don't know.
I'm not gonna make it. I'm slowing
you down. - What would you be doing?
Come on, Ryan. It's eight o'clock.
You've just left the hospital
after an eighteen-hour shift.
Driving home.
The radio.
I listen to the radio.
- There we go.
Let me guess.
NPR? Classical? Top forty?
Anything. I don't care, as long
as they don't talk. I just drive.
And where are you driving to?
I just drive.
- What do you miss down there?
Is there a Mr. Stone?
No.
- Nobody special?
Somebody down there looking
up, thinking about you?
Ryan?
I had a daughter.
She was four.
She was at school playing tag.
Slipped, hit her head, and that was it.
Stupidest thing.
I was driving when
I got the call, so...
Ever since then, that's what I do.
I wake up, I go to
work, and I just drive.
O2 down to one percent.
Well, I've got good
news and bad news.
The good news is, we're about
five minutes from the ISS
and I know where the
Russians stash their vodka.
And that is good, because
I'm runnin' on fumes here.
The bad news is, I'm gonna be about ten
minutes short of breakin' Anatoly's record,
and I...
What? - I'm redlining.
My O2 tank pressure is low.
Your tank is out of oxygen but you
still have it in your suit. - Got it.
So you have to sip, not gulp.
Wine, not beer.
Sip, Ryan.
Houston, in the blind, we
have a visual of the ISS.
The station must have been evacuated
because the first Soyuz is missing.
The second Soyuz exhibits surface
damage, and its chute has been deployed.
Any use as an escape pod
for re-entry is impossible.
Shouldn't we be turning?
We're drifting again.
Not yet. I wasn't
kidding about those fumes.
This can has one or
two good thrusts left...
if we're lucky.
Steady.
Aim.
Fire!
Brake! Brake! You have to brake!
- I can't, the can's empty.
We're gonna hit hard! Grab
a hold of anything you can!
What do I do? What do I do?!
Ryan!
The tether broke, I'm detached!
I'm detached!
Grab a hold!
Grab anything!
Ryan!
Give me five!
- I've got you.
I've got you. Right here, right here.
Shit!
- No. No, no, no...
Got ya.
You just... hold on and I'm gonna
start pulling you in. I'm gonna start...
Hey, Doc. - Just hold on. Hang
on. I am gonna pull you in.
Ryan, listen. - I'm gonna pull
you in. - You have to let me go. - No.
The ropes are too loose. I'm
pulling you with me.
You have to let me
go, or we both die.
I'm not letting you go! We're fine!
- No.
Ryan, let me go.
- No. No.
You're not going anywhere.
It's not up to you. - No, no, no, no...
Please don't do this.
Please, please, please, please don't do
this. Please don't do this. No, no, no.
Please don't,
Matt. Please don't do this.
You're gonna make it, Ryan.
No!
I had you. I had you! I had you.
Ryan, do you hear me?
Do you copy?
- My CO2 alarm went off.
My CO2 alarm went off. - Look,
you need to board the station.
Do you see the airlock?
Hey, Ryan, you copy?
Look for the
airlock.
It's above you, next to
the Zarya module.
You see it?
- Yes.
Yes, I see it. I see it. - Good.
That's where you want to go.
Now you're getting
lightheaded, right?
Yeah. Yes. - That's because you're
breathing CO2. You're losing consciousness.
You need to board the station.
- Okay.
That second Soyuz is
too damaged for re-entry,
but it's perfectly fine
for a little Sunday drive.
Sunday drive?
Look to the west. You see that
dot in the distance?
That's a Chinese station.
- Yes.
You're gonna take the Soyuz, and
you're gonna cruise over there.
Chinese lifeboat is a Shenzhou.
I've never flown a Shenzhou.
- It doesn't matter.
Its re-entry protocol is
identical to the Soyuz.
Okay.
You never flown the Soyuz either?
- Only a simulator.
Well, then you know.
- But I crashed it.
It's a simulator, that's
what it's designed for.
Every time. I crashed it every time.
You point the damn thing at Earth.
It's not rocket science.
And by this time tomorrow,
you're gonna be back in Lake Zurich
with a hell of a story to tell.
You copy?
Ryan, you copy? - I'm gonna take
the Soyuz and come get you.
No, you're not.
- I'm coming to get you
No, I've got too much of a head
start on you. - I'm coming to get you.
I'm afraid that ship already sailed.
Ryan, you're
gonna have to learn to let go.
But I... - I want to hear you say
you're gonna make it...
Come on, Ryan, say it.
I'm gonna make it.
- All right. Keep going.
What kind of name is Ryan for a girl?
Dad wanted a boy.
- Are you close to the airlock?
Not yet.
- Keep going.
So now that we have some
distance between us...
you're attracted to me, right?
- What?
Well, people say I have beautiful
blue eyes.
You have beautiful...
You have beautiful blue eyes.
I have brown eyes.
You want to know the good news?
- What?
I'm gonna break Anatoly's record,
and I think mine's gonna
stand for a long, long time.
No. I'm coming to get you.
Oh, my God.
- What? What?
Wow.
Hey, Ryan?
- Yeah?
You should see the sun on the Ganges.
It's amazing.
Where are you? Where are you?
Comms. Comms. There you are.
Okay. Matt, this is Ryan, copy.
Matt, this is Ryan, copy.
Matt, I made it, I'm here, I'm
on the station. Do you copy?
Come on, Matt, talk to me.
Tell me where
you are, give me your position.
Where are you? Give me a visual.
Just tell me what you see.
Come on. You've been yammering
since we left Cape Canaveral,
and now you decide to shut up?
Talk to me. Just say something,
say anything! I don't care!
Hey, tell me about, uh, Mardi Gras.
Tell me about the hairy guy. Huh?
Tell me what happened.
What happened to the hairy guy?
Please talk to me.
Please.
Houston, in the blind...
this is Mission Specialist Ryan
Stone reporting from the ISS.
All communications with Mission
Commander Matthew Kowalski
have been lost.
Radio transmission absent.
Visuals nonexistent.
To confirm, I, Ryan
Stone, am the sole survivor
of STS-one-five-seven.
What now?
Okay.
Okay. Where is it, where
is it? Where is the power?
Great, just like training.
Undocking, undocking.
Undocking. Red.
Okay.
Okay, where is it?
Where is it?
Come on.
Okay.
Okay, I remember this,
I remember this.
You don't have four minutes.
We're going manual.
Come on.
Okay. Active-Activate, undock.
Seven minutes to get out of here.
All right, okay.
What... what?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on!
That's right, that's right.
That's right, that's
right, that's right.
Come on.
Great.
Clear skies with a chance of
satellite debris.
Okay, we detach this, and we go
home. Piece of cake.
Okay.
Okay, what do we have?
Okay, all right.
Shit.
Okay, come on.
Come on, come on.
All right.
I hate space.
Shut up.
Okay.
All right.
That's good.
Okay.
Let's stabilize you.
Let's go visit the Chinese station.
Houston, in the blind,
Tiangong is approximately one
hundred kilometers to the west,
and I am off its course by about thirteen
degrees. I will correct trajectory.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
I will engage S-Ka-Dae
in five... four...
three... two... one.
What's happening, what's
happening? Come on, come on.
One.
Come on, come on.
You gotta be kidding me.
You gotta be kidding me!
No! Don't you fuck...
Houston, in the blind. Houston, in
the blind, this is Dr. Ryan Stone.
I'm calling from the
Soyuz TMA-one-four-M.
I'm currently out of fuel
and adrift, do you copy?
Houston. This is Dr. Ryan Stone.
Do you copy?
Houston. This is
Ryan Stone. Do you copy?
Houston, this is Missish... Mission
Specialist Ryan Stone, do you copy?
Houston, Houston,
please confirm identity.
Houston, you're coming in
over an A.M. frequency. Copy.
Do you copy?
Is this the Chinese station? Is
this Tiangong? Copy.
Mayday, can you copy?
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
Yes, yes. Mayday, mayday.
Mayday, mayday.
Aningaaq.
Is that...? Is that your...?
Is that your name?
Aningaaq is your... is your
name? Is that your name?
Mayday!
No, no, no. No, my name
is not 'Mayday. ' I'm Stone.
Dr. Ryan Stone, I need help. I am...
Those are dogs.
They're calling from Earth.
Aningaaq, make your dogs bark
again for me, would you please?
Your dogs. Dogs, you
know. Woof, woof. Dogs.
Oh, I'm gonna die, Aningaaq.
I know, we're all gonna
die. Everybody knows that.
But I'm gonna die today.
Funny, that. You know, to know...
But the thing is, it's
that I'm still scared.
I'm really scared.
Nobody will mourn for me,
no one will pray for my soul.
Will you mourn for me?
Will you say a prayer for me?
Or is it too late?
I mean, I'd say one for myself,
but I've never prayed in my life,
so...
Nobody ever taught me how.
A baby.
There's a baby with you, huh?
Is that a lullaby you're singing?
That's so sweet.
I used to sing to my baby.
I hope I see her soon.
That's nice, Aningaaq. Keep
singing, just like that.
Sing me to sleep, and I'll sleep.
Keep singing. And sing, and sing.
No, no, no, don't!
Check your watch. Thirteen
hours and eleven minutes.
Call Anatoly and tell
him he's been bumped.
It's a little gloomy in here, isn't it?
- How did you...?
Trust me, it's a hell of a story.
- But how did...?
That's better.
I found a little extra...
a little extra battery power.
It helps that I didn't
have you around to distract me.
I have to say, I'm glad to see ya. I
didn't think you were gonna make it.
Did you find the vodka?
- You...
You never told me where...
where it was, so... - Well...
To Anatoly. Na zdorovje.
Huh? - No. - No? All right.
Let's get out of here.
The Chinese station's about a hundred
miles. Just a little Sunday drive.
We can't.
- Sure we can.
There's no fuel, I tried everything.
Well, there's always something
we can do. - I tried everything.
Did you try the soft landing jets?
They're for landing. So...
- Well, landing is launching.
It's the same thing. Didn't you
learn about that in training?
I never got to land the simulator.
I told you that.
But you know about it.
- And I crashed it every time.
Listen, do you want to go back,
or do you want to stay here?
I get it, it's nice up here.
You can just shut
down all the systems,
turn out all the lights...
and just close your eyes
and tune out everybody.
There's nobody up
here that can hurt you.
It's safe.
I mean, what's the point of going
on? What's the point of living?
Your kid died. Doesn't
get any rougher than that.
But still, it's a matter of what
you do now.
If you decide to go, then
you gotta just get on with it.
Sit back, enjoy the ride.
You gotta plant both your feet on
the ground and start livin' life.
How did you get here?
- I'm telling you, it's a hell of a story.
Hey, Ryan?
- What?
It's time to go home.
Landing...
Landing... Landing is launching.
I said...
Okay, landing, landing.
Landing is green.
Okay.
Okay, landing. All right.
Okay. Soft landing jets trigger automatically
at three meters before landing, so...
You're a clever son of a
bitch, Matt.
I need to... I need to get rid of
the B.O... and the engine module.
Right. Okay.
Okay.
Tri-module separation.
Go.
Okay.
Houston, here's the tricky part.
Soyuz has to think
we are three meters off the Earth.
All right. Okay.
Hey, Matt? Since I had to listen to endless
hours of your storytelling this week,
I need for you to do me a favor.
You are gonna see a little girl with
brown hair, very messy, lots of knots.
She doesn't like to
brush it. That's okay.
Her name is Sarah.
Can you please tell her
that Mama found her red shoe?
She was so worried
about that shoe, Matt.
But it was just right under the bed.
Give her a big hug
and a big kiss for me,
and tell her that Mama misses her.
You tell her that she is my angel.
And she makes me so
proud. So, so proud.
And you tell her
that I'm not quitting.
You tell her that I love her, Matt.
You tell her that I love her so much.
Can you do that for me?
Roger that?
Here we go.
You're losing altitude, Tiangong.
You keep dropping and you're gonna
kiss the atmosphere.
But not without me,
because you're my last ride.
Okay.
Wait.
Five...
four...
three...
No more just driving.
Let's go home.
Steady. Okay, come on, come on.
Steady, steady.
Come on. Come on.
Where are you? Where
are you? Forty-five,
ninety, one-eighty.
Come on.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
All right.
Damn it.
Down, down, down.
Come to Mama.
Okay.
Okay. Shit!
Come on. Shenzhou, come
on. Shenzhou. Shenzhou.
Fuck! Okay, this way. Shenzhou.
Where are you? Come on,
where are you? What's this?
In the Soyuz, the
power button is here.
Okay, undocking,
undocking.
Eeni, meeni...
Okay, that doesn't sound
good. Miny, meeni... moe.
No hablo chino.
Miny... moe.
Okay. Okay, good.
Houston. Houston, in the blind.
This is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone
reporting from the Shenzhou.
I'm about to undock from Tiangong...
And I have a bad
feeling about this mission.
Reminds me of a story, Houston...
Never... Never mind the story,
Houston. Never mind the story.
It's getting hot in here. Okay.
All right.
Okay.
All right, the way I see it,
there's only two possible outcomes.
Either I make it down there in one piece
and I have one hell of a story to tell,
or I burn up in the next ten minutes.
Either way, whichever
way... no harm, no foul!
Because either way...
it'll be one hell of a ride.
I'm ready.
Shenzhou, in the blind, this is
Houston. Indicate FM frequency.
Our radars detect you
on a re-entry trajectory.
If you copy, please confirm identity.
This is Houston.
- It's freezing, it's boring as hell.
...is: No money down!
...messages, we'll be right...
- Please confirm identity.
Skies over the Midwest
are completely clear...
We've deployed a rescue
mission to retrieve you.
Rescue mission is on the way.
Shenzhou, in the blind, this is Houston.
We've deployed a rescue
mission to retrieve you.
Thank you.