Somebody asked me,
"Phil, if you could be anywhere,
where would you be?"
I said to him,
" Probably right here...
...EIko, Nevada."
Our nation's high at 79 today.
In California, they'll have
warm weather tomorrow...
...gang wars and some
overpriced real estate.
In the Pacific Northwest,
they'll have some...
...very, very tall trees.
Clear across the Rockies
and Great Plains.
But look out, here comes trouble.
Oh, boy!
Front coming our way!
Look out!
What will that mean to us?
One of these big blue things!
This cold, frigid arctic air,
this big mass out of the north.
It'll meet up with all this
moisture out of the Gulf.
They'll mix at high altitudes
and cause snow.
It won't hit us here in Pittsburgh.
It'll push off and hit Altoona.
Close call!
Let's look at the five-day.
As you can see, nothing to be
too scared about.
Bundle up warm, but you can
leave your galoshes at home.
I won't be here at 10:00.
Tomorrow's Groundhog Day.
I'll be in Punxsutawney for our
country's oldest Groundhog Festival.
According to the legend,
tomorrow, February 2nd...
...if the groundhog wakes
and sees his shadow...
...we've got six more weeks
of winter.
Sounds like fun.
You must really enjoy it.
This is your third year in a row.
Four, Nan.
Four.
Thanks, Phil.
Next, our entertainment editor
looks at sex and violence in movies.
Stay with us.
We're clear.
Have fun in Punxsutawney.
For your information, Hairdo,
a major network is interested in me.
That would be the
Home Shopping Network.
Thanks, Larry.
Go wait in the van.
That was nice, Phil.
" Big trees"!
Stop, Kenny.
Look, can you handle
the 10:00 or not?
If you don't want to rush back,
I can do the 5:00 tomorrow.
Stay an extra second in Punxsutawney?
Please!
Rita thinks it'd be
a great idea...
...to stay for other events.
You'll get incredible footage.
The people and the fun.
The excitement!
You haven't worked with her yet.
She's really nice.
I think she'll be
a really good producer.
You guys are going to have fun.
She's fun. But not my kind of fun.
I'll be here for the 5:00.
Can you keep a secret, Larry?
I'm probably leaving PBH.
So this will be the last time...
...we do the Groundhog together.
What's wrong with
the Groundhog Festival?
In San Diego...
...I covered the swallows returning
to Capistrano for six years.
Someone will see me interview
a groundhog and think I have no future.
I think it's a nice story.
He comes out.
He looks around.
He wrinkles up his nose.
He sees his shadow or not.
It's nice! People like it!
You are new, aren't you?
People like blood sausage too.
People are morons!
Nice attitude.
Look in the mirror and see how you
look when you do that groundhog thing.
For me? Once?
He comes out, and there he
looks at his little shadow.
Want some blood sausage?
I have some...
I like blood sausage.
Rita, I can't stay here.
Prima donna.
- What's the matter?
- I hate this place.
I stayed here two years ago.
I was miserable.
- I won't stay here.
- You're not staying here.
I'm not?
Larry's dropping me off.
I booked you in
a nice bed and breakfast.
Great.
I think this is one of the traits
of a good producer.
Keep the talent happy.
Anything I can do.
Would you help me
with my pelvic tilt?
Within reason. Want to come
to dinner with Larry and me?
No, thank you.
I've seen Larry eat.
You get your sleep.
See you in the morning.
Don't be late.
Did he actually call himself
"the talent"?
Campers, rise and shine!
Don't forget your booties,
- It's cold out there!
- It's cold every day!
- Is this Miami Beach?
- Not hardly!
Expect hazardous travel
later today with,,,
,,, that blizzard thing,
That blizzard thing,
Here's the report,
The National Weather Service
is calling for a big blizzard thing,
There's another reason
today's especially ex citing...
Especially cold,
The big question
on everybody's lips...
- Their chapped lips,
- On their chapped lips,
Will Phil come out
and see his shadow?
- Punxsutawney Phil!
- That's right, woodchuck chuckers!
It's Groundhog Day!
Get up and chuck me a hog!
- Morning!
- Morning.
- Off to see the groundhog?
- I am.
Think it'll be an early spring?
I'm predicting March 21 st.
Good guess!
I think that actually is
the first day of spring.
- Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
- I slept alone, Mrs. Lancaster.
Like some coffee?
Is there any possibility of getting
an espresso or cappuccino?
I really don't know...
How to spell espresso or cappuccino.
This looks fine.
I hope you enjoy the festivities.
- I'm sure I will.
- There's talk of a blizzard.
We may catch a break and
it will blow right by.
The moisture coming
out of the south...
...by midday will
push on to the east.
At high altitudes it'll crystallize
and give us what we call snow.
Our high will get to
about 30 today, teens tonight.
Chance of precipitation,
about 20% today, 20% tomorrow.
Did you want to talk about
the weather or just chitchat?
Chitchat.
See you later.
Will you be checking out today?
Chance of departure today, 100%.
Phil Connors!
I thought that was you!
How you doing?
Thanks for watching.
Don't tell me you don't remember me.
I sure as heckfire remember you.
Not a chance.
Ned!
Ryerson!
Needlenose Ned.
Ned the Head.
Come on, buddy,
Case Western High!
I did the whistling bellybutton
trick at the talent show.
Bing! Got the shingles real bad
senior year. Almost didn't graduate.
Bing again!
I dated your sister a couple times
till you told me not to anymore.
Well?
Ned Ryerson?
Bing!
Bing.
Did you turn pro with
that bellybutton thing?
I sell insurance.
- What a shock.
- Do you have insurance?
If you do, you could
always use more.
Am I right or am I right
or am I right?
I would love to stand here
and talk with you.
But I'm not going to.
See you.
That's all right!
I'll walk with you.
I see an opportunity,
I charge it like a bull.
Ned the Bull, that's me now.
I got friends who live and die
by the actuarial tables.
I say it's all one big
crapshoot anyhoo.
Ever heard of single-premium life?
That could be the ticket for you.
Oh, God!
It is so good to see you!
What are you doing for dinner?
Something else.
It's been great seeing you,
Needlehead. Take care.
Watch out for that first step.
It's a doozy!
Phil!
Phil, over here!
Where have you been?
It was horrible.
A giant leech got me.
You're missing all the fun.
These people are great!
Some of them partied all night.
They sing till they get cold.
Then they go sit by the fire
and get warm.
Then they come back
and sing some more!
They're hicks, Rita.
So did you sleep okay without me?
You tossed and turned, didn't you?
You're incredible.
Who told you?
It's groundhog time.
Okay.
On me in three...
...two, one.
Once a year, the eyes of the nation
turn to this tiny hamlet...
...to watch a master at work.
The master?
Punxsutawney Phil...
...the world's most famous weatherman.
The groundhog.
Who, as legend has it,
can predict an early spring.
The question we have
to ask ourselves is:
" Does Phil feel lucky?"
Every year, the guy comes with
a big stick and raps on the door.
They pull the little rat out,
talk to him.
The rat talks back.
Then they tell us when it'll end.
Isn't he cute?
Do you like the guys
with the prominent upper teeth?
This February 2nd, at 7:20
and 30 seconds...
...Punxsutawney Phil...
...the seer of seers...
...prognosticator of prognosticators...
...emerged reluctantly...
...but alertly...
...in Punxsutawney, PA...
...and stated in groundhog-ese...
..." I definitely see a shadow."
Sorry, folks.
Six more weeks of winter.
On me in three...
...two, one.
This is one time where
television fails...
...to capture the excitement
of a large squirrel...
...predicting the weather.
I'm grateful to have been here.
From Punxsutawney...
...this is Phil Connors.
So long.
Want to try it again
without the sarcasm?
We got it.
I'm out of here.
Prima donnas.
Oh, boy.
Take a look at this.
What is going on?
I don't know. Perhaps that
blizzard we're not supposed to get.
This is impossible.
Nobody honks this horn but me,
okay, pal?
Take it out of here.
Commander, what's going on?
Nothing.
We're closing the road.
- Big blizzard moving in.
- It's a couple of flakes.
Don't you listen to the weather?
I make the weather.
All this moisture from the Gulf
will push off to the east in Altoona.
You got that moisture on your head.
You can go back to Punxsutawney...
...or you can freeze to death.
It's your choice.
So, what's it going to be?
I'm thinking.
Come on, all the long-distance
lines are down?
What about the satellite?
Is it snowing in space?
Don't you keep a line open
for emergencies or celebrities?
I'm both.
I'm a celebrity in an emergency.
Can you patch me through
on that line?
Could I have one more of these
with some booze in it?
I like it here.
Going to the groundhog dinner?
No, I had groundhog for lunch.
Wasn't bad.
Tastes like chicken.
You two run along.
Looking foxy tonight, man.
Is your troop selling
cookies again this year?
That's so funny.
So, what are you doing?
I think I'll go back to my room...
...take a hot shower
and maybe read Hustler,
Suit yourself.
Yo, mom.
Isn't there any hot water?
Oh, no, there wouldn't be today.
Of course not.
Silly me.
Sweet dreams.
Campers, rise and shine!
Don't forget your booties,
- It's cold out there!
- It's cold every day!
- Is this Miami Beach?
- Not hardly!
Nice going, boys.
You're playing yesterday's tape.
- With that blizzard thing,
That blizzard thing?
Here's the report,
The National Weather Service
is calling for a big blizzard thing,
There's another reason
today's especially ex citing...
Especially cold,
The big question
on everybody's lips...
- Chapped lips.
- Their chapped lips,
Will Phil come out
and see his shadow?
- Punxsutawney Phil!
- That's right, woodchuck chuckers!
It's Groundhog Day!
Get up and chuck me a hog!
What the hell?
Morning!
Off to see the groundhog?
Think it'll be an early spring?
Didn't we do this yesterday?
I don't know what you mean.
Don't mess with me, Pork Chop!
- What day is this?
- It's February 2nd.
Groundhog Day.
I'm sorry.
I thought it was yesterday.
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
Did I sleep well?
Like some coffee?
Yes, please.
I think I'll have a double.
I hope you enjoy the festivities.
There's talk of a blizzard.
Ever have déjà vu,
Mrs. Lancaster?
I'll check with the kitchen.
That's okay.
Thank you.
Will you be checking out today?
I'd say the chance
of departure is 80 percent.
75-80.
Excuse me!
Excuse me.
Where's everybody going?
To Gobbler's Knob.
It's Groundhog Day.
It's still just once a year,
isn't it?
Phil Connors!
I thought that was you!
My, oh my, Phil Connors!
Don't say you don't remember me.
I sure as heckfire remember you.
- Well?
- Ned Ryerson?
Bing! First shot
right out of the box!
So how's it going, old buddy?
I'm not feeling well.
Would you excuse me?
It's funny you should mention
your health. Guess what I do now.
Do you sell insurance?
Bing again!
You are sharp as a tack today!
Do you have life insurance?
If you do, you could
always use more.
Right! I mean, who couldn't?
But you want to know something?
I gots a feeling...
...you ain't got any.
Am I right or am I right
or am I right?
I got to go.
Watch out for that first step.
It's a doozy!
Phil! Over here!
- Where have you been?
- Rita. Do me a favour.
I need someone to give me a
good, hard slap in the face.
How's that?
Good!
If you need help with the other cheek,
I'm right here.
Something's going on.
- Are you drunk or something?
- Drunk's more fun.
Can I be serious with you
for a minute?
Can you?
I'm being serious!
I'm having a problem.
I may be having a problem.
It's groundhog time.
See? I knew you'd say that!
I really feel...
...weird.
Let's just do this.
Then we'll talk.
All right, on me in three...
...two, one.
Well, it's Groundhog Day...
...again...
...and that must mean we're
up here at Gobbler's Knob...
...waiting for the world's most famous
groundhoglweatherman...
...Punxsutawney Phil...
...who's about to tell us how much more
winter to expect.
This is a riot!
Isn't he cute?
This February 2nd, at 7:20
and 30 seconds...
...Punxsutawney Phil,
the seer of seers...
...prognosticator of prognosticators...
...emerged reluctantly...
...but alertly in Punxsu...
Oh, my gosh!
I know there's a blizzard.
When will the long-distance
lines be repaired?
What if there is no tomorrow?
There wasn't one today.
Morning!
Off to see the groundhog?
Did you sleep well, Mr...
Phil Connors! I thought...
Don't say you don't remember me.
I sure as heckfire remember you!
It's me, Ned! Ryerson!
Needlenose Ned! Ned the Head!
Phil! Over here!
Can I talk to you?
It's not work-related.
- You never talk about work.
- We have to talk.
- It's a creative meeting.
- We've got work to do!
I don't.
I've already done it twice.
When you get finished,
meet me in the diner.
- What's that all about?
- I don't know.
Prima donnas.
More coffee?
Just the check, please.
These sticky buns are heaven.
Aren't they?
Just put that anywhere, pal!
Good save!
Tell me why you're too sick to work.
It better be good.
I'm reliving the same day
over and over.
Groundhog Day. Today.
Okay. I'm waiting for the punch line.
Really! This is the third time!
It's like yesterday never happened!
I'm racking my brain trying to imagine
why you'd make this up.
I'm not making it up.
I'm asking for help!
What do you want me to do?
I don't know! You're a producer.
Come up with something.
You should get
your head examined...
...if you expect me to believe
a stupid story like that!
Phil? Like the groundhog Phil?
Yeah. Like the groundhog Phil.
Look out for your shadow, pal!
Morons, your bus is leaving!
You guys ready? We better go,
to stay ahead of the weather.
- Let's talk about it in Pittsburgh.
- I'm not going back to Pittsburgh.
- Why not?
- Because of the blizzard!
You said it was going
to hit Altoona.
I know that's what I said.
I think you need help.
That's what I've been saying.
I need help.
No spots.
No clots, no tumours.
No lesions.
No aneurisms.
At least none that I can see.
If you want a CAT scan or an MRI,
you'll have to go into Pittsburgh.
I can't go into Pittsburgh.
- Why can't you go into Pittsburgh?
- I told you, there's a blizzard.
Right. The blizzard!
You know what you may need,
Mr. Connors?
A biopsy.
A psychiatrist.
That's an unusual problem...
...Mr. Connors.
Most of my work is with couples,
families. I have an alcoholic now.
You went to college, right?
It wasn't veterinary
psychology, was it?
Didn't you take a course that
covered this stuff?
Sort of, I guess.
Abnormal psychology.
So...
...what do I do?
We should meet again.
How's tomorrow for you?
Is that not good?
I was in the Virgin Islands once.
I met a girl.
We ate lobster.
Drank piña coladas.
At sunset, we made love
like sea otters.
That was a pretty good day.
Why couldn't I get that day...
...over...
...and over and over?
Some guys would look
at this glass and say:
"That glass is half empty."
Other guys would say,
"That glass is half full."
I peg you as a "glass is half empty"
kind of guy. Right?
What would you do if you were
stuck in one place...
...and every day was exactly the same,
and nothing you did mattered?
That about sums it up for me.
Good luck.
I'll drop you off.
This thing sticks a little bit.
You got to jiggle it...
Come on up here, pal.
Give me your keys, pal.
Give me the keys.
Friends don't let friends drive, right?
Stand up here.
Take a deep breath. You feel okay?
You're all right.
You want to throw up here
or in the car?
I think, both.
I don't think I should drive.
I don't either.
Watch your head.
Watch your knees.
Don't break anything.
Let's not forget seat belts.
Who else could go for some
flapjacks right now?
Let me ask you a question.
Shoot.
What if there were no tomorrow?
No tomorrow? That means there'd be
no consequences...
...no hangovers.
We could do whatever we wanted!
That's true.
We could do whatever we want.
If we wanted to hit mailboxes
we could let Ralph drive!
They want you to stop.
Hang on!
It's the same thing
your whole life.
" Clean up your room! Stand up
straight! Pick up your feet!
Take it like a man!
Be nice to your sister!
Don't mix beer and wine, ever!
Don't drive on the railroad tracks!"
That's one I agree with.
I don't know, Gus.
Sometimes I think you just have to...
...take the big chances.
This is the police! Pull over now!
We're talking in here!
I bet he swerves first.
I'm not going to live by
their rules anymore!
I noticed that.
You make choices
and you live with them.
My knee!
Let me handle this.
Three cheeseburgers,
two large fries...
...two chocolate shakes
and one large Coke.
And some flapjacks!
Too early for flapjacks?
Yes!
Rise and shine, campers!
Don't forget your booties!
It's cold out there today!
It's cold every day.
What is this, Miami Beach?
Not hardly!
Slept like a baby.
I'd love some of your coffee.
- I hope...
- Flurries moving in later...
...but the blizzard's going to hit
outside of town.
Mrs. Lancaster?
Was anybody looking for me
here this morning?
Perhaps a state official?
Maybe a blue hat, gun, nightstick?
No, no one like that!
Will there be?
Apparently not.
Will you hold my room for me?
I'm staying an extra day.
Catch you tomorrow, pops.
- Phil Connors!
- Ned?
I like to see a man of advancing years
throw caution to the wind.
It's inspiring, in a way.
My years are not advancing
as fast as you think.
More coffee?
Keep it coming.
Sure thing.
Just put that anywhere, pal!
Good save!
Don't you worry about cholesterol,
lung cancer, love handles?
I don't worry anymore.
What makes you special?
Everybody worries.
That's exactly what makes me
so special.
I don't even have to floss.
What?
"The wretch, concentred all in self
" Living, shall forfeit fair renown
"And doubly dying, shall go down
"To the vile dust from whence he sprung
" Unwept...
"... unhonoured and unsung"
Sir Walter Scott.
You don't like poetry?
I love poetry!
I just thought that was Willard Scott.
I was confused.
You think I act like this
because I'm egocentric?
You are egocentric.
It's your defining characteristic.
You guys ready? We better go,
to stay ahead of the weather.
Thanks, Larry.
Would you like a doggie bag?
I'll stay and finish.
I thought you hated this town.
It's beginning to grow on me.
Larry, quit staring.
- These are excellent.
- Bon appétit,
You see the groundhog
this morning?
I never miss it.
What's your name?
Nancy Taylor. And you are?
- What high school did you go to?
- What?
High school.
Lincoln, in Pittsburgh.
Who are you?
Who was your 12th grade
English teacher?
Are you kidding?
In 12th grade,
your English teacher was...
Mrs. Walsh.
Nancy. Lincoln. Walsh.
Thanks very much.
Nancy?
Nancy Taylor!
Lincoln High School!
I sat next to you in
Mrs. Walsh's English class!
- I'm sorry.
- Phil Connors!
- That's amazing!
- You don't remember me?
I asked you to the prom.
Phil Connors?
I was short and I've sprouted.
How are you?
Great.
You look terrific!
You look very, very terrific!
Listen, I got to go do this report.
Are you a reporter?
A weatherman with
Channel 9, Pittsburgh.
I should have known! That's great!
But maybe later we could...
Yeah, whatever!
Stay right here.
Promise me?
I'll be right back. Wish me luck!
Good luck!
Oh, Phil.
Oh, Rita.
Who's Rita?
How should I know?
What is this,
some kind of one-night stand?
On the contrary, Nancy...
...I love you.
I've always loved you.
This is going to seem sudden but...
...Nancy, will you be my wife?
Rita.
- Nancy.
- Whatever.
A gust of wind.
A dog barks.
Cue the truck.
Exit Herman.
Walk on to the bank.
Exit Felix, and stand there with a
not-so-bright look on your face.
All right, Doris. Come on.
Fix your bra, honey.
That's better.
Felix!
How you doing, Doris?
Can I have a roll of quarters?
Ten... nine... eight...
...car...
...six... five...
...quarters...
...three... two...
Felix?
- Did I bring out two bags or one?
- I don't know.
I thought we were going
to a costume party.
It's like I said, I love this film.
I've seen it over 100 times.
Phil!
Told you...
...call me " Bronco."
Sorry, Bronco.
Hi, Nancy.
My own fiancée...
...doesn't remember me.
That'll be one adult and...
- Two adults.
- Two adults, I guess.
- Groundhog who, as legend has it,
can predict an early spring,
The question we have
to ask ourselves today is,
"Does Phil feel lucky?"
Rita, if you only
had one day to live...
...what would you do?
I don't know.
What are you dying of?
No, the whole world
is about to explode.
What do you do?
I want to know
where to put the camera.
What are you looking for?
A date for the weekend?
No, I'm just interested in you.
What do you want?
What do you like?
What do you think about?
What kind of men
are you interested in?
What do you do for fun?
Are you trying to
make me look like a fool?
I'm trying to talk like normal people.
Isn't this how they talk?
- Close.
- Okay, so talk to me.
Let me buy you a cup of coffee.
And a doughnut.
All right.
So what do you want out of life?
I guess I want what everybody wants.
Career, love, marriage, children.
Are you seeing anyone?
This is getting too personal.
I'm not ready to share this with you.
How about you?
What do you want?
What I really want
is someone like you.
Oh, please!
Why not? What are you looking for?
Who's your perfect guy?
First of all, he's too humble
to know he's perfect.
That's me!
He's intelligent,
supportive, funny...
Intelligent, supportive, funny.
Me, me, me.
He's romantic and courageous.
Me also.
He's got a good body but doesn't
have to look in the mirror often.
I have a great body, and sometimes
I go months without looking.
He's kind, sensitive and gentle.
He's not afraid to cry.
This is a man
we're talking about, right?
He likes animals, children,
and he'll change poopy diapers.
Does he have to use the word " poopy"?
He plays an instrument,
and he loves his mother.
I am really close on this one.
Really, really close.
It's Phil Connors!
Hello.
Thanks for watching.
What are the chances
of getting out today?
Van won't start.
Larry's working on it.
Wouldn't you know it?
Can I buy you a drink?
Jim Beam, ice, water.
For you, miss?
Sweet vermouth on the rocks
with a twist, please.
What are the chances
of getting out today?
Van won't start.
Larry's working on it.
Wouldn't you know it?
Can I buy you a drink?
Sweet vermouth, rocks,
with a twist, please.
For you, miss?
The same.
That's my favourite drink.
Mine too!
It makes me think of Rome.
The way the sun hits
the buildings in the afternoon.
What should we drink to?
To the groundhog!
I always drink to world peace.
Can I buy you a drink?
Sweet vermouth, rocks,
with a twist, please.
For you, miss?
The same.
That's my favourite drink.
Mine too!
It makes me think of Rome.
The way the sun hits
the buildings in the afternoon.
What should we drink to?
I'd like to say a prayer
and drink to world peace.
To world peace.
- This is wonderful!
- See? Didn't I tell you?
How do you know so much
about Punxsutawney?
I spent a lot of time here.
Small-town people are
more real, down-to-earth.
- That's how I feel!
- Really?
- Some white chocolate?
- Yuck, don't make me sick.
No white chocolate.
There is something
so familiar about this.
Do you ever have déjà vu?
Didn't you just ask me that?
People place too much
emphasis on their careers.
I wish we could all live
in the mountains.
That's where I see myself
in five years.
How about you?
I agree. I just like
to go with the flow.
See where it leads me.
Well, it's led you here.
It's about a million miles
from where I started in college.
You weren't in broadcasting
or journalism?
Believe it or not, I studied
19th-century French poetry.
What a waste of time!
I mean, for someone else
that'd be a total waste.
So bold of you to choose that.
It's incredible.
You must be a very strong person.
People place too much
emphasis on their careers.
I wish we could all
live in the mountains.
That's where I see myself
in five years.
How about you?
I agree. I like to go
with the flow, see what happens.
Well, it's gotten you here.
It's a million miles
from where I started in college.
You weren't in broadcasting
or journalism or anything like that?
Believe it or not, I studied
19th-century French poetry.
You speak French!
I haven't done this since I was a kid.
Me neither. It's fun!
Clean fun.
I hope one day I can do this
with my own children.
Where'd you get that?
Well, I went over
to the snowman shop.
Hey, an assassin!
I'll protect you!
I shall die for you.
You shall not take her!
Find cover!
I'm getting some good ones.
That's a boy! Good try.
Help me!
What?
I'm just amazed,
and I'm not easily amazed.
About what?
How you can start a day with one
kind of expectation...
...and end up
so completely different.
Do you like the way
this day is turning out?
I like it very much.
It's a perfect day.
You couldn't plan a day like this.
Well, you can.
It just takes an awful lot of work.
Come in.
I want to show you something.
- I don't think I should.
- I agree.
That's why I want to show you one thing,
then kick you right out.
It's just lovely.
Would you like to sit
and stare at the fake fire?
It's a really wonderful room.
It is now.
I don't think we should do this.
I don't either.
On second thought,
I think we should.
It's the perfect end
to a perfect day.
Well, it's a little fast for me.
Me too.
Maybe I should go.
Where would you go?
Why?
We've got a perfect fire.
I've got some French poetry here.
Baudelaire...
I will read to you.
I've got some ice cream on
the windowsill. Hold on a minute.
Rocky road.
I love rocky road.
Yeah, I thought so.
You have to stay.
No, really, I'm tired.
We can see each other tomorrow.
No, tonight.
It's got to be tonight.
No, Phil, really.
Just stay for a while and
if you like it, stay longer.
And if you like that, stay longer.
Let's not spoil it, okay?
I don't want to spoil it either.
You know I can't stay with you.
Why not? I love you.
You love me?
- You don't even know me.
- I know you.
Oh, no. I can't believe
I fell for this!
This whole day has been
one long setup.
No, it hasn't.
And I hate fudge. Yuck!
No white chocolate, no fudge.
What are you doing?
Are you making some kind of list?
Did you call my friends
and ask them what I like?
- Is this what love is for you?
- This is real. This is love.
Stop saying that!
You must be crazy.
I could never love you because
you'll never love anyone but yourself.
I don't even like myself.
Give me another chance.
That's for making me
care about you.
I haven't done this
since I was a kid.
It's fun!
And good, clean fun too.
That's what's missing in the world.
I can't wait to do this
with my own children.
I want lots of kids!
I want to adopt, I want my own kids,
I want to have foster kids.
I got this at Snowman City.
Hey! Some kid just
threw a snowball at us.
Come here! Let's have some fun!
I wish these were my own kids.
Are any of you up for adoption?
Here's a humdinger over here!
Wasn't that great?
Stop it!
Phil! Over here!
Where have you been?
You're missing the fun.
Phil, you look terrible.
What happened? Rough night?
Okay, campers.
Rise and shine.
Don't forget your booties,
because it's cold out there.
It's cold out there every day.
This country's largest lake,
Chapala, is located near Guadalajara,
What is Mexico?
- Correct,
- Lakes and Rivers, 400,
Seneca is the largest
of these lakes,
What are the Finger Lakes?
- What are the Finger Lakes?
- Correct,
- This lake in Bolivia...
- What is Titicaca?
- Correct,
For 1,000.
- Milky-coloured...
- The Rhone.
,,, when entering Lake Geneva,,,
,,, this river is
clear blue upon exiting,
- Jim?
- The Rhone,
Good for $1, 000,
You're $500 off the lead right now,
This is pitiful.
A thousand people...
...freezing their butts off,
waiting to worship a rat.
What a hype.
They used to pull the hog out,
and they used to eat it.
You're hypocrites! All of you!
You got a problem, Larry?
Untie your tongue.
Come here and talk.
Am I upsetting you...
...princess?
You want a prediction
about the weather?
You're asking the wrong Phil.
I'll give you a winter prediction.
It's going to be cold.
It's going to be gray.
And it's going to last you
for the rest of your life.
Once again the eyes of the nation
have turned here...
...to this tiny village
in Western Pennsylvania.
There is no way that this winter...
...is ever going to end...
...as long as this groundhog
keeps seeing his shadow.
I don't see any other way out.
He's got to be stopped.
And I have to stop it.
Real good, Phil.
Real good.
He's out of his gourd.
I'm worried. There's something
really wrong with Phil.
There's a lot of things
wrong with Phil.
Hi, Phil.
I've come to the end of me.
There's no way out now.
Just remember, we had
a beautiful day together once.
All right, little fellow.
Good job. He just smiled at me!
Did you see that?
I believe he did.
Okay, little fellow.
There you go.
Hi, there. Something I can
do you for?
Hey! What are you doing?
Get the word out.
Somebody kidnapped Phil!
We are going after him!
Why would anybody steal a groundhog?
I could think of reasons.
Pervert.
He must have just snapped!
This ought to be good.
What is he doing?
What can he be thinking?
Not bad for a quadruped.
Check your mirrors. Side of your eye.
Side of your eye.
That's it.
Hey, they're chasing us!
Come on, make it fun.
Don't drive angry.
There's no way out
except the way we came in!
We got him now!
What is he doing?
I don't know.
If you got to shoot,
don't hit the groundhog.
Mustn't keep them waiting.
It's showtime.
On me in three...
...two...
...one.
Phil!
He might be okay.
Well, no. Probably not now.
Nuts.
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
Would you like...
...some toast?
Oh, my God!
That's him.
He was a really, really great guy.
I really, really liked him...
...a lot.
I'm sorry?
What was that again?
- I'm a god.
- You're God?
I'm a god. I'm not the god,
I don't think.
Because you survived a car wreck?
You folks ready to order?
I didn't just survive a wreck.
I wasn't just blown up.
I have been stabbed,
shot, poisoned...
...frozen, hung, electrocuted
and burned.
Oh, really.
Every morning I wake up without a
scratch, not a dent in the fender.
I am an immortal.
Special today is blueberry waffles.
Why are you telling me this?
Because I want you to believe in me.
You are not a god.
Take my word. It's 12 years
of Catholic school talking.
I can come back if you're not ready.
How do you know I'm not a god?
Please.
- How do you know?
- It's not possible.
I'll come back.
Doris.
This is Doris.
Her brother-in-law owns this diner.
She's worked here since she was 17.
She wants to see Paris...
...before she dies.
Boy, would I!
- What are you doing?
- Debbie and her fiancé.
Do I know you?
They're supposed to get married.
She's having second thoughts.
What?
Lovely ring.
Bill's been a waiter three years,
since he left Penn State to work.
He likes the town,
paints toy soldiers, and he's gay.
I am.
Gus hates it here,
wishes he'd stayed in the Navy.
I could've retired
on half pay after 20 years.
Excuse me. Is this a trick?
Maybe the real God uses tricks.
Maybe he's not omnipotent...
...he just knows everything.
- Who's that?
- Tom.
He worked in the coal mine
till it closed.
- And her?
- Alice.
Came from Ireland when she
was a baby. Lived in Erie.
He's right.
- And her?
- Nancy.
Works in a shop, makes noises like
a chipmunk when she gets excited.
- It's true.
- How do you know this?
I told you, I know everything.
In five seconds, a waiter
will drop a tray.
- Five, four, three, two, one.
- This is nuts.
- Okay?
- Okay, that's enough.
What about me?
Do you know me too?
I know all about you. You hope
for more than Channel 9 Pittsburgh.
Well, everyone knows that.
You like boats but not the ocean.
You go to a lake in the summer
with your family.
There's a dock and a boathouse
with boards missing from the roof...
...and a place you used to
crawl underneath to be alone.
You're a sucker for
French poetry and rhinestones.
You're very generous.
You're kind to strangers
and children.
When you stand in the snow
you look like an angel.
How are you doing this?
I told you. I wake up every day.
Right here.
Right in Punxsutawney.
And it's always February 2nd.
And there's nothing
I can do about it.
If you still can't believe me, listen:
In 10 seconds...
...Larry is going to come
and take you away from me.
But you can't let him.
Please believe me.
You've got to believe me.
You guys ready? We better go,
to stay ahead of the weather.
What's that?
"... to stay ahead of the weather."
Maybe it really is happening.
How else could you know so much?
There is no way.
I'm not that smart.
Maybe I should
spend the day with you...
...as an objective witness,
just to see what happens.
This sounds like a science project.
Concentrate.
You got to want it.
You got to want it, Rita.
Come on. It's more
in the wrist than the fingers.
Be the hat. Come on, go.
- It'd take me a year to get good.
- Six months.
Four to five hours a day,
and you'd be an expert.
- Is this what you do with eternity?
- Now you know.
That's not the worst part.
What's the worst part?
The worst part is that...
...tomorrow you'll have
forgotten all about this...
...and you'll treat me
like a jerk again.
I am a jerk.
No, you're not.
It doesn't make any difference.
I've killed myself so many times...
...I don't even exist anymore.
Sometimes I wish I had
a thousand lifetimes.
I don't know.
Maybe it's not a curse.
It just depends
on how you look at it.
Gosh, you're an upbeat lady!
I want you to know it's been
a really nice day for me.
Me too.
And maybe...
...if it's not too boring,
we can do it again sometime.
I hope so.
You're still here?
I thought you were supposed
to disappear. Or I was.
Not until 6.
You rat!
I never said midnight.
You knew I was waiting for midnight.
Are you going to leave?
Good.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
You can fall asleep.
I promise I won't touch you.
Much.
It's all right. I'm not tired.
What were you saying?
I think the last thing
that you heard was...
...only God could make a tree.
Really?
What I wanted to say was...
...I think you are the kindest...
...sweetest, prettiest person...
...I've ever met in my life.
I've never seen anyone...
...that's nicer to people
than you are.
And the first time I saw you...
...something happened to me.
I never told you...
...but I knew I wanted
to hold you...
...as hard as I could.
I don't deserve someone like you.
But if I ever could...
...I swear I would love you...
...for the rest of my life.
Did you say something?
Good night, Rita.
Good night, Phil.
Campers, rise and shine!
Don't forget your booties,
- It's cold out there!
- It's cold every day,
- Is this Miami Beach?
- Not hardly!
Who wants coffee?
Get it while it's hot.
Thanks, Phil.
Larry?
Skim milk, two sugar.
Thanks, Phil.
Pastry?
We're setting up.
Pastry, Larry?
Take your pick.
Thanks. Raspberry. Great.
I talked with Buster Green,
the head groundhog honcho.
He said if we set up here
we'll get a better shot.
- What do you think?
- Sounds good.
Larry?
Yeah. Let's go for it.
Good work, Phil.
Maybe we'll get lucky.
Let me give you a hand.
No, no. You got your coffee.
I'll get it.
We never talk.
Do you have kids?
I'd like a piano lesson.
I'm with a student. But if you
want to come back tomorrow...
I kind of want to get started.
I can give you $1,000.
Come on in.
Morning!
Off to see the groundhog?
Buon giorno, signore!
Think it'll be an early spring?
"Winter, slumbering in the open air
Wears on his smiling face...
...a dream of spring"
Ciao!
How does she look?
Great.
Thank you.
Did you know he could ice sculpt?
Not bad. You say
this is your first lesson?
Yes, but my father
was a piano mover, so...
- Phil Connors, I thought it was you.
- Ned Ryerson.
I have missed you so much.
I don't know where you're headed,
but can you call in sick?
I got to get going.
It's good to see you, Phil.
Hello, father.
Let's get you someplace warm.
Remember me?
You brought the old man in?
How is he?
He just passed away.
- What did he die of?
- He was just old.
It was just his time.
- I want to see his chart. Excuse me.
- Sir!
You can't come in here.
Sir, this is a restricted area.
Where's the chart?
Sometimes people just die.
Not today.
Gets hard down there at the bottom.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Come on, dad.
Come on, pop.
Come on. Come on, breathe.
Breathe, pop! Breathe, pop!
When Chekhov saw the long winter...
...he saw a winter bleak
and dark and bereft of hope.
Yet we know winter is just
another step in the cycle of life.
But standing here among
the people of Punxsutawney...
...and basking in the warmth
of their hearths and hearts...
...I couldn't imagine a better fate...
...than a long and lustrous winter.
From Punxsutawney, it's Phil Connors.
So long.
Nice speech. Very nice.
Thank you.
- How was that for you two?
- My man, you touched me.
- Thanks, Larry.
- Thank you.
I got to go.
That was surprising.
I didn't know you were so versatile.
I surprise myself sometimes.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
I'd love to. Can I have a rain check?
I've got some errands.
Errands? What errands?
I thought we were going back.
What do you say?
You little brat.
You have never thanked me!
I'll see you tomorrow...
...maybe.
You totaled it.
- It's only a flat tire.
- What are we going to do?
- It's an earthquake!
- It's not an earthquake.
What is it?
Thank you, young man.
It's nothing.
I had the tire and the jack.
Just be comfortable.
It'll be a minute.
Who is that?
He must be from the motor club.
He's having a heart attack!
Do something!
Call 411, an ambulance, a lawyer,
doctor, anything!
I think that did it.
If you're going to eat steak,
get sharper teeth.
- Enjoy your meal.
- Thank you.
Who was that?
- I'm fine, I'm fine.
- Are you sure?
Eat, eat!
People don't understand,,,
...what's involved.
This is an art form.
I think most people just think...
...that I hold a camera
and point it at stuff.
There's a lot more to it than that.
Would you be interested in seeing
the inside of a van?
You know, I really have to
get back to the party.
Great idea.
I'll go with you.
Let me just drop a tip here.
Hi! How are you?
Rita, this is Nancy.
We were going to the party.
You going?
Sounds like fun.
Maybe we should call Phil.
I think he's already in there.
Isn't he good?
He's great!
He's my student.
I'm so proud.
Thank you.
Hello, welcome to our party.
I didn't know you could
play like that.
I'm versatile.
It's that nice young man
from the motor club.
Thank you again.
It's nothing, ladies.
He's the fastest jack
in Jefferson County.
What was that all about?
Don't know. They've been
hitting on me all night.
There you are!
I never thanked you properly
for what you did.
He would've choked for sure.
He may have. He was trying
to swallow a whole cow.
I owe you one, buddy.
Hang on to him, dear.
He's a real find.
What did you do today?
Same old, same old.
Excuse me, Mr. Connors.
Fred, how was the wedding?
Thank you for making
Debbie go through with it.
All I did was fan her flame
of passion for you.
You are the best.
No, you are.
Rita, this is
Debbie and Fred Kleiser.
- Here you go, kids. Congratulations.
- What is this?
No way!
WrestleMania!
How'd you know?
We'll be in Pittsburgh anyway!
Thank you. You're a real pal.
Oh, this is the best.
I don't understand.
I guess not.
How does everyone know you?
You come once a year.
You're the most popular
person in town.
Excuse me, Dr. Connors?
I want to thank you
for fixing Felix's back.
He can help around the house again.
Well, I'm sorry
to hear that, Felix.
Dr. Connors?
It's kind of an honorary title.
What is going on?
I really don't know.
There is something
going on with you.
You want the long or short version?
Let's start with the short
and go from there.
Okay, folks, attention.
Time for the bachelor auction.
You know the rules.
All the eligible bachelors
come in front.
And you ladies...
...you bid on them!
Do whatever you want with them...
...no questions asked!
I don't want to know about it,
as long as it's legal.
Get out your pocketbooks,
and remember it's all for charity.
What are you doing down here?
Go on, get up there.
I got 10 bucks
that says you're mine.
Buster, I got your first victim.
Phil Connors, come on up here!
All right! Now, what am I bid
for this fine specimen?
Five dollars!
The bidding has begun
at five dollars.
Ten dollars!
Fifteen!
- Twenty!
- Twenty-five!
Thirty!
- Thirty-five!
- Forty!
Forty-five!
Fifty!
Fifty-five!
Sixty!
I'm bid $60.
Do I hear more?
$339.88.
We won't accept any more bids.
I think that's sold...
...to the little lady for $339.88!
Congratulations!
Okay, bachelors, who's next?
All right! Now, what am I
bid for this guy?
Do I hear a buck and a half?
Anybody?
75 cents?
I bid a twopence!
Sold to the lady for 25 cents.
I got him!
Phil Connors,
I thought that was you.
This is Ned Ryerson,
my new insurance agent.
I'll say.
I haven't seen him for 20 years.
He comes up and buys whole life,
term, fire, auto, dental, health...
...with the optional death
and dismemberment plan.
This is the best day of my life.
- Mine too.
Where are we going?
Let's not spoil it.
Let's not...
I got that.
Why can't I look?
Because you bother me a lot.
I'm getting cold.
How long do I have to sit here?
I'm giving you your money's worth.
You paid top dollar for me.
Well, I think you were a bargain.
Sweet of you to say.
You're right.
Is it finished yet?
I still have to put
cherry syrup on the top...
...then we can eat it.
Come on, Phil.
I'm freezing!
One second, one second.
Let me turn it in the light.
It's amazing.
It's beautiful.
How did you do that?
I know your face so well,
I could've done it with my eyes closed.
It's lovely.
I don't know what to say.
I do.
No matter what happens tomorrow...
...or for the rest of my life...
...I'm happy now...
...because I love you.
I think I'm happy too.
Please, Not again,
- That's a great song,
- It's not,
Don't listen to this man...
It's too early.
Something is different.
Good or bad?
Anything different is good.
But this could be real good.
Why are you here?
I bought you.
I own you.
But why are you still here?
You said, "Stay,"
so I stayed.
I said, "Stay,"
so you stayed.
I can't even make a collie stay.
I got to check something.
Stay.
They're gone!
They're all gone.
- Do you know what today is?
- No, what?
Today is tomorrow.
It happened.
- You're here.
- I'm here.
Why weren't you like this last night?
You just fell asleep.
It was the end of a very long day.
Is there anything I can do
for you today?
I'm sure I can think of something.
It's so beautiful!
Let's live here.
We'll rent to start.
Subtitles by
GELULA & CO., INC.