Come on. Let's go, guys.
I'm missing the Oscars.
Hey, Calabrese, nice to see you again.
- This is the friend I told you about.
- Good to meet you.
Calabrese...
...I know you.
Who are these other mystery guests?
Murder is a very serious
business, my friend.
And an expensive one.
You'll be very well compensated,
Mr. Calabrese.
Money now, and a lot more
when I get in that office.
You can take that to the bank.
Slowly. Slowly.
And always with caution.
Listen to me! I want you to turn
Senator Caldwell into a memory.
I'm not waiting for him
to die of natural causes.
All I'm counseling is a little patience.
The man is public.
He's in the papers every day.
Next time I read about him,
I want it in the obituaries.
Who are you?
Get out of the shadows.
Enough bullshit.
Can you do the job or not?
If you can't...
We'll do it.
Gentlemen, enough bickering.
This is business.
We understand each other.
Then let's just stick to business.
It's a light plane.
A Lear P-61.
We want it to take off,
but we don't want it to land.
You told me this dock was clean.
Mikey! Quit playing
with yourself back there.
Get that bastard!
I don't want him to get an hour older!
He won't, Mr. Assemblyman.
No kidding.
- And the winner is...
- Ben Kingsley for "Gandhi!"
Amigo, are you deaf?
Storm on three.
Line 3.
Throwing away dimes now?
This doesn't go out.
For your ears only.
What?
Calabrese.
I got his ass on film.
You're full of shit.
Him and his pet cockroach, Valerio.
On film and audio, laying out a hit.
Two guys I couldn't make out,
but I think they'll come up on the film.
I think this is the big one.
Our own little Academy Award.
It's good. Ready?
- Shoot.
- Listen, Carlito.
Nobody but us knows about this.
- How you doing tonight?
- What can I do for you?
Got champagne?
Right next to the caviar.
- That was funny.
- Great.
In the big cooler in back.
How come you're not watching
the Oscars tonight?
I hate the Oscars.
You're not having a good time?
Who needs the goddamn movies?
I got a show in here every night.
I got horror, sex...
...freaks, violence.
And I don't have to pay no 4 bucks.
You should film it.
Get your own show.
l'll be great in a porno.
Better dial 911.
You don't want to call 911.
Holy shit!
You remember me, viejo?
You remember.
He grew some hair
since we last seen him.
Where's the rug?
You know what I want.
Go ahead!
Move!
Take my life savings.
Where's a cop when you need one?
They're out eating doughnuts.
I got half a mind to bash your...
Now you only got half a mind.
Let's go, hero!
That's it, right here.
What are you grinning at?
You know...
...there's only four of you guys...
...and you only have
one shot left in here.
Go low, man!
Get the maricon, man!
Get off the floor!
Get him!
l'll cut your heart out!
Yeah? Come and cut my heart out!
Come and cut my heart out.
Come on, punk.
I know what you're thinking.
Mine's bigger than yours.
It's not fair.
l'll throw it away.
What if I show you
what it's like to be a victim?
- Come on.
- You're fucking dead, man!
It's still not fair.
Okay, l'll get down on my knees.
Better?
Come on.
Looks like you won the Oscar, Storm.
You'll be very well compensated,
Mr. Calabrese.
And there's more
when I get in that office.
You can take that to the bank.
I know that voice.
Is that you, honey?
Yeah, baby.
In the flesh.
What are you doing?
Come on.
I'm raiding the icebox.
I gave up my diet for Lent.
Champagne?
Does that put you in the mood?
Think this could do it?
I had to bribe him to go to bed
with six cookies...
...and a glass of orange juice.
I wish I could sleep like that.
Maybe I can help you.
Is that for me, Dad?
You faker.
Here you go.
There you go.
- Did you say your prayers?
- I wanted to do them with you.
You know there's a trick...
...to getting what you want
in your prayers.
You ask for things for other people,
like your mom and Uncle O'Malley.
Then how do I get stuff for myself?
That's why God invented work.
Want to say a little prayer with me?
Come here.
Want to say your prayers?
Now I lay me down to sleep...
And we say together.
...I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
If I die before I wake...
...I pray the Lord my soul to take.
Very good.
Good night, Dad.
Sleep well, champ.
Here's to us.
I had a shitty day.
There's blood on your shirt.
It's not my blood.
So you don't have to worry.
If people knew how sweet you are...
...they'd never be scared of you.
I'm not scared of you.
Maybe you should be.
I'm in a silly mood.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I'm ready.
What?
Motherfuckers!
Mason!
Sweet dreams.
Becker! Storm on three!
I got the coke on the dresser.
Put yours in the nightstand.
I got it.
Got all the tapes?
A shitload. Hurry!
Just hurry!
The kid!
Get that kid and kill him!
That fucking Storm!
Get your ass in the van
and stop complaining.
- What the fuck happened?
- Another dead asshole! Let's go!
Assemblyman Trent,
when did you meet Mason Storm?
I've known him since I was...
Jesus Christ!
...City Attorney and...
...he was a young...
...homicide detective.
We worked together...
...on several cases.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Assemblyman Vernon Trent, distraught
over the loss of an officer he knew.
A terrible set of circumstances
here outside the emergency room...
...and a calamity-filled
mob scene of policemen...
What makes people do this?
Would somebody please tell me that!
Hulland!
Captain Hulland!
Is he a national treasure?
You know they always said
Storm was superhuman.
That's because he was always
jacked up on coke.
You listen to me.
I'm going to tell you something.
He was clean. He had more honor
than this whole department put together.
If I ever hear you
talk that puke again...
...l'll put you where you belong.
What the fuck is I.A. doing here?
- Taking over the show.
- Bullshit!
This is Homicide, not Internal Affairs.
We got 2 cops down,
money and drugs everywhere.
This is from the Commissioner.
Capt. Hulland?
Storm is dead.
O'Malley...
...I know you and Storm were tight.
For what it's worth...
...I'm sorry.
The most unstoppable
son-of-a-bitch I ever knew.
He got stopped tonight.
Excuse me.
Are you with the police?
Lt. O'Malley.
What do you got?
A live cop is what I've got.
- Lieutenant, what's happening?
- No comment. It's over.
We got a pulse.
Your man's alive, Lieutenant.
Who else knows he isn't dead?
Just the people in here.
I want to see each of them.
And no one else comes in here
as of now. You got that?
Lieutenant, this is still a hospital.
I appreciate your problem.
But I'm acting under orders
of the police commissioner.
- I hope you can document that.
- I can and will.
Mason Storm's going to vanish,
and you'll help make that happen.
Until he can give us some answers,
the deader he is, the safer he is.
Don't worry, buddy, I'm in your corner.
...and you can take that to the bank.
The governor today appointed
Assemblyman Vernon Trent...
...to the Senate seat vacated
by the tragic death of Senator Caldwell.
Your support fuels my efforts
and inspires me to work even harder.
I will not tolerate crime in this state.
And you can take that to the bank!
It's 6 A.M.
Morning, Martha.
What do we got here?
Inquiring minds want to know.
Doctor Carlin's ordered
a glucose drip for Jimmy C.
Max's E.E.G. monitor's
developing a nice electronic hiccup.
Poor Max.
And your boyfriend turned his head.
He did?
I thought he was going to sit up.
I almost shit.
See you for a cup of tea
in a few minutes.
I knew it.
You moved your head today,
you little devil.
Let's see,
what can I do for you here?
Very nice!
Great.
I've got a little surprise for you.
Be right back.
Would you like a little pussy?
A little bitty pussy.
Look what I've got here.
John Doe, can you hear me?
I know my words are getting through.
I don't care what the doctors say.
I'm going to keep
talking to you today...
...and tomorrow and the day after,
till you respond.
Besides, you've got so much to live for.
Please wake up!
Got to go see Jimmy C.
Bye.
Stupid machine.
Nurse.
We need to run some tests.
Alert X-ray for a CAT scan.
Call the lab.
We need a complete blood work-up.
John Doe.
Here we are.
Internal Affairs.
Detective Sergeant Goodhart.
My name's Andrea Stewart. I'm calling
from the L.A. Coma Research Center.
I'd like to speak to
Captain O'Malley, please.
What is this in regards to?
I have a John Doe coma patient,
code access 461-Zebra...
...with instructions to notify
in case of change in condition.
What's the change?
The patient has come out
of a coma after 7 years.
Nolan, get Hulland, quick.
I'm sorry, Captain O'Malley's
no longer with this division.
l'll take the information.
And please, contact
no one else on this matter.
It would be better
for the patient's welfare.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the President of the United States.
President Bush has caught
the public eye with his antics.
From throwing the first ball
on opening day...
...to kissing a pig
for the farmer's affections.
George Bush is becoming
a real crowd pleaser.
This is Andrew Louis
for Cable Hospital News.
What year is it?
- Try not to talk.
- What year is it?
It's 1990.
Your charts go back for 7 years.
Do you have any recollection
of anything?
I remember everything.
You're the first patient
to come out of a coma of this duration.
You'll be famous.
You'll be on the news.
Listen to me very carefully.
I'm a cop.
My wife and family were murdered.
That's how I got here.
If you don't get me out
of this hospital...
...within an hour, we'll both be dead.
You're my cutest patient,
but not my only one.
- You're making a mistake.
- L'll be back.
No. Don't go.
How's it going, brother?
Who are you?
I'm Danny, the physical therapist.
I'm going to give you a massage.
- L'll make you feel all right.
- Get the fuck out.
l'll just take you down the hall.
Can I see your list of patients
in your coma care unit?
Get me out. Thanks for the massage,
but stop and get me out of here.
Just relax. You'll get out
of here real soon, I promise.
Morning, Sherry.
How you doing?
Thanks.
Thank you.
- You know that doctor?
- No.
John Doe.
Excuse me.
Doctor?
I have to check everyone
on these floors.
Can I get your I.D., please?
You can't have too much security.
If you feel up to it, l'll get you some
lemon chiffon pie out of the freezer.
Get me out of here.
Don't worry.
l'll take good care of you.
If you want, l'll hook you up
with some pizza.
You got to learn to relax.
Orderly!
Give me a little help.
Give me some help down here.
What's wrong?
Russ! Russ!
What happened?
He's dead.
My poor back.
You son-of-a-bitch!
Stop, you son-of-a-bitch!
Oh, my God!
Russ! Danny!
l'll get you, Storm!
J.D.!
Oh, my God!
Now will you listen to me?
Hold tight!
Sorry.
Stop!
Hang on!
Watch out!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are going to put a stop to it...
...and we're going to start right here!
We are going to put an end...
...to violence in this state,
and you can take that to the bank!
Hulland, plaster Storm's ass
with slime in the press.
Make him responsible for that mess
at the hospital. Tail people he knows.
We know how to do our job.
Then show me. I'm starring in the
son-of-a-bitch's home movies.
If that crap gets out,
I'm looking at 30 years.
As many of you already know...
Geraldo.
Who's this guy?
...our program came to an
unexpectedly violent conclusion.
Are you crazy? I can't come in to work.
I can't even go to my apartment, Martha.
People are dead.
Then where are you?
I can't tell you.
Besides, you're better off not knowing.
The people's candidate, Senator
Vernon Trent, promises no new taxes.
And you can take that to the bank.
What am I going to do with this guy?
I want to help him...
...but he's all over TV. He's some kind
of crooked cop involved in...
Why are you out of bed?
I've got you.
Police speculate that Storm...
...who is known to have ties
with criminal elements...
...could have involved
his contacts in his escape.
Storm was thought to have been
a murder victim. A casualty...
...of his own greed.
A widespread search is now being...
This is Mason Storm. I'd like
to speak with Jerry Dunphy, please.
No, it's not a joke.
We can't stay here.
They'll trace us from the hospital.
Nobody knows I'm here.
I'm house-sitting.
This place belongs to
a doctor friend of my parents.
He's in China on research for 6 months.
The medical center
only has my apartment address.
Not even my friends have this number.
You've got to believe me.
You're safe here, okay?
This reporter was contacted personally
by the infamous...
..."Coma Cop,"
fugitive officer Mason Storm...
...who, until days ago,
had languished in a 7-year coma.
Storm said he's innocent of all charges
proffered against him in the press...
...and that he has
indisputable proof of this.
He has promised me a first look
at his alleged proof.
I want 24-hour surveillance
on that son-of-a-bitch...
...and those 2 nurses from the hospital.
No, I can do it myself.
You do it, then.
You give me this beard?
You tried.
- You ever been to Chinatown?
- Yeah. Why?
This is a list of herbs and needles
that I need for my recovery.
Where did you learn to write Chinese?
When I was a kid, my dad was a
missionary. I was raised in the Orient.
As a young white boy over there...
...I needed to learn how to fight,
as you can imagine.
I remember...
...my first martial arts teacher
once said to me:
"So why do you come to me?"
I say,
"To learn how to fight."
And he says,
"So you want to hurt people."
"But do you want to be great?"
I say, "Yeah."
"I want to be great."
He says, "Then first learn how
to heal people to be great."
"To hurt people is easy."
Look at you!
You look great.
Like it?
That's enough.
Why don't you go sit down?
That bad?
If you need me,
l'll be in the outer room.
O'Malley's the key.
We got to find him.
You can't compare blood pressure
readings now with when you're in a coma.
What's this?
555 over four digits.
That's crazy.
Let me see that.
Martha's chicken scratches.
She probably can't even read them.
Know what it is?
It's a phone number.
After you phoned...
...I asked everyone here at the home...
...and there is no O'Malley here.
But it is possible that...
...O'Malley is a relation
of someone here.
Why don't you leave me your number and
l'll call you if there's any contact.
Can I phone you?
Of course, my dear.
- Here, let me do that.
- That's all right.
You old devil.
Mason Storm.
Hi. I'm sorry.
I don't mean to interrupt.
I was just passing by and I thought...
...you might like a flower.
I like that.
Now I lay me down to sleep...
Now we say it together, okay?
...I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
If I die before I wake...
...I pray the Lord my soul to take.
This is Martha Coe.
I can't come to the phone...
Pick up, Martha.
Please pick up.
Are you there?
I'm coming over.
You called it right, Axel.
Our girlfriend just showed up.
Martha, open up.
It's me.
What's up?
Looking for Martha?
You know where she is?
Haven't seen the news?
She's dead.
She was strangled over in Westwood.
Know something?
You look like the bitch
whose picture's on TV.
The one whose house they found her at.
Hey, get over here!
Okay, boys, mount up.
Ernie, you forgot my buttermilk.
Shit!
O'Malley.
That's Sonny, all right.
The kid's a track star.
He does the hundred in 11 flat.
He's going to be real fast,
like his old man was.
What do you mean "was?"
I'm not over the hill.
At least, I hope not.
How'd pull this off?
He made it to my house
the night you were shot.
I got him hidden, played it out
like he was dead...
...staged his funeral
with yours and Felicia's.
Everybody bought it.
Where is he?
Is he safe?
Ventura Trinity Prep School,
under my mother's maiden name, Wade.
No one has any idea that he's your son.
So that was your mother that Andy found.
Your nurse friend? Yeah.
She left a number and I traced you here.
I don't know how to thank you.
I have no words.
Just seeing your ugly ass alive
is enough for me.
That night in the hospital...
...I found the audio tape in your vest.
I must've played that tape 1000 times...
...Iooking for little quirks
in the voices, phrases that repeat.
Nada.
Where is the tape?
- I turned it in for evidence.
- What?
Don't worry, I made a dupe.
Meanwhile, I thought you'd
take some pleasure in this.
And there's more in the car.
You were not wrong, my friend.
You were not wrong.
What's happened to you?
I'd been on the case
maybe a year and a half...
...trying to find out
who pulled the trigger.
But it was like swimming through shit.
Everywhere I turned,
people told me to back off, get lost.
Then one morning the phone rings.
Immaculate Heart Emergency.
Someone ran my mother off the road.
Her back's broken.
She's paralyzed.
I'm sorry, O'Mal.
That night, there's a note in my locker
letting me know it's not an accident.
What the hell could I do?
I'm there with my hands tied
behind my back. I can't wave or salute.
So, I put my papers in.
Took a 3/4 pension.
You know me,
I never would have backed off.
But there was Sonny to worry about.
What if they found him?
- Or you?
- No, you did the right thing.
Then wasn't the time.
Now's the time.
We're outgunned and undermanned, but you
know something? We're going to win.
And l'll tell you why.
Superior attitude.
Superior state of mind.
We'll get them, buddy.
Believe me.
Every fucking one of them.
Listen, O'Mal, one more favor.
Get Sonny out of that school now.
With me up and running, these guys will
do anything to find Sonny to get to me.
Get him some place safe, anywhere.
Consider it done.
I'm going straight to get that film.
Soon as you get that audio,
and Sonny's safe...
...we'll bring it in to Jerry Dunphy.
We'll see quite a show on the news.
You got it, partner.
I must've played that tape 1000 times...
...Iooking for little quirks
in the voices, phrases that repeat.
Two guys I couldn't make out,
but they'll come up on the film.
- You can take that to the bank.
- I know that voice.
Your charts go back 7 years. Do you
have any recollection of anything?
I have them on the same film in
the same camera, right where I left it.
The people's candidate, Senator
Vernon Trent, promises no new taxes.
And you can take that to the bank.
More money when I'm in office.
You can take that to the bank.
I'm going to take you to the bank,
Senator Trent.
To the blood bank.
Martha's dead.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
O'Malley was here today.
He was?
How did he get here?
You found him.
The old lady was his mother.
My son's alive.
We better get out of here.
Really. Let's go.
This ain't going to be
my best packing job.
Where are we going?
Out of here.
- Hurry up.
- I'm just about done.
Mason!
Down!
It's jammed!
Let's go.
Get down!
Come quick.
Let's go!
I'm gonna slit your throat!
You're going to bleed like a pig!
They're out back!
We're on them.
Move!
Hang on!
Hulland!
You son-of-a-bitch!
I forgot to lock the door.
You like my coche?
How hot is it, homes?
Smoking.
You got it.
Maybe you should wear
these kind of clothes all the time.
Only next time,
we'll use your credit card.
Daddy, I don't want you to go.
You look really great for someone
who changed in a gas station.
We're from Hillstar Real Estate.
We can market your home effectively.
We aren't even thinking about selling.
In fact, we're adding a nursery.
It's a mess.
- I'd love to see the nursery.
- It's right over here.
We don't know if it's a girl or a boy,
so we're doing a splatter effect.
- What are you doing, hon?
- Raiding the icebox.
I think the plasterer
fell off the ladder!
What about your baby?
Careful!
Just the way I left you.
Good grief!
I'm sorry, but I think
your contractor's doing a lousy job.
These things happen.
Thank God.
Hang on, Mrs. O'Malley.
O'Malley left there
3 hours ago with the tape.
It doesn't matter
about the tape.
We have to get this film
to Dunphy's studio...
...before I have a nervous breakdown.
Mrs. O'Malley, listen.
I'm across from the Bonaventure Hotel.
I need you to do me a favor.
Have O'Malley deliver a message
to the desk under Andrea Smith.
No, we're not checking in.
That's too dangerous.
But the desk will hold the message
if you tell them we're coming in later.
All right? Thanks.
Andrea...
...Smith.
Bonaventure Hotel...
...and leave a message...
...at the desk.
Baby, that's beautiful.
I love it.
Where's my glove, Uncle 'Mal?
Take it easy.
Sonny, hurry up, dear.
Sonny, forget the mitt.
We got to get going.
The number for the
Bonaventure Hotel, please.
Sonny, when this is over, you, me
and your pop will rent a fishing boat...
...catch the biggest fish in the seas.
And I'm not talking goldfish either.
The last time I went fishing with pop...
...we caught an old tire.
Not this time, Sonny.
We're going to get us a big, fat tuna.
- It's them.
- Let's go.
Captain Hulland, L.A.P.D.
I need to check any messages
for an Andrea Smith.
I wonder, do you have any messages
for an Andrea Smith, please?
Don't worry, Sonny's okay.
He's with O'Malley, who has the tape,
and they're headed for Union Station.
Great. Let's go get the car.
Just a minute.
Cover me.
Don't move.
You're surrounded.
Come on.
Send for back-up!
What's going on?
You can't do that in Dallas!
That's a rented car!
Get the goddamn car.
Get the car!
Your train is the Southwest Chief.
It departs for Albuquerque at 11:10.
- Thank you.
- Have a safe trip.
My hands are shaking.
Don't worry, kid.
Even your old Uncle Mally's paws
wobble a bit from time to time.
Put this on.
And watch out for the hot dog.
Don't spill that mustard.
I know it's hard to put together
after all these years.
I'm sorry I had to tell you your dad
was dead. I thought it was best.
I know it's awkward.
But your father loves you very much.
You've got to get to know each
other again. It'll take a little time.
Now listen up.
If your dad gets here on schedule, you
both get on the train. If he doesn't...
...you'll be going alone. One of us
will be one step behind. Don't worry.
One step behind.
Just like we planned it in the car
on the way down here.
O'Malley, long time no see.
Sonny, make sure
your father gets this.
What are you doing?
Taking a trip?
Yeah.
Me and my kid are visiting
my mother in New Mexico.
That's your son?
That's funny.
He doesn't look much like you.
Does he, Quintero?
As a matter of fact...
...I think I've seen
his ugly face before.
Kind of looks like Mason Storm.
Enough of this fucking around.
We want the tape.
Run, Sonny!
Take him.
We're going after the kid.
I love you, Sonny.
You fucks don't deserve
to wear your badges.
Come here,
you little son-of-a-bitch!
- The kid's got the tape.
- Get his ass!
He's going in the alley!
I'm going to call the police!
Get out of the way!
Help! Help!
This guy's crazy.
He broke my gate!
Stop!
Please stop!
My hand's bleeding bad.
Stop!
You little bastard!
Come on, don't mess with me.
You fuck!
My leg!
Come here or l'll kill you!
I broke my fucking leg!
Coma Cop,
let's see what you got.
You're still a loser.
I remember you.
Take care of him.
- Where are you going?
- One more take-out order.
- You'll be safe with her.
- You're okay with me.
Who are you?
It's a very long story.
You got a few minutes?
Senator.
I know it's a bad time,
but a few things have happened...
I want Quintero and the others here now.
Storm is just nuts enough
to come after me.
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
Can we have
just a little privacy, please?
l'll be downstairs.
We're not going to make
the ballet tonight. Take a hike.
Get lost!
l'll show you guys how to break.
How's the action, boys?
Mind if I play?
I know what you're thinking.
If I have this is my hand, I can't play.
How's this?
l'll put it away.
Well?
Somebody hand me a cue.
Impressive.
That's for my wife.
Fuck you and die!
Son-of-a-bitch!
How does it feel to know
you're about to die?
I'm going to give you more time
than you gave my wife and son.
I got to tell you something!
You can't do this!
It wasn't me!
Now you're a good cop.
Vernon?
Let's try in here.
Maybe you're behind this painting.
No. You're so good
at this, Vernon.
Maybe you're under the bed.
No, not under the bed.
What about in here?
Vernon, where are you?
How do you like this, Vernon?
I'd like to kill you so bad,
I can barely contain myself.
But I've been thinking.
Death is far too
merciful a fate for you.
So what I'm going to do is...
...put you in prison.
A nice petite white boy like you
in a federal penitentiary...
Let me put it this way. You won't be
able to stay anal retentive very long.
I'm going to take
these handcuffs here...
...then I'm going to arrest you,
and l'll take you in. How's that?
What are you doing?
Please. No!
I missed.
I never miss.
They must have been smaller
than I thought.
Freeze!
Drop the gun!
Slowly!
Get on your knees,
with your hands in the air.
Thank God.
Thank God you guys are here.
Do it now!
You got to stop him.
Let me go!
Storm, no!
Hold it right there.
Please, sergeant, talk to him.
Tell him to let me go.
Give me the gun.
We saw the film.
We know you were set up.
Senator, you're under arrest.
Cuff him.
What the hell are you talking about?
What are you talking about?
You can't do this to me!
I'm a Senator, for Christ's sake!
We're sorry, Storm.
You're a dead man, Storm!
- Are you all right?
- I love you, Storm.
I'm the Senator!
How about a nice vacation?
This guy is going to be famous.
I can hear tomorrow's weather report.
"Killer Storm strikes back."
It shows Senator Trent making a deal
with his underworld cronies.
You're going to be
very well compensated, Mr. Calabrese.
Money now, and a lot more
when I get in that office.
You can take that to the bank.
We have the greatest respect
for Storm's courage.
You told me this dock was clean.
What the hell's going on here?
Are you people listening to me?