I'm really going to miss you,
you know that?
Sam, just couple of weeks.
Which is gonna seem
like an eternity, right?
An eternity, and then some.
Oh, it's better, you
bloody englishman.
- Say it again.
- Say what?
I love hearing you use english
swear words. Say 'bloody'.
'Bloody'.
- Say 'bugger',
- 'Bugger'.
You bugger, you bloody bugger.
That's the word.
- Oh, crap.
- Oh, you smooth talker, you.
I have to get dressed, run through
my notes, rehearse my presentation.
Have a nervous breakdown, ignore your
half-naked girlfriend. Give me two seconds.
Just stay right there and don't
move your cute British butt.
- Don't tell me, there's a gift.
- There's a gift.
There's always a gift.
It makes me feel very guilty.
Well, that is the general idea.
I have a present, too. I'll give it
to you later because it's a surprise.
Great. I love surprises.
- It's perfect.
- I know.
Vintage Portobello Road,
it's only ten pounds.
And it does come with this.
Nice lining, silk.
What?
I have to get ready, you know
how important this meeting is.
If it goes well, you know
what that you could mean.
Ian...
Sam,
please have mercy.
You know, that's what I was thinking, that
after you close the deal and knock them dead...
it would be a perfect time
to step back, relax, and...
- And?
- And go to Ohio.
I want you to go to my mom's wedding
with me. You can meet everyone.
You're not coming?
I tried to free things up but
you know how hectic work's been.
I'm really sorry.
That's okay.
Look, I'm really sorry to
let you down about Indiana.
Ohio.
Bugger, I'm sorry, again.
I'm just going to have to meet
your mom at the next wedding.
What wedding?
Ours. Next year.
Me? Marry you?
A guy who confuses the buckeye state
with the hoosier state? I don't think so.
- I'm going to take a shower now.
- Be my guest.
Sam?
I am cool. Ready for breakfast?
Bon appetite.
Hey, I don't care how big this
meeting is. You are going to eat.
Sorry, there's no time.
Aw, I'm such a klutz.
Show me.
- Better?
- Much.
Good.
One day accessing one's genetic make-up
will be as easy as running a credit check.
That knowledge gives us the power
to alter our destiny.
Alter destiny?
You believe that?
Yeah, of course I do. I'm telling you,
in the next fifty years...
People are still going to die.
It'll still rain right after you wash your car,
and the stones will still be touring.
That stuff's out of your control. The only
things you can control are your own choices.
Okay.
Well, that would be the
other point of view.
But I don't have time to debate destiny.
I'm just practicing my speech.
Excuse me.
In case we don't talk later,
dinner tonight. Tantra, seven o'clock.
Tonight, seven o'clock?
You're kidding, right?
Kidding? Not that
I'm aware of.
My concert.
The one I've been preparing for
for three years. Ring a bell?
Yeah. Your graduation concert.
I didn't forget that. That's...
Tonight. Seven o'clock.
I'm an ass.
I'm so sorry, Sam.
I can't believe I did that.
Good luck. In your meeting.
Not that you need it. You'll be great.
I'm sorry.
You've got to be kidding me.
Oh no, the stupid jerk.
You know, don't be late. I'll take care
of this. See you tonight at the concert.
Concert? What concert?
I was kidding. Kidding you see, because
it turns out I forgot the thing and...
Oh, this must be that british sense
of humor I keep hearing about.
Okay.
I'll see you tonight.
Gentlemen, we at AGS are not only
at the forefront of biotech...
not the forefront,
the vanguard!
Bollocks!
What happened?
I cracked it this morning.
But it says eleven o'clock.
Well, the hands
must have moved.
At least it'll be right
twice a day.
Do me a favor.
Call Tantra, push my
reservation to nine.
And have someone dash over to Harvey Nicks.
I need a present for Samantha...
For Samantha's graduation concert.
How did you remember that?
I'm not sure, could be
because she told me.
She sent you an invitation which is on your desk,
we programmed the date into your palm...
Okay, got it, got it.
Thanks.
Anyway, I promised her a surprise.
So, how about a sweater?
Something cashmere?
Red! Red's her
favorite color.
She's already got one.
A red cashmere sweater. She was
wearing it last time she was here.
She went on and on about
how much she loved it.
Really? Where was I?
Right next to her.
'You have no idea... '
'What I feel inside'
'Hold me, babe'
Sorry to make you pick me up
all the way over here.
Don't know why
I put up with you.
Pick up, pick up...
Cute hair!
Shit. Voicemail.
I just found your blue folder.
The one with all the notes in it.
I'm on the way to
the hotel right now.
Go.
Sorry, sorry.
Ladies, gentlemen,
today we are given an
opportunity to help mankind.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Yes?
Could you please take this folder into
the conference room for me?
My... Mr. Wyndham's
expecting it.
I'm sorry, miss, but that's
against hotel policy.
But he could lose his job.
That's tragic.
But alas, not my problem.
God, even when you guys
are nasty it sounds polite.
Now, in terms of
your investments...
Shit. Briefcase is open.
I have to go in.
Excuse me for interrupting,
Mr. Wyndham.
This is for you, I just thought that you might
need the exact same folder you already have.
I see.
Okay, well...
false alarm. Terribly sorry.
I just thought, I just wanted to make sure
you, he had everything he needed.
Because he worked so hard on it.
I mean, really dedicated...
and he deserves for this
to all go perfectly.
Not like this.
This is my fault. Me.
So anyway, really nice
to meet all of you.
You were right, they really are
a serious-looking bunch.
In a good way.
So, in conclusion...
Ian's good. Give him the money.
See you later.
So, move on, shall we?
I forgot my purse.
He already had the folder.
Take this folder.
I never want to see it again.
- I think that went well.
- Did it?
Yeah, the glaring, the awkwardness.
The cold stare from Ian.
Just what I was hoping for.
I think I talked too much.
Come on, let's go to work.
There's a guy there who loves
your delightfully impulsive nature.
I can't do it. I'm bad.
Come here.
You are not bad.
Do you know why?
Because if you were bad, then that
would mean I was a bad teacher...
and in fact I am
a fabulous teacher, right?
Hence, you couldn't
possibly be bad.
You've got a point.
Come on.
Let's all play together.
You're ready?
One, two, three...
Did you land the money then?
I had them, I had them
in the palm of my hand.
I can't believe Samantha
pulled that stunt after...
She spent all morning being peeved at me for
'not being in the moment' or some such bollocks.
All birds are like that.
Especially the yanks.
Where do they come up with them?
Oprah.
Oh, right.
You're up guys.
Excuse me, miss. I couldn't help
but notice that you work here.
I was just wondering
what time you... knock off?
Oh, just piss off, will you?
Oh, shit. Sorry, mate.
That's all right, mate.
I should be heading off anyway.
Samantha. Right.
See you later, boys.
Bye bye, Romeo.
- I think she liked you.
- Definitely liked you, mate.
I just need an objective
person to tell me...
if the surrealist nudes
should go on the east wall...
or wether I should put the
multiple falus sculptures there.
They look pretty amazing
when the sun hits them.
I bet they do.
Is that Ian?
What's he doing?
Surprise.
Clifton Hall, please.
That's a music school, isn't it?
Yeah, there's a concert
there tonight.
Your girlfriend's a musician.
That's right.
And you're having problems
with your love life.
How in the world
did you know that?
People in my profession are second only to bar
men in knowing about the problems of the heart.
So what's the trouble?
Ah, don't wanna talk about it.
That's a good idea. The thing
will probably just fix itself.
Well, I can't seem
to make her happy.
How can you love someone
so much and not know how...
how to love her?
So you do love her?
Yes, very much.
Yeah, well that's
all that matters.
She's going away tomorrow,
for two weeks.
She wants me to go with her.
What if she never came back?
What sort of a question is that?
Well, come on, picture it. You wave goodbye
at the airport she gets on an airplane...
you never see her again.
Could you live with that?
No.
No, I couldn't.
Well, you know what to do.
Appreciate her,
and what you have.
Just love her.
It's not for another two blocks.
You can't show up
empty-handed.
You know, if Ian bought a ticket
and if he's coming home with me,
that's really sweet. I mean,
maybe he's coming around.
I hope so, you deserve it.
And if Ian doesn't know that,
he's nothing but a deep shit.
You always know
exactly what to say.
Now remember,
you are the bee's knees.
It's a good thing.
Have a great time tonight.
Thank you, bye.
Next, Melvina Walters will sing...
Juliet's Waltz, by Guno.
Hi, thanks.
Ready?
Uh, yeah. See you later.
Enjoy the great trip.
Hey Oliver, oh,
you made it, hi!
Are you kidding? He wouldn't
have missed it for the world.
She was the best one.
I love Miss Andrews,
everyone does.
It I was just a
few years older...
You!
- This is for you.
- Thank you.
Ian, is this not just
the cutest card?
Yeah, we should go.
- Well, I...
- That's okay,
we need to go too.
It was a disaster,
Dunbar passed, Drown is pissed
and I'm screwed.
- God, Ian, I'm so sorry...
- Forget it.
So, what else is going on?
Lottie has an exhibit tomorrow.
Some bigshot gallery, the 'Zinc'.
I went down there to help with...
Sounds like fun.
Wanna dance?
When have you ever
seen me dance?
So where did you go this afternoon after
your meeting? I called your cell a zillion times.
Oh, I turned it off.
Didn't wanna hear from anyone.
Spent the rest of the day
walking around the city, thinking.
About?
About us, and whether
we're gonna make it.
No I didn't mean that,
you don't understand.
I have to admit our morning was not
the greatest, and the meeting was...
I was wondering what to do,
and then I met this cab driver.
A cab driver, you talked...
Sounds weird, but
it was good, really.
He made me realize that even though you
and I have problems, we share a lot too.
We enjoy each other, and
I should appreciate that.
It's underneath everything,
and despite this awful day,
I adore you.
I guess what I'm saying is, I...
I wanna soldier on.
I really do.
Okay?
No.
No what?
I don't wanna soldier on.
Ian, if I were to stay in London now,
it would only be for you.
For us, and I would
do that in a heartbeat...
if I thought that
we were really special.
- We are.
- Really?
You never tell me how you feel
or talk about yourself.
You don't wanna meet my family,
you forgot my graduation,
we ran into my favorite student, and
you act as if he has something contagious.
Ian, I know you have
the best intentions...
but I just feel that I'm a very
high second priority for you.
That hurts.
And the worst part is
I'm starting to get used to it.
I don't understand.
I know.
It's what kills me.
If there'd just been one day, Ian...
one day, when nothing else
mattered for us...
- I adore you!
- I don't wanna be adored.
I wanna be loved.
Where are you going?
Spend the night at Lottie's,
to the airport tomorrow and...
I can't do this anymore.
I saw you at the
travel agency today.
Where are you going?
Johannesburg, business.
Samantha, Samantha wait, please.
You can't do this to me.
You can't leave me.
You're saying, you're saying
that I'll never see you again?
You coming or not?
In or out my friend,
it's your choice.
Samantha!
No, Samantha!
Baby, baby please no!
Baby, baby please...
Help me, help me, help me!
So sorry.
I wanted to be with her...
I really did.
How can this happen?
How could she go?
Read one word, and I'll kill you.
I was just kidding!
You're, you're, you're here!
Yes yes, and you're scaring me.
I, I, I...
You...
I...
Okay, I'm gonna approach you,
and and, now I'm gonna hug you.
It's okay, everything's
gonna be okay.
I'm really gonna miss you.
Me too, I really will miss you Sam.
I hope you know that.
It's important that
you believe me.
I believe you.
And I would hate, hate for you to
have to go through so much pain,
so, instead of missing me, why
don't you come with me to Ohio?
Samantha...
You're definitely not coming.
I can't.
Of course you can't, work,
I know, big meeting...
I... I had a meeting...
and you...
Ian, calm down.
Calm down!
Look, you're very prepared for today
and you're gonna be great.
Don't go anywhere.
What are you doing?
Sit, don't move your
cute british butt.
- There's a gift.
This can't be happening.
Well of course it can.
I like buying things for you,
and I wanna say
goodbye properly.
Portobello Road.
10 pounds!
Plus, look at this.
Oh my God!
Okay, not the reaction
I was looking for.
I'm sorry, I just, I had
a terrible nightmare.
And I can't seem
to get rid of it.
I... and you...
We?
We...
should... eat?
Yes, yes! We should
have breakfast.
Let's have breakfast, together.
Okay.
I am the coolest.
Samantha?
Watch out, the coffee pot!
I see it, crazy yelling man.
I know, I just thought
you might hurt yourself.
Sam?
Oh, I'm sorry. Am I too loud?
No. I was actually hoping
that you'd sing.
You need to get out more.
You are a great songwriter.
And you need to let people see that.
It's an amazing gift.
You're biased.
That's true.
God, I am such a klutz.
You burned yourself
on the hand.
Keen Powers of observation.
Ian, what's wrong with you? I burn myself
with that damn thing every other day.
You do?
Yes, I do.
What are you doing?
We always go that way.
And do you know why?
Why?
Because that's where
you work and I teach.
Let's try a new way.
Loop around. It might be fun!
I like this route better,
don't you?
Care to explain?
I just thought the scooter
seemed a little... speedy.
Watch where you're going!
You've got to be kidding me.
It wasn't a dream.
What?
All these things happening today,
every single one,
I already knew
they would happen.
What do you mean?
The leatherjacket. The burn.
The coca cola spilled on your sweater.
I already saw or dreamt those things.
Some happened a little differently, but...
Okay Ian, calm down. You know,
sometimes I've had deja vu, and it...
But it's not deja vu.
In deja vu...
it feels like it's already happened.
You don't know what's going to happen.
Alright, what happened in the dream
that freaked you out so badly?
It was...
it was awful.
Okay. Let's be
logical about this.
In your dream or vision,
or whatever, what happens next?
You go back to the apartment to wash
your sweater and I go to my meeting.
That is awful.
On the way to my meeting,
my watch cracks.
Okay. So here's what
we're going to do.
We'll walk to your office together.
And if your watch cracks...
then we'll know something's
going on, and we'll deal with it.
Okay?
Almost there.
We're holding hands.
I like holding hands.
Me too.
Do you have the time?
Sorry. Watch.
Sore subject.
It's fine.
You're just nervous.
You're right,
I'm sure you're right.
So, you okay?
You ready for the meeting?
Yes.
Good luck. Not that you need it.
You're going to be great.
I'll see you tonight
at the concert.
Concert?
What concert?
I was kidding.
That was me kidding.
You know, the british sense of...
Nevermind.
Bye.
Yeah, see you tonight.
Do me a favor. Call Tantra and
push my reservation to nine.
And have someone dash over to
Harvey Nicks. I need a present for...
For Samantha's graduation concert?
You forgot. I reminded you twice.
Yes, no, I don't know. I don't know
if I did or didn't forget.
I forgot yesterday,
but I don't think I forgot today.
Did you wear that yesterday?
Quite possibly.
On the pittance you pay me,
I've only got a few things.
Claire, can I ask you
a question?
If you must.
Did you ever have a dream and
the next day everything feels familiar?
You know, like it's
from the dream?
Yes. I have.
For example last night,
I dreamt that you would bore me to death
first thing this morning, and lo and behold...
Come on, seriously.
Seriously?
Yes.
Ian, I believe dreams
are very important.
They should be listened to.
You really think so?
Yes.
And I also believe that you
should get over to that meeting...
or you'll be sacked,
and I'll be on the dole.
And those are
AGS's main objectives.
To design new ways
to treat, cure,
or prevent the countless illnesses
that inflict humankind.
I'm happy and more than
a little proud to report...
that AGS is way ahead
of the competition in this area.
Now...
in terms of your investments...
these 7-year projections clearly document
everything we've discussed so far.
We've amortized the cost of the
research over a 10-year period.
I knew it!
I knew you'd be here!
Okay.
You've heard my pitch, and I can tell by
the unbridled excitement on your faces...
Come on, guys. Settle down.
This is not a party.
This research isn't about perfect projections
or amortized costs or beating the competition.
It's about giving people the most
precious gift possible... time.
This is a great opportunity,
and I say grab it.
What do you think?
- Did you land the money?
- I did.
And it was the strangest thing because the other
time when Samantha walked into the meeting,
I thought she messed
everything up.
Oh, I didn't tell you guys
about the dream I had.
Of course not, because
that would be tonight.
Okay. Tell us
about the dream.
It's more of a deja vu.
Deja vu. Sometimes dismissed
as a random neurological event...
but is often a message
from deep within the soul.
And when the soul comes tapping
at the door, it's time to let him in.
Oprah.
No.
Dr. Phil.
You're up guys.
No, no, no. That's not
what I'm talking about.
There are certain things that
I know are going to happen.
Excuse me?
But haven't we met before...
in my dreams?
Oh, just piss off, will you?
You see? I knew
that would happen.
We all knew that would happen.
Can you remember anything useful?
Like the 3:30 winner at Newmarket?
No I'm afraid not.
But everything's the same.
It's just in a slightly
different order.
Slightly different order.
I've got to go.
Mackenzie street, please.
Yes, sir.
You've got to be kidding me.
Excuse me, sir?
You're the driver
from yesterday.
Anything's possible.
Yesterday you knew
certain things about me.
About your love life?
Yes.
Yeah well people in my profession
are second only to barmen...
in knowing about
problems of the heart.
And that, you said that exactly.
So if you're the same,
if this cab ride is the same...
then everything else today
will be the same.
At the end of the day, my
girlfriend gets into this taxi...
it stops at a light,
it's hit, and she...
Is that going to happen?
Is it?
What if she doesn't
get in the cab?
What if I take her
out of London?
Maybe if we stay
in the apartment...
Tell me, what can I do?
There must be something I can do!
Just one thing.
Appreciate her.
And what you have.
Just love her.
Will you let me out?
Let me out right now!
Certainly, sir.
No, that's alright, sir.
Why not?
You paid me yesterday.
Better hurry up.
You haven't got much time.
Samantha Andrews,
where is she?
I have no idea.
Are you alright?
Oliver?
There's three next door, as well.
Samantha!
I'm sorry.
Sam?
Lottie!
Come on...
Can I help you?
Hi. I know you don't know me.
I'm a friend of Lottie's.
This will sound really strange,
but I need to get into her apartment.
Never seen you around before.
Actually I'm her best friend's boyfriend.
Do you know Samantha Andrews?
Of course. I love miss Andrews.
Everyone does.
If I was just
a few years younger...
Zinc!
Hey, can we eat at some point?
I barely had breakfast.
Don't be such
a big girl's blouse.
A wimp. A wuss.
Cry-baby.
Samantha!
Thank God I found you.
Lottie, I'm sorry, but I have to get
Samantha out of here right now.
What is with you today?
You have to trust me. Things are happening
from yesterday. They're jumbled up...
but they're happening
again in some way.
We already went through this.
I know, and maybe you're right.
Maybe it's stress. But all I know...
is that we have to
leave London. Immediately!
I promised Lottie.
You've helped loads. You're right.
The fallacies will look great in the garden.
Ian, I have my concert tonight.
Remember?
I'll have you back
in time. I swear.
Let's go. I have to get you out
of London now. Just trust me on this.
Okay, let's go.
Now will you tell me
where we're going?
You said anywhere I want to.
So stop asking. Just enjoy not
knowing what's going to happen.
Hang on a minute.
What do you think?
If you don't want to stop here
we can just keep going.
- But how did you even know that this was my...
- You told me where you were from.
I've never met your family.
They've been busy.
I really want to see
where you grew up.
I want to see where little Ian
went to school and played soccer.
Sorry, football, american.
I want to see where you
became the man I love.
If you had something to hide, you
shouldn't have said 'anywhere you want to'.
I think I heard thunder.
It's gonna pour.
You do know it's raining, right?
You're just trying to
get out of this. Keep going.
Feed me soon
or face the consequences.
This was a lot steeper
when I was a kid.
They must have come in here with
heavy machinery and flattened it out.
Unless you've changed.
Me? Not possible.
Are we going to that shack?
- No. We need to get to the top, so keep walking.
- Yes, chief.
So what's at the top
of 'Ian's magical hill'?
Nothing, really.
Except the solitude.
Being away from everything.
I'd go up there to read or think.
I felt safe there, at peace.
It's definitely going to pour.
Pouring rain in England?
Not likely.
Come on.
No wonder you never took me to meet
your family. They have a very small house.
Why didn't you
tell me about them?
I'm always yapping about my friends and
family, but you never talk about yours.
Sam, let's just forget
about everything.
You know...
I just want to...
I just want to be here.
With you.
You really don't want to
talk about your past, do you?
The past doesn't matter.
What matters is only now.
You really are
acting funny today.
Keep it up, okay?
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
If for some reason you thought
you didn't have a lot of time left...
You mean today?
No, I mean in life.
If you had one day left,
what would you do?
That's an odd question.
I'd just like to know.
Well, let's see...
my last day on earth.
Shoe shopping. And eating
ten hot fudge sundaes.
And there's that Calvin Klein underwear model.
Might be fun to get to know him better.
It's an easy answer.
A no-brainer.
I'd spend it with you.
Really?
Of course.
Just being together.
Like now.
Doing nothing.
And that's it?
Nothing else?
A closeness.
An intense closeness.
Really sharing things
with each other.
Silly things. Difficult things.
That's what I've always wanted
for us, and if we could have that...
nothing could hurt us.
I love you.
Good.
The rain's letting up. Do you want
to go to the top of your hill?
No.
I want to take you
somewhere else.
Do I have to climb?
Maybe we should
wait another minute.
Good idea.
Your dad was a
very handsome guy.
So I guess you took
after your mom, right?
He spent a lot of time here?
Yeah, he did.
After he got laid off
in '93. Here all the time.
When I was a kid,
my dad was my hero.
I thought he was the
strongest man in the world.
He was so proud.
His job at the factory wasn't
just any job to him, you know?
Everyone loved him.
And his family,
we all worshiped him.
He sounds wonderful.
He is.
Well, he was.
Then the owner decided to relocate
and they all lost their jobs.
He never found another.
This became his second home.
From the age of 15 on
I don't think I ever saw him sober.
And I've been determined
not to let that happen to me.
To live my life
at the whim of others.
You don't have to.
I know that now.
I just wish I could
have helped him.
You were only a kid.
I know.
But to watch your father,
your hero, just...
dissolve right before your eyes...
You really loved your dad.
Yeah.
I hope he knew how much.
Wherever he is, I bet
he knows how you feel.
Ian, death doesn't
put an end to love.
You think so?
I know it.
Why didn't you ever
tell me any of this?
I guess...
I guess I just didn't want
to feel any of it.
I'm so glad we're here.
Me, too.
I wish we didn't have to go.
Go where?
Back to London. My graduation concert.
Any of this ringing a bell?
Let's not go back.
Let's just get on a train
and ride off somewhere.
Let's see. I've been playing
violin for 16 years.
I've been studying for 3 years. I'm about to graduate
from one of the finest music schools in London.
I think we should go home.
You coming?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Just a small surprise.
Something you're going to love.
Okay.
I don't think
there's enough time.
Don't be silly.
Maybe we should go back
to the apartment.
Come on. You said you've
always wanted to do this.
And you know why I haven't?
Because I'm scared of heights.
Baby, there's nothing to be
afraid of. I'll be with you.
The doors.
It's beautiful.
Still scared?
That's weird.
I guess I forgot.
Hey, I'm sorry for being
such a big girl's blouse.
What?
Where did you get that from?
Lottie. Did I use it right?
It couldn't have been better.
Thank you.
What for?
The perfect day.
I think I'll wear this to dinner.
You're going to love the singing tonight.
Is it that opera
that I'm so fond of?
I'd rather stay here
and listen to you sing.
Be serious.
I am. I don't understand why you
don't let people hear your songs.
What are you afraid of?
Success or failure?
Yes.
Sam.
I will sing them. I will.
When?
One day. Someday.
Have you seen my keys?
- Your...?
- Keys. I just had them.
It's alright. I've got them.
I've got to run by the office.
The office? Now?
I wasn't there all afternoon.
The place could crumble without me.
It'll just take a second.
See you there.
Yeah.
Hi. I need 75 copies and
I'll be back in a couple of minutes.
No problem.
Ladies and gentlemen...
that was to have been the last
performance of the evening,
but we have a very
special treat for you.
Samantha Andrews,
a visiting artist from America...
has agreed to grace us with
one of her own compositions.
Samantha.
You don't want to let down
your future fans.
You are in big trouble.
# Today, today I bet my life
# You have no idea...
# What I feel inside
# Don't be afraid to let it show
# For you never know
# If you let it out
# I love you, you love me
# Take this gift and don't ask why
# Cause if you will let me
# I'll take what scares you
# hold it deep inside
# And if you ask me why...
# I'm with you
# and why I'll never leave
# Love'll show you everything
# One day
# when youth is just a memory
# I know you'll be standing
# right next to me
# I love you, you love me
# Take this gift and don't ask why
# Cause if you will let me...
# I'll take what scares you
hold it deep inside
# And if you ask me why...
# I love you and why I'll never leave
# My love'll show you every-thing
# My love'll show you everything
# My love will show you every-thing
# Our love will show us everything.
I can't believe you did that!
What an amazing feeling! Do you
have any idea how terrified I was?
You certainly didn't show it.
You were great.
In the beginning
I couldn't even breathe...
and then this calm came over me.
My god, what an amazing feeling!
You were so incredible.
You're biased.
Guilty as charged.
Hey, I'm starved.
Where are we going to eat?
Anywhere you want to.
Okay.
You like this place? I thought
you'd hate it. Cozy, intimate...
It's exactly my style.
You looked really cute
today in your meeting.
I mean, strong and manly.
What are you saying?
You strong like bull.
But you didn't come to work today.
I mean, I didn't see you.
I brought you the blue folder
but you already had it...
so I slipped away.
You did look really cute
by the way.
Close your eyes.
Happy graduation.
Oh my God.
Some of the charms are old
and some are new.
That's a musical note.
A violin. This one's a flower.
But there's no sense in that at all,
except it was exquisite, like you.
Let's see.
The train that we took today.
That's the Eiffel tower that
you've always wanted to see.
And there's a frying pan.
You're the only person I know that
can actually do the flipping thing.
This one's a heart.
My heart.
It's yours now.
Are you ready?
You sure we can't walk?
It's pouring rain, silly.
Here we go.
Wait!
What?
I love you.
I love you, too.
I want to tell you
why I love you.
It's raining.
You know that, right?
I have to tell you this
and you need to hear it.
I've loved you since I met you...
but I wouldn't allow myself
to truly feel it until today.
I was always thinking ahead.
Making decisions out of fear.
Today, because of
what I learned from you...
every choice I made was different
and my life has completely changed.
And I've learned that if you do that,
you're living your life fully.
It doesn't matter if you have
five minutes or fifty years.
Samantha, if not for today,
if not for you...
I would never
have known love at all.
So thank you for being the person
who taught me to love.
And to be loved.
I don't know what to say.
You don't have to say anything.
I just wanted to tell you.
Thank you.
Let's go home.
Are you coming?
Of course.
Ludgate Square, please.
Yes, ma'am.
You haven't got much time.
Anything's possible.
I'm so sorry.
I can't believe he's gone.
Why am I here and he isn't?
Some things are just out
of our control, sweetie.
Ian had a premonition,
or a dream or whatever.
He knew.
And he kept trying to tell me
but I didn't believe him.
Right before we got
into the cab...
he told me about
how I taught him to love.
Loving him was so easy for me.
He just wanted
to say everything.
# It'll be all right...
# You said, tomorrow...
# Don't you cry...
# Don't you shed a tear
# When you wake up...
# I will still be here
# We'll battle all your fears
# And now I'll...
# take my heart back
# Leave your pictures on the floor
# Steal back my memories
# I can't take it anymore
# I've cried my eyes out
# Oh, and now I face the years
# The way you loved me...
# Vanished all the tears
# Just a little more time
# was all we needed
# Just a little more time for me to see
# Oh, the light that life can give you
# Or how it can set you free
# So now I'll take my heart back
# Leave your pictures on the floor
# Steal back my memories
# I can't take it any more
# I've cried my eyes out
# Oh, and now I face the years
# The way you loved me...
# Vanished all the tears.