ÿÿÿ[? Katie Melua:
ÿÿÿJust Like Heaven]
ÿÿ? Show me how
ÿÿyou do that trick ?
ÿ? The one that makes
ÿme scream, he said ?
ÿme laugh, he said ?
ÿ? And threw his arms
ÿaround my neck ?
? You ?
ÿÿÿ? Soft and only ?
ÿÿ? Lost and lonely ?
? You ?
ÿ? Strange as angels ?
ÿ? Dancing in
ÿthe deepest oceans ?
ÿÿÿ? Twisting in the water ?
ÿ? You're just like a dream ?
ÿÿ- [woman] Elizabeth.
ÿÿ- [sighing]
- How long was I out?
- [woman] Um, about six minutes.
Thanks.
OK. I'll be right there.
ÿ[woman] OK, I'll be outside.
ÿHey, Fran.
ÿÿHey, what are you
ÿÿstill doin' here?
- How long you been on?
- Uh, twenty-three.
ÿÿTwenty-three?
ÿÿTime to go, Elizabeth.
That's not gonna get me
an attending slot.
Adams? She needs to know
how to redress her sutures,
but then she
can be discharged.
No, no. Ellis needs an EKG. I
don't like these swollen ankles.
ÿÿ- All right.
ÿÿ- Thanks.
Hey. I took care of Trauma Two
while you were sleeping.
ÿ- I wasn't sleeping, I was...
ÿ- You're welcome.
ÿÿYou're on in five and eight.
ÿÿ[man] Excuse us.
ÿÿMove aside, please.
ÿÿJenny? You seen Jenny?
Sorry. Sorry. I'm here.
Hi, Mr. Clarke.
I'm Dr. Masterson.
ÿÿÿ- We're gonna need a CBC,
ÿÿÿlytes and a UA.
ÿÿÿ- [Jenny] OK.
ÿAnything I can do to make you
ÿfeel more comfortable today?
ÿÿ- Marry me?
ÿÿ- Wow.
No, I have my own bus pass.
ÿÿWell, then how could I refuse?
ÿLet me just call my sister and
ÿsee if I can borrow her dress.
ÿYou sit tight.
ÿKeep an eye on my fianc?,
ÿand decrease his morphine drip.
ÿ[? Kay Hanley:Lust For Life]
Doin' OK?
ÿClear bed four.
Sir, you wanna step over...
ÿÿ[grunting]
ÿ[man] Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
ÿÿÿ[straining] I got it.
ÿÿÿI got it.
- I was just about to...
- You're welcome.
ÿÿ? I have a lust for life ?
ÿÿÿ? Lust for life ?
ÿÿThank you.
UTI progressing to infection....
Viral pneumonia. Diabetic coma.
ÿUna problema con sus rinones.
I'll have a Venti, triple-shot,
sugar-free, vanilla,
nonfat cappuccino.
ÿÿOoh! Doctor.
ÿÿ- Mr. Clarke?
ÿÿ- Will you marry me?
Of course, Mr. Clarke.
But first, we need to
find you a robe. Jenny?
ÿSorry. Sorry. I'm here.
Going full Kabuki tonight, Fran?
ÿÿÿI found the dark circles
ÿÿÿwere scaring the patients.
And she's got
a hot date tonight.
Oh, stop! I'm going out
to dinner with my ex
and his mother.
He still hasn't told her
we're divorced.
I won't be responsible for
killing an 80-year-old woman.
ÿÿÿI'll trade nights
ÿÿÿwith you.
ÿÿI've gotta go home and sew
ÿÿsix caterpillar costumes
with Velcro legs
for Katie's dance class.
ÿÿI don't know
ÿÿhow you guys do it.
ÿÿNick is totally pushing me
ÿÿfor kids. I don't have time
ÿÿto shave my legs.
ÿÿStop shaving.
ÿÿHe'll leave you alone.
Really?
Elizabeth, you're so lucky
that all you have to worry
about is work.
[man] Dr. Masterson,
are you in there?
Yeah, I'll be right out.
ÿÿÿ- Ankle in bed two.
ÿÿÿ- OK, there's no fracture.
ÿÿÿ- Just wrap it up
ÿÿÿand send him home. Thanks.
ÿÿÿ-[cell phone rings]
- Hello?
-[woman] Are you really coming?
Yes, I'm coming.
Good. Because this guy is great.
ÿ[Elizabeth] Have you met him?
ÿIs he there?
ÿI, uh, haven't actually
ÿmet him in person.
ÿAbby, you're not setting me up
ÿwith a stranger.
ÿHe's a friend of an old friend.
ÿI hear he's really nice.
ÿNo. What does that mean, he's
ÿfat with a good sense of humor?
Not again, Abby.
Look, it wasn't easy
to get this guy to come.
ÿÿÿHe doesn't do
ÿÿÿthis kind of thing either.
ÿDo you girls
ÿhave to do that here?
ÿDo we not have six other rooms
ÿin the house? Help Mommy.
ÿÿI'm in the seventh circle
ÿÿof hell, you better show up.
ÿI'll be there.
ÿI'm just busy tonight.
Don't you dare. You don't know
the meaning of the word "busy."
I'm doin' you this huge
favor here.
ÿÿBeggars can't be choosers,
ÿÿElizabeth.
ÿÿÿI am completely capable
ÿÿÿof meeting men on my own.
[shrieks]
I know, honey. I'd just like you
to meet one who's not bleeding.
ÿÿÿI'll have you know,
ÿÿÿI've already had two
ÿÿÿmarriage proposals today.
ÿÿÿ- Marry me.
ÿÿÿ- Yes, Mr. Clarke.
Yes, of course.
Make that three.
ÿÿ-OK, I'll see ya at seven.
ÿÿ- It is seven.
ÿÿThirty. 7:30.
ÿÿWhat are you making?
ÿÿÿLasagna. Mom's recipe.
ÿÿÿNo carbohydrate comments.
ÿPlease. I'm going on a day
ÿand a half of cafeteria salad.
ÿAnything'll do.
ÿÿ[gasping] Who put SpongeBob
ÿÿin the pasta?
ÿ- [girls screaming]
ÿ- [Abby] I gotta go.
ÿÿSo, what are you gonna do?
The only other option
is Phoenix.
ÿ- [man] Would you consider it?
ÿ- Phoenix, San Francisco. Hmm.
Old people and melanomas
versus, you know, great sushi
and desperate women.
ÿÿ- [man] Walsh likes you.
ÿÿ- Dr. Walsh. Gunshot victim,
ÿÿinternal hemorrhaging.
ÿ- How long have you been here?
ÿ- Twelve hours.
A few more.
ÿÿ- All right, Brett.
ÿÿ- I'll scrub up.
ÿÿ- Elizabeth.
ÿÿ- Yes, sir.
ÿI was going to wait
ÿuntil tomorrow,
but I wanted to let you know
that I've made my decision.
ÿÿI want you to stay on
ÿÿas an attending physician.
Really? Thank you. Oh!
- Hey. Hey.
- Thank you, Dr. Walsh.
ÿÿÿYou've earned it.
ÿAnd unlike some others, you
ÿspend more time being concerned
with what's best for the
patient than kissing my ass.
ÿÿA risky move,
ÿÿbut I like it.
Sir, I can't thank you enough
for this opportunity.
There's so much
I want to do around here.
I can't wait
to get started.
ÿÿ- Elizabeth?
ÿÿ- Yes?
ÿThe only thing I need you
ÿto do right now is go home.
ÿÿÿ- But, sir, I... I have...
ÿÿÿ- Go.
ÿÿYou've been
ÿÿhere 26 hours.
ÿI know all.
ÿ- [man] Dr. Masterson.
ÿ- Yeah?
Um, I have
a bowel obstruction in six.
ÿÿÿI think that's what it is.
ÿÿÿCan you take a quick peek?
ÿUh... Yeah, of course.
ÿÿÿ[thunder clapping]
ÿÿÿ[car alarm beeps]
ÿÿÿ- Brett.
ÿÿÿ- Congratulations.
Thank you. I didn't know
Walsh was gonna...
I have an offer in Phoenix.
Life's good.
ÿÿÿThat's great.
ÿÿÿIt's fine.
ÿ[? The Cars:Good Times Roll]
ÿÿ? Let the good times roll ?
ÿ- Hey, Abby, it's me.
ÿ- Hey.
ÿÿÿI'm sorry I'm late.
ÿÿÿI know, but I'm on my way.
ÿDon't worry.
ÿYour date's late too.
- [Elizabeth] I have good news.
- What?
ÿI got the attending position.
ÿI'm staying in San Francisco.
ÿÿWhoo! Oh, that's great!
ÿÿGet over here. We're
ÿÿbreakin' out the champagne.
ÿÿ- I'll be there in a minute.
ÿÿ- OK, see you.
ÿÿ[volume increases]
ÿÿ? Let the good times roll ?
ÿÿ[screeching]
[honking]
ÿ[woman] This place is heaven.
ÿÿIt's been photographed
ÿÿfor magazines.
Yeah. I think I told you I was
gonna need something furnished.
ÿWell, it is furnished.
ÿÿÿWhere's the couch?
ÿÿOh, do you believe
ÿÿall of this space?
Yeah, it's great for all
those raves I'll be throwing.
ÿÿI'm... sensing a "no."
- Wow, huh?
- [opera music playing]
I know. This place
isn't usually available,
ÿbut the couple's spending all
ÿtheir time in Palm Springs now.
Huh?
David, I'm just not quite sure
what you're looking for.
Maybe if we could
communicate a little more.
Maybe if you could
let me know a bit more
about what's going on with you,
with your job, your family
situation.
- I don't wanna talk about that.
- Here's another idea:
Maybe stop looking for a couple
of months. Start again.
You've gotta know
where you wanna live.
ÿÿÿI just...
ÿÿÿI'm... I'm not...
ÿÿÿ...getting
ÿÿÿwhat it is you...
[chuckles] Oh.
Hey, well... no. David.
David, are you kidding?
Wait, David.
Look, come on.
A place like this,
it is long gone by now.
No, listen, there's 90 vultures
and just one carcass.
All right, fine.
I'll call them.
He did? OK.
Well, right.
As soon as I know.
Thank you so much
for your help. Mm-hmm.
Well, it's pretty obvious
why this hasn't rented.
There's no one-year lease.
It's a month-to-month sublet.
ÿ- Why?
ÿ- Some family matter.
They were pretty
close-mouthed about it.
ÿÿÿWow, what a view.
ÿ[woman] David.
ÿÿWow.
This is... sensational.
Oh, my God. And it's
got the private access?
They didn't
do much with it,
but, I mean, you really
could do something with this.
Isn't this gorgeous?
Well, there's a few places in
the Richmond we haven't hit yet.
ÿÿÿI like the couch.
The couch.
ÿÿGood couch.
ÿÿ[? Beck:Strange Invitation]
ÿ? I've been drifting along ?
ÿÿ? In the same stale shoes ?
ÿ? Loose ends tying a noose ?
ÿÿ? In the back of my mind ?
ÿÿÿ? If you thought that you
ÿÿÿwere making your way ?
ÿ[woman on TV] David.
ÿDavid, come here.
? To where the puzzles
and pagans lay ?
ÿÿÿ? I'll put it together ?
ÿ? It's a strange invitation ?
[both screaming]
ÿWhat? What?
- There's nothing
worth stealing.
- What?
ÿ- There's no money, no drugs.
ÿ- I'm not stealing anything.
OK. I'm sure there's
a homeless shelter nearby.
I'll give you money
for cab fare and a meal.
But please, don't blow it
on more beer, OK?
ÿÿI am not homeless.
ÿÿI live here.
OK. You can't live here,
because I live here.
This is my apartment.
ÿÿ- Since when?
ÿÿ- Since I rented it.
- You rented it.
- Yeah.
- Know what? I don't need this.
- What?
ÿ- Rent scam, right?
ÿ- What are you talking about?
ÿThere's probably five other
ÿpeople who paid deposits
ÿand got the keys.
- And moved in all their things?
- Yeah... What?
This is my stuff.
All of this.
That's my couch,
that's my coffee table.
Is that a ring?
Have you ever heard
of a coaster?
Or a trash can,
for that matter?
I don't care who you are,
you're gonna mop that up.
ÿI'm getting the bucket.
It's like a pig
moved into my house.
ÿÿ- Um, what?
ÿÿ- Like a filthy pig.
ÿÿÿYou... You moved in when?
ÿHello?
- I told you to get out.
- [gasps] Jesus!
ÿÿ[man] OK. So,
ÿÿwhat's this all about?
[David] What? Nothin'.
Nothin'.
ÿSo, you called
ÿme for nothin'?
I've, uh, been sort
of seeing someone.
ÿSeeing someone? That's what
ÿI'm talkin' about. Finally.
ÿ- You think it's a good thing?
ÿ- Absolutely.
ÿYeah. The last time I tried
ÿto hook you up, you bailed out.
ÿThis is good, and the fact
ÿthat you initiated it yourself,
ÿthat's important. OK?
ÿNow, who is she? Do I know her?
I mean I'm seeing someone
that's not there.
ÿÿÿShe's emotionally
ÿÿÿunavailable?
ÿÿÿOh, you mean like
ÿÿÿa hallucination.
Twice, in my apartment.
A woman.
ÿAttractive?
Not really there, Jack.
ÿÿÿRight. Right. OK.
ÿSo when you saw this woman,
ÿwere you drunk?
I mean,
I had a little buzz.
ÿÿDave, don't lie to me,
ÿÿit doesn't help.
OK, fine, I was wasted.
But still, I shouldn't be seeing
some little blonde control freak
running around my apartment.
Why are you writing this down?
This isn't a session.
ÿÿÿThat's insulting, OK?
ÿÿI'm your friend Jack here,
ÿÿI'm not charging you.
But if this thing
rolls into a second hour
ÿwe're gonna have to work out
ÿsome kind of deal. I'm kidding.
ÿÿÿSo, hold on a second.
ÿÿÿYou were drunk,
you saw this blonde,
controlling...
- I gotta stop drinkin'.
- No.
ÿ- No?
ÿ- Yeah, drink, party.
ÿÿJust do it
ÿÿwith other people.
ÿÿGod gave us alcohol
ÿÿas a social lubricant.
ÿÿÿMake men brave,
ÿÿÿmake women loose.
What is that,
some Berkeley shrink thing?
No. Look around you, OK?
ÿÿSee this?
ÿÿThis is the world.
Join it.
Stop swimming around
in your own mind.
That is a dangerous neighborhood
you should not go into alone.
ÿÿÿCome on, Dave.
ÿÿÿIt's been two years, man.
ÿNo more hiding out.
Absolutely not.
[? Pete Yorn:
Just My Imagination
(Running Away With Me)]
? Just my imagination
running away with me ?
? It was just my imagination ?
ÿÿÿ? Running away with me ?
? Just my imagination ?
? It was just my imagination ?
ÿÿÿ? Running away with me ?
ÿÿ- ? Running away with me ?
ÿÿ- ? Just my imagination ?
ÿÿÿ? Running away ??
Are you insane?
What are you doing?
ÿÿOh, God, what is this?
ÿÿI didn't want to,
ÿÿbut I will call the police.
ÿI'm sleeping. It's a dream.
ÿIt's one of those dreams
ÿand you know you're dreaming.
How do you keep
getting in here?
ÿIt's you who's in here.
Oh, my.
This is more serious
than I thought.
ÿÿÿGo away, you don't exist.
I'm gonna ask
a series of questions.
I want you
to answer honestly.
Has your recent
alcohol consumption increased?
ÿÿÿYeah, so?
ÿÿÿSo are you hearing voices
ÿÿÿor seeing things
ÿthat aren't quite real to you?
ÿÿÿAs a matter of fact, yeah.
Have you recently sought
consult from a mental
health professional?
ÿÿWhat? How do you know that?
ÿÿStay away from me.
Do you often feel paranoid,
like people are out to get you?
ÿWhy are you asking me
ÿso many questions?
I'll take that as a yes.
Listen to me.
ÿÿYou have fantasized,
ÿÿquite convincingly,
ÿÿthat you've rented
ÿÿan apartment that, in fact,
ÿÿÿbelongs to somebody else.
Pick up that pillow.
Pick it up. It's OK.
There's a small red stain
on the back
where I once spilled
cherry cough syrup.
Yes, that's it.
How else would I know that?
Or the fact that these sheets
that you're now soiling
are from Nordstrom.
I still have the receipt,
it's in that drawer there.
Open it up and check.
I think you need to
come to terms with the fact
that you may be mentally ill.
ÿÿÿ- Really?
ÿÿÿ- Yes.
This is my apartment.
These are my sheets.
That's my nightstand.
That's my picture...
ÿ- Where's my picture?
ÿ- What picture?
ÿÿÿThere was a picture there
ÿÿÿof my...
There was a picture
right there on the nightstand.
That was empty when I moved in.
ÿÿÿIt was just there.
OK, you know what? I've had
enough. I am calling the police.
ÿÿÿ- No, no, no, no.
ÿÿÿ- It's too late.
ÿÿÿWhat'd you do to my phone?
Why can't I...?
ÿYou stay right there.
ÿI'm gonna use the one
ÿin the kitchen.
ÿÿÿHey, Grace,
ÿÿÿDavid Abbott here.
ÿÿÿUh, the people who sublet
ÿÿÿthis apartment to me,
ÿÿ- do you have their number?
ÿÿ- Why? Is something wrong?
Uh, no, no. I was just wondering
about the previous tenant,
that's all. Just wondering.
ÿÿOh, well, you know,
ÿÿthe woman that I dealt with,
she didn't wanna talk about it.
It was some kind of tragedy
in the family.
ÿÿÿI didn't press for details
ÿÿÿ'cause I don't need
ÿÿÿany more drama.
ÿ- So you think this girl died?
ÿ- Well, you better hope so.
ÿÿÿ'Cause that's the only way
ÿÿÿthey're gonna get off
ÿÿÿthis month-to-month thing
ÿÿÿand give you a real lease.
- That's not the reason I was...
- Come on, David, grow up.
ÿÿLook, it has a view,
ÿÿit has a fireplace.
ÿÿPeople would kill their
ÿÿgrandmothers for a lot less
ÿÿin this city. [chuckles]
ÿÿÿ[? Screamin' Jay Hawkins:
ÿÿÿI Put A Spell On You]
ÿÿÿ? I put a spell on you ?
? Because you're mine ?
ÿÿ? Stop the things you do ?
- Can I help you with anything?
- No.
I mean, do you
believe in this stuff?
ÿÿWell, you don't...
ÿÿuntil you do.
ÿÿThat's a little dated.
ÿÿÿI recommend
ÿÿÿthe Rosemary Preston.
ÿÿÿIt's totally seminal.
'Scuse me.
Where's your UFO section?
It's back
and to the left.
Ufology. It's not
even a real science.
ÿSo, what kind of
ÿencounter have you had?
ÿÿ- Encounter?
ÿÿ- Ectoplasm?
ÿÿÿSoniferous ether?
ÿÿÿI have a killer s?ance book
ÿÿÿif you're into communication.
Uh, communicating
is not her problem.
ÿÿRighteous.
ÿÿI have exactly
ÿÿwhat you need.
ÿÿÿYeah.
ÿÿÿCrap!
ÿÿThere.
"Spirit, awake.
Spirit, partake.
ÿSpirit, without fear.
Spirit, appear."
ÿÿAre... are you here?
ÿCome on, I think you're here.
ÿÿOK.
ÿÿÿI've got a hot, moist
ÿÿÿcup of coffee in my hand.
ÿÿThere is no coaster
ÿÿon this table.
ÿÿÿI'm going to set it down
ÿÿÿon this lovely mahogany...
ÿÿÿ- Don't you dare!
ÿÿÿ- Ah!
We... We need to talk.
ÿ- About what?
ÿ- Um...
Has it crossed your mind
that there might be something
a little off about the way
you've been spending your days?
Actually, yes. It's weird having
a squatter in your living room.
I am not...
OK, let's start over.
Hi, I'm David Abbott.
And you are...?
ÿI am, uh...
ÿÿÿI'm Elizabeth.
ÿÿÿMy name is Elizabeth.
You... You didn't know that.
You... you had to read that.
ÿI think I know my own name.
OK. When was the last time
that you remember
actually talking
to someone other than me?
ÿÿThe other day.
And... And when
you're not here,
what do you do
with the rest of your day?
ÿÿÿWell, certainly a lot more
ÿÿÿthan you do, that's for sure.
Let's not stray
from the point, Lizzie.
Don't call me Lizzie.
I'm not in kindergarten.
ÿÿ- My name's Elizabeth.
ÿÿ- You think. Let me ask you,
has anything, uh, dramatic
happened to you recently?
ÿÿLike what?
I don't know,
like dying maybe?
How dare you say that to me?
OK, calm down.
ÿÿÿGet your hands off of me,
ÿÿÿyou pervert!
ÿÿÿCalm down. I'm not...
ÿÿÿI'm not here to hurt you.
ÿI'm trying to help you
ÿface the fact that...
ÿÿÿ- I'm not dead.
ÿÿÿ- Look around you.
ÿThere should be
ÿa bright light nearby.
ÿ- There's no light.
ÿ- Walk into the light,
ÿElizabeth!
ÿÿÿThere is no light!
ÿÿÿI am not dead!
I think I would know
if I was dead!
[gasps]
What's happening to me?
ÿÿYou're dead!
ÿÿÿStop saying that!
ÿÿ- Missed.
ÿÿ- [grunting]
OK. OK, that's enough.
That's enough.
You're just giving me
a headache! Get off of me!
OK. All right, all right.
It's not my fault
you're the way you are.
I just want you
out of my house.
ÿ- You get out!
ÿ- Whoa!
- [screaming]
- [trolley bell dinging]
ÿRest in peace.
ÿÿÿ- [gasps]
ÿÿÿ- I'm not leaving.
Another one, my, my.
ÿ[Elizabeth] ? Tomorrow
ÿI love ya tomorrow ?
ÿ? You're only a day away ?
ÿ? Tomorrow, tomorrow ?
ÿ? I love ya tomorrow ?
? You're only a day away ??
- Fine!
- [turns TV off]
? The sun will
come out tomorrow ?
ÿÿÿ? Bet your bottom dollar
ÿÿÿthat tomorrow... ?
You know what? That's it.
I've had it with you.
I've tried to be nice,
but now you're outta here!
The power of Christ
compels you!
ÿÿThe power of Christ
ÿÿcompels you!
ÿThe power of Christ
ÿcompels you!
ÿÿThe power of Christ
ÿÿcompels you!
ÿHe can't even see me.
ÿÿA little more left.
- You're mopping that up.
- More, more.
[speaks Chinese]
They're gonna set off
the smoke detector.
ÿÿÿ- [smoke detector beeping]
ÿÿÿ- [people yelling]
ÿÿ[? Bowling For Soup:
ÿÿGhostbusters]
ÿDad, we got it!
ÿÿAll set, sir.
ÿÿWe have the spirit.
ÿÿOoh! A butter dish.
- You sure?
- Oh, definitely.
ÿÿI have him right here.
ÿÿÿI'm gonna go
ÿÿÿgive him a flush.
ÿÿThat's it?
ÿYou just sit there?
Hey, you want bells and whistles
or a reading?
Oh, come on.
He can't see me, either.
For some hideous reason,
only you can.
OK, there's somethin'.
Definitely a presence.
How original.
Tell me more.
ÿIt's hostile.
ÿWants you outta here.
Actually, he's not bad.
ÿYou should move, dude.
- I should move?
- I would.
ÿÿI like him.
No, I'm not gonna move.
ÿÿÿCan't you feel that, man?
There's like this cancer-causing
ray of spirit hate
ÿÿÿsearing right
ÿÿÿtowards your body.
ÿThis kid's got a gift.
ÿÿÿ- I'm not moving!
ÿÿÿ- Why not?
It's not like it's
that great an apartment.
ÿ- What?
ÿ- Yes, it is.
ÿÿ- It's got a view.
ÿÿ- And a fireplace.
Whatever, dude.
ÿYo, do you have,
ÿlike, a diet anything?
ÿÿÿI'm, like,
ÿÿÿ99.9 percent parched here.
Could really use a cola.
ÿYeah. Come on.
[gulping]
ÿÿÿMove out?
ÿÿÿThat... that can't be it.
- Could you talk to her
and tell her she should pass on?
- [burps]
"Could you please
talk to her?"
ÿÿ- I'm ignoring you.
She won't accept
that she's dead.
ÿÿI told her to walk to the
ÿÿlight. She wouldn't do it.
ÿÿÿThat's because
ÿÿÿthere is no light.
God, you're infuriating!
Wait, what's goin' on?
ÿÿÿBlah, blah, blah.
You know what?
Do you think I like this?
ÿÿÿDo you think this
ÿÿÿis easy for me?
ÿÿÿI know something's different,
ÿÿÿsomething is not right.
ÿÿ- I'm walking through walls.
ÿÿ- You know,
I don't think
I can help you.
This is one of the most alive
spirits I've ever been around.
ÿÿ- She's not goin' anywhere.
ÿÿ- What do you mean?
I agree with her, dude.
She's not dead.
But you, whoa.
You gotta deal with this...
'Cause seriously, that's like
the darkest aura I've ever seen.
Suckin' the life right outta
you. It's killin' you, man.
You have
to let her go, dude.
ÿÿÿHow can I,
ÿÿÿwhen she won't leave?
Not your spirit girl.
I'm talkin' 'bout
the other one.
The one you're
keepin' in here.
That's what's really
haunting you, isn't it?
- I don't wanna talk about that.
- [chuckles] Oh, I get it.
You were dumped.
Probably for some guy
who doesn't have a couch
fused to his ass.
Shut up.
You can dish it out
but you can't take it?
ÿYou bring Father Flanagan
ÿand the Joy Luck Club in here
ÿto get rid of me.
But I talk about you
getting dumped once...
You don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
Shut the hell up!
Sorry for your loss, bro.
ÿÿÿA word to the wise, girl.
ÿÿÿShow some respect
ÿÿÿfor the dead.
[Elizabeth] David?
I'm sorry.
It occurred
to me now that I...
...probably don't
know you all that well.
I got this place for the roof.
ÿÿÿI was gonna do
ÿÿÿa whole garden out here...
...eventually,
I think.
Now I'm babbling.
I, uh...
I'm really sorry.
Most people who deal with loss
ÿreally find it helpful
ÿto talk about things.
ÿÿI don't wanna talk about it!
Anger works too.
ÿÿÿWho was he talking about?
ÿÿÿLaura. Her name was Laura.
ÿÿWho's Laura?
She was my wife.
What do you
think I am, stupid?
What is this?
Oh, come on.
ÿ- [people chattering]
ÿ- [siren wailing]
Don't. This is
not gonna help.
How would you know? Have you
ever been in a bar in your life?
ÿ[? Ron Hacker:Big Brown Eyes]
ÿ? Said she loved me
ÿGonna love me
ÿtill the day I die ?
ÿÿÿWhoo! Oh!
ÿÿThe groundhog emerges!
ÿÿÿI didn't think you'd make it.
ÿÿÿAll right! All right!
It's Jeff, Jody,
Kim, Valerie.
ÿThis is my buddy, Dave.
- Nice to meet you.
- What are you drinkin'?
ÿÿÿ- Coffee.
ÿÿÿ- Scotch!
ÿÿ- Don't you dare!
ÿÿ- Make it a double!
You don't have to wait. I can
start the hangover right now.
ÿÿÿYeah. Whoo! Yeah.
ÿÿHe's excited
ÿÿto be out. I know!
ÿÿÿFriday night!
- You can't drink feelings away.
- Watch me.
Um... So you OK?
Say goodbye, walk to the door,
let's get some food
in your stomach.
ÿWho made you my mother?
ÿÿÿUh... [chuckling]
ÿÿHow you comin' along
ÿÿwith those hallucinations?
- That was nothing.
- You're not a well man, David.
ÿÿ- It's just a lack of sleep.
ÿÿ- Sleep? You gettin' any?
Eight hours.
- Twelve.
- [David] Nine, tops.
Opium addicts
are more alert than you, David.
- Will you knock it off.
- Don't you dare!
Don't!
ÿÿLast chance.
ÿÿWhat are you
ÿÿgonna do about it?
[grunts]
Dave, buddy!
ÿ[all gasping]
ÿÿÿI'm so...
I'm sorry. God!
ÿ- [woman] You freak!
ÿ- [Jack] Dave, that is uncool!
ÿÿÿ[applause]
ÿÿ- Ugh!
ÿÿ- Good God!
ÿÿÿYou're gonna thank me
ÿÿÿfor that one day.
For making me look
like a lunatic in front
of all those people?
[groans]
Ugh!
ÿWhy are you still here?
That's a scary question.
I have no idea.
Why are you the only one
that can see me?
ÿDon't ask me.
All I know is
when I'm not with you,
it's like I don't... exist.
ÿÿOh, my God.
Maybe I am dead.
Oh, come on now.
I'm... I'm sorry
that I said you're dead.
ÿÿMaybe you're not dead.
ÿMaybe you're
ÿjust very... light.
If I could just
remember something
about who I am, or was.
I mean, then I'd
know once and for all.
I'm trying
to figure it out. I...
I just can't
do it by myself.
ÿ[chuckling]
ÿÿYou're not asking me to...
ÿÿto help you, are you?
Look.
You have two realities
to choose from.
First one being that a woman
has come into your life
in a very unconventional way
and she happens
to need your assistance.
ÿÿRight.
The second one is that
you're an insane person,
sitting on a park bench
talking to yourself.
I think I prefer
the first one.
OK.
Let's find out who I am.
[doorbell rings]
ÿNo.
ÿÿÿI think that
ÿÿÿapartment was vacant.
ÿÿ- That was a woman?
ÿÿ- Nobody live there.
ÿÿ- Like I was a ghost
ÿÿbefore I was dead.
ÿÿ- [doorbell rings]
ÿÿHi. Can I help you?
Finally, somebody normal.
I bet we were friends.
ÿHi, I'm... I'm David.
ÿI am a new tenant here.
ÿHi, David, Katrina.
ÿCome on in.
ÿ- She's friendly, I like her.
ÿ- This'll just take a sec.
ÿÿÿI have a question.
ÿÿÿThe apartment upstairs,
ÿÿÿit belonged to a young woman.
ÿYeah, I think there
ÿwas somebody up there.
ÿÿBut she was, like,
ÿÿtotally antisocial.
OK, maybe we
weren't close friends.
ÿÿKinda like a cat lady,
ÿÿbut without any cats.
ÿÿRight?
OK, I think we're done here.
Let's go.
ÿÿÿ- OK, thank you.
ÿÿÿ- Look. This is so retro,
ÿÿÿbut I've got a window
ÿÿÿI can't get open.
ÿÿÿ- She's got to be kidding.
ÿÿÿ- What?
- What?
She wants you to come in.
ÿÿWell, if it's painted shut
ÿÿand you use a screwdriver
ÿÿto jam it, it sometimes...
ÿÿÿOh, tried it.
ÿÿÿWon't budge.
No preliminaries.
Incredible.
I'd like to help,
but I have dinner plans.
Well, I got dessert.
I just threw up in my mouth.
ÿWell, OK. I...
I, um...
ÿÿÿNice to meet you.
- You too, Dave.
- Thanks.
Why is she wearing
workout clothes?
If you were gonna work out
in the middle of the day,
the only reason
to wear workout clothes,
do you really need
a push-up bra?
ÿÿThe whole point's
ÿÿto strap 'em down.
ÿ- You're not comin' anymore.
ÿ- Why? Something might
ÿjog my memory.
Too bad.
You're like an AM radio
that someone shoved in my head
and I can't turn off.
You don't think she was
completely un-classy
ÿand predatory?
ÿThose happen to be
ÿtwo of men's favorite things.
Why don't you
date a pit bull?
Maybe I will.
ÿÿÿ- Damn it!
ÿÿÿ- What?
[sighing] I locked my key
in the apartment.
There's a spare key
under the fire extinguisher.
I guess she's sexy if you're
into that whole tall, big boobs,
long legs,
model-y sorta thing.
ÿÿI guess if you
ÿÿwanna be that guy.
Look, there are five
other units here,
and not one person even
remembers what you look like.
Talk about being
disconnected from people.
ÿ- Are you sure you want that?
ÿ- Oh, yes, I'm sure.
Next drawer on the left.
ÿÿÿThere's a funnel in there
ÿÿÿtoo, if you need it.
- Check it out.
- What is it?
New leads.
Look, there's an address
written on here.
I can't make that out.
Is that a five or a six?
ÿÿÿUm, I think it's a...
ÿÿNo, no, no, that's a five.
ÿÿDefinitely a five.
So we have an address,
a dry cleaning ticket
ÿÿÿand a book of matches.
ÿÿÿYou know what that means?
We could start
a very small fire?
ÿThere's still hope.
ÿÿ[man] Oh, yes,
ÿÿthese pants were jet black.
ÿÿArmani, I believe.
Yes. I remember them.
They were expensive.
Do you remember anything else
about the woman? It's important.
She's pleasant,
but a little dull maybe.
- Dull?
ÿI think of her, I think
ÿof sadness, loneliness.
I don't need a psychological
profile from this guy.
ÿÿ- Can we just get the pants?
ÿÿ- Can I get the pants?
ÿÿItem left too long.
ÿÿWe give them
ÿÿto homeless shelter.
Gave away my pants?
Are you insane?
They were Armani.
OK, let's go.
[clears throat]
Are you coming or not?
They're pants,
what do you need 'em for?
ÿÿÿ425, I think.
- Look familiar?
- Not really.
[doorbell rings]
ÿÿHi.
ÿHello.
ÿÿÿ- Can I help you?
ÿÿÿ- Hi.
This might sound a little odd,
but I was wondering if you knew
a certain woman.
ÿÿBlond,
ÿÿabout five-foot-one...
ÿÿÿ- Two. And a half.
ÿÿÿ- Two and a half?
Oh, my God. Who are you?
ÿÿI don't know you. I...
- Did my wife hire you?
- I'm sorry, what?
I knew she'd find out.
Whatever she's payin' you,
I'll double it.
ÿÿ- Anything you want.
ÿÿ- I'm not looking for money.
- [woman] Donald! Who is it?
- That's her.
Come back around six.
ÿÿÿ- I'll have a check ready.
ÿÿÿ- Wait... But...
ÿÿWow.
- Hmm.
- What?
ÿYou don't think I actually
ÿhad sex with that old horndog.
- Kinda looks that way, Lizzie.
- It's Elizabeth.
And that's disgusting.
Well, look
on the bright side.
At 6:00,
I'm coming into some money.
ÿÿÿ- Thank you.
ÿÿÿ- You're welcome.
Oh, my God.
Maybe I was a slut.
A lonely,
home-wrecking slut.
I mean, seriously.
So, what if I was a slut?
- There's nothing wrong
with a sexual appetite.
- Not at all.
Look who I'm talking to,
Mr. Tried To Feel Me Up.
ÿÿI'm trying
ÿÿto agree with you.
- [gasps] David.
- What?
This is it.
You recognize it? Good.
ÿÿOK. Come on.
This is Moose's.
I loved this restaurant.
ÿ- You ate here a lot.
ÿ- No.
ÿ- I never did.
I remember looking
in that window and wishing
I could eat in here.
ÿÿWhat, were you a homeless
ÿÿstreet urchin? Why didn't you?
I wanted to, I just
never got around to it.
Maybe the dry-cleaner guy
was right about me.
ÿHello, can I help you?
ÿNo, thank you.
ÿMaybe some other time.
ÿÿ[man] Kenny!
Ivan, call 911,
we need an ambulance!
- [woman 1] You OK?
- [woman 2] Undo his collar.
ÿÿÿ- Is he breathing?
ÿÿÿ- I can't tell.
ÿ- We should do mouth-to-mouth.
ÿ- [man] God. We need a doctor.
We really have to find a doctor.
Is there a doctor here?
Anyone?
ÿÿÿ- Feel his chest.
ÿÿÿ- [David] What?
His chest,
check and see if it's bloated.
ÿÿ- How would I know?
ÿÿ- Just do it!
ÿÿÿExcuse me. Pardon me.
ÿÿÿI need to feel his chest.
ÿÿCan you feel his ribs?
ÿÿNo, but I can if I press down.
- What are you doing?
- Does he feel bloated?
ÿÿ- Mmm... I think so.
ÿÿ- Think what?
ÿÿÿTell them you'll need
ÿÿÿa sharp paring knife
ÿÿand a bottle of vodka.
ÿÿI need a sharp paring knife
- Ivan?
- Yeah, got it.
- What's wrong?
- It's a tension pneumothorax.
ÿÿ- It's a tension nemothaxer.
ÿÿ- Pneumothorax.
- Pneumothaxer.
- Pneumothorax.
- Pneumathurman.
- Never mind.
ÿÿÿ- Never mind!
ÿÿÿ- But what is it?
ÿÿÿAir is escaping out of
ÿÿÿthe lungs into his chest.
...out of his lungs
into his chest.
ÿÿÿ- Open his shirt.
- No, you do it.
- I'll do it.
ÿA valve at the opening of the
ÿlungs. If it doesn't close,
ÿÿit constricts the lungs
ÿÿand compresses the organs.
I want you to feel for his ribs
again. A little bit lower.
ÿÿThe spot between two ribs,
ÿÿdo you feel that?
ÿÿÿOK, splash
ÿÿÿsome vodka on it.
ÿÿ- All right. Get the knife.
ÿÿ- OK.
Uh, can I ask everyone just
to stand back a little bit here?
A little bit further, please.
A little bit further. Thank you.
ÿÿ- What am I doing
ÿÿwith the knife?
ÿÿ- Make an incision.
You know what? No.
ÿ- This man's life is at stake.
ÿ- I... I can't stab a man.
ÿOK. There's nothing
ÿto be afraid of.
ÿÿÿYou're gonna make
ÿÿÿa hole for the air to escape.
So put the knife
on that spot.
Oh, my God.
How do you know this?
ÿI don't know, I just do.
ÿNow do it! Put the knife there.
ÿÿÿNow, you're gonna need
ÿÿÿto push harder than that.
ÿ- A little bit harder.
ÿ- Oh, God!
ÿÿOK! OK, good!
ÿÿThat's enough.
ÿAll right, now, take the
ÿpourer out of the vodka bottle.
ÿÿ- What?
ÿÿ- You're doing good. Now...
Hold on.
ÿ- Go.
ÿ- Put the pourer
ÿin the hole you made.
ÿWhat?
ÿIt's gonna keep the wound open
ÿso air can escape. Do it!
ÿÿÿ- I can't.
ÿÿÿ- Do it.
- He's breathing.
- [David] He's breathing!
He's breathing!
ÿI'm a doctor.
ÿI'm a doctor!
I know. Thank God.
The ambulance
will be here right away.
ÿÿÿ[Elizabeth] Ask him where
ÿÿÿthe nearest hospital is.
Do you know where
the nearest hospital is?
A few blocks,
St. Matthews.
- Thank you.
- St. Matthews?
I may have been a homewrecking
whore, but I saved lives.
David, I worked
in that hospital.
I know it,
it sounds so familiar.
ÿÿÿ- I've never saved a life.
ÿÿÿ- It's the best.
One minute you're looking
at this monitor,
it says "game over,"
then you bring it back,
a little blip and it's there!
ÿ- What's that?
ÿ- That's just a little blood.
ÿÿÿ- [groans]
ÿÿÿ- [thuds]
ÿDavid?
ÿ- I work here.
ÿ- You did?
ÿÿThe receptionist,
ÿÿher name is Amita.
ÿIt's all coming
ÿback to me now.
ÿÿThere's Bill and Karen
ÿÿand Michael and, uh...
ÿElizabeth?
ÿYou mean Elizabeth Masterson?
Masterson.
Yes, that's my name.
Yes, that's it.
Elizabeth Masterson.
Dr. Masterson is, um...
...is not active
on our staff right now.
Hold on.
Let me talk to someone.
Excuse me, doctor?
ÿÿOh, no, she's got the tone.
ÿÿ- What tone?
ÿÿ- The tone.
ÿÿÿWhen you're trying
ÿÿÿto pass the buck
ÿonto somebody else
ÿto tell you your friend died!
Excuse me, sir.
I need you to go to
the third-floor nurses' station.
Oh, no, it's Fran.
She's my mentor.
They wouldn't send us up here
if it wasn't bad.
ÿÿ- [Fran] Mr. Abbott?
ÿÿ- Hi, yes.
ÿÿ- Fran Lo.
ÿÿ- Nice to meet you.
You've been inquiring
about Elizabeth Masterson?
Right. Could you tell me
what happened to her?
First I need to know
your relationship with her.
ÿTell her you're my boyfriend.
ÿShe can't tell you anything
ÿÿunless she knows
ÿÿwe're intimately connected.
We were romantic
with each other.
- What do you mean?
- Boyfriend-girlfriend.
I know what romantic means,
but I... I have
a hard time believing that.
ÿÿ- What? Why?
Elizabeth's whole life
was this hospital.
"Was"? Did she say "was"?
I don't know of a single date
she'd ever been on.
ÿÿWe were fairly recent.
ÿÿI live in her apartment...
ÿÿ- David.
ÿÿ- Building.
So, you don't know
about the accident.
ÿÿÿ[David] Accident.
Oh, God, David.
I remember it.
ÿIt was awful.
I was... I've been away.
It was three months ago.
ÿÿÿ- [heart beating]
ÿÿÿ- Three months.
ÿÿI'm sorry.
I was away for awhile
on a business trip.
ÿ[beating intensifies]
ÿÿÿ[beeping]
ÿÿOh, my God.
What was that?
You were, like, flying.
ÿOh, my God. It's you.
It's you,
it's really you.
You're... you're not dead,
you're alive.
I know, David, but I'm
in a coma. This is not good.
Well, it's way better than dead.
Look at you.
Your body is healing, it's...
You don't have any scars.
You look pretty.
ÿIt doesn't matter how I look.
ÿÿÿThree months,
ÿÿÿthat's a persistent coma.
ÿÿÿOK, well, we're here now.
ÿÿÿLet's do something.
ÿÿLike what?
Like... I don't know.
You're the doctor.
ÿRight. Right.
ÿÿ- Forget it.
ÿÿ- What?
ÿÿI was gonna
ÿÿsay that we...
ÿÿÿI need to find a way
ÿÿÿto put myself together again.
ÿOK, good, good. That's great.
ÿHow do we do that?
ÿÿMaybe I should
ÿÿtry this.
Something's happening!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
I think it's working!
ÿÿÿYeah? No.
ÿÿÿLet me try again.
ÿÿI mean, really focus on it.
Hold on inside there.
ÿÿÿI'm not sticking.
ÿIt's like I'm no longer
ÿconnected to this body.
All right, all right, all right,
all right. Turn around.
ÿÿÿ- What?
ÿÿÿ- I want to try something.
ÿÿOK.
You felt that.
My hand tingled.
You are still connected
to your body.
ÿÿÿThe monitor doesn't agree.
Machines don't know everything.
ÿÿÿEverything in my training
ÿÿÿtells me they do.
Then how are we having
this conversation?
- I don't know.
- [door opens]
Mr. Abbott? I'm sorry.
I have an appointment,
and I can't leave you
here unattended.
Can I just have a couple
more minutes, please?
ÿI'm saying goodbye.
ÿÿ- Of course.
ÿÿ- Thank you.
ÿÿÿMy nieces must have
ÿÿÿmade these things for me.
Wow, that's
an amazing likeness.
ÿÿ[Elizabeth chuckles]
Look at this.
ÿThat's the picture
ÿfrom my nightstand.
Abby must have brought it.
You look great.
Look at me now.
These levels
aren't changing, David.
If anything,
they're decreasing.
ÿÿHey, um...
- I'm gonna have to leave soon.
- All right.
Want me to wait
downstairs in the lobby?
ÿNo, no, that's sweet.
ÿYou should go.
Thank you
for helping me.
ÿÿIt was my pleasure.
Um... Are you sure you don't
want to come back with me?
ÿÿÿAfter all, it is your
ÿÿÿapartment. It's fine.
After I made
it here, I...
...can't imagine
leaving myself, you know?
ÿOK, I know, I just...
It just feels weird
leaving you here alone.
ÿÿI don't know
ÿÿwhere else I belong.
Mr. Abbott. I'm sorry.
ÿGoodbye, Elizabeth.
Goodbye.
Oh, I hate this.
She finally gets a life,
and then....
ÿÿYou know what?
ÿÿThat guy was cute.
ÿÿÿAt least she got a chance
ÿÿÿto hang with him for a while.
Yeah. It woulda been awful
if she'd gone through
her whole life
not knowing
what it was all about.
ÿÿ- [moaning]
ÿÿ- Oh, my God. Jenny?
No wonder
I could never find you.
I guess you got my job.
Yeah. I think I've
earned it. I deserve it.
Everything
you thought it would be?
It is. And it's time to upgrade
from the 330 to the 740.
ÿ- Goin' to the dealer tonight.
ÿ- [phone rings]
Hold on. It's Walsh,
I have to take this.
ÿÿHello?
ÿReally? You want me to do it?
ÿSure, of course I can.
ÿÿDude, did you know I can get
ÿÿa built-in jack for my iPod?
Did you know there's
people out there dying?
ÿÿÿI'm in a coma,
ÿÿÿhave you noticed?
ÿÿI know. Sweet!
ÿÿ[children laughing]
ÿÿÿZoe? Lily Vanilli?
ÿÿOh, my God,
ÿÿyou guys got so big!
Beat ya!
ÿÿÿ- Did not!
ÿÿÿ- Did too!
Did not!
Did too!
ÿHow could I feel him
ÿand not you guys?
ÿÿÿ- Did not!
ÿÿÿ- Did too!
ÿÿ- Oh, that's funny.
ÿÿ- Abby.
ÿÿÿI remember saying
ÿÿÿno running, no screaming!
- Abby, can you feel me?
- All right, chill, I'm serious.
ÿÿI guess not.
ÿÿÿ- I hope you feel better.
ÿÿÿ- Get well soon.
ÿI love you.
I remember
when you pushed us...
It's so sweet you guys
come and visit me.
ÿ- And I really miss...
ÿ- Excuse me.
ÿÿÿ- Mrs. Brody, hi.
ÿÿÿ- Hi.
Dr. Rushton. Could I
have a quick word?
ÿÿ- Sure.
ÿÿ- What do you want?
First of all, I hope you
know how much we all love
and miss Elizabeth.
ÿPlease. He's doing high fives
ÿhe's not in Phoenix.
And because she was
a senior resident here,
we've taken some fairly
extraordinary measures
to make her feel more
comfortable these last
three months.
ÿÿLily! Turn it back!
ÿÿZoe, what did we talk about?
ÿÿÿWatch your sister. Sorry.
This is hard to say.
Um, when we come
to work here,
we are asked
to sign release forms.
ÿOK.
I don't like
the sound of this.
Did you know your sister's
opinion about artificially
prolonging life?
ÿ- No.
ÿ- She was against it.
ÿReally?
ÿÿOK, that was before.
ÿÿI am completely for it now.
Honestly, most in our
profession feel that way.
ÿÿNot me!
ÿÿI'm perfectly happy.
Come on, Abby!
You have got to feel me,
I'm your sister!
But there's still some
brain activity, isn't there?
ÿPeople have woken up
ÿfrom this kind of coma.
- All the time.
- Not on any record I've found.
Of course they have!
Otherwise, what am I doing here?
- Ugh, I feel car sick.
- [kids laughing]
ÿ- What are you doing?
ÿ- We're looking for the stick.
ÿWhat stick?
- You said she had a stick...
- Stop! Come on.
ÿTV is going to become
ÿa very dim memory for you two.
Mrs. Brody,
Elizabeth did sign a release.
But because
of the special situation,
ÿÿwe won't take any terminal
ÿÿaction without your explicit
ÿÿapproval.
Now, I've prepared
this paperwork...
Don't sign that.
I'm here!
ÿ- ...if you decide to sign...
ÿ- I'll think about it.
ÿÿÿAbby, I'll baby-sit more,
ÿÿÿI swear!
ÿÿÿAnd those jeans you love?
ÿÿÿThey're yours!
ÿÿÿWe sometimes find
ÿÿÿthat it's easier
just to ask God's forgiveness
and not prolong the inevitable.
ÿÿÿI said I'd think about it.
Thank you, Abby.
ÿYou always looked out for me.
ÿÿÿYou here?
ÿÿI guess not.
[doorbell rings]
ÿI'm locked out.
ÿÿÿ[? Kelis:Brass In Pocket]
ÿ? Got brass ?
ÿ? In pocket ?
? Got bottle ?
ÿ? I'm gonna use it ?
ÿ? Intention ?
ÿ? I feel inventive ?
ÿ? Gonna make you, make you ?
ÿÿ? Make you notice ?
[Katrina] Doesn't this location
make San Francisco bearable?
ÿÿWait, you're not from here,
ÿÿare you? Oh, good.
ÿÿAnd what's with all
ÿÿthe single men in this town?
ÿEvery time I meet
ÿa good-looking guy... lesbian.
It's tough.
I'd get on the phone
and I'd be like,
ÿ"Hello? Osama?
ÿCommunism is so over.
ÿLike, give your
ÿpeople toilet paper."
So, like,
if I had to choose?
ÿÿIf I had to choose.
ÿÿWow.
ÿI guess I'd have
ÿto go with the midget.
Uh, I'm sorry...
ÿThe locksmith,
ÿdoes he know to ring my unit?
Uh, I think so.
ÿÿÿUm, where's your bathroom?
ÿÿ- It's right down the hall.
ÿÿ- OK.
ÿ[gasping] Oh! Whoa!
ÿÿ- Elizabeth!
ÿÿ- Yeah.
No, I just... I didn't think
you were gonna come back.
ÿI thought you were gonna stay
ÿat the hospital with your body.
It's terrible. They're trying
to get my sister to sign papers
authorizing permission
to take me off of life support.
- No! What? They can't do that!
- I know. I said that.
Nobody could hear me.
And I just wanted
to talk to you.
ÿÿ- [Katrina] David!
ÿÿ- Uh, just a minute!
Well, that didn't
take very long.
ÿNo.
ÿÿNo, she barged in.
ÿÿShe got locked out
ÿÿof her apartment.
You don't have to explain.
I get it.
ÿÿÿNo, you don't
ÿÿÿget anything.
She's just using
the bathroom...
Her voice sounded
like it came from the bedroom.
ÿIt did?
[Katrina] Come here.
I wanna show you something.
When you know,
you know, right?
I had no idea that's....
You had no idea
she was naked on your bed.
ÿNo.
You're wondering
what she looks like.
ÿ- No, I'm not.
ÿ- A little?
ÿÿNot enough to go look.
Tell you what.
I'll do a little recon for ya.
ÿÿ- Please don't!
ÿÿ- Don't worry. I'm a doctor.
- Elizabeth. No, no, no, no, no.
- Relax.
ÿÿOoh!
ÿShe's got a tattoo on her ass.
ÿIt says "All aboard."
ÿ- Really?
ÿ- In three languages.
ÿ- Oh, that's funny.
ÿ- She's very cultural.
You know,
you sound jealous.
ÿ- Oh, please.
ÿ- You do.
[Katrina] Are you
talkin' to someone?
- Hey, what's goin' on?
- Eyes up top, David.
ÿÿÿN-Nothing.
ÿLook, I'm sorry if I'm
ÿcoming on a little too strong.
ÿÿÿThat's just my style.
ÿÿÿI hear you sometimes.
ÿÿUp here...
ÿÿÿ...by yourself...
ÿÿÿAnd I just figured...
ÿÿÿ...maybe he's lonely.
I know I am.
ÿÿÿIs it wrong for me
ÿÿÿto want to touch someone?
To be close?
Feel a warm body
next to me?
ÿÿ- David, just do it.
ÿÿ- What?
Go ahead, be with her.
It's what you both want.
ÿÿ- No, it isn't.
ÿÿ- Are you all right?
ÿÿDo you... wanna take
ÿÿsome kind of medication first?
ÿÿIt's cool if you do.
ÿDavid, it's OK.
ÿShe's beautiful, and she's
ÿright here in front of you.
ÿ- And I'm in the way.
ÿ- No, you're not.
Elizabeth.
Elizabeth. Elizabeth!
ÿIt's Katrina.
ÿUh-oh.
[clears throat]
ÿThat was quick.
Come on,
nothing happened.
ÿÿWhat'd you say to her?
Um... That I was
seeing someone.
[chuckles] Honestly?
Well, I didn't mention that I
was the only person who could.
ÿÿÿYou know, I haven't, uh...
ÿ...haven't really been
ÿwith anyone since...
...since Laura.
She was cursing
at her shoe.
ÿÿHer heel had broken.
ÿÿÿAnd then she just
ÿÿÿkinda sat down
and put her hand
to her head.
ÿÿCerebral hemorrhage?
ÿAnd...
ÿI couldn't do anything
ÿto help her.
ÿÿShe was, like, gone.
ÿÿI couldn't even say goodbye,
ÿÿand she was just...
ÿÿShe's gone.
ÿÿÿWhat was she like?
ÿÿÿOh, you know, she was just
ÿÿÿa big pain in the ass.
No, really.
I mean, the bras
on the doorknobs,
leaving the car with the...
with the gas needle below empty.
She couldn't put gas in the car.
It was impossible for her.
And just total stubborn
inability to master a remote.
So she would just
randomly click buttons,
ÿuntil the TV was snarled into
ÿsome unmanageable condition.
I mean, I'm so...
I'm mad just thinking...
ÿ...thinking about her.
ÿÿÿI'm sorry, David.
ÿYour sister really wouldn't
ÿsign those papers, would she?
ÿI don't know.
ÿÿI hope not.
Won't even matter
if I don't wake up soon.
ÿMy brain activity's
ÿdecreasing every day.
ÿÿÿMaybe that's not
ÿÿÿsuch a bad thing.
You're kind of
a smarty-pants.
No, it'll bring you down
to my level.
You're not dumb, David,
just a little lazy.
ÿCute, but lazy.
ÿÿÿThank you.
ÿÿÿI wasn't always like this,
ÿÿÿyou know.
ÿÿWhat were you like?
ÿÿCome on.
ÿÿI wanna show you something.
ÿÿ- [Elizabeth] Where are we?
ÿÿ- [David] It's an estate.
ÿÿThe guy's in Hawaii
ÿÿthis time of year.
[Elizabeth] Are we trespassing?
[David] Don't worry,
we're not going inside.
ÿHere it is.
ÿÿYou said you love gardens.
[Elizabeth] What is this place?
I made this place.
This is my work.
I was a landscape architect.
I had my own company for awhile.
ÿDavid, I've been here before.
ÿÿÿWhat do you mean?
ÿI know this is gonna
ÿsound really strange,
ÿÿbut I dreamed of this place.
ÿÿÿThese flowers, everything.
It's beautiful.
ÿÿÿI had no idea, David.
What a joy it must be
to create a place like this.
Yeah, it was.
ÿÿÿIs it gonna be again?
Sure.
Promise?
[phone ringing]
Oh, wow.
Who the hell's calling me?
ÿHello?
ÿÿÿDavid, it's Grace.
ÿWell, you are the luckiest man
ÿin San Francisco.
Thank you.
Why do you say that?
Great news,
the apartment is yours.
And they're willing
to give you a nice long lease.
ÿÿÿHow long a lease?
ÿÿReally long.
ÿÿAnd I'm gonna send it over,
- and I'll talk to you tomorrow.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Why are they giving me
a long lease now?
It's a terrible story.
The tenant was in
some kind of coma,
and it is what it is,
so they're gonna pull the plug.
ÿBut get this: they are gonna
ÿthrow in that couch you like.
-David?
- What?
We gotta go talk to your sister.
ÿÿÿWhy? What are you
ÿÿÿgonna say to her?
What kind of dirt
do you have on her?
ÿ[? Kay Hanley:Lust For Life]
ÿ[Elizabeth] Her
ÿmiddle name is Ellen.
ÿIn the third grade she told
ÿeverybody it was Leia,
ÿlike Princess Leia.
ÿÿÿAll right. What else?
Um... She's
lactose intolerant?
ÿÿÿAll right, look, the only
ÿÿÿway this is gonna work
ÿÿÿis if I could tell her
ÿÿÿsomething that only you know.
ÿÿSomething so intimate,
ÿÿso personal...
Oh! Oh!
She kissed her ex-boyfriend J.J.
five minutes before her wedding.
ÿÿÿOh, that'll work.
ÿÿÿThat's good.
- [Elizabeth] Nobody knows that.
- I think I like her already.
[doorbell rings]
ÿSo, how did you know Elizabeth?
ÿYou must've worked together.
ÿÿGod knows she
ÿÿwasn't dating anybody.
ÿÿEverybody likes
ÿÿto rub that one in.
Actually, this is gonna be
a little difficult to swallow...
[children] Tea!
My nieces? They're
supposed to be at school.
- Hi.
- [British accent]
Would you like some tea?
ÿÿWell, yes, thank you, madam.
Abort. Don't do this in front of
them, it's gonna freak them out.
ÿÿI'm sorry, you were saying?
ÿÿHow did you know her?
ÿÿÿ- Lie. Lie your butt off.
ÿÿÿ- We worked together.
ÿ- No!
ÿ- No.
No. You're not credible
as a doctor. Make something up.
ÿI mean, I didn't work
ÿwith her. We worked
ÿtogether on my illness.
I was a patient of hers.
ÿÿÿLily? Can you see me?
ÿ[David] I was sick.
ÿI had, uh, meningitis.
ÿÿÿSpiral meningitis.
ÿÿÿOoh. I'm so sorry.
Spiral meningitis?
It's not even a disease.
ÿÿOh, no, it's OK.
ÿÿI'm much better now.
I, uh...
Elizabeth, uh,
she believed in me,
ÿbelieved that I would recover
ÿwhen nobody else did.
And then I did.
ÿÿÿThat sounds just like her.
But why are you
telling me this?
ÿÿUh... Because I know
ÿÿabout Elizabeth's situation,
ÿÿand I just wanna say that...
ÿLily.
- ...there are things...
- You know I'm here, don't you?
ÿÿ[David] ...sometimes that...
ÿÿÿ...that are beyond
ÿÿÿour understanding.
And so, I just
wanted to ask you...
Actually,
I just want to beg you
to, um... to give her
a little bit more time.
She's gonna pull
through this thing.
I just know it.
That's really
sweet of you to say,
but...
it's kinda too late.
ÿAbby.
- What do you mean?
- Abby, what did you do?
ÿÿ- It's David, right?
ÿÿ- Mm-hmm.
ÿYou see, it's too late because
ÿI've already signed the papers.
ÿÿOh, Abby. I'm here.
Can you feel me?
I'm right here.
ÿÿWe're terminating life support
ÿÿtomorrow at noon,
ÿwhile the girls
ÿare in school.
ÿÿÿI mean, the past three months
ÿÿÿhave been so hard on them,
ÿÿÿon this whole family.
Well, I understand that.
I really do.
But I think you're makin'
a grave mistake here,
ÿ- because I really believe...
ÿ- It's for the best. Really.
ÿÿÿThis is what
ÿÿÿElizabeth wanted.
ÿÿÿI mean, I spent my
ÿÿÿwhole life thinking
ÿÿÿI knew what was best for her.
ÿÿÿWhat she should wear,
ÿÿÿwhat men she should date.
ÿÿThis is the last thing
ÿÿElizabeth asked for.
ÿÿAnd for the
ÿÿfirst time in my life,
ÿI'm gonna
ÿrespect her wishes.
ÿÿÿOh, Abby.
Look.
This is gonna sound
really strange to you, but...
Oh, no.
...the truth is,
is that Elizabeth
is here with us right now.
She came here with me,
she's standing next to you,
begging you to wait.
ÿÿÿRight next to me?
ÿ- Right there.
ÿ- David, stop.
No, let me do this.
I don't know how or why,
but somehow I can see
your sister's spirit.
I know it's crazy,
but I also can talk to her.
So why don't I have her just
explain the whole thing to you,
and I'll translate.
ÿCould you just hold on,
ÿjust a sec?
OK, tea party's over.
Time for Wiggly Safari!
ÿÿ[both] Yeah!
ÿ- OK, David, this could work.
ÿ- I think I was
ÿgetting through to her.
- You need to get her
to the hospital.
- Right to the hospital.
- Get her to rip those papers...
- Get outta here, freak!
ÿI'm not makin' this up!
ÿWhy would I?
Abby, calm down,
just calm down!
ÿÿÿI'll chop you!
ÿÿÿI swear, I will chop you!
ÿ- Tell her about J.J.
ÿ- I know about J.J.
- What?
- I know what you did with J.J.
I'll tell everybody.
How do you know that?
Nobody knows that!
ÿÿÿGet outta here! Get going!
ÿÿYou kids OK?
ÿÿMommy, is Auntie Elizabeth
ÿÿgonna have more tea?
ÿWhat?
ÿWell, I don't
ÿthink your sister's
a very spiritual person.
She's just
bein' a good mom.
Tryin' to keep her kids
away from a crazy guy.
ÿÿÿI think I would have
ÿÿÿliked to have been a mom.
ÿYou'd make a good one.
Thanks.
ÿGuess I'll never really know.
ÿÿÿCome on, Lizzie.
ÿÿÿThis can't be it.
- Lizzie?
- OK, I'm sorry.
ÿI know you don't
ÿlike to be called that.
I'm warming up to it.
ÿÿI can go to
ÿÿthat hospital.
I could talk to your friend,
Fran. I could...
ÿ- No, David.
ÿ- ...talk to the asshole guy.
Brett? No. Just stop,
they'll put you
in a straitjacket.
There's no way anyone's
gonna believe I'm still here.
ÿÿÿYour niece,
ÿÿÿthe little girl. She saw you.
Oh, great.
My fate's in the hands
of a four-year-old
who has seven other
imaginary friends.
ÿÿWait.
ÿÿThere is someone else.
What do you mean?
Come on.
ÿÿÿ- [David] Darryl!
ÿÿÿ- Dude.
ÿ- Yeah.
ÿ- Whoa, whoa.
ÿThe spirit's
ÿwith you, isn't it?
ÿYou can't bring that thing
ÿin here. What are you thinking?
ÿ- You were right. She's alive.
ÿ- Righteous.
She's in a coma. Her family's
gonna take her off life support.
ÿÿÿNot so righteous.
ÿÿÿSo, what, are you
ÿÿÿguys socializing now?
We've... acclimated.
ÿÿÿYeah, I can tell.
ÿÿÿIn fact, I'm sensin' some
ÿÿÿpretty intense feelings
ÿÿÿshe has for you, bro.
ÿ- Really?
ÿ- No, I don't.
ÿMajor red aura.
ÿSomebody's embarrassed.
ÿ- I am not. Can we focus here?
ÿ- OK.
- Ask him if there's a spell....
- Or a chant. Anything to get...
ÿ- My spirit...
ÿ- ...back in her body?
ÿWhoa. You're totally asking
ÿthe wrong question, man.
Why is that wrong?
ÿLook, I have the gift.
ÿÿI didn't ask for it,
ÿÿbut I do.
ÿÿÿI can sense these things,
ÿspirits, whatever
ÿyou wanna call 'em.
Why they're hangin' here
in the first place?
That's their
unfinished business.
So do I have the gift?
ÿÿÿDude, please.
ÿÿÿYou definitely don't have it.
ÿÿYou're a civilian.
But if I don't have it,
how is it that I can see her
and talk to her
when no one else can?
- Exactly.
- Exactly what?
ÿÿThat's the right question.
What the hell
is he talking about?
God, I feel like it's
right there in front of us.
I just can't
get a handle on it.
ÿÿHow do you solve a problem
ÿÿthat isn't possible
ÿÿin the first place?
Because nothing seems
impossible to me anymore.
I mean, why did I move into your
apartment in the first place?
Why can I see you
when no one else can?
I mean, why was I down
in that restaurant
when that guy collapsed?
It all seems
interrelated somehow.
ÿ- What are you doing?
ÿ- I don't know.
I feel like I missed something
here. Wait a second.
ÿÿRosemary Preston lives
ÿÿright here in San Francisco.
We could go talk to her.
ÿÿI'll call Information,
ÿÿmaybe she's listed.
Where did you get this?
It was just
at the hospital.
ÿÿYeah. I, uh...
ÿÿI took it.
ÿI'm sorry. I...
ÿÿÿI just...
ÿÿÿI wanted to have
ÿÿÿa picture of you.
ÿÿÿI wasn't sure that I was
ÿÿÿgonna ever see you again.
ÿÿI'm sorry.
ÿÿNo, don't be sorry.
ÿÿThat's really nice.
ÿÿI really like that picture.
ÿYeah. Yeah,
ÿI liked it too.
I had just gotten
my MCAT scores back.
ÿÿWell,
ÿÿyou must've done well.
No, actually, I bombed.
My scores were so low
I couldn't even get
into correspondence school.
ÿÿÿ- And that's a good thing?
ÿÿÿ- No.
I know it sounds kinda crazy. I
wanted to go back to the library
and start studying immediately,
but Abby said no.
The only thing to do
was to burn my scores
ÿand drink margaritas.
ÿÿLots and lots of margaritas.
ÿÿÿ[David] Well,
ÿÿÿlooks like she was right.
[chuckles] It's just funny
because the one time
I completely failed
at something,
I had more fun
than I'd ever had in my life.
ÿYou look happy.
I was happy.
But what was I doing
with the rest of my time?
When I think about my life
and I...
ÿAll I can remember is working.
ÿYou know? Working and working
ÿÿand trying so hard.
And for what?
You help people.
You save lives.
Yeah. Including my own.
I saved my life, for later.
I just...
I never thought
there wouldn't be a later.
ÿÿNo, don't say that.
ÿÿThere's still time.
ÿÿWe're gonna see this lady...
ÿYou know, I just don't want
ÿto spend my last night crying.
Or... fighting my fate.
I wanna do
something with you.
ÿÿOK. OK, great.
ÿWhat do you want to do?
ÿÿÿYou want to fly to Paris?
ÿÿÿSee the Eiffel Tower?
ÿÿÿNo problem.
ÿYou wanna dance on a beach
ÿin Bali? Let's go! Let's do it!
ÿÿÿAnywhere in the world
ÿthat will take
ÿMasterCard or Visa.
ÿÿÿAnywhere.
There is something
that I would like to do.
ÿÿÿAnything.
ÿÿI'm so bad at this.
ÿÿÿWhat? What is it?
Are you nervous?
ÿÿ- A little.
ÿÿ- Why?
ÿÿÿI don't know.
How can you be nervous
when I can't even touch you?
ÿI think I'm more nervous
ÿbecause you can't touch me.
Why?
ÿÿÿYou know in the hospital
ÿÿÿwhen you touched my hand?
ÿÿI felt it.
ÿÿI mean,
ÿÿmy spirit felt it.
ÿÿÿI don't know how.
But I think if you could
ever really touch me...
ÿÿ...I might wake up
ÿÿfrom all of this.
I can almost feel that.
ÿMe too.
ÿÿI think I know what
ÿÿmy unfinished business is.
What?
You.
ÿÿÿElizabeth.
ÿÿÿElizabeth?
ÿÿÿ- Elizabeth?!
ÿÿÿ- I'm right here.
Oh, good, good.
I thought you were gone.
Suddenly I know
what I'm supposed to do,
ÿÿbecause this time
ÿÿI can do something.
ÿÿWhat are you talking about?
Lizzie, when we first met, I
kept saying that you were dead.
ÿÿBut it was me that was dead,
ÿÿand you brought me back.
ÿYou saved me.
ÿÿAnd now it's my turn
ÿÿto save you.
ÿÿHow?
ÿÿÿI'm gonna steal your body.
ÿÿDavid.
David. David, what are you
thinking? You can't do this!
ÿÿ- Why can't I?
ÿÿ- Because you'll go to jail.
So? If something happens to you,
you think I care where I'll be?
At least this'll buy us
a little more time.
The things you'd have to know to
even start to pull this off...
You know them.
You'll talk me through it.
ÿÿÿOK, you're
ÿÿÿgonna need a van.
ÿAnd somebody
ÿwith no morals.
[? Emerson Hart:
Bad Case of Lovin' You]
ÿ- Whoa, whoa!
ÿ- Oh!
ÿÿ- What are we movin' again?
ÿÿ- Medical supplies.
ÿ- You didn't tell him?
ÿYou have to.
ÿ- Shh.
You know, David,
he looks familiar to me.
ÿÿÿ- You saw him at the bar.
ÿÿÿ- Saw who at the bar?
ÿNo one, never mind.
ÿHere we go!
ÿ- [screeching]
ÿ- [honking]
OK, and we're in such a hurry
to move this stuff because why?
ÿÿThere's a one-day sale
ÿÿon hospital beds.
ÿÿI always wanted one.
Oh, great. Now you're
gonna become a bed potato.
- You gotta tell this poor guy.
- Not yet.
ÿ- Not yet what?
ÿ- We're not there yet.
OK, Dave,
be honest with me.
Has your imaginary friend
come out to play, huh?
ÿÿÿ- Oops.
ÿÿÿ- Oh, God!
Whoa!
ÿ? I've got a bad case
ÿof lovin' you ??
OK, grab a cart.
You need
a blood pressure cuff
ÿand a portable ventilator,
ÿright there, that yellow thing.
Dave, what the hell are you
doing? This isn't a sale, man!
ÿÿAll right. OK.
I knew you wouldn't come
if I told you.
ÿ- Do I really wanna hear this?
ÿ- My imaginary friend
ÿÿÿis not imaginary.
She is the spirit
of a girl in a coma upstairs
ÿÿÿwho they're about
ÿÿÿto take off life support.
We've got to get
her body someplace safe.
ÿÿÿ- Really?
ÿÿÿ- Really.
- You should've told him.
- He wouldn't have believed me.
ÿÿÿ- Does he believe you now?
ÿÿÿ- I had to get him
ÿÿÿinto the hospital!
ÿÿÿLet me take you
ÿÿÿto the psych ward.
ÿÿÿThere are people up there
ÿÿÿwho can help you!
ÿÿÿNo time.
ÿÿÿIt's 11:30 right now.
ÿShe's gonna be dead
ÿin half an hour!
ÿÿÿTell him I know
ÿÿÿthis is a stretch.
ÿElizabeth is standing
ÿright behind you right now.
ÿÿShe says she knows what
ÿÿa stretch this is for you.
ÿÿ- Oh, does she? OK.
ÿÿ- Yes.
Well, if your friend's
really behind me,
ask her what I'm doing:
rock, paper or scissors?
- Rock.
ÿÿ- Scissors.
- Paper.
ÿ- Rock again.
ÿÿ- He's flipping me off.
ÿÿ- Are you flipping her off?
ÿÿÿ- You're flipping her off!
ÿÿÿ- How...?
OK. OK, sometimes
people with emotional
and mental disturbances
can have psychic moments.
But even if she was real,
do you know what you're
risking for this woman?
ÿ- Yes!
ÿ- Why?
ÿBecause I love her.
ÿI love her.
ÿÿÿI do, I love you.
No one's ever
said that to me before.
- David?
- What?
- Tell him thank you.
- We're really grateful, Jack.
I'm not
doin' it for you.
ÿÿÿThen why are you doing it?
Because someday, trust me, I'm
gonna need help movin' a body.
When that day comes, I don't
wanna hear any shit from you.
OK, get me on the gurney, quick.
[Jack] Oh, my God. David.
[David] I know.
She's pretty, right?
ÿÿThat's really sweet,
ÿÿbut we've gotta go.
No, that's not it.
This is her.
This is the woman
I set you up with, the woman
you stood up that night!
ÿI was gonna
ÿmeet Elizabeth?
And she didn't make it either,
because she had an accident.
ÿÿIt was you.
Is that it?
Is that why?
ÿÿI was supposed to meet you.
ÿÿÿHow did you know her?
I'm friends with her sister.
We went out years ago.
ÿÿI knew I'd seen him before.
ÿÿThat's J.J.!
- Jack is J.J.?
- Yeah.
What did you...? No one's
called me J.J. since college.
He's older and hairier,
but it's him.
He's the one who tongued
Abby at the wedding?
How the hell did you know?
Nobody knows.
ÿÿÿ- It's Elizabeth.
ÿÿÿ- Oh, my God.
ÿ- She really is here.
ÿ- I told you!
Well, let's get her
on the gurney!
I don't want them killing
Abby's sister! Come on.
ÿÿÿBe really gentle.
ÿÿÿ[gasps]
[phone ringing]
ÿYeah.
ÿÿÿI'm here already.
ÿ- That's Brett.
ÿ- He's here 15 minutes early!
ÿÿÿ[Brett] Soon as the sister
ÿÿÿshows, we're ready.
- He's comin' in.
- [Brett] That's OK. All right.
ÿÿ- He's smart. His name is...
ÿÿ- Dr. Rushton?
ÿÿÿ- Yeah.
ÿÿÿ- Well, hi, David Abbott.
ÿÿÿBuy some time.
ÿÿÿTell him you're a doctor.
ÿÿÿI'm a, uh...
ÿÿÿI'm a doctor.
You're a special consultant
from PAC Medical.
I'm a special consultant
ÿDr. Walsh sent me down
ÿfor a final evaluation.
I had no verbal or written
instructions to that end.
There's new evidence
to support that full...
ÿÿFunctionality can be restored.
ÿÿWe need to run some tests.
ÿÿÿWho's we?
ÿÿÿTell him your team
ÿÿÿis downstairs.
ÿÿMy team is downstairs with
ÿÿa signed order from Dr. Walsh.
ÿÿ- You got it.
ÿÿ- This is the first
ÿÿI've heard of this.
You won't mind
if I talk to Dr. Walsh?
ÿÿGo confirm with him.
ÿÿWe'll wait right here.
I'll just get him
on the phone.
- [Elizabeth] David!
- OK, I'm not convincing
as a doctor!
Oh, God, David, the felonies
just keep pilin' up!
ÿÿÿ- That way, David.
ÿÿÿ- Go this way.
- [Fran] Brett!
- [Abby] What happened?
Are you OK?
ÿÿThis is Dr. Rushton. I need
ÿÿsecurity on the third floor.
ÿÿDon't jostle.
ÿÿBut go faster.
ÿÿ- Take a right up here.
ÿÿ- Right here! Right, right!
ÿ[chatter over radio]
ÿÿÿThe elevator!
ÿÿÿHold it!
ÿÿÿWe need you to...
ÿÿÿ[grunting]
ÿÿÿOh, shit.
ÿÿÿStop right there!
ÿÿÿStop! Stop! Stop! Hold it!
Come on! Hey, hey, hey!
ÿÿ- David.
ÿÿ- Elizabeth.
Oh, my God, David.
My breathing tube is gone.
ÿÿÿ[David] What? No!
- Well, what can I do?
- It's too late. It's happening.
ÿ- No.
ÿ- It's strong.
ÿ- Be stronger.
ÿ- [beeping]
ÿIt's pulling me away.
ÿÿ- No! Stay with me!
ÿÿ- [flat-line tone]
ÿÿ- [guard] I got ya.
ÿÿ- Elizabeth!
- No!
- David.
ÿ- [guard] Give me a sedative!
ÿ- Help her!
- Gimme five of Haldol.
- Help her! Elizabeth!
- Hold him.
- No! Elizabeth!
ÿÿÿ[beeping]
What's going on?
ÿÿ[Brett] That's not possible.
ÿÿThat's not possible.
ÿÿÿ[coughing]
Elizabeth?
Can you hear me?
I can't believe
we almost let you go.
Honey? It's me, Abby.
- Abby.
- Yeah.
ÿÿÿI think I bumped my head.
It's OK.
Hey.
ÿHello.
It's me.
ÿI'm sorry, I don't...
ÿÿÿHoney, it's David.
ÿÿÿYou don't remember David?
ÿThe apartment.
ÿÿThe rooftop.
ÿGarden.
Nothin'.
Honey, you don't
remember him at all?
ÿÿ[? Amos Lee:Colors]
ÿÿ? Yesterday I got ?
? Lost in the circus ?
ÿ? Feeling like such a mess ?
ÿÿÿ? Now I'm down ?
? Just hanging on the corner ?
? I can't help but reminisce ?
? When you're ?
ÿÿÿ? Gone ?
? Colors seem to fade ?
[girls]
Aunt Elizabeth, come on!
ÿ? Your mama called ?
? She said that you're
downstairs crying ?
ÿ? Feeling like such a mess ?
ÿÿ? Yeah I hear you ?
ÿ? In the background bawling ?
ÿÿÿ? What happened to your ?
ÿÿ? Sweet summertime dress? ?
ÿÿ? But when you're ?
ÿÿÿ? Gone ?
ÿ? All the colors fade
ÿwhen you're ?
ÿÿÿ? Gone ?
ÿ? No New Year's Day parade ?
? You're gone ?
ÿÿÿ? Colors seem to fade ??
ÿÿ[Abby] We only
ÿÿrented it for a month.
ÿÿÿ- Did you move something?
ÿÿÿ- No.
It's funny, I just have
this strange feeling,
ÿÿlike... something's missing.
Everything's here,
just as you left it.
ÿÿÿI guess it's just
ÿÿÿbeen a long time.
ÿYou sure you're
ÿgonna be OK?
Yeah. I'm gonna be good.
- So I'll see you guys Saturday.
- OK. The girls'll bake for you.
ÿÿHi.
ÿÿÿUh... Don't worry, I'm...
ÿÿI just wanted you
ÿÿto have your garden.
How did you get up here?
ÿÿSpare key.
ÿÿUnder the fire extinguisher.
ÿÿÿLook, the last thing
ÿÿÿI want to do is scare you.
Goodbye, Lizzie.
ÿWait.
ÿYeah?
ÿThe key. I need the key back.
ÿÿÿOh, right.
How do I know you?
ÿMaybe from your dreams.
ÿÿÿ[Elizabeth] If you could
ÿÿÿever really touch me,
ÿÿÿI might wake up
ÿÿÿfrom all of this.
ÿÿÿIt wasn't a dream.
ÿÿNo.
David.
ÿYeah. Yeah.
ÿÿÿRighteous.
ÿÿÿ[? The Cure:
ÿÿÿJust Like Heaven]
ÿÿ? Show me, show me, show me
ÿÿhow you do that trick ?
? The one that makes me scream
she said ?
ÿ? The one that makes me laugh
ÿshe said ?
ÿ? And threw her arms
ÿaround my neck ?
? Show me how you do it
and I promise you ?
ÿÿÿ? I promise that
ÿÿÿI'll run away with you ?
ÿÿ? I'll run away with you ?
? Spinning on that dizzy edge ?
ÿ? I kissed her face
ÿand kissed her head ?
ÿ? And dreamed of all
ÿthe different ways ?
ÿÿ? I had to make her glow ?
ÿÿ? Why are you so far away?
ÿÿShe said ?
ÿÿ? Why won't you ever know ?
ÿ? That I'm in love with you ?
? You ?
ÿÿÿ? Soft and only ?
ÿÿ? Lost and lonely ?
? You ?
ÿ? Strange as angels ?
ÿ? Dancing in
ÿthe deepest oceans ?
ÿÿÿ? Twisting in the water ?
ÿ? You're just like a dream ?
ÿÿÿ[? Katie Melua:
ÿÿÿJust Like Heaven]
ÿ? Daylight licked me
ÿinto shape ?
ÿÿ? I must have been
ÿÿasleep for days ?
ÿ? And moving lips
ÿto breathe his name ?
? I opened up my eyes ?
? I found myself alone, alone ?
? Alone above the raging sea ?
? That stole
the only boy I loved ?
ÿÿ? And drowned him
ÿÿdeep inside of me ?
? You ?
ÿÿÿ? Soft and only ?
ÿÿ? Lost and lonely ?
? You ?
ÿ? Just like heaven ?
ÿÿÿ? Soft and only ?
? You ?
ÿÿ? Lost and lonely ?
ÿ? Just like heaven ??