Come in.
Thank you.
November
Please, tell me your name,
age and date of birth.
My name is Nonomiya Keita,
and I am six years old.
My birthday is on
the 28th of July.
Whom do you think
Keita resembles most,
his father, or his mother?
It'd seem to my wife,
for her mild temper
and her kindness to others.
Does he have any serious defect?
Probably the same thing:
he wants to do everything calmly.
He doesn't seem to mind losing.
For me, his father,
it is a little disappointing.
Keita,
what is your favourite season?
Summer.
And what did you do last summer?
I went camping with my father
and we also flew kites.
Is your father good
at ﬂying kites?
Very good.
FUKUYAMA Masaharu
ONO Machiko
MAKI Yoko
LILY FRANKY
Written and Directed by
KOREEDA Hirokazu
Like Father, Like Son
Has it changed?
They must be doing very well.
It's not the stadium I knew.
Lower your voice.
- I'm here!
- Did you study a lot?
Dear parents,
we are through for the day.
We wish a safe way home.
Thank you.
Keita.
I've never taken you camping,
have I?
Why did you say so, then?
The principal advised me to.
You've learned a lot
of things at school...
You also said:
"The omelette my mother made me."
- Did you pass it successfully?
- Yes.
- Have you painted balloons?
- With a very nice monster
- A nice monster?!
Damn,
you caught me red-handed!
Very strange seeing
you here on a Saturday.
I intended to leave before you came.
- The mock-up looks very good.
- Thank you.
I've checked it three times.
Your turn.
I won't be bothering you any more;
I'm off.
I won't be long,
shall we go eat somewhere?
I've planned going to the
movies with my wife.
Thanks to you and your hard work,
I have time to stay with
my family.
- I'm counting on you.
- I appreciate it
That's the South and that's the North,
isn't it?
Yes, the sun rises from here.
I'll put a couple of families
in the park.
- With dogs?
- Yes, it'll look more like everyday life.
Everyone,
the boss invites to have something to eat,
it's got very late.
You can choose between pizza,
rice with meat...
It doesn't seem bad to me
him going to a private college.
Ryota thinks he should make an effort
now for the sake of the future.
The fixed is ringing.
- Will you answer it?
- It must be daddy.
I'll tell you about aunt, bye.
Well?
It's daddy.
Are you coming to dinner?
I thought you'd get home later.
Shouldn't he be
practising the piano?
He's through with the exams,
so, for once...
He must be disciplined.
If you lose a day...
You'll be three days late
trying to recuperate, I know.
Come on, Keita.
It's piano time.
Come on, let's play.
Have you already had dinner?
The bath is ready.
Almost nothing,
a slice of pizza.
Why didn't you send me
a text message?
Isn't there anything?
I'll make some pasta for you.
Minura has send us
home-cooked pasta.
Seems great, let's have it.
Don't overcook the pasta.
Don't worry, I'll be careful.
No eggs in the evening,
too much coleslaw.
Just one won't do me anything,
isn't it so, Keita?
Punished!
Why am I being punished for?
Come on, you try once again.
I hope Minura
is all right with the new job.
Of course he is.
He is made for living
in the country.
You don't seem to care.
You used to always protect him.
I haven't got enough time
to waste it on losers.
Listen, listening to you,
I also am a loser.
Is he sleeping already?
He was stressed and tired.
We did our bets,
now it's up to him.
He's trying hard,
he wants to be like you.
Don't you think he has
has grown up?
You think so?
It'd seem he told Daichi
to leave him alone.
Let's hope it's true.
In our days,
kindness is a defect.
At the interview you said
it was his strength.
You should praise him more.
It's enough that one of us
pampers him.
May I?
Thank you for taking the day off.
Keita was thrilled.
I'd love being able to dedicate at last
the Sundays to him.
I'll have more time when this
project will be over.
It's been six years I've been hearing
you saying the exact same thing.
Is that true?
Yes, it is.
I almost forgot.
They've called from
Maebashi hospital.
What hospital?!
That's where I gave birth to Keita.
Yes, and?
I don't know,
they said they wanted to talk to us.
About what?
They'll tell us when we go there.
I'm worried.
I hope it's nothing bad.
Swapped children?!
That used to happen long ago,
when we were born.
Yes.
Most cases
are from the end of the '60s.
From those experiences,
we started writing the names
with marker
on the sole of the new born babies.
What happened, then?
Well...
How do you know the child
is not the other couple's son?
The blood test
made when he enrolled school
doesn't match his parents'.
- But ours do.
- No.
Are you sure?
Then... Keita...
...is not our son?
Three male babies were born in that
hospital that same day.
We must first do their DNA tests.
Then we'll know...
Two to go, one to go.
"CONGRATULATIONS, KEITA"
Come on, together.
Congratulations, Keita,
for having passed the entrance exam.
- Very well.
- Come on.
- That's the way to do it!
- Great.
- The tomato is good.
- Really?
That's how you eat.
Open your mouth.
A fried crayfish.
A crayfish.
Let me see.
- That's very good.
- Very good.
Now.
Very good.
Do you want to see it?
Press here.
- If you press here,
you'll see the ones before. - Yes.
- Come on, once again.
- And if I press here...
All four together.
Open your mouth.
"The results of test #1,
taken from Nonomiya Ryota,"
"The results of test #2,
taken from Nonomiya Midori"
"The results of test #3,
taken from Nonomiya Keita"
"show they are not related. "
"Report conclusions."
Now I understand.
That's exactly why I asked you
if that small town hospital
was sure.
My mother had me there...
- And my brothers.
- That's not enough.
You were very busy.
I was feeling very lonely.
My mother, at least,
could come and see me.
How come I didn't realize it?
I am the mother.
- Yes, it's here.
- We were delayed.
I told you to fill the tank.
Here they are.
Please forgive us,
we are very sorry for being late.
My wife had the idea...
...I should change clothes
just when we were leaving the house.
Good afternoon.
- The Saiki family.
- Good afternoon.
I can't...
It's been such a terrible surprise.
I am his wife,
my name is Yukari.
- And they are...
- Nonomiya, and my wife Midori.
This is Ryusei.
And this is Keita.
We took it last summer,
we went to Sunpia.
Don't we have a sharper photo?
This one?
- Where did we take it?
- In Karasugawa.
Yes, the Karasu River.
They still fish salmons and
trout in this river.
Look, look.
Ryusei and his brothers;
he's the one with the water gun.
What's his birth date?
The 28th of July.
The same day...
Maybe we've met here then...
I was rather sick after
I gave birth,
so I had to stay in bed.
He was born in a very sunny day,
very bright.
It made us think of
an Okinawan sunny day.
That's why we named him Ryusei,
like the kanji for "sunny day".
In cases like this,
100% of the parents
choose the to make the swap.
For the future of the children,
you should decide as soon
as possible.
- Before primary school begins.
- That's too soon.
We are talking about April,
that's less than six months.
- They are not pets.
- Even if they were.
You are right.
Even a pet, you don't swap it.
Besides,
haven't you thought about
any other possibility,
aside such a drastic one?
Yes, of course,
the hospital lawyer, Mr. Orima,
is looking into the case.
I can imagine that, for a parent,
it's a very difficult situation.
Undoubtedly, right now,
and if we think
about the children's future...
Did you find it all right
that we met without them?
Yes, we'd also like
to meet Keita.
All right, we'll keep in touch.
- It's very late.
- I know, I'm sorry.
It doesn't matter.
Well, how did it go?
How are they, what do they do?
- He has a shop.
- A shopkeeper?
Come in.
- Mother.
- Yes.
I forgot to give you this.
A present from the
"Tiger" candy shop!
- I think it's green beans sweets.
- You've guessed.
It's not about the
green beans sweets, mother.
If you insult the green beans sweets,
you'll rouse the tiger.
- How is Keita?
- Sleeping.
We played a lot of
play-station tennis.
I'll be stiff tomorrow.
I didn't want to say anything
at the time,
but, when old Yamashita,
our neighbour,
saw Keita for the first time,
she said:
"He doesn't look like
neither of them."
That was...
It was two years ago.
I believe.
Ryota, your husband,
is really a privileged person,
compared with our family.
There were people who didn't
favoured you two getting married.
A lot of people thought that.
It's possible that so much
negative energy...
It's got nothing _to do with
people envying us.
My poor little girl.
This is Shinjuku station's
west exit area.
It's an honour presenting
the Shinjuku Spiral Tower to you.
It's a terrible tragedy.
I'll try not to let it
affect my work.
But, what will you do?
Swap them?
No; anyway,
we haven't got to that point yet.
Raising them both could be
a solution.
Both of them?
Yes, don't you like it?
What's the matter?
Don't you want to meet our son?
Of course I do.
But, if we go on like this,
we'll end up doing what the hospital says.
Everything will be fine.
Trust me.
Please, forgive us.
She started cleaning up
just when we were about to leave.
Hey, my name is Saiki Ryusei.
My name is Yamato.
My name is Miyu.
Come on, introduce yourself.
Hi, my name is Nonomiya Keita.
Hi, how are you?
Thank you for waiting,
here are your beverages.
And here is your food coupon.
Come on, Ryusei!
I also ordered a lot.
It's ¥6,030.
No, no.
- Allow me.
- No, it's out of the question.
I'd like an invoice.
- Write it on Maebashi hospital.
- Yes.
- And add this too.
- Yes, thank you.
You aren't eating, you're devouring,
you've dirtied your hands.
I've finished.
Shall we go play?
I also want to go and play.
Come on, go.
- Miyu!
- Take care of your brother.
Ryusei, watch over them.
Kids learn fast.
I wonder how much we could ask them
in damage
and impairment.
Money doesn't matter,
but it could help
find out how this happened.
Of course.
I think the same way, but...
You'll see,
the only they can prove their good faith
is by financially compensating us.
Exactly, that's how things work.
Have you already seen a lawyer?
If that's the case,
allow me to take care of this.
A friend of mine has a lawyer's office.
Very well, ask him his opinion.
- Daddy!
I'll call him.
My neck hurts.
Oh mother!
I didn't think he looked like us.
But he did.
A friend who's very frank accused
me of having had an affair.
I found that very cruel.
But I never imagined
something like this.
- Goodbye, goodbye
- Goodbye, Keita, see you soon.
What's this?
A note from Ryusei's mother:
"Count on me".
"Count on me"?!
That's rather arrogant.
You should prepare yourself.
We might have to sue them.
Sue them?
Forgive me, I was in an
unexpected press conference.
- I know you are busy.
- I've thought about it.
I'm not interested in the money,
I want to know how it happened.
The hospital's lawyer
is a red-neck.
He knows about bankruptcies
and that's about all.
He doesn't understand anything.
I am grateful for your interest.
Do you mind?
I don't want the case
to get in court.
I'd like to get custody
of both kids.
That's a surprising idea.
You want to be the
other child's father?
I'd like him to live with us,
he's of my blood.
Your blood?
In our time and age this doesn't matter.
It's not about that,
but about being a father.
Notwithstanding everything,
you go on with your paternal obsession.
Come on, let it go.
Look here.
In England,
if the State considers the parents
incapable of taking care of their children,
they end up in the
custody of an institution.
Yes, if they are drug addicts,
or if the mother uses the house
to prostitute herself.
The mother raises her voice straight away
and the father doesn't react.
I doubt a court would consider this
to be parental neglect.
They do have rights.
We could give them a lot of money
if they'd let us adopt him legally.
They won't accept.
You could suggest that at
the right moment.
You don't change.
You're as stubborn as ever.
As your lawyer,
I advise you to team up with them and
ask for compensation from the hospital.
January
What conclusion have you reached?
This our fourth meeting already.
Maybe
it's a good idea they start sleeping
in the other house.
Children adapt easily at this age.
We might consider this option,
but that has nothing to do
with the compensation.
Of course, of course.
What do you think,
Mr. Saiki?
Well...
The meetings are going fine,
but we should consider a solution,
don't you think so?
You say we should solve this,
but is there a textbook for this?
Well put.
I don't know if I like the suggestion
But it could turn out all right.
You have the same blood,
and that's what counts.
Once they feel that,
things will settle on their own.
We must also take into consideration
Yamato and Miyu.
I don't want to rush into things.
Exactly. we don't see what
need there is to hurry things.
What about you, Mr. Nonomiya'?
I suggest we try
this coming weekend.
On Saturday nights,
for instance.
Grown-ups are speaking,
go and play.
Keita,
do you like playing the piano?
You don't have to,
if you don't like it.
But, daddy says it's good for me.
You are right, and, then, there's the
concert. We'll go on, then?
We're going on!
I'm hopeless.
I've won!
Keita eats soba, yes.
I haven't yet given him
raw fish.
Listen, Keita.
We'll be leaving from here
at 10 am.
Because...
On target.
Because tomorrow you'll stay
at Ryusei's home.
- Agreed?
- Agreed.
You'll see,
it's some kind of a mission
to make you stronger.
- Do you know what a mission is?
- Yes.
- You do?
It's part of a strategy so you...
...grow up and
become stronger.
Oh mother...
It really is pathetic...
- Good afternoon.
- Hi.
Hi.
Take good care of him, please.
Ryusei,
please climb in the back.
Oh, my God.
Chuji.
HEY,
did you know that Spiderman
is in fact a spider?
- Man, it really is cold.
- How are you doing?
Fine, fine.
I have to change the
bathroom bulb.
Shut the door, it's cold.
Do you want a LED one?
I'll have to piss more
quickly with so much light.
4O UV will do.
¥190.
Do you have any plans
for next Saturday?
- At 6am.
- Playing baseball again?
- Aren't you a little too old for this?
- We'll let you pitch.
That sort of thing is not for me,
my shoulder is old.
- It's old.
- But you had a kid!
- All right, we'll see
- I'm counting on you, thanks.
Croquettes?
Yes, croquettes
Three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
ten!
Eleven.
- Twelve...
- This number smells nice.
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
Fifteen.
Here's the food.
Great, time to eat!
I'm hungry.
It's good, very good.
Hurry up,
or there'll be nothing left for you.
It's hot, be careful.
- And for daddy.
- Only one egg for daddy.
He must eat more eggs
with the sukiyaki.
- Eat.
- Is that good?
It's too hot, I can't eat it.
I'll lower the flame.
It's good.
- You like it?
- It's good.
Ryusei.
Would you like me to
teach you how to use the chopsticks?
This way?
Look.
Wait, watch how I do it.
Move them like this.
Come on, you try.
Keita, son.
Please,
put this on the altar, will you?
There.
Coming!
Is it time already?
Can I toll the bell?
- Of course.
- Good morning.
- Have you already done this?
- Yes, in my grandmother's house.
- Your grandmother's house?
- Yes.
- All right, hi to everyone
- Hi.
- Good morning.
Grandpa, this here is Keita.
Please, say hi to him.
Don't get too close, it burns.
There's smoke.
I think it works.
The batteries for the car.
Great!
- Which one?
- That one.
- That one is the "Skytree".
- Yes.
Oh, my God.
What time is it?
- A quarter to three.
- Thank you.
- Would you like to go home?
- What?
- Would you?
- Yes, let's go home.
I'm back!
Welcome home!
Have you behaved yourself?
We've made you come a long way.
Don't worry,
I was born in this town.
- And Ryota?
- He had a very important meeting.
He works a lot.
Let's hope
my husband will do likewise.
"Leave for tomorrow
what you could do today",
is my motto.
Sure, go on like this,
and you'll be dead before doing anything.
Don't try scaring me,
I've still got a couple of years left.
Hey, what's this?
Nothing, a park incident.
I ran a lot and I fell.
He bled a little,
but then I stopped it.
You bled?
Did it hurt?
Did you know they
all bathed together?
It's very small.
Like half of ours.
How is Ryusei's mother?
In the beginning I was very scared,
but she is very kind.
That's good.
Keita.
What would you say
if we ran away?
Where to?
- Somewhere far away.
- Where is far away?
In a place where
nobody knows us.
And what will daddy do?
Well, daddy...
Daddy is very taken with
his work.
Wait, Ryusei!
Yamato!
Wait, Yamato!
That's for sure.
Your hair is wet.
Wait, come here.
- Stay put, I'll dry you.
- I already am dry.
No, you are not.
- But I am!
- It's soaking in the back.
- Turn around.
- Don't try my face.
Come here.
Come on,
tonight we'll all sleep together.
They admit damages were inflicted,
but they don't even
bother to excuse themselves
That's why you should
have come with me.
It's useless picking on me.
We'll put you a dressing.
In Ryusei's home,
they call it a
sticking-plaster.
They do?
All right, done.
Come, go and say
daddy good night.
- Good night daddy.
- Sleep tight.
How did lunch go, all right?
A success, Kaoru ran into
an university boyfriend.
The manager
was very disappointed.
Did they say anything about me,
made any comments?
Did they wonder why, as a mother,
I didn't realize it?
No, not at all.
In fact,
you are wondering about that.
- No, I am not
- You're lying.
You think
everything is my fault.
When will I go again to Ryusei's
home to spend the night?
Next Saturday.
May I take this with me?
Sure you can.
That's great.
He can fix no matter what.
That's wonderful.
Well,
we'll ask him
to fix the radiator.
Mother, won't you stay?
April
I have knitting classes,
I have to go.
Besides,
it feels like staying in a hotel,
I'd rather go home.
During the war,
a lot of kids were separated from their
parents, or lost them,
and other people adopted them.
What really matters
is who brings you up.
I haven't yet decided
to bring him up.
But, then, why all this?
Why make him come and go?
We'll talk about it
and we'll see what
decision we'll take.
Forgive me.
An old woman like myself
shouldn't butt in.
On the contrary,
your opinion counts a lot.
I thank you for that.
We are ready now.
Dressed like this,
you are more handsome
than any prince.
Good morning.
- They have already arrived.
- Yes.
Mr. Saiki.
Good morning.
The hospital has paid for me
taking the shinkansen.
Come in, please.
- This is for you.
- Thank you very much.
Come on, come here.
Ryusei has already told me
it looks like a hotel.
Keita, hi!
You are so handsome!
You must be the prince
of a far away land.
It's a pleasure meeting you,
I'm the grandmother.
Of course, you are Keita's grandmother,
I'm pleased meeting you.
But you are so young...
Flattery won't take you anywhere.
I don't think I'll ever see you again,
so there's no need for it.
- May I?
- Of course.
Keita, what did you pick up?
- Let's see.
- A nice petal.
- Stop filming him.
- You don't have to.
Look, I'm filming myself, see?
Tsuyuki Mao.
- Tsuyuki Mao, answer
- Yes.
Nonomiya Keita.
Yes!
I can't understand ii.
When I saw Keita's little face,
I thought of Ryusei.
But, now, I'm looking at him,
and his is Keita's face,
isn't it so?
Mr. Nonomiya-san!
Ryota-san!
Your turn!
Such pain, such pain!
I can't do it any more,
it's over.
They've worn me out.
One must have them
before being 40.
I am too old.
You are younger than I.
You should find time
to be around your son.
Well, there's all kinds of families
in this world.
Don't you bathe together?
In our family, the idea is
one must be independent.
Well, if that's the case,
of course it's very honourable.
But, believe me,
it's worth dedicating some time to him.
Let's be honest,
in these last six months
I've spent more time with him
than you have.
Come on,
there are other things besides time!
Don't you think that,
for kids, giving them time is everything.
There are things at work
that only I can do.
But no one can play the role
of the father other than you.
Hey!
RYusei!
We're leaving.
You'd say they are brothers,
it's unbelievable.
One pork curry to go, please.
One second, please.
My father-in-law is with us,
I think he must be hungry.
Little by little he is
sliding back into childhood.
It's like we had four kids.
Or rather five, I'd say.
I can't take care of all of them.
Do you mean me?
If that is the case, who knows,
maybe we could take of those two.
Those two?
Keita and Ryusei.
Wait,
did you mean that?
Yes.
Don't you find it possible?
I can't believe it.
You are insulting us.
- If we think about his future...
- Our kids don't have a future?!
I have larger financial means.
There's a lot of stuff
you can't buy with money.
You want to buy a child now,
is that what all it's about?
Didn't you say you were
interested in the money?
Forgive him, he's tired,
he doesn't realize what he's saying.
The children are looking at us.
The pork curry is ready.
You've never lost a game,
have you?
He doesn't have a clue
what other people feel.
How will you settle this'?
You hit at him
like it was nothing.
I can't still believe,
he surely must have got mad.
Shut up for a second, please,
and let me think.
Right when we had started
to get along very well...
Why should I put up with
a shopkeeper giving me advices?
Don't start again.
You're back!
- Cafie' latte, for mother
- Thank you.
And a black one for daddy.
Thank you.
- Here's the change, mother.
- Thank you very much.
Here it goes!
Your turn!
That's the way to do it!
It went out, Keita,
it has to hit inside.
It's not good,
careful not to hit outside.
Do you remember nurse Miyazaki?
No.
- Who knows when I met her...
- What will she say?
I suppose the hospital
will try to prove
that the working conditions of
the staff were good ones.
She started ironing
when we were leaving...
Please,
this is not the moment for nonsense.
Please forgive us
for the other day.
Yes, of course.
No, no, it also was our fault.
I swear to tell the truth,
and nothing but the truth,
in full accord with my conscience,
without withholding anything
and with no intent of hiding the truth.
- Saiki Yukari.
- Nonomiya Midori.
Miyazaki Shoko.
Admitting the hospital
made a mistake,
shouldn't you have realized it?
You are the baby's mother.
In ordinary circumstances,
probably I would have.
But I suffered a post-partum haemorrhage.
I barely was conscious
during a couple of days.
Do you think you'll be able
to swap children without difficulties?
I don't know.
Even if we'll decide to swap them,
there's nothing that guarantees
the children will adapt.
The pain this mistake
caused our family
won't go away easily.
It's a pain we'll have to put up with
for many years.
Tell me the schedule
you had at the time.
Were you supposed to be on night-shifts
for a number of days in a row?
No.
Compared with other hospitals,
the shifts were very good.
If that's how things were, why do you
think this accident happened?
It was no accident.
It wasn't an accident?
What do you mean by that?
The Nonomiyas seemed
very happy with their son.
I did it on purpose.
I had a lot of problems
raising my husband's children.
I vented my frustration
on other people's children.
The Nonomiyas had the most
expensive home of the lot.
She told me her husband was
working for a big company.
Her family was coming
to see her all the time.
In comparison with her,
I had nothing.
Can you describe how you
were feeling back then'?
Sincerely,
I was happy to find out
I wasn't the only one who
had problems.
All right,
let's see.
What pushed you to confess
right now?
My husband's children
love me now.
That's why what I did back then
seemed really monstrous.
I want to be punished
for what I did.
I ask you for forgiveness
from the bottom of my heart.
I am very sorry.
She can't have thought she'd alleviate
her frustrations on our expense.
She was aware her husband had children
when she married him.
She looked relieved.
For her is like shop lifting.
She didn't look like she understood
the consequences of her actions.
Now she says she's feeling happy.
How can anyone be so selfish?
I'd say
the hospital should pay more
in damages and losses.
- That's obvious.
- Yes, of course, much more.
Please,
don't forget to ask
Mr. Suzumoto.
Yes.
- She'll go to prison, won't she?
- Yes.
Of course she'll go to prison.
Well, five or six years
don't seem enough to me.
Unfortunately,
the crime has been expired.
Expired?!
Yes,
that's what Suzumoto told me.
We could accuse her
of kidnapping,
but it expires after five years.
- That's ridiculous!
- Lower you voice, please.
We can't allow it to be
that easy for her.
We'll always suffer,
and nothing will happen
to this woman.
She knew her crime had expired,
that's why she confessed it.
I am sure.
I'll never forgive her.
Never.
Ever.
June
Let's see how you are doing.
Look what
a flower stem Megumi is making.
She's making it very well.
She was taking
blood pressure pills.
Is it the second one?
The third.
At least it
wasn't Mr. Nobuko.
Well, yes.
Try calling her "mother"
when you see her, all right?
Yes?
Don't I usually do that?
Just imagine:
father is so weak that he asked
his sons come and see him.
Better this way, it'll do him good
being a little weak.
When he sees the roses,
he'll start crying.
- The change.
- Thank you
- Thank you for ordering from us.
- Thank you for coming.
It's the only restaurant
in the entire neighbourhood.
Have you recovered entirely
from your illness?
If I hadn't,
you wouldn't be here visiting.
I've already told you last time
I couldn't give you any more money.
I don't need any money.
I work as a concierge
in a Minowa neighbourhood building.
And she
works part time.
- Stop playing the stock market.
- That's enough, Ryota.
You like salmon roe,
eat your fill.
I'd love being able to.
But I have to be careful
with the uric acid.
I'll make an exception.
Why do roe taste so good?!...
What about horse races?
By the way you look
you must have lost a lot.
You're again betting
on the wrong horse, mother.
Why do you insist on suffering?
You've got the wrong horse.
Betting is no good, you'll see.
It seems I'm like you in this.
Well,
that's how marriage life is.
Don't go out of your way
for him.
You work more than a nurse.
If I am your nurse,
you must pay me ¥1,000 an hour.
That's more than I get paid.
Three years of practising,
but always plays the same
"Tender Flower".
There's no one who takes a nap.
Shout, they'll hear me.
Exactly, I want them to hear me.
Well,
have you got to know him yet?
I mean your son, the real one.
- Yes, we know him
- Does he look like you?
Of course he does.
That's what family means.
Ones children are like one,
even if not living together.
Come on, father,
let's not start with this.
Don't you think so?
Listen to me,
it's a matter of blood.
It's the same in humans
as it is in horses.
This child will be
more and more like you.
But Keita
will every time look more like
his natural father, believe me.
Swap the children
as soon as possible
and never see this family again.
It's not that easy.
It's slippery, be careful.
I know it's slippery,
don't be such a bore.
Are you my wife?
I only wanted to be kind to you.
Go on like this and you'll
find yourself without any friends.
It's been a while since
I haven't had any friends.
Even if your father said it,
it's enough living with someone,
blood counts for less.
Love the other person
and you'll end up being like her.
It happens in married couples.
And, probably,
the same thing happens with children.
In my case,
that's how I felt inside
during the years I raised you.
- Come back soon.
- Yes.
Tell Manami I'll soon come and see
her precious bedspreads.
Yes, please, do come.
Goodbye.
And the next time,
bring something to drink,
forget the flowers.
- I'm happy your father is well.
- He acted it.
I had to ask for a day off.
Did he say anything about Keita?
No, not much.
Keita, father's back.
- Welcome back.
- Thank you very much.
For Father's Day,
he made it at school.
Keita,
thank you very much.
The second one is for
Ryusei's father.
I want to thank him
for having fixed the robot.
I understand.
You are very kind and generous.
Why don't we go on
like until now?
Like nothing happened.
Every day that goes by,
Keita will look more and more
like you.
And Ryusei
will look more and more like us.
Can you
love him like before,
knowing it's not of your blood?
That has got nothing to do.
You are only worried
of your son looking like you
because you don't feel
a true bond with him.
The longer we'll take,
the more difficult it will be.
For us.
For the children.
Keita, you take care of them.
I have to go.
- Go, goodbye.
- Goodbye!
The bento is ready.
¥400 please.
Keita, there's another
piece of fried chicken for you.
- Be careful on your way home.
- Goodbye.
When the summer will come,
we'll have sparklers
in the garden.
We'll swim in the pool
and we'll eat freshly cut
watermelon.
- You too, Keita.
- Yes.
So beautiful.
I am at home.
I've got here already.
Yes, you've been a great help,
thanks.
I'll talk to you.
Welcome home.
Where is Ryusei?
Having a bath.
I didn't realize what time it was.
I'm sorry
you have to take care of him.
But tomorrow I have a day off.
It has always been this way,
it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
Who were you talking with?
With Yu-chan.
She says Yudai wants to open
a sun' articles shop
when he turns fifty.
The best part is that
he knows nothing about sun'.
You shouldn't
keep in touch with her.
As mothers,
we have a lot of things to share.
But you don't understand this.
He plays very well.
Of course.
Keita, I don't understand you.
If you lack the will
to play well,
it would be_better
you gave it up.
Not everyone
can work as much as you do.
Has working become a defect no?
Not all of us can work as much
no matter how much we'd like it.
I think Keita takes after me.
Is he asleep?
I did what you asked me.
You obviously want
Keita to leave.
You said you'd solve it.
Liar.
I didn't think it'd end like this.
You had decided this
from the very start.
Six years with Keita
count for nothing with you.
- Blood is more important.
- You are wrong, that's not how it is.
Are you telling me that?
What did you say when you found out
Keita wasn't ours?
Don't you remember it any more?
Yes, I remember it.
I don't understand how
you can not see it.
Forgive me.
- It's not your fault.
- No!
It's not about that.
I'll remind you what you said.
"Now I understand".
It made sense then.
What makes sense now?
Never
were you able to accept that Keita
doesn't have your ability.
I'll never forget
what you said back then.
Ready?
You're very good.
Great.
Ready? Let's go.
Can I have it?
Through there.
The camera,
do you want me to give it to you?
Why?
Don't you want it'?
That's it, I don't want it.
I understand.
Listen, Keita,
when you go to your home,
it'd be better if you'd call father
and mother with "uncle" and "aunt".
Even if there will be times
when you'll feel alone,
you shouldn't call us.
Promise that.
Is it a mission?
Yes, it's a mission.
Do I have an objective?
It's not clear yet.
Keita,
you won't understand now
the meaning of this mission.
But I am sure that,
in ten years' time, you will.
In Ryusei's home,
will I also play the piano?
As you'll wish.
If you'll want to go on playing,
tell them, and we'll arrange it.
Listen, there'll be no kites
around here today.
It's the time for the
ayu fish to spawn.
They've laid cables
to protect them from the birds.
Let's go!
Enough now!
RYusei!
When we were kids...
Well,
the truth is I'm a little
older than you.
But my father
used to make kites from bamboo sticks
and very fine white paper.
He'd cut paper strips from the
newspaper for the kite's tails.
Nowadays,
kites fly like on their own.
Back then it was much more
difficult making them fly.
My father
was not the kind that'd
fly kites with their kids.
I understand.
But there's nothing forcing you
to act like your father.
Please,
do fly kites with Ryusei.
I will.
A train went by.
It went by!
He doesn't show it,
but lots of things scare him.
He was very late in going
to the bathroom alone at night.
I always had to go with him.
But when Yamato was born,
he turned into an older brother.
He promised that when Yamato
wouldn't be using diapers any more,
he'd take him to the
bathroom at night.
Keita
has been telling me sine he
was little that he wants a brother.
But
I can no longer have any children.
That's why
I think he'll be happy
with a brother
and a sister,
even if it happens this way.
Keita,
when you go home,
you mustn't worry about anything.
Ryusei's mother and father
also love you very much.
More than you do, daddy?
More than I do.
Hey,
how about taking a photo
with all of us'?
- Yes.
- Let's go.
Ready?
Come on, don't move.
Smile.
Let's all smile.
Come on, get ready!
One,
two,
and three!
- Why are you laughing?
- Why am I laughing?
- I don't see the joke.
- Neither can I.
"I shouldn't bite the straws.
I go to English classes every day
and I study a lot.
I must behave when I go the toilet.
I bathe alone,
without making any noise.
Or play the play-station
for half an hour a day.
I must call you mother and father."
Why?
You are not my father.
From now on,
I'll be your father.
Why?
It doesn't matter.
Well,
they...
I'll explain it to you.
Your father and mother
live there.
Like they always did.
But now
you can call us
father and mother, all right?
Why?
It doesn't matter.
You want to explain it to me
because it doesn't matter
- One day you'll understand.
- Why?
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't?
Why?
- That's what I'm wondering also.
- Why?
Brush your teeth.
Here.
It's better like this.
Let's see,
what's the matter?
Did you hurt yourself?
All right.
Let's see what we can do about it.
Here?
Is it here, here, here?
Are you all right now?
August
Utsunomiya
Engineering Department?
Yes.
Why are you sending me?
Nohara could take care of it.
Well...
The trial date is drawing near,
there's little time left.
I am sorry, sir,
but I am the plaintiff.
Yes, I know that very well.
You see,
you've always stepped on the gas.
There are moments
when one should push the brakes
But you are where you are
because you didn't push the brakes.
It wasn't the same thing,
times are changing.
Try spending more time
with your family.
The ramen boxes
can be blue or red.
- And which do you like best?
- I like the red ones.
The red ones are with soy sauce.
- Isn't it so?
- I don't know.
Yes?
Father hasn't arrived yet,
we won't tell any one.
Why did you draw this?
You made mother cry.
Did you ask her to forgive you?
No?
Very well.
Go to bed.
Aren't you saying good night?
Good night.
"Father Mother"
You are making noise.
I said enough!
That's too much.
This doesn't work,
this is broken.
Tell your mother
to buy you another one.
When I go back home,
daddy will fix it.
Ryusei.
You'll never go back
to that house.
From now on, you'll be living here.
I am your real father.
Let me see it.
I've just told you have won,
but it doesn't seem to make you too happy.
I haven't won, nor have I lost.
Well, in many trials,
it is not too obvious
who wins and who loses.
No, that's not I mean.
It doesn't sound like you,
you could start with agreeing with me.
I don't do it to agree with you.
Do you care what others think?
You've really changed a lot.
I almost forgot.
Here.
The nurse gave it to me.
Besides what the hospital gave,
that's the most she can give
in good faith.
Good afternoon.
Listen,
I came to give it back to you.
I'm very sorry.
What you did
destroyed my family.
Teru.
It has nothing to do with you.
It has.
She's my mother.
Nonomiya residence, hello.
It's Ryota.
Ryota, what do you know?...
Thanks for coming the other day.
Listen.
Shall I call your father'?
No.
I've called to ask for forgiveness.
No, Ryota,
don't get serious at this time.
It's for back then.
I don't want to go back,
it's past history.
I want to talk trivial things
with you, it doesn't matter.
What star wears a whig
and what other had surgery.
All right.
Your father's calling me
there's no saké lefi.
Very well.
I understand.
We are using much less water
in the Green Roof project,
now that we are channelling
the rain water.
If we add all the water used
at irrigating the plants
and filling the trench,
we don't go over
42.6 cubic meters.
I have also started
as an architect, same as you have.
This forest was created for man,
for research.
And this,
was born here?
Yes.
Insects reproduce themselves
easily here.
But fifteen years are needed
from the moment
a cicada lays eggs
until they turn into larvae
and get out from the ground.
That much?!
Do you think it's a long time?
Hello.
I'm sorry, it's me, Nonomiya.
I'm sorry for being late.
Hi, what's the matter'?
Apparently,
he decided he wanted to ﬂy a kite.
A kite?!
He sneaked into the suburbs
train behind an adult.
That's smart,
he's very good at this kind of things.
That's nothing to be proud of.
- You should have punished him.
- What's your suggestion?
That we should have sent him back
on an empty stomach?
That's not the way we are.
I understand your point of view.
If you think he doesn't adapt,
he can stay with us for a while.
Of course.
We have no problems
with having both Ryusei and Keita.
Everything will be fine.
I'll take care of that.
RYusei!
Ryusei, let's go home!
You don't have
to call us
father and mother right away.
Take your bath
and stop fooling around.
Keita.
If I caress him like this,
it's like
it was you.
I also ran away from home.
I wanted to see my mother.
But my father came immediately
and dragged me home.
- And now what?
- Let's go to father!
Oh, my God!
RYusei!
Ryusei, Ryusei, are you all right?
Father!
Are you hurt?
Father, are you hurt?
Enough now!
Careful!
You are going to win,
you are going to win!
I've won!
- Did you find it?
- Where was it?
- The smallest one.
- Thank you very much.
On your marks, attention...
Go!
- You've fished your father.
- Careful.
Cancer, Scorpio,
Gemini.
Sagittarius.
Libra.
Aquarius.
- Virgo.
- Look...
A shooting star...
Make a wish.
What have you asked the star for?
That I may go back with father and mother.
Ryusei.
I'm sorry.
It's nothing.
What happened?
Now I love Ryusei too.
Why are you crying,
then?
Because
I feel awful about Keita.
It's like I'm betraying him.
I wonder how Keita's feeling?
Do you want to have breakfast'?
Don't you want to eat?
Welcome.
Bulbs, isn't it?
How many watts?
- I'm back home.
- Welcome home.
Ryusei, what's the matter?
Keita.
Keita!
Forgive me.
Daddy
couldn't go along without
seeing you any longer.
I've broken the rules to see you.
Father is not my father any more.
You are right.
But, listen,
during six years...
I was your father during six years.
I was not a good father,
but I was your father.
The flower you gave me...
I'm sorry, but I lost it.
I am sorry.
In the camera
are all the photos you
took of me.
And the piano...
Father also stopped
playing the piano.
Listen,
the mission is over.
They are back already.
Welcome.
Come on.
Yes.
- Let's go inside.
- Yes, let's go inside.
Did you know Spiderman
really is a spider?
I had no idea.