- One orange.
Chungwa moja.
Two oranges.
Machungwa mawili.
One pineapple.
Mananasi moja.
[Speaking African
Language]
Mm-hmm.
[Speaking African Language,
Loud Chatter]
Omouri! Omouri!
[Laughing and Cheering]
[Omouri Laughing]
Here he is, the cleverest
boy in the world.
[Laughing]
Hi, Mom.
And what's this?
It's, uh, it's a picture.
Oh, my goodness.
And, uh, there's the Comoros.
Of course, it is.
Mrs. Odone, may I please have a word?
Very skillful, sweetheart.
And, uh, Jupiter.
Jupiter, next
to the Comoros?
I'll be right there, Lorenzo. Yes?
Okay, Mommy.
Is Lorenzo having problems at home?
Not that I know of.
He suddenly started
throwing paints around.
He went wild destroying
other children's paintings.
Surely he must
have been provoked.
Came out of the blue.
He's normally a terrific kid.
How were they annoying you?
Were they teasing you?
No.
Were they touching your paints?
How were they annoying you?
They just were.
Doing what?
Things.
What kind of things?
Things that make me feel annoyed.
[School Bell Rings]
Mrs. Odone.
Another incident?
Yes. Today it
was much worse.
Mrs. Odone, is there
some trouble at home?
Why do you assume the trouble's at home?
There's nothing here...
that explains
his behavior.
It's... disturbed.
[Italian Opera]
[Singing Along]
[Skipped item nr. 43]
[Muttering]
[Screaming]
[Aggravated Screaming]
[Child Yelling]
[Screaming]
He does present
as a hyperactive.
Hyperactives repeat tasks endlessly, don't they?
They perseverate, yes.
Lorenzo's activities all have a beginning,
middle and end.
He's learned
three languages.
How could he
be hyperactive?
[Laughing]
[Indistinct Conversation]
Gifted children
can also be disturbed.
Lorenzo needs to be referred
to our I DP committee.
What's that?
For what?
Individual
disability placement.
Lorenzo needs to be
in a Special Ed class.
Any Special Ed
our son needs will
be provided at home.
[Mrs. Odone]
Anyhow, it was snowing...
and he began to rub
my hands to warm them.
Uh-oh.
No, no. He then
produced photos of
his wife and children.
Oh, that old game.
Oh, Deirdre.
Had I known this was
the man I was going
to wait 10 years for,
I'd have let you
pick up the check.
[Mr. Odone] I did pick it up.
[Indistinct Chatter]
[Bell Ringing]
[Man]
Please keep your seats.
[Mrs. Odone]
I'm sorry, but l...
I even left the tip.
[Mrs. Odone Laughing]
Look at him, Mother.
[Woman]
That's not fair.
[Laughter]
[Door Opens]
Lorenzo's fallen off
his bike...
and he is really bleeding.
Shh. That's a boy.
Oh,
such a brave boy.
[Woman]
Doin'just fine here.
[Mr. Odone]
You're going
to be okay.
It's Christmas day,
you know.
All across the country,
little boys are trying out
their new bikes.
Hey, champ, you better tell
your folks to lighten up.
What are they gonna do when
you're playing nose tackle
for the Redskins?
[Church Choir Music]
[Skipped item nr. 86]
[Panting]
[Skipped item nr. 88]
The E.E.G. Is normal,
the skull X-ray is normal...
and the CT scan is normal.
I don't know what
to tell you. This boy
is neurologically intact.
Doctor, we spent three years
in East Africa...
In the Comoros.
We were wondering i...
If he might have picked up
some rare parasite.
It's possible.
[Loud Classical
Music]
Lorenzo,
what are you doing?
Lorenzo!
[Music Stops]
Sweetie?
Mm-hmm?
Can you hear Mommy?
This, uh, may be an auditory
processing difficulty.
The ears hear, all right,
but the brain has
trouble listening.
So...
this means
something is
affecting his brain;
but what, a tumor?
Multiple sclerosis?
It could be any one
of a dozen things.
Listen, my friend,
I'd like you to stay
in the hospital
for three days.
Your mom and dad
can come too.
We're gonna
run some tests and get
to the bottom of this.
[Doctor]
Can you hear this sound?
Focus right
on that spot for me.
That helps me out.
All right, Lorenzo,
close your eyes.
[Woman] Keep your
eyes closed, buddy.
Stay nice and still.
[Opera Music]
[Mrs. Odone]
Easter festivals existed
long before BabyJesus,
back to pagan times
when they marked
the beginning of spring.
And the egg
tells us...
that the earth
is gonna be reborn,
like a baby chick.
Mrs. Odone, Mr. Odone,
Dr. Judalon
is ready now.
Hey, Lorenzo,
would you like to go
feed the goldfish?
It's all right,
sweetheart, go ahead.
We'll be right back
in a few minutes.
Go ahead.
[Doctor]
This way, please.
Please have a seat.
[Air Conditioner
Rattling]
Well, we certainly don't
need that noise, do we?
So.
Please, Doctor,
without equivocation.
There is a family of
diseases that's quite rare. ;
the leukodystrophies.
Lorenzo has one of them.
It's called A.L.D.
What A.L.D. Is is an inborn
error of metabolism...
that causes a
degeneration of the brain.
It only affects males,
usually between the ages
of five and ten.
Its progress
is relentless.
The end is inevitable.
All boys with A.L.D. Die,
usually within
two years of diagnosis.
And there are
no exceptions?
I am so sorry.
Are you
absolutely sure?
Yes.
Lorenzo shows the
definitive sign.
He has an abnormally high
level of fat in his blood,
certain very long-chain
saturated fats.
Uh... these fats, um,
destroy his brain?
But, but how?
Well, there is an enzyme
that should metabolize
these fats,
but in A.L.D. Boys,
it's defective;
so, they collect
in the nerve cells,
a little bit like
cholesterol in the arteries.
And...
in some way,
this liquefies the
white matter of the brain.
"Some way liquefies"?
Could you be
more specific?
Well, to be honest,
we're not quite certain
just how it works.
You know what myelin is?
Myelin is the fatty sheath
that insulates the nerves.
It's a little like plastic
around electrical wires.
Without it, the nerves
cannot conduct an impulse.
What A.L.D. Does is
strip away the myelin.
It corrodes it,
if you like.
This causes degeneration
of the brain.
As the brain degenerates,
the body loses its functions.
But surely someone
somewhere must be
working on this, no?
We would go anywhere,
mm-hmm.
Yes.
The problem is ten years
ago this disease hadn't
even been identified.
We're still trying to
understand just what it is.
I would like to
offer you some hope,
but...
Then there...
there's absolutely
no treatment?
Normally, at this point,
we try to be constructive,
we try to focus on
what can be done,
but in this case...
[Child Speaking
and Laughing]
When we get home,
can we read a story?
Of course,
my darling.
Lorenzino,
let's go home.
[Quiet Sobbing]
[Moaning]
[Crying]
[Groaning]
[Phone Rings]
[Woman on Intercom]
Mr. Odone, I have a Dr. Judalon
on line three.
Good.
Put him through.
They're waiting for you
in the finance committee
meeting.
Thank you.
Hello?
[Dr. Judalon] Augusto,
I just got off the phone...
to Gus Nikolais,
Professor of Neurology...
at the Institute of
Childhood Diseases
here in Washington.
If there is a
so-called world expert
on the leukodystrophies,
well, Nikolais
would be it.
Ah, good.
I don't want to raise
any false hopes,
but he's working on
an experimental protocol
based on a diet.
Wonderful.
[Panting,
Labored Breathing]
Peanut butter,
red meat, cheese...
Unpeeled fruits,
spinach, olive oil.
But these are healthy foods.
But they contain very
long-chain saturated fats.
L...
I still do not
understand why they are
so harmful to Lorenzo,
why they're destructive
to his brain.
How can spinach
and peanut butter
make the difference?
The body needs these fats
in order to create cells.
The excess is burned off;
that's normally, of course.
In an A.L.D. Boy,
these saturates
can't be broken down...
and they build up
in the brain.
Somehow this buildup
strips the myelin covering?
Yes, exactly.
For the moment,
we don't know why this is.
But we feel that by
withdrawing the saturated fats
from the diet,
we will prevent them
accumulating in the brain.
- And if we could?
- There's no way to reverse
neurological damage.
All we can hope for...
is to slow
the cascade of symptoms.
If it's any consolation,
you'll be
helping us understand
the biochemistry of this...
heartless disease.
So, can we enroll Lorenzo
in our trial?
I suppose so.
Good.
Then I will pass you over
to our dietician...
and meanwhile,
we should arrange
some genetic counseling.
Dr. Nikolais, it's
highly unlikely that we
will have another child.
No, but your sisters
and their daughters
may all be carriers.
We need to test them.
Only my family?
What about his?
No, no. A.L.D. Is passed
only through the mother.
But I thought you
understood all this.
We, uh, we knew
it was inborn.
We assumed that
meant a combination
of our genes.
That's true in
other inherited diseases,
but A.L.D. Is only carried
on the female chromosome.
Excuse me.
Are you saying
that Lorenzo got this
directly from me?
Well, in the sense
that A.L.D. Is sex-linked,
yes.
It goes
from mother to son.
Then how did I get it?
The woman gets it
from her mother.
If I inherited
the defect, why don't
I have the disease?
No, the woman is only
the carrier, nothing else,
but with
each conception,
she has a 50-50 chance
of passing on the defect.
And when that happens,
it's the cruelest kind
of genetic lottery.
Lottery?
It's a clumsy word.
I use it because it's...
It's all arbitrary.
No one is to blame.
Um, if Michaela's
mother had this,
and her
mother's mother,
why was there
no warning?
I suppose if you went back
into the family tree, you'd...
But remember,
a short time ago...
this disease didn't even
have a name.
Mrs. Odone, you have enough
to put up with without...
You have nothing
to blame yourself for.
Thank you.
[Woman Over Phone]
I don't think it's
a good idea.
So she
doesn't want me.
What about mother?
She's packed
and ready.
Don't you get it?
Michaela doesn't want
anybody around.
Well, what about
Father Killian?
Hell no. She's not
even going to mass now.
What is happening
there, please?
Let it rest, okay?
No.! What about
Lorenzo's birthday?
I'll call you.
Bye.
Deirdre.
Deirdre...
This is wrong.
She needs her family here.
She doesn't want nobody.
She's too angry.
We cannot afford
the time to be angry.
Look what she's dealing with.
She does not have to deal
with this alone.
She feels
incredibly alone and
incredibly unlucky,
like she's been
singled out by God.
Oh, Deirdre!
Here's Kenise, a carrier
with two girls; me,
a carrier with no kids;
and Mariah's got a boy,
but she's not a carrier;
so, poor Michaela
gets this laid on her.
This did not happen
only to Michaela.
Sure.
You got two kids
already...
[Michaela]
Let me make you
something, sweetheart.
I'll get you a big quart
of fruitjuice.
She waited
all this time
to have one child.
She's not gonna
have another.
[Laughter,
Indistinct Chatter]
[Knock At Door]
Francesco.
Cristina!
Ah, buon giorno.
Oh, Francesco.
[Speaking Italian]
[Michaela,
Speaking Italian]
[Michaela]
Everyone, this is Lorenzo's
sister and brother...
who came all the way
from Rome.
[Simultaneous Greetings
From Crowd]
[Laughter]
[Uproarious Laughter]
This does not
make sense.
Lorenzo's saturated fats
have risen.
We eliminate them
from his diet,
and in his blood
they increase.
If these very long-chain
saturated fats are
destroying his mind,
then surely we should
take him off the diet.
[Nikolais]
Mr. Odone,
please be patient.
Your son has been on
the diet only six weeks.
Wait until the end
of the trial.
What about the other boys?
What results are you
seeing in them?
As with Lorenzo,
it's too early to tell.
We need the study to run
for the full six months.
That will tell you
what is obvious now,
that avoiding apple skins
and pizza...
has no effect on
this brutal disease.
Augusto...
Please, Doctor,
is there anyone...
who is chasing
a definitive
therapy, hmm?
You judge us
too hastily.
The French have tried
bone marrow transplants.
In Boston, we're about
to try immunosuppression.
Why have we not
heard of this before?
The transplants
were disastrous...
and the immunosuppression
is highly experimental,
so the protocol
has been limited
to six boys,
all more profoundly
afflicted than your son.
For God's sake,
how afflicted
does he need to be?
[Augusto]
It's a school, Lorenzo,
like any other school.
It's full of doctors?
Yes, darling,
some of
the cleverest
in America.
What color's
that cross?
Red.
That's right, it's red.
I'm going to speak
to your parents,
but Leah's
gonna stay and take
your blood pressure, okay?
I'll be right back.
[Leah]
I'll just put this
around your arm.
Look, it's important
you both know exactly
what's going on.
Cyclophosphamides
are no picnic.
This is all-out
chemotherapy.
We're gonna
be suppressing
his immune system.
It's very high-risk.
We're gonna need...
to keep him here
at least three weeks.
[Leah] That's it.
Lorenzo's still walking,
he's still talking, he's
still communicating,
but that
can all change.
Now, knowing
all of this,
do you still want us
to go ahead with it?
Given the alternatives,
yes.
[Lorenzo
Breathing Heavily]
The faculty is very
grateful to Lorenzo
for doing this.
[Indistinct Chatter]
[Doctor]
This is Lorenzo Odone
whom I've spoken about.
Please.
Now, young Mr. Odone,
you need to come with me.
You are getting
so big.
I'm gonna put you
up here so we can
all see you, okay?
Attaboy.
Ten weeks after diagnosis
we observe a hemianopia...
with transient
horizontal nystagmus.
The pupillary
light reflexes
are still intact,
yet there's
no optic atrophy.
However, there is
evidence of early
occipital lobe involvement.
[Slurred Speech]
Beg your pardon,
Lorenzo.
Why... are... aw...
these... people... here?
He asks why all
these people are here.
Well,
they're all doctors and
they want to learn...
how to help other boys
in the future.
[Slurred]
Other boys with the boo-boo?
Yes, darling.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you, Lorenzo.
Now, in the
scanning speech,
we look for both ends
of the pathology:
Centrally,
for the dysphasia;
and peripherally,
for the dysarthria.
Now, Lorenzo,
would you walk
for me, please?
That a boy.
That's right.
Hold my hands.
Two months ago, there
was simply motor lag.
Now, note the
characteristic gait.
[Gasping and Straining]
It's due to hyperreflexia,
but exacerbated by
encroaching paresis.
[Labored Breathing]
You're doing
very well, Lorenzo.
Keep coming.
Only if you stop
talkin' like that.
[Audience Whispering]
[Man]
Hello, Mr. Oh-Don.
Have I got that right?
[Odone]
It's "Odon-nay."
Odone. I'm sorry.
Ellard Muscatine.
I'm with the
A.L.D. Foundation.
We heard about
your boy, Lorenzo,
and we'd like to
offer some help.
You, you're
a doctor?
Heck no. I'm a machinist
from Aliquippa, Pa., but
I'm an A.L.D. Parent.
This is my
second time around,
so I know
exactly what you're
going through.
Uh, my wife Loretta
and I,
we run the foundation.
We organize counseling,
conduct seminars,
fund research.
We have
500 member families,
and not only American,
but from Portugal, Israel,
Japan, Australia.
And we're growing
all the time.
[Heavy Breathing]
And we wanted you
and Mrs. Odone...
[Gasping For Air]
To know that
you're not alone.
Hi. Ellard Muscatine.
Welcome to the conference.
Augusto Odone and...
Oh! Odone, oh!
Michaela.
Very nice to meet you.
Please come in.
This is my wife, Loretta.
These are the Odones.
Great. I'm so happy
you were able to come.
[Ellard]
A lot of it
is denial.
We don't want to say
there's anything going on,
that we're strong
and we can handle it.
But this is the place
and this is the time...
to let it all out,
let the barriers
come down,
and to share your feelings
and get it off your chest.
It's hard to believe
that things can get worse,
but they will.
One thing nobody
wants to talk about...
is what happens or doesn't
happen between the two
of you in the bedroom.
One whole year
we couldn't touch
one another.
[Woman]
My husband stood by me
all the way,
but does it test
the men.
The weak ones
up and go.
Even the strong
ones leave.
My guy hung in there
when our first boy
took sick,
then we
had Jake tested.
Arlen wanted
a bunch of boys,
a whole ball team.
He's gonna
have 'em too,
with some other gal.
[Loretta]
We'd like to
thank the parents...
who gave generously
to the fund...
for the
immunosuppression trial.
The doctors have told us
that this experiment...
contributed greatly to
the understanding of A.L.D.
Betty and Tom Knolls,
$250 in memory of Corey;
Dr. And Mrs. Liebowitz,
$500 in memory ofJoel;
Mr. And Mrs. Higgins,
$1,000 in memory of
Adrian and Julian.
26 people have sent in
recipes for the newsletter.
We still need ideas
for our snack foods
and breakfast treats.
Remember, all recipes
should be low-fat...
and use
only the foods allowed
on the institute diet.
[Michaela]
Excuse me.
Yes, ma'am.
Our son's complied
with this diet...
and yet his levels of
saturated C-24 and C-26...
have risen
for two months.
That's exactly what's
happened toJaybird.
Ah, well, perhaps,
before we talk about
publishing cookbooks,
we should
ask ourselves...
if the diet
is working at all,
shouldn't we?
Damn right we should.
This is not the way
we do things.
There are
two families here
with this paradox.
Maybe there
are more.
Shouldn't we open
it for discussion?
My boy's levels
are rising.
Now there are three.
So, uh,
maybe we should...
Could we have
a show of hands...
Yes.
And see how many
families there are?
This is a formal pilot study.
It has to run
the full six months.
We don't
take it on ourselves
to interpret experiments.
That's the responsibility
of the doctors.
Come on!
Let's at least have
a show of hands!
That would
be misleading.
The medical folks call
this evidence anecdotal.
- What's wrong with
a show of hands?
- It wouldn't have any meaning.
Excuse me.
May I say something?
Sure.
The only way the doctors
can get useful results...
is with
a strict protocol...
and statistical samples
in a control group.
And a proper time frame.
Doctors have to be
very careful.
The clinical trials
must withstand a tremendous
amount of scrutiny.
This is the way that
medical science works.
That's the only way
scientists can get
the information they need.
So what
you're saying...
is that our children
are in the service
of medical science.
How foolish of me.
I assumed medical science...
was in the service
of the sufferers.
Yes, uh, thank you.
Now I think it's time
we get back to our agenda.
Why, so we
can discuss...
further salvaging
our marriages and
managing our grief?
What about
the children?
No one here is
discussing the children.!
Thank you.
If Mary has nothing
further to add,
I would like to
introduce Dr. Chapel...
who will talk about
the nasogastric tube
and suction machine.
Would you join me in
giving him a warm welcome?
[Applause]
Thank you, Madame President.
Thank you, Ellie.
[Lorenzo]
Now hold my hand.
Yes.
Now the story.
What story is that,
sweetheart?
"La Notte
de San Lorenzo."
San Lorenzo who is...
My patron saint...
and saint of
my father's village.
That's right.
And what
happened to him?
He was in Rome...
Mm-hmm?
And I forgot.
Mm-hmm. Well,
many years ago,
the bad guy...
says to him:
"Bring us the riches
of your church."
And Lorenzo,
he brings them
the beggars...
and the sick people,
and he says:
"These are our riches."
Yes. Bravo,
Lorenzino.
Oh, that's wonderful,
sweetheart.
Bravo.
So clever.
And tonight,
August 10th is...
La Notte de
S-San Lorenzo.
[Michaela]
The night of
the shooting stars.
[Augusto]
When anything
can happen.
[Italian Opera]
Shh-shh-shh!
When we first went
to the Comoros,
what did we do?
We got to know
the country, right?
Yes.
We studied, we got
to know the language,
resources, its laws.
We studied, right?
We should treat
Lorenzo's illness
like another country.
I don't quite see
the analogy.
All right, A.L.D. Has
many dimensions, right?
Yes.
So in order
to understand it,
we need a command of, uh,
genetics, biochemistry,
microbiology, neurology,
- ology, -ology, -ology.
We don't have time to
go to medical school.
The doctors
are in the dark.
They're groping
in the dark.
They've got Lorenzo
on a turvy-topsy diet.
And that bloody
immunosuppression,
it's brutal, useless.
Michaela,
we should not...
have consigned him
blindly into
their hands.
He should not suffer
by our ignorance.
We take responsibility,
so we read a little...
and we go out and
inform ourselves, hmm?
But... to miss
time with him...
while he can still speak
to us...
Oh, yes,
I know, I know.
But he expects it
of us.
I want to take Lorenzo
off the diet.
He's been eating
cardboard for 19 weeks.
What's it getting us?
And feed him what?
Normal foods,
things a child likes.
Full of the long-chain
fats that we know
destroy his myelin?
Look, on the diet, his
blood fats are still rising.
Yes, I know.
It doesn't
make any sense.
But we don't know enough.
We don't know enough.
We don't know it
clearly enough.
Here, Michaela, let me
show you something.
All right.
Un piccolo acquaio.
A kitchen sink?
Yes, yes,
a little kitchen sink.
All right.
Now here is the tap...
and here's the sink basin
and the plug hole, right?
Very long-chain
saturated fats...
are introduced by
what we eat, all right?
Yes.
Also produced by the body,
or manufactured by the body,
these very same fats.
Biosynthesis.
Biosynthesis, right.
All right.
Now normally they are
not harmful because...
this enzyme eliminate
the excess, right?
But in Lorenzo,
this enzyme is defective
from genetics.
His plug hole
is blocked, right? Hmm?
Yes.
Now, we know that...
very long-chain
saturated fats...
are made up of carbon atoms:
C-2, -4, -6, -8,
all the way up the chain,
all right?
In Lorenzo,
his saturated C-24...
and C-26...
rise to four times
the normal level.
[Sighs] Okay, now,
here's where
we have a little paradox,
our mystery, okay?
Why, when we reduce
the dietary intake
of saturated fats,
does the level
in our sink,
which we would expect
to go down, go up, hmm?
So, logically, we should
take him off the diet.
Well, Michaela,
just as logically,
we should not.
Let's not do what
the doctors did.
Let's not act
without knowing why.
Why, when we turn off
this tap,
does the level
in our sink rise, hmm?
I married a plumber.
You married a man...
with a simple mind,
who asks simple questions.
Here, Michaela,
brain food.
Come on.
Oh, thank you.
Polish rats!
I think I have an explanation
for the paradox.
Lorenzo, kiss
your clever mother.
Polish rats with
a fatty acid
storage disease.
Here, let me use
your kitchen sink.
Here's our tap
for what we eat.
Right.
All right.
And here's our tap...
for biosynthesis.
I see, biosynthesis,
mm-hmm.
When the rats
were deprived...
of a specific fat
in their diet,
their body cells compensated
by overproducing it.
If this holds true
for humans...
Then the diet
is useless...
unless we can stop it
from overproducing,
slow down biosynthesis,
see?
Yes, yes, and
there's more.
For this, I deserve
two kisses, my darling.
Ah!
In this summary,
it talks about
the concept...
of fatty acid
manipulation.
[Deirdre]
What's that?
They stop the rats
producing one kind
of fat...
by loading their diet
with another kind.
Maybe we could stop Lorenzo
from producing saturated
C-24 and C-26...
by loading his diet with
another kind of fat,
you know, one
that's less harmful.
We should have
this translated
as soon as possible.
I have some news
t-t-too.
It's a letter
from Omouri.
He wouldn't open it
until you got home.
Omouri.
Yes.
Michaela, by tomorrow morning,
your Polish rats...
will be speaking to us
in English, hmm?
I've been thinking.
I found that article
by accident. I just as
easily could have missed it.
And it was written by a Polish
biochemist, who, I'm sure,
knew nothing about A.L.D.
Well, Michaela,
still it give us
a new line of inquiry.
Yes, of course, but
it could take months,
and there will be other leads
and that will take more time,
and it's time we don't have.
All these experts,
working in isolation,
each one on his own piece
of the jigsaw.
[Indistinct Conversation]
Yes, a symposium is
the best way to accelerate
the exchange of information.
In that sense,
it's a very good idea,
Mr. Odone.
Only, uh,
may I say something?
Have you any idea
how many children
in the United States...
die every year from
choking on French fries?
Many more than from
adrenoleukodystrophy.
Ours is what is known
as an orphan disease.
It's too small
to be noticed,
too small to be funded,
especially with
the iron hand
of Reaganomics.
So, while, as I say, this
remains a very good idea,
I'm afraid it's a luxury
we just can't afford.
We appreciate that,
so we have, uh,
prepared a budget...
based on 40 participants
for two days.
We think it can be done
for $35,000. My wife and I
will raise the money.
We can't ask you
to bear the cost.
No, no,
That's out...
no, no, no.
That's the least
of our concerns.
And, of course, your institute
will not be at risk,
because the Odones
will underwrite any shortfall.
Hmm? And, uh, we took
the liberty of drafting
an invitation list.
Forgive me, Dr. Nikolais.
We wish to make two conditions.
We would like the symposium
to emphasize therapy,
and Michaela and myself
would like to participate
in the discussions.
Martha, I'm afraid we'll
have to add to your work load.
But it's in a very good cause.
We've decided to convene
the first symposium on A.L.D.
We should notify
the Muscatines.
Of course. Well,
the foundation could help
with the arrangements.
They could even,
perhaps...
find some funds.
Now, how can we
make this work?
How about we hook it
to the back of the next
foundation family conference?
[Michaela]
When would that be?
Next summer,
fourth ofJuly weekend.
That's nine months away.
It'll take every bit
of that time to invite those
busy doctors and raise money.
I don't think so.
What's your time frame,
Mrs. Odone?
Five weeks from now,
November 10th and 11 th.
[Labored Breathing]
That's not possible.
I think it is.
Pardon me, but what is
the point of rushing it?
As A.L.D. Parents,
we both know the answer
to that inane question.
Look, if you want to make
the symposium happen, you're
going about it the wrong way.
Mrs. Muscatine, at least
we are going about it.
[Lorenzo Mumbling]
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I don't understand.
He wants his diaper changed.
[Dial Tone]
Mrs. Muscatine, look...
Hello? Hello.
[Clicking Receiver]
They should be hung
by their eyelashes.
They're not gonna help?
Doesn't look that way.
I'll take him.
No, no, no, I got it.
What are you gonna do,
mortgage the house?
Not till I have to.
Michaela.!
I've spent the last couple
of months pulling on the
heart strings of Washington...
to raise money for
multiple sclerosis,
sudden infant death syndrome...
and cystic fibrosis.
Then why exclude
adrenoleukodystrophy?
Because, you see, I also
cover politics, the arts,
women's issues and stuff,
and my readership actually likes
to have a little balance
of what I report.
I cannot do another
medical story right now.
Maybe in another month.
Joyce, I think
you should meet my son.
My friends,
this is so generous.
You know, Augusto, our wives
are eager to form a committee...
to perhaps help
with hospitality.
Oh, wonderful, wonderful.
[Excited Chatter]
So much money.
Not only will we be saving
money, but they'll be
extremely well fed.
We have for breakfast
French pastry, correct?
Lunch,
U.N. Finger food.
The British will do
a ripping afternoon tea,
[Knock At Door]
And for dinner, I know
a marvelous Italian cook.
[Laughter]
Are you needin'
another pair of hands?
I'll lick envelopes,
serve coffee, whatever.
Oh, this is for your boy.
I grow the best
organic produce
in Virginia.
Thank you.
You don't remember me.
Wendy Gimble.
Foundation family conference.
I yelled louder than you.
Yes, of course.
You have two boys.
Well, we lostJaybird,
butJake here is fine.
We think what you're
doing is fantastic.
[Deirdre] It's okay.
Hello, Jake. Come on in.
Thank you.
It's all right.
I read in the newspaper
about what you were doing.
It was about time somebody
did something about this.
Come meet the others.
- Is that Lorenzo?
- You'll make it.
Yes, Lorenzo, this is Jake.
He's a young man of your age.
Look, Lorenzo,
a great big pumpkin.
Let's go down and
feel how big it is.
[Indistinct]
[Lorenzo
Mumbling]
What, sweetheart?
[Garbled]
I want to play.!
I'm sorry, Lorenzo.
Let's, let's try that again.
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
This morning
I could still understand him.
If we could clone
the errant gene,
we'd be able to identify
the deficient enzyme,
mass-produce the gene,
implant it into
A.L.D. Sufferers...
and normalize
their metabolism.
How long
would that take?
Qu'est-ce que vous pensez,
professor?
Si tout va bien,
une dizaine d'annes.
[Man]
Oui. Seven to ten years.
You see, science
has its own time,
and very often,
any new advancement will be
a matter of serendipity.
[Professor Nikolais]
For the last six months,
all our A.L.D. Boys
have been on a regimen...
which excludes
saturated C-24 and 26.
But despite this restriction
in the diet,
these long-chain fatty acids
have remained the same,
in some cases,
even increasing.
Now this
compensating increase...
I put down to biosynthesis.
But, uh, Gus,
if you could maintain
the diet and somehow
inhibit biosynthesis,
you'd have a therapy.
[Nikolais]
No, no, we wouldn't...
quite have a therapy.
You'd have a way of lowering
the fatty acids to normal.
[Speaking Japanese]
If you wish to inhibit
biosynthesis,
have you considered
fatty acid manipulation?
[Speaking Japanese]
There is some literature.
A rat study,
Russian or Polish.
[Michaela] Polish. Straszak.
I have copies right here.
"Polish Journal of
Biological Sciences,"
1979, Volume II.
They loaded the diet
with one fat...
and decreased biosynthesis
of another.
Yes, I remember this article.
And also in Canada,
they have seen the same thing
in miniature swine.
As a matter of fact,
I've seen it
in human cells,
in human A.L.D. Cells.
From patients with A.L.D.,
I took fibroblasts,
skin cells, okay?
Each one
carries the same genetic defect.
I incubated them
with oleic acid and
reduced the levels...
of saturated C-24 and C-26
by more than 50%.
Excuse me, Doctor,
you said, uh, oleic acid?
Yes. Monounsaturated C-18.
It's the principle component
of olive oil.
Surely this is the basis
for a therapy, then.
Slow down.
These are preliminary studies
in cultured cells.
- We don't know it will work
in a human being.
- Well, take the olive oil...
and try it in a patient
and see.
Yes.
Olive oil is forbidden
in the diet. C-24, C-26.
Yes, but use
whatever Dr. Rizzo...
fed his fibroblast.
Exactly.
Pure oleic acid would be very
toxic to an intact organism,
an animal or a human.
It would need to be
the triglyceride form,
which is edible, but
that's not available.
Then can't you take
ordinary olive oil...
and extract
the C-24 and C-26?
You could,
but it's a very complicated
procedure, and it would be
very, very expensive,
especially to produce
the quantities needed
for a clinical trial.
- Have you tried contacting
chemical companies?
- No one will tool up for that,
not for an experiment,
not for something
with no market.
Then you haven't tried.
No.
[General Conversation]
[Augusto]
If we were able to give him
triglyceride, then...
[Indistinct]
Yes, it has to be triglyceride
to be edible.
[Michaela]
Edible form.
Triglyceride, yeah.
[Man On Phone]
No one in this department
can help you.
Do you know anyone who does?
I'll send you back to
the switchboard. Ask for R&D.
[Operator]
Which extension, please?
Research and development.
Hello?
[Woman]
R&D.
Yes, I'm seeking
a triglyceride form
of oleic acid.
Your name, Doctor?
No, I'm not a doctor.
Are you with a company?
No. I'm the mother
of a sick child.
A mother.
That's right.
And you want?
Oleic acid.
Lines are busy.
I'll wait.
Papa makes you
spaghetti al pomodoro,
seasoned with basilico,
the royal herb
for our prince, huh?
[Affectionate Chatter]
There's really no remedy.
It's a very rare disease.
Take a little.
That's a boy.
The most positive lead
came from the symposium,
and that was the oleic acid
in triglyceride form.
There you go.
Right now it's
our only hope.
[Whispering]
[Woman]
Don't fret, Mrs. Odone.
You will hear from him
within the hour.
You be sure of it.
Thank you.
That's 301...
Don't worry.
I have the number.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
So as the swallowing
reflexes weaken,
he's less and less able
to handle his own saliva.
We'll all have to be
pretty vigilant.
I mean, we really have
to stay on top of this.
If we allow any saliva
to get down into
his respiratory tract,
we've compromised
his airway.
[Phone Ringing]
We don't want to do that.
Okay, put your thumb
over the valve.
When you no longer
want to suction, just
release your thumb.
Hi, it's Protochem again.
I'll connect you to our
Mr. Pellerman.
Yes, I believe you're looking
for some oleic acid?
[Michaela]
Yes, in triglyceride form.
You're a very lucky lady.
We've been testing
a glycerol trioleate here...
as an industrial lubricant.
Is it fit
for human consumption?
I don't see why not.
It's a purified olive oil.
Without saturates?
Pure, monounsaturated C-18
in triglyceride form?
Yes, ma'am.
You're sure?
Happens we have one bottle here,
one liter sitting idle
on the shelf.
Marvelous. How can we
get our hands on it?
I'm sorry. Go ahead?
How can we get
our hands on it?
This is...
it's beautiful.
And, of course,
it's entirely harmless.
Gus, you're talking
to an Italian.
It's only olive oil.
Yes, it's harmless.
It's like, uh, sugar.
And yet to a diabetic,
sugar can be lethal.
The trouble is
we don't know
to what extent...
Lorenzo
can metabolize fats.
Well, Gus, it's been
seven months...
since Lorenzo
was diagnosed.
Now he's silent.
He's immobile.
Augusto,
I am a scientist,
and I'm of absolutely
no use to you whatever...
unless I can maintain
my objectivity.
And I am not a scientist.
I am a father.
And nobody can tell me
what dressing I put
on my kid's salad.
Okay?
Augusto.
This science of medicine,
you know, it's not like physics.
There's no
mathematical certainty.
And because we deal with
human beings who suffer,
it can appear
heartless.
I know.
You realize, of course,
that any collaboration of mine
would have to be unofficial.
Si, si, of course.
Now, the dose.
We think, uh,
40 grams a day.
No, that's too much.
Too much?
Say 30.
Thirty.
Yes, any more than that
might damage your son's liver.
Si, si. Excuse me.
Thank you.
Darling,
they're about to start.
[Opera]
We're going to send this blood
away to establish a baseline,
my brave boy,
because today, we all start
the fight against the boo-boo.
There. All done.
Lorenzino, this year
we celebrate Thanksgiving
a little early,
with a fine barracuda like
we used to eat in the Comoros.
And Papa has cooked it
with aromatic dill, huh?
And now,
we add this
special olive oil,
which Mama found, hmm?
All right.
Here we go, hmm?
Deirdre.
All right, Lorenzo,
here we go.
[Children Chattering]
There we go.
You did good,
buddy boy.
You did real good.
Your auntie means
"well," darling.
In this house,
we cherish our adverbs,
and I expect you
to do the same when
you get your voice back.
[Lorenzo Wheezing]
[Phone Ringing]
Hello?
Mrs. Odone?
Yes.
This is Dr. Nikolais'office.
I have Lorenzo's results,
and there's been a small drop
in saturated C-24 and 26.
About 15%.
15%?
Dr. Nikolais said
not to get carried away.
It could be
a spontaneous variation.
Am I allowed
a tiny squeak of joy?
We'll know more
next month.
Thank you.
[Coughing,
Choking]
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Nurse]
Don't move him.!
Get something to
hold down his tongue.!
[Lorenzo Screaming]
[Michaela]
Oh, my baby.!
[Panting]
So, this is
a kind of seizure
like epilepsy.
No, not a seizure.
It's a paroxysm.
It's triggered by
saliva in the windpipe.
But we suction him.
Regularly.
Yes.
Even so, some saliva
gets caught in the trachea.
What, in any other child,
would just be a cough
to get rid of it,
in Lorenzo becomes
this scrambled chain
of reflexes...
that amplifies into
what you have just seen.
If this happens again,
what can we do about it?
Just help him try
to ride it out.
[Indistinct]
We're all flyin' blind
here, folks. The best
I can offer is sedation.
But if it's not epilepsy,
then he's aware of what's
happening while it's going on.
Well, it's possible.
And if he has another episode,
we could talk him through it.
It's possible, Michaela.
It's possible.
[Lorenzo's Labored Breathing
Continues]
Si, si,
a 50% drop, right?
[Woman] That's correct.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Fantastico.!
I very well understand
that we are not scientists,
but we have
observed this in...
[Nikolais]
Let us do it
our way, Augusto.
All right.
Yes. Mm-hmm.
I've got to go.
Okay.
Thank you.
Good night.
Okay, bye.
Nikolais says
it is very interesting.
Interesting? A 50% drop?
But he said it's too early
to draw a conclusion.
Rizzo might consider
a trial, and he asked us...
not to tell
the other parents.
What?
That's immoral.
Yes, it is.
Here's something
that can finally...
But the parents
have to hear!
Yes, they do.
We'll tell them.
They can judge
for themselves.
But the foundation has
the mailing list.
We'll call the Muscatines.
You're kidding.
No, I can eat crow in
the name of a good cause.
Michaela,
now go easy.
[Ringing]
Mmm. Delicious.
That was worth
driving 300 miles for.
Now, my friends,
dessert.
[Muscatine]
Here, let me move this.
And, Loretta,
a little science.
Thank you.
There you are.
Loretta.
"Dear A.L.D. Parents."
- You want us to send this out.
- Yes, we'd be happy to pay
for copying and postage.
- But you're advocating
a therapy here.
- Oh, no.
We're merely reporting
a positive advancement
in the diet.
It would be wrong for us
to keep this information
from the other parents.
Mrs. Odone, we have
an advisory board
of eminent doctors.
We parents take our guidance
from them. After all, they are
the ones with medical degrees.
Yes, my dear, but you see,
Nikolais already
knows about this,
- and the wretched man
does absolutely nothing.
- Because Dr. Nikolais...
- is a responsible...
- No, because Dr. Nikolais
has another agenda.
[Speaking Italian]
You know, Loretta,
sometimes...
the interest
of the scientists...
is not the same
as the interest
of the parents.
Scientists are human,
and sometimes
they can be wrong.
As president
of the foundation,
you represent us,
the families, see.
And you serve
the families best
by informing them.
And all we ask...
is that you please
send this letter
to them, that's all.
Our parents
suffer enough...
without being made
the victims of false hopes.
But...
No, we can't give credence to
every jerk that comes along...
- with a pocketful of apricot...
- This is not Laetrile.
We're talking about
an extract of olive oil,
Olive oil.
An idea put forth
by the scientists...
at the symposium.
And it works.
It works in Lorenzo.
It works in an
A.L.D. Boy to a degree
that is significant.
Very significant.
For God's sake,
don't you think...
that other parents have
a right to know this?
I mean, we know this
is a deadly disease,
so they have
a right to choice, and
if they feel as we do,
they can put pressure
on the doctors, because
as parents,
we should challenge
these guys.
We push them.
Unless somebody...
someone is willing...
to question, to provoke,
how would there be progress?
- We feel there is progress.
- Loretta, we know that,
but all we say is
start a dialectic
with the doctors.
- Are you gonna tell us
how to run the foundation?
- We're merely asking you...
to disseminate information.
You're going to
teach the doctors?
We call that arrogance.
Arrogance?
Yes, uh, it is...
arrogance.
It comes from
the Latin word...
"arrogare."
You know the root,
what it means?
It means to claim
for oneself.
That's the root.
It means to claim
for oneself.
And I claim the right
to fight for my kid's life,
and no doctor,
no researcher,
no bloody foundation...
has the right to stop me
from asking questions...
which might
help me save him!
And you, you have no right
to stop the sharing
of information.!
- So you think about it...
- Our job is to be there
for the parents,
to comfort them,
not to get them
all stirred up.
If the doctors think you are
onto something, they will let us
know in their own good time.
Their own good time
is not our time.
Oh, that is...
What, they are so powerful,
they are so powerful...
that you would be silent?
What...
they are not gods.
You know, this,
this acquiescence
is so disgusting!
You think you know so much.
Let me tell you something!
When Michael got sick,
we thrashed about for
anything that might help him.
You know the best thing
that happened?
He was taken quickly.
Now Tommy,
he has lasted three years.
For two of'em,
he's been without
his sight, his mind,
everything that makes him
a human being.
He's a vegetable.
Oh, boy. You know,
if you would stop
all this denial,
you wouldn't do a thing
to prolong your boy's suffering
and indignity one minute longer.
Has it occurred to you
that maybe he doesn't want
to be around anymore?
[Augusto] Si, si, thank you.
It has to be a mistake.
No.
No, Nikolais
says not.
Augusto.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Should we risk
raising the dose?
No, he's too fragile.
Any more might
harm his liver.
[Bell Ringing]
[Children Shouting
and Cheering]
Lorenzo, my darling,
listen to Mama.
[Gasping]
You're going to have
to be brave as only you
know how, sweetheart.
We're going to count
together, all right?
Listen to Mommy's voice,
and the boo-boo
will let go of you.
One, two, three,
four, count to five...
[Lorenzo Screaming]
Michaela?
You know, I've been
a nurse for 18 years,
eight of them spent
in I.C.U. Pediatrics,
and I know that you can't
always play by the rules,
but this boy
shouldn't be at home.
He should be placed
in a properly equipped
hospital.
Why don't you say
what you mean?
I'm not comfortable
with this situation.
Well, Lorenzo and I
aren't comfortable with
your lack of comfort.
I, I can't continue
to be a party to this.
I gotta give you my notice.
I'll stay until you...
No, I think you should
finish tonight.
Michaela, come on.
Your agency will receive
a check in the morning.
Look, Ruth, we're all
a little strung out here.
[Michaela] She's talking
about placement, Deirdre.
It's a euphemism for hospice.
Lorenzo has had
quite enough to endure.
We are not going
to expose ourself
to doubt and despair.
She's exhausted.
I mean, that's all it is.
Look, I don't know.
Somebody had to say
somethin', you know?
Good luck, hon.
Buona sera, Odone.
Look what I found.
Look at this.
Would you look at this?
Let me show you.
Here, where are we?
Right here.
That was June of'83,
just 21 months ago.
You know, it's time
you guys take it easy
on yourselves.
[Sigh]
Deirdre.
If we knew why
it only work halfway,
then we might know
what to do next.
Augusto, how many mornings
have I found you asleep...
under a pile of research papers
with the light still on?
And then you wake up
and drag yourself
into the office.
How long can you
keep this up?
If you get sick,
and you will, what are
you gonna do for money?
What, what are you
telling me?
For God's sake, he's my kid.
Yeah, so are
Cristina and Francesco,
and it's been a year
since you've seen them.
[Lighter Clicking]
Listen to me.
Okay?
There has to be
a life beyond Lorenzo.
What are you telling me?
That I should give up
on this now?
Oh, man, we both know
that even if you get
his levels down to normal,
his brain
can't fix itself.
I mean, how much myelin
does he have left?
You ever ask yourself
that question?
Deirdre, now that's enough.
No. Don't bullshit me.
That is enough.
I know you do,
but she doesn't.
Not ever.
You have to
help me with her.
I mean, she doesn't eat;
she doesn't sleep.
I'm afraid for her.
I think she's losing it.
You've seen how
she is with him.
She just can't let him go.
Poor Deirdre.
Spoken as only a woman
who's never had a child
could speak.
Michaela, Deirdre
was speaking out of love.
I am only telling you
what I see. For both your
sakes, there has to be...
life beyond Lorenzo.
Do you think because
he has no voice...
that he has no will to live?
He asserts it through us!
If you can't understand that,
there's no place for you
in this house.
Michaela, for God's sake.!
She is your sister.
I think you're
losing it, Michaela.
Well, then I think
you should go.
Augusto, help her pack her bags.
I'm going back to our son.
[Speaking Italian]
You think I'm crazy
because I speak for our son?
[Speaking Italian]
I am so sorry.
I never wanted this to happen.
How can l...
How can I enjoy anything
when he enjoys nothing?
How can you talk to me
about loving him when
you trivialize him...
into some kind of
biochemical crossword puzzle?
Don't! No!
[Lorenzo Gasping]
Mrs. Odone.!
Get a tube.
Have you got the tube?
Don't nod. Say yes.
My attention's on Lorenzo.
I can't see you.
Darling, look at me.
Open your eyes.
Listen to Mommy's voice.
We're going to count. One, two,
[Screaming]
Three, four, five, six.
[Screaming Continues]
[Crying]
I'm sedating him
as much as I dare.
I don't know what else to do.
[Lorenzo Crying]
How can he endure this
for so many hours?
Augusto,
I don't think he'll have
to endure it much longer.
[Lorenzo Screaming]
[Whimpering]
Michaela,
let me take him.
You need rest.
I'm fine.
I could use
a cup of coffee, though.
Okay.
[Lorenzo Sobbing]
Lorenzo. Lorenzo,
listen to Mama.
Can you hear me,
my darling?
If this is too much
for you, my sweetheart,
well, then, you fly.
You fly as fast as you can
to BabyJesus.
It's okay.
Mama and Papa
will be okay.
[Crying]
[Lorenzo Sobs]
I have rarely seen anything
like this boy's tenacity.
They have a bed
available upstairs.
No, no, no.
In a hospice, no.
It'd be easier
on everybody.
But it would not do honor
to Lorenzo.
Michaela.
Yes?
Come.
What?
Come, come.
Nurse.
Yes.
Now, today we eat, moglie mia.
Every last mouthful.
I'm not hungry.
No, no, no.
You eat. Sit.
Michaela,
you sit. Sit.
From tomorrow morning,
the Odones need
all their energies.
Now, listen, we set out to
normalize Lorenzo's blood,
right?
And with the oleic oil,
we got it half right.
But that was luck.
Oh, it was
rather more than luck.
No, no, no, it was luck.
It was merely observation.
Rizzo observed something
in a test tube, right?
We tried it on Lorenzo.
Rizzo observed a 50% drop
in fibroblasts.
We observed a 50% drop
in Lorenzo.
Now, Michaela,
that is luck.
That is observation.
That is all it is.
It is not understanding.
And until we understand
why this work only halfway,
how can we expect
to succeed all the way?
Right?
Mmm.
I need to understand, Michaela.
You need to understand.
So, tomorrow we go
back to the library.
No, no, no.
We review all
the literature,
everything on
fatty acid metabolism,
every word published
in the last decade.
So eat. You eat.
Whatever energy,
whatever time I have left,
I want to spend with Lorenzo.
You will not have to leave
his bedside. I will go
to the library, make copies.
I bring it home for you.
Augusto, we are on
our second mortgage.
You can't afford
not to go to work.
Michaela, I will work.
I fit it in somehow.
Michaela, this is important.
I need you.
I need you,
Michaela.
So eat.
Bravo.
Bravissima.
[Groans]
[Muttering]
Betty! Betty!
Betty, all these
fatty acids studies,
they all concentrate
on the middle of the chain...
because medium-chain saturates
are implicated in cholesterol!
Shh!
So what do these
researchers do? They think,
"Cholesterol, cholesterol."
C-12, C-14,
C-bloody-16!
Augusto, what is it
that you're looking for?
I am looking...
I am looking for the long end
of fatty acid chains!
Write it down for me.
These researchers should be
doing something about it!
Write it down.
Long-chain fatty acids.
C-18 through C-26...
saturated,
monounsaturated, okay?
Okay, now I want you
to go off to lunch.
[Muttering]
I want you to have yourself
a good lunch, and I'm going
to see what I can do.
This is the best I could do
on a moment's notice.
It's one article from
a veterinary science journal
about pigs.
But at least it's on
your long-chain fats.
Oh, well,
thank you, Betty.
Listen, I'm, I'm
very sorry about...
Oh, well,
you're Italian.
[Lorenzo Crying]
[Michaela]
72, 73, 74,
and 75,
76, 77,
78, 79,
That's nice going,
Mrs. Odone.
80. That's it, my love.
You know only
the strongest, bravest boy,
only a very special person
like you is chosen
to fight the boo-boo.
I'll give him
a little water, okay?
20 cc's?
Yes. And, Nancy, why don't
you tell Lorenzo what
an excellent job he did.
[Nancy]
What an excellentjob
you did, Lorenzo.
Sometimes I wonder, my love,
if people realize how incredible
you truly are.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Is this a new hobby
or a nervous tic?
No, this is a simple mind
at work is all.
See, each paper clip, Deirdre,
- is two carbon atoms, right?
- Oh, God.
No, no, no, really.
It's two carbon atoms,
all right?
So, we have C-2, C-4,
C-6, you know?
Now here's what I try to do.
I try to make a chain,
a very long chain,
of monounsaturated fats.
- This is the good guys, right?
- Okay, what are these,
the bad guys?
Yes. These, these here
is the bad guys.
All right? Now, Deirdre,
what I'm trying to do,
I'm trying to understand
the relationship...
between the good guys
and the bad guys.
So, okay,
I am the enzyme, right?
And I reach out
and I grab a carbon atom...
and I put it on my chain,
right?
Here's my chain, right?
Now, here, you be
the bad guy enzyme.
No, no, no.
Do this for me. You be
bad guy enzyme, all right?
Take these, all right?
Now you reach out and
you grab carbon atom...
and you put it on
your bad guy chain, okay?
Oh, Augusto, I had enough
trouble with the kitchen sink.
No, no, you just do this.
Do this and then I explain,
okay?
All right, all right.
So let's each start now...
making our chains, okay?
All right, putting that on.
That's good, Deirdre. Good.
- We put another one on...
- Here's your stuff
on enzyme complexes.
Ah, thank you.
Mille grazie.
Prego.
Prego.! Very good.
Now, did you make
the extra copies?
Oh, you bet.
Oh, thank you
very much.
For Michaela?
How is she?
She's fine,
she's fine.
So, here we are.
We're making our chains more
or less the same rate, right?
Mm-hmm.
That is what
we'd expect, right?
But now, Deirdre,
if we were enzymes...
in the bodies of little rats
and little pigs and Lorenzo,
then, the faster I go,
the more you slow down.
Now why would that be?
Why would the faster I go,
why would you slow down...
if we're both
separate enzymes?
It means that there has to be
some kind of relationship
going on.
We affect each other some way.
There's some kind of interplay.
But what is it?
What is it?
One, two, three,
four, five,
[Soft Murmur]
Six, seven candles.
And Mommy will blow them
out for you.
Make a wish.
[Child's Voice
Murmuring in Italian]
Counting "C"Fats
in Italian]
[Counting Continues
and Grows Louder]
C- venti-quattro,
c- venti-sei,
c...
Michaela! Michaela!
They are the same enzyme!
There is one enzyme
for both chains!
It's the same
bloody enzyme!
So, if we keep the enzyme busy
making monounsaturates...
It distracts it
from elongating
the saturates.
Right! So we have a way
to trick nature.
Yes, it's a principle called
competitive inhibition.
Right. So, Gus, Gus,
you think it's
a reasonable hypothesis?
Oh, I think it's more.
What you've done is to clarify
the biochemical pathway.
Augusto, I really want
to congratulate you.
This, this would explain
why oleic acid is only
partly successful.
Yes, it's C-18, you see.
It's too low down in the chain.
Right, right.
So, we add
a second barrier.
We block the bad guys
further up the chain,
the saturates,
further up the chain
between C-22 and C-24.
Then, we stop
the bloody things
completely.
- And how do you do that?
- By adding monounsaturated C-22.
- But that's erucic acid.
- Yes, exactly.
How does he get it?
Um...
Martha?
[Intercom]
Yes, Doctor.
Among our animal studies,
you'll find a, uh,
a file on erucic acid,
with an "E."
R-U-C-l-C.
[Martha]
Okay.
Thank you.
You, you don't believe
it will work?
Well, I think what
you people have done is
to postulate a theory...
which could be
of enormous benefit.
But as for erucic acid,
it creates cardiac problems
in rats.
And once it's
not safe for rats,
- I don't know what
justification there can be...
- Here we are.
For using it... thank you...
as a therapy on humans.
But, Gus, Gus.!
Erucic acid is
the chief component
in rapeseed oil, right?
- Yes.
- Rapeseed oil is a common food
in China and India.!
Yes, and their rate
of heart disease...
if far lower than
in this country.
Look at these documents.
"Cardiac lipoidosis,
myocardial lesions,
"cholesterol deposits
in the adrenal gland...
and damage to
the reproductive system. "
I'm afraid
the weight of evidence
is much too great,
and no human studies
review committee...
will ever do anything
but discard erucic acid
out of hand.
But don't you see that
the human studies have been
accomplished by history?
They have been eating the stuff
in these countries
for thousands of years.
You can't expect me
to start a protocol...
- based on that kind of...
- Perhaps you should examine
your protocol...
when children are dying, and
find a way to research...
Michaela, Michaela.
These isolated...
Michaela!
It's common sense.
Michaela, we simply have
a contradiction, that's all.
We seek more information.
We do not dismiss erucic acid
out ofhand.
[Nikolais]
Michaela, Michaela,
if I ignore all this evidence,
and we embark on a therapy
based on erucic acid,
huh?
Something goes wrong.
What then?
Then I suppose
the risk/reward ratio is
too unattractive for you.
I beg your pardon?
The life of one boy is not
enough reward for you...
to risk the reputation
of the institution...
and the esteem
of your peers.
That was uncalled for.
Your responsibility is merely
towards your own child.
My responsibility is towards
all the boys that suffer...
from this disease,
now and in the future.
Of course I anguish
for the suffering of your boy.
And of course I applaud you
for the efforts you make
on his behalf.
But I will have nothing
to do with this oil.
We are not asking,
doctor, for your anguish
or your applause.
We are asking merely
for a little courage.
Okay.
All right.
[Augusto]
Whatever the doctors say,
reason tells us, this
is a risk worth taking.
But, my friend, we need
a sympathetic collaborator.
If it was in my hands,
I would do anything to help.
I really would.
I have a boy of my own.
But I don't like
our chances.
They said the same thing
about the oleic acid...
and here it was,
sitting on the shelf.
This is another ball game.
Extracting saturated C-24
and 26 from rapeseed oil,
that's very tricky.
It would take our best
chemists at least a year!
Then you would never
get it past the F.D.A.
Erucic acid for
human consumption?
I'm sorry, but...
no one in the country's
gonna touch it.
What about outside
this country?
Well, I wouldn't know
where to send you.
Oh, Mr. Pellerman,
we're agents for over
a dozen foreign companies.
There must be one
that could help.
- We need to look at the list.
- You and your wife
have enough to do.
I'm sure Mr. Pellerman
would be happy to make
the calls for you.
We'd have
to be covered legally.
If anything goes wrong,
this company is not going
to be held liable.
Oh, we wouldn't
hold you liable.
No. No, no.
And it would be
greatly appreciated...
if we could
circulate this.
"The Interplay of
Monounsaturated and
Saturated Fatty Acids:
Therapeutic Application
in A.L.D." Wow.
You wrote this?
Yes. We felt that if
we were asking for help,
our rationale needs
to be very clear.
[Man]
We've read your paper.
And I must say...
it's a beautiful piece
ofbiochemistry.
[Augusto]
We approached over 100 companies.
They all say, "too difficult."
My first impression was
that it's bloody impossible.
But I've been doing difficult
fractionations for 40 years.
I'd like to have a stab
at it.
How long you think,
Mr. Suddaby?
I've only six months before
I retire, so we'll see.
I let you get on with it,
but call me if you
have any questions.
Righto, bye then.
[Knocking]
[Michaela]
Who could this be?
Ah! It's your
good friend Wendy...
with all sorts of lovely
vegetables and fruits.
Oh!
Michaela.
Look what you
brought us!
Hi, Lorenzo.
Jake's not in school today?
He's not
feeling so good.
I'm going for a walk
with Mrs. Gimble.
We shall be back
shortly.
I've given him...
his oxcarbamazepine
and 50 mils of water.
Would you like me
to do anything else?
He would love a story.
Do you have
a problem with this?
Fine.
He's had a couple
of tantrums.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's okay.
Dr. Rizzo's got him
in the oleic acid trial.
That's good.
Hi, Jake.
Hi, sweetie.
Thank you for
my potatoes.
Say hello, son.
Hi... Mrs...
O-O-O-Odone.
He saw...
He saw the way
Jaybird went.
He knows what's
in store for him.
[Crying]
[NancyJo]
"They forgot their
sadness and hunger.
"They followed the bird.
They came to an opening
in the forest.
"Before them was a little
cottage gleaming in the
rays of the setting sun.
"'Look, Gretel,' exclaimed
Hansel. 'That cottage
is made of gingerbread.'
"'It really is,' replied
Gretel, tasting a bit she
had pulled from the wall.
"'The roof looks as
though it were shingled
with butterscotch.'
"'The windowsils are made of
chocolate,' declared Hansel.
'And the windowpanes are
made of clear candy..."'
NancyJo, do you think
you could muster just
a tad more enthusiasm?
Lorenzo loves the sound
of language!
I'm paid to nurse!
Not read stories.
And you've decided that his
mind doesn't need as much
nurturing as his body?
What mind?
I beg your pardon!
Nothing.
Get out.
Look, Mrs. Odone...
Just get out.
I've read up on this
disease. I know what
it's done to his brain.
Lower your voice.
Lorenzo doesn't need to
hear this from a subliterate!
Face it, lady.
The lights are out
and there's nobody home!
Just get out!
Go!
Well, merry Christmas.
Get out!
Happy holidays!
"Near a great forest lived
a woodcutter with his children,
Hansel and Gretel.
"Times were very hard
and a day came...
"when there was no food
except stale bread.
But Hansel..."
was like you, my darling.
"He was a clever lad...
"who knew how to solve
difficult problems.
The woodcutter
was very sad."
[Augusto]
Are you going to keep
doing this?
She brought it on herself.
She consigned herself
to the outer darkness.
Michaela, NancyJo,
she was a good nurse.
You trained her well.
But I want someone who can
give more than medication.
Someone who'll minister
to his mind and soul.
I think I found him.
What?
I wrote to Omouri.
I asked him to come
stay with us.
Omouri?
Lorenzo is surrounded by women.
I don't want our son
to grow up hag-ridden.
You cannot take a boy out
of this fishing village...
and bring him here
to nurse Lorenzo.
Not to nurse him.
To be his friend, to bring
the Comoros into this room.
We cannot uproot
this young man...
from his family,
his way of life.
Where will he live?
Here, in
Lorenzo's room.
But...
he has no English.
He is a Muslim.
An African.
We cannot bring an African
to this racist country...
to be a second-class
citizen.
This is Washington, D.C.
He'll be part of this family.
I'll teach him English.
There's so much
we can do for him here.
Oh, Michaela.
Here, sit down.
Sit down.
Now, the last time
Omouri saw Lorenzo...
he was climbing trees.
He was a wild and
vibrant boy, full of life.
In the letter that
you wrote to Omouri,
did you tell him what
he will see when he
walks into this room?
I told him he
would see a young man...
who was very, very ill
and had need of a friend.
That is all?
How would you have
me describe him?
As a biochemical conundrum?
No, no!
You know he
is not that for me.
Augusto,
when you look at him,
what do you see?
Tell me the truth!
How do I tell the man
to give up?
His health won't take it.
The hours he's working
are daft. Our expectations
were unrealistic.
Look, Don's a man who's been
working all his life in
face creams and cosmetics.
With this oil,
he's having the time
of his life!
You tell him, 'cause I won't.
All right. For his own
sake, I'm gonna have to.
Then you can call
Mrs. Odone and tell her
that you've pulled the plug.
Best leave him be.
I think you're right.
[Airplane Engines]
Omouri.
[Labored Breathing]
Lorenzo,
Omouri is here.
[Singing An African Song]
Morning!
Morning.
Good morning,
Mr. Suddaby.
There's a bottle of pure erucic
acid triglyceride on my bench.
Will you see that it
gets to young Mr. Odone
as soon as possible, please?
I'm off home now.
Bye-bye.
Good-bye,
Mr. Suddaby.
Well, we'd better
get on with it.
[Telephone Dialing]
Four parts of
our old friend oleic.
And, uh...
one part erucic.
And the journey begins,
like all good journeys,
with... food.
Oh, where's the
wretched nurse?
I'm gonna take my
baseline myself if
she doesn't get here soon.
I think a month
is much too long.
We take my blood levels
every week and I have a
cardiogram every few days.
We should know enough to
start Lorenzo even sooner,
don't you think?
[Knocking]
Oh, at last.
Hi!
How's the mother tiger?
Augusto didn't
tell you.
I'm here to be
Lorenzo's rat.
That's a very kind offer,
but I can't let you.
I'm a carrier just the same
as you. My blood levels
are just as high as yours.
I've had
my baseline taken.
And I'm starving!
Oh, I have been wanting
to meet Lorenzo's main man.
[Omouri]
I am content to greet
Aunt Dierdre.
[Dierdre]
It's good
to meet you too.
[Augusto]
Now, Michaela,
I want no argument.
Michaela,
you cannot test it.
Lorenzo needs you
fit and well.
You would put Dierdre at risk
without discussing it?
Hey, hey.
Dierdre.
I backpacked
all through India.
I must've eaten
rapeseed oil up the wazoo.
Ah, I've been fasting
all day.
All right.
Try it.
Okay.
Here goes.
[Augusto]
So, does it
taste awful?
No?
Good.
It's good.
Eat. Eat.
[Suddaby]
Your sister had
no side effects?
None. If we can normalize
the levels of a carrier
so quickly, who knows?
We're going to start
Lorenzo immediately.
Marvelous.
We're terribly
grateful to you.
Oh, no, no.
Not to mention Deedee,
the family rat.
[Suddaby Chuckling]
What dosage will
you give the lad?
We don't have time to be
conservative, so we've
decided on eight grams.
Okay.
[Whimpering]
[Sucking Sound]
Goin' to Montana
to throw the hoolihan
[Phone Ringing]
Gonna feed them...
Hello.
[Man]
Mr. "Odon"?
Odone. Yes.
Look, we have a problem
with this blood sample.
You have a problem.
What is the problem?
Could there have been
a mistake in the labeling?
No! No mistake.
Why?
We ran the
assay twice...
and the levels of C-24
and C-26 read normal.
[Chuckling]
They read normal?
Well, ah... ah...
I, I, l...
Do you have the sample
in front of you?
Yes.
What is the name
on the sample?
Lorenzo Michael
Murphy "Odon."
That's Odone.
No, there's no mistake.
But thank you
very much.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Where the fiery
are raring to go
Whoopie-ti-yi-yo
get along little dogies
You know Wyomin'
will be your new home
[Whispering]
What's going on?
Lorenzo's levels are normal.
Play, play!
Wonderful!
[Wendy]
Drink it up, son,
every last drop.
Mama says this is the
only bottle in the world.
[Chuckling]
Now that we have destroyed
Lorenzo's blood fats,
I'm sure that Mr. Suddaby
will make us plenty more.
Mama says
this is bootleg.
Bootleg.
Look, I know this is only a
fraction of what it cost you...
No, no, no!
Wendy, no, no.
You gotta take it, please?
We work on
the barter system.
Our oil.
Your produce.
There aren't that many potatoes
in the world.
Okay.
Here you go.
When are you
gonna tell Nikolais?
We told him and the
other doctors and we
sent all the figures.
Have you heard back?
They deliberate.
They want more study.
Wendy, that's enough.
The other kids
have to wait?
Oh, great.
We know what to do
about that, don't we?
The doctors had a hard time
swallowing the first oil.
They want to see how it goes
with Lorenzo on the second.
But we don't have time,
do we?
No.
So we leave science
to its own concerns, huh?
Grazie.
Good-bye, Jake.
Merry Christmas.
What happened
to the suction machine?
There's no need, Michaela,
not for four hours.
I turn the machine off.
All last night he made
to swallow for himself.
Augusto?
We hope to make an
announcement quite soon...
about a new development
in our diet therapy.
It's going to be
quite expensive.
With the help of the government
and this wonderful foundation,
we are going to start a trial
before the end of the year.
I can hear from that
that you wish us godspeed.
[Woman]
Excuse me, Doctor,
are you referring to the oil...
the Odones have invented
for Lorenzo?
We'll take
questions later.
It's all right, Loretta.
It's a good question.
I should've mentioned
it perhaps, but...
The Odones have been
extremely active and
we are in their debt.
It's because of them
that we are now preparing
a protocol for review...
by the human studies
committee.
If then we can persuade
the government to fund us,
then we shall know
whether this oil...
is of more than temporary
therapeutic value.
But it works.
The Odones have got
Lorenzo's blood levels
down to normal.
[Nikolais]
It is for that reason
we are conducting this trial.
You don't really expect me
to endorse a therapy just...
on the basis of one
hopeful observation.
There's two!
My boy's been taking
the oil for six months.
His blood levels are normal
and he's doing just fine.
You are playing
with people's hopes.
Where did these Odones
get off, thinking they
know more than the doctors?
Where did you get
this oil?
From the Odones.
They bring it from England.
They don't have approval
from the F.D.A. It is bootleg.
Give the doctors...
Come on! It's a mixture
of two cooking oils.
What's the dosage please?
Can you tell me?
What are the side effects?
How would
we pay for it?
It must be a formally
approved protocol before
we can raise the funds.
As I understand it, it will
cost over $ 1,000 a liter.
Let me say you're not going
to get any insurance company,
any government to support you
unless you have the approval.
The only way to get
the approval is through
thorough testing.
That's what they told
the Al DS people about A.Z.T.
They fought and got it.
They were dying and
didn't have time to wait!
We padded our walls yesterday.
I want that oil!
[Arguing, Shouting]
There, my darling.
That's a sweet boy.
What a big,
strong boy.
Yes, my darling.
Yes.
You see, Michaela,
it is as though he is trapped
down in some dark cave.
Because he's lost
so much myelin,
he can't find
his way out.
We know his simple
functions are intact.
He breaths. He swallows.
His heart beats.
From the outside world,
he receives sensation.
A touch.
Pain. Cold.
And here are the
primal feelings: Fear.
Hunger. Desire.
Up here in the neocortex,
the higher brain,
locked here...
are his reasoning,
imagination and memory,
the things that make us
each ourselves.
So, how does
he reach us...
when a simple swallow
is such a huge task?
To find...
to find the way, the path
from his mind...
to the outside world...
is like willing himself
through a brick wall.
So he waits.
He waits.
Michaela,
do you ever think...
that...
maybe all this struggle,
it may have been
for somebody else's kid?
[Crying]
Yes.
[Sighs]
But I promised,
I promised him...
his world would
never be silent.
He would
never be alone.
Yes.
[Michaela]
"One morning a little rabbit
sat on a bank.
"He pricked his ears
and listened to the
trit-trot of a pony.
"A gig was coming
along the road.
"It was driven by
Mr. McGregor and beside
him sat Mrs. McGregor.
"As soon as they had passed,
Benjamin Bunny...
"slid into the road
and set off...
"with a hop, skip and a jump
to call upon his relations...
"who lived in the woods
at the back of
Mr. McGregor's garden.
"That wood was full
of rabbit holes.
"In the neatest hole of all,
lived Benjamin's aunt
and his cousins. ;
"Flopsy, Mopsy, Cottontail
and Peter.
"Old Mrs. Rabbit was a widow.
She...
"earned her living by knitting
rabbit wool mittens.
I once bought a pair..."
What's the matter, my darling,
you don't like this story?
Lorenzo?
You don't like
the story?
He does that
a lot lately.
When?
Mainly at story time.
Sweetheart,
listen carefully
to Mama.
Is your middle name
Patrick?
No.
Is it Peter?
No, Mommy.
Is it Michael?
Michael Murphy?
Yes! Only you don't know
how to say that, do you?
Will you teach Mommy
how to say no?
When you close your eyes,
does that mean no?
What an idiot!
That was a yes question.
You don't want to hear
any more Benjamin Bunny,
do you?
That's an emphatic reply.
Very well, young man,
no more Benjamin Bunny.
I don't know how Mommy
could've been
so thoughtless.
We're going to take all
these baby books right
to the children's hospital.
It's time
for the big stuff.
Something heroic.
There you go. You gotta
tell us what you want.
The Once and Future King
by T.H. White.
"The boy slept well in
the woodland nest where
he had laid himself down.
"At first he only dipped
below the surface of sleep,
"and skimmed along like
a salmon in shallow water;
"so close
to the surface...
"that he fancied himself
in air.
"He thought himself awake
when he was already asleep.
"He saw the stars above
his face whirling on their
silent and sleepless axes,
"and the leaves
of the tree rustling
against them.
"He heard small changes
in the grass.
"Distilled noises of footsteps
and soft, fringed wing beats,
"and stealthy bellies
drawn over grass blades...
"or rattling against
the bracken at
first frightened him...
then interested him. "
[Imagining. ; Loud Screeching]
Okay.
Is it your thumb?
Is it your
index finger?
Your middle finger?
Your little finger?
It's your little finger.
Think you can move
your little finger?
Okay.
Tell your brain
to tell your arm
to tell your hand...
to move
your little finger.
Come on, sweetheart,
tell your brain...
to tell your arm
to tell your hand...
to move
your little finger.
Come on, my friend,
what a wonderful thing.
A "yes."
Then there'll be a
"could be" and maybe
even a "shut up, Mommy."
Right now we just have
to get to "yes."
So tell your brain
to tell your arm...
to tell your hand to
move your little finger.
Come on, my love,
tell your brain...
to tell your hand to move
your little finger.
- Come on, Lorenzo.
- You can do it, can't you?
You can do it.!
[Omouri]
Come on, Lorenzo.
[Excited Gasping,
Laughing]
[Augusto]
They are born without
myelin, right?
[Man]
The only naturally dismyelinated
higher animals in existence.
And this is passed
from mother to son.
Yes.
The mother is from Edinburgh.
That's Jasmine.
She doesn't shake,
but her male pups do.
You think you can stop
them from shaking?
We hope so.
By implanting nerve cells,
we expect to see the growth
of new myelin.
We've been partially
remyelinating rats and mice
for ten years now...
and it's repeatable.
If we could fund this work,
it could be the first
in higher animals.
Hmm. And then
in human beings, huh?
Well, in time.
Yes.
Dr. Duncan, if I help you
raise these funds,
and if we can get
the researchers
together to collaborate,
I think we can achieve
very much in a short time.
Augusto, we scientists
are a very competitive lot.
Such a collaboration's
a lovely idea,
but sadly that is
not how science works.
That's not
necessarily so.
Because, remember,
the Manhattan Project?
Twenty-eight months,
it took them
twenty-eight months.
Now, if scientists can
come together to build
the atomic bomb,
surely they come
together to remyelinate
some puppy dogs.
[Yipping]
[Michaela]
Papa called last night
from Italy, my darling.
He's missing his Lorenzaccio
very, very much.
But he wants me
to tell you he's making
a big dinner tonight.
A banquet ofbrain food
for the cleverest doctors
in the world...
who've gathered together
to put the myelin back
in the shaking puppy dogs.
And if they
can achieve that...
someday, there might be
a way to help all the people
who've lost their myelin.
Not only the boys
with A.L.D.,
but the people
with multiple sclerosis and
many other diseases, Lorenzo.
Then think,
my brave boy,
if they can ever give you
back your myelin,
you'll be able to tell
your brain...
to tell your toes,
your fingers, your anything,
to do what
you want them to do.
[Michaela And Lorenzo's Voice]
And then, one day,
[Lorenzo's Voice]
I'll hear my voice...
and all these words
I'm thinking...
will get outside
my head.
[Laughing]
Oh-ho!
Now it broke!
This is Charles
and this is Harry.
They've both been on
Lorenzo's Oil for two years.
My name is Michael Benton
and I'm 12 and a half years old.
I've been taking Lorenzo's Oil
for four and a half years.
I was diagnosed with
adrenoleulsodytrophy
when I was 13 years old.
I've been talking
Lorenzo's Oil
for three years.
Some of the activities
I'm involved in are
baseball, basketball...
I've been taking
Lorenzo's Oil for 16 months.
[Indistinct]
I've been on Lorenzo's Oil
for four years.
I've been taking Lorenzo's Oil
for one year.