You know how blind I am without them.
Howard, don't cry.
Murder.
- Good luck, John.
- Any contractions?
Only the ones you give me.
- What's coming?
- Red Ball, double homicide.
One male, one female.
Killer's male, white, 40s.
Agatha nailed the time at 8:04 a.m.
The twins are a little fuzzy on that.
Location's still uncertain.
Remote witnesses are plugged in.
This will be case number 1108.
Morning, detectives.
Case number 1108,
previsualized by the Pre-Cogs...
...recorded on holosphere
by Precrime's Q-stacks.
My fellow witnesses are Dr. Katherine
James and Chief Justice Frank Pollard.
Good morning.
Will the witness preview and validate
1108 at this time?
Affirmative. I will validate.
Go get them.
- Standby.
- Time of murder: 8:04 a.m.
That is 24 minutes, 13 seconds
from now. This is a Red Ball.
You know how blind I am without them.
All right, Howard Marks,
where are you?
Howard? Howard, breakfast.
Four score and seven years ago...
- He looked familiar.
- Who?
A man standing in the park
across the street.
- Seen him before.
- How can you tell?
You're blind without your glasses.
Where are your glasses?
- In the bedroom.
- You're running out of time.
- You know how blind I am...
I show eight Howard Markses in the
District. Sorting by race and age.
Run their license and registration.
See if I can capture an address here.
I was thinking I'd stay home today.
- What about your meeting?
- I've been working too much.
- Can you grab that?
- It's unclear.
- Six licenses. Where do you want them?
- Over here, please.
You know how blind I am without them.
Got him in the Foxhall.
4421 Gainsborough.
Send DCPD. Set up a perimeter.
Tell them we're en route.
I was thinking maybe I'd play hooky,
stay home today.
- "We've come to dedicate a portion..."
- What do you think?
- What about your meeting?
- I'll reschedule.
I've been working too much anyway.
- "But in a larger s..." Good.
- We could have lunch together.
- What do you say?
- "We cannot consecrate...
- I would love to.
- "The brave men, living and dead...
I have an open house
at the Ressler place.
- Have consecrated, far above our
poor power to add or detract. "
I guess that's why you look so nice.
Chief! We got a problem
with our location.
- It's no longer there.
- Shit!
- Time frame?
- Thirteen minutes.
Investigator from the fed's here.
I don't need some twink
from the fed poking around.
I wrote it on your calendar.
See if the neighbors knew
where they went.
- Check all relations.
- Checking.
Just get him some coffee,
tell him how I save your ass every day.
I got coffee, thanks.
Danny Witwer,
the twink from the fed.
Oops. Gum?
I'll give you the full tour
some other time.
They moved two weeks ago. Nobody
knows where. Still searching for family.
Time horizon, 12 minutes.
He's scrubbing the image, looking for...
...clues as to where
the murder will happen.
Original running bond brick pattern,
Georgian details. Brick was repointed.
And that this nation, under God,
shall not perish from the earth.
Victims are pronounced here,
killers here.
Beyond that, all we have to run on
are the images that they produce.
- Show a cop on horseback.
- Near the Capitol?
- No Maglev system.
- The Mall?
Georgetown.
The Pre-Cogs can see a murder
four days out. Why the late call?
A Red Ball. Crimes of passion have no
premeditation, so they show up late.
Most of our scrambles are flash events.
We rarely see premeditation anymore.
People have gotten the message.
I show a match with Dwight Kingsley,
18th-century architect.
- He did two dozen houses in D.C.
- Time horizon, 10 minutes.
Look at this kid.
In this one,
he's on the left side of the man.
Yes. So?
This one he's on the right.
Merry-go-round.
It's a park.
There's only 16 of these old
merry-go-rounds left in the city.
Two in Georgetown, one in
Barnaby Woods, the others in Woodley.
It's gotta be Barnaby Woods.
Evanna, flight time?
The way I drive?
Three minutes after wheels up.
- Clear.
Time horizon, six minutes.
Let's go to bed.
Let's do it in here.
- But the bed is soft.
- I'm soft.
Shit.
Which one is it?
- Not the bed.
- Come on.
I don't want to be on the bed.
- We're catching up to the future.
- Shut up, Evanna. Jad?
- Jad?
- Go ahead.
- Did he close the front door?
- What?
Did Marks close the front door?
Front door...
I didn't wanna be on the bed.
- Negative. The front door is open.
- Time horizon, 30 seconds.
I forgot my glasses.
Howard.
You know how blind I am without them.
Howard, don't cry.
Marks!
Look at me. Look at me.
Positive for Howard Marks.
By mandate of the District of Columbia
Precrime Division...
...you're under arrest for the future
murder of Mrs. Marks and Mr. Dubin...
...that was to take place today
at 0800 hours and four minutes.
- I didn't do anything. Sarah?
- Give the man his hat.
Oh, God.
Don't put that halo on me. Sarah!
- Put your hand on your head.
- Help me! I wasn't gonna do anything!
I'm Officer Scott with the
Precrime Trauma Response Unit.
Sit here a minute and listen to me.
Your husband is being arrested
by Precrime.
Oh, God, Howard, no.
Howard, don't cry.
Please, don't cry.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I thought they stopped the murder.
That's just an echo.
Pre-Cog déjà vu, if you will.
The really bad ones
the Pre-Cogs see over and over again.
Wally, erase the incoming.
Imagine a world without murder.
- I lost my best friend.
- I lost my aunt.
- I lost my dad.
- I lost my wife.
Just six years ago, the homicide rate
had reached epidemic proportions.
It seemed that only a miracle
could stop the bloodshed.
But instead of one miracle, we
were given three: The Pre-Cognitives.
Within just one month
under the Precrime program...
... the murder rate in the District
of Columbia was reduced 90°%°.
- They were waiting for me.
- He was gonna rape me.
- I was going to be stabbed.
- Right here.
Within a year, Precrime effectively
stopped murder in our nation's capital.
In the six years of our experiment...
... there hasn't been a single murder.
And now Precrime can work for you.
We want to make certain
that every American...
... can bank on the infallibility
of the system.
And to ensure that what keeps us safe
will also keep us free.
- Precrime. It works.
- It works.
Precrime. It works.
On Tuesday, April 22, vote "yes"
on the National Precrime Initiative.
What's the matter? Can't sleep?
- Just need a little clarity.
- True that.
You want the customary clarity or
the new and improved kind of clarity?
Give me the new stuff.
New and improved clarity.
Clarity, clarity. Yes, indeed.
Come on. Come on.
Don't bust my balls. You've only given
me four, and some of these are duds.
Sweet dreams, chief.
Don't worry.
Your secret's safe with me.
I could use a little juice on my side.
What do you think you know?
It's like my daddy used to say:
"In the land of the blind...
...the one-eyed man is king. "
I'm home.
Overhead.
Wall screen.
- Sean.
- Hi, Daddy.
Can you teach me how to run faster?
Because all the kids in my class
run faster than me.
That's good.
Keep your knees up.
Like that. Like that.
High. High. Like that.
- See, you're a natural runner.
- Gotta keep running.
Yeah. Gotta keep running.
Gotta keep running.
- Will I be as fast as you someday?
- Oh, I think you'll beat me someday.
- You're gonna beat everybody.
- I think you'll beat everyone someday.
- I gotta go. Bye.
- No, no, no. Wait, wait.
- You gotta give me a kiss.
- Not on the lips.
Only Mommy kisses me on the lips.
Yeah, all right. All right.
I love you.
- I love you, Sean.
- I love you, Daddy.
Reminds me of Rosarito Beach.
Remember?
We had 20 dollars and...
Waiting in that van so the sun
would shine on our vacation.
John. John. John,
put the camera down.
Look, I'm all ready for bed.
What is this? No. Put it away.
It's time to put the camera
to sleep...
... and time to come
and take care of your wife.
Why don't you put the camera down
and come and watch the rain with me?
No? I promise I'll make it
a memorable moment.
Put the camera down
or you're not getting anything tonight.
A gentleman at Justice
wants to take this away from us.
In a week, people will vote
on whether or not...
...what we've been doing has been
a noble-minded enterprise...
...or a chance to change the way
this country fights crime.
John...
...watch this Danny Witwer,
the observer from Justice.
- I met him yesterday.
- Let him look around.
Answer his questions,
but watch him.
If there's any problem,
make sure we know about it.
When the Pre-Cogs declare a killer,
their name is embedded in the wood.
Since the shape and grain of each piece
is unique, they're impossible to forge.
You understand the legalistic
drawback to Precrime methodology.
- Here we go again.
- I'm not with the ACLU on this...
...but we arrest individuals
who've broken no law.
- They will.
- The commission is metaphysics.
The Pre-Cogs see the future,
and they're never wrong.
But it's not the future if you stop it.
- Isn't that a fundamental paradox?
- Yes.
You're talking about predetermination,
which happens all the time.
- Why'd you catch that?
- It was gonna fall.
You're certain?
But it didn't fall. You caught it.
Preventing it doesn't change
the fact that it was going to happen.
You ever get any false positives?
Someone intends to kill, but doesn't.
How do the Pre-Cogs tell the difference?
They don't see what you intend to do,
only what you will do.
Why can't they see
rapes, assaults, suicides?
Because of the nature of murder.
Nothing's more destructive to the
metaphysical fabric that binds us...
...than the untimely murder of a human.
- That wasn't Walt Whitman.
Iris Hineman. She developed Pre-Cogs,
designed the system and the interface.
Speaking of interfacing,
I'd love to say hello.
- To Hineman?
- To them.
- Cops aren't allowed inside the temple.
- You've never been inside?
We keep strict separation so that
no one can be accused of tampering.
- I'll be the first one to go in then?
- Maybe you didn't hear me.
- If it's a question of authority...
- There is no question.
You don't have any.
I have a warrant in my pocket
that says different.
- Show it to me.
- Sure.
This investigation of Precrime
and its personnel is conducted...
...under the direct supervision and
permission from the attorney general.
I'm here as his representative...
...which means you're now operating
under my supervision.
Seems you've been left
out of the loop.
All right, we're ready. Let's go.
- Hold it right there. Hold on.
- Not cleared for access.
Eye-dent: John Anderton. Approved.
- Wally.
- No, no, no, no.
Danny Witwer from Justice.
We're to give him the run of the farm.
- I can't touch you.
- Don't touch anything.
- You can't be in here.
- Just answer his questions.
- Tell me how...
- They're sleeping.
Sorry. Tell me how all this works.
The photon milk acts as both a
nutrient supply and conductor.
It enhances the images they receive.
We call the female Agatha.
The twins are Arthur and Dashiell.
We scan by way of optical tomography.
White-light pinpoints pulse
along the length of the headgear...
...and are reread after absorption
through their brain tissue.
In other words, we see what they see.
They don't feel pain. We keep
their heads stocked with dopamine.
Plus, we maintain careful control
over their serotonin levels.
Don't want them to drift off
into too deep a sleep.
- They can't be kept too awake either.
- Don't think of them as human.
No. They're much more than that.
Science has stolen
most of our miracles.
In a way, they give us hope,
hope of the existence of the divine.
It's interesting that some people
have begun to deify the Pre-Cogs.
Pre-Cogs are pattern-recognition filters.
That's all.
- Yet you call this room the "temple. "
- A nickname.
The oracle isn't where
the power is, anyway.
The power is with the priests,
even if they had to invent the oracle.
You guys are nodding like you know
what he's talking about.
Well, come on, chief. The way we work,
changing destiny and all...
...we're more like clergy than cops.
- Jad.
- Yeah?
Go to work. All of you.
Sorry. Old habit.
I spent three years at Fuller Seminary
before I became a cop.
- My father was proud.
- What does he think of your work?
I don't know. He was shot and killed
when I was 15 at our church in Dublin.
I know what it's like
to lose someone close.
Nothing's like the loss of a child.
I don't have any children, so I can
only imagine what that was like.
To lose your son
in such a public place like that...
Now we can make sure that
kind of thing doesn't happen to anyone.
- Tell me what it is you're looking for.
- Flaws.
There hasn't been a murder
in six years. This system is...
Perfect. I agree.
If there's a flaw, it's human.
It always is.
John.
Wally.
Can you see?
What happened? Her ACTH levels
just shot through the roof!
- What'd you do?
- She grabbed me.
Impossible. They're not aware of us.
In the milk, all they see is the future.
- She looked straight at me.
- It could have been a nightmare.
- She spoke to me.
- To you?
What'd she say?
"Can you see?"
You the sentry?
Yes, sir, I'm Gideon.
You're Chief Anderton.
The music relaxes the prisoners.
I don't ever see you Precops down here.
Am I in trouble?
Not yet.
I'm interested in a murder.
- I got plenty of those. Kill type?
- Drowning.
That narrows it down.
Not too many in here for that.
- Victim's Caucasian, female.
- This about the Justice Department?
I'm supposed to spruce up for a tour
they got tomorrow. You like this tie?
Stop.
Roll back.
There.
She's a golden oldie. One of our first.
Probably before your time.
- This is the composite of the three?
- That's right.
Combined data stream
based on all three previsions.
- Just show me Agatha's data stream.
- For that...
...we go for a ride.
My God.
I'd forgotten there were so many.
And to think they'd all be out there
killing people if it wasn't for you.
Look at them.
Look at how peaceful they seem.
But on the inside: Busy, busy, busy.
Okey-pokey.
Now that is one bad man.
He drowned a woman named
Anne Lively out at Roland Lake.
The killer's a John Doe,
never identified.
Why is he still a John Doe?
Why wasn't he ID'd from the eye scan?
Those are not his eyes. He had them
swapped out to fool the scanners.
You can get it done on the street
for a few thousand bucks these days.
Okay, so you want
just the female prevision.
That's right.
We don't seem to have her data.
Try again.
This is odd. See?
We have the two previsions. We got
what Art saw. We got what Dash saw.
But Agatha's isn't here.
Probably just a glitch.
Tell me about the intended victim,
this Anne Lively.
Looks like she's a neuroin addict,
like our John Doe here.
Address history
includes the Beaton Clinic.
So she cleaned up.
Where is she now?
I guess glitches come in twos.
You finally crawl your way out
of one hole just to fall into another.
No.
Can't let you take that out of here,
chief.
- It's against the rules.
- Anything else against the rules?
Careful, chief. You dig up the past,
all you get is dirty.
The third prevision was what,
kind of fuzzy or something?
No, the third prevision,
Agatha's prevision, wasn't there.
That's not all. There are a dozen more
cases with missing previsions.
You'd think we'd have found
the cure for the common cold.
- It's stress.
- What's this?
Herbal tea with honey.
I hate herbal tea.
Almost as much as I hate honey.
Just drink it,
before I pour it in your lap.
- Can I get you anything, John?
- No, thank you.
Witwer's scheduled for a tour
of Containment tomorrow.
Yeah, give him a tour.
- Lara called me.
- What?
She's worried about you.
Quite frankly, so am I.
I'm fine.
I understand you've been spending
a lot of time in the Sprawl.
- I go running down there.
- In the middle of the night.
What if Danny Witwer
insisted on a full chem run?
I'm fine.
The minute Precrime goes national,
they are going to take it away.
- We won't let them.
- No?
How is an old man and a cop on the
whiff ever going to stop them?
My father once said to me...
..."You don't choose the things
you believe in. They choose you. "
There's a reason you are here.
Had Precrime been in place earlier,
your loss would have been prevented.
Remember, the eyes...
The eyes of the nation
are on us right now.
I'm not the generation
anyone listens to...
...but people trust you when you
speak of your belief in Precrime.
They know that it's a belief born of
pain, not politics. I understood that.
I may have even encouraged it
to help with the cause.
But now,
your pain is hurting both of us.
They're not going to take it
away from us.
I won't let them.
Bingo.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Hey, buddy.
- I made up a club.
- Yeah?
- We're called the Crescos.
- The Crescos.
- We made up a soccer team.
- Yeah?
- We practice at school.
- With Connor?
Your daddy's in a lot of trouble,
Sean.
- Wait!
- No!
Jad, how come you're not with
Father Witwer?
We're in motion on something. We got a
white, male victim, about 5' 10", 170.
He takes a round in the 10-ring
and goes out a window.
- Red Ball?
- Nope. Brown Ball.
It's premeditated.
Amazing. There's someone within
200 miles still dumb enough to do that.
The victim's name is Leo Crow.
This is case number 1109. Time of
occurrence: Friday, 1506 hours.
Start search for Leo Crow. Case 1109,
previsualized by the Pre-Cogs...
...recorded on holosphere
by Precrime's Q-stacks.
My fellow witnesses are Dr. Katherine
James and Chief Justice Frank Pollard.
Good morning.
Are you ready
to preview and validate 1109?
- Ready when you are, John.
- Standing by.
I love this part.
I've got no address. No tax returns
for the last five years.
Check NCIC.
Maybe he's got a number.
We'll send a protection team
as soon as we lock location.
It looks like federal housing.
Concrete, glass, egg crates.
Ouch. About a thousand of those
in the District.
Fractured images coming in.
Numbers nine...
Nine, six.
Female, senior. She's smoking a pipe.
She's laughing.
Okay, now I'm inside a room.
Windowpanes, aluminum extrusion.
Two figures resolving in the room.
- Wait!
- No...
Looks like we got a third party.
Wearing sunglasses,
just out the window.
You're not gonna kill me.
Goodbye, Crow.
- Goodbye, Crow.
- Wait!
Wait. Wait.
You say something, chief?
No.
I'll get this one.
We got time on this one, Jad.
Mind getting me a piece
of cake they're eating?
- I'm starving.
- Sure, chief.
I think I'll get one for myself too.
Take your time.
Chief Anderton,
what is this that I'm seeing?
I'm confused about...
- Anderton, wait!
- Goodbye, Crow.
Anderton, wait!
I like you, chief.
You've always been nice to me.
Give you two minutes
before I hit the alarm.
Hold that, please.
Thanks.
- You're in a lot of trouble, John.
- You set me up.
I'll write the paranoia off to the
whiff you've been doping on.
Easy.
- Easy.
- Seems I've found a flaw.
What are you gonna do?
Possession will cost you six months
and your badge.
I guess we won't be working together
after all.
Now put the gun down, John.
I don't hear a Red Ball.
Lamar. Lamar.
- Lamar?
- John, what is happening?
It's Witwer. He set me up!
Stop, just wait.
- Witwer! It's Witwer.
- Who's the victim?
- Somebody.
- Who?
- Somebody... Leo Crow.
- Who is he?
I have no idea!
I've never heard of him.
But I'm supposed to kill him
in less than 36 hours.
- How could Witwer have access?
- Can you fake a cerebral output?
- Why would anyone want to?
- Can you?
- I doubt it.
- Would Hineman know?
- Now listen, come in.
- What?
I'll protect you until we
get to the bottom of this.
Talk to Wally. See if Witwer's gone
inside the temple again.
Ask Jad for any off-hour
eye-dents into the analytical room.
Who's Leo Crow?
Security lockdown enabled.
Revised destination: Office.
Lamar, they found me.
Is there any way to override
the lockdown?
- No, no, no.
- No?
I'll meet you anywhere you say.
You can come to my house, John.
I can't. They'll get me.
I'm not gonna get haloed.
You can't run.
Everybody runs.
- Oh, my God!
- Hey, hey.
Oh, my gosh, are you okay?
I'll bring him in. Unharmed.
You're not gonna do that.
I'm taking control.
What?
Fletcher is second in command.
It's his show to run. You can observe.
- Do it. Find him.
- Yes, sir.
He came to see you the other day
right before he was tagged.
- What did you talk about?
- The Mets.
John doesn't think they have a deep
enough pitching roster.
Why are you protecting him? You knew
he was doping, yet you did nothing.
- The man lost a child, for chrissake.
- Six years ago.
- What did you talk about?
- None of your business.
It's my business. Investigation of a
supervising officer for a capital crime...
...falls under federal jurisdiction
so as to rule out any conspiracy.
- He's my suspect.
- He's my subordinate.
Call the attorney general. I'm sure
he'd clarify the issue for you.
I don't want John Anderton hurt.
I'm going to enjoy working here.
A road diverges in the desert.
Lexus.
The road you're on, John Anderton,
is the one less-traveled.
- Make sure you...
- Diamonds...
Good evening, John Anderton.
John Anderton! You could use
a Guinness right about now.
- John Anderton...
- Escape from it all.
Get away, John Anderton.
Forget your troubles.
He's been eye-dented on the Metro.
The train stops at 20th and 33rd.
Send units to each location.
- Better make 20th.
- Have faith.
Fire them up!
- Hey, Fletch.
- Hey, John.
- That was a rough landing.
- Yeah.
- Work on that.
- It's the shit knee of mine.
- Yeah.
- Don't do it.
Hey, don't do this.
John?
Don't run.
You don't have to chase me.
You don't have to run.
Everybody runs, Fletch.
You know we'll catch you.
Everybody runs.
- It doesn't have to be like this, John.
- Everybody runs.
Get your sick-sticks ready.
Everybody runs, Fletch.
Slow down, chief. Just take it easy.
No sudden moves, chief.
John, it's okay.
- Fletch...
- Easy does it, chief.
Got a grip?
- Got a grip?
- Yeah.
Anderton!
Go away! Get out of my kitchen!
Get out of my house!
Get out of my house! Go!
- Get them out of here!
- Anderton, stop!
Pull him off me, Fletcher.
Get him off me.
Get him out of here!
What's the matter with you?!
Get out of my house! Go!
By mandate of the District of Columbia,
I'm placing you under arrest for...
Go to sleep.
You two stay with me!
Dr. Hineman.
You're trespassing.
I don't have visitors.
That would be from the doll's eye,
the vine...
...the baneberry that scratched you
during your illegal climb over my wall.
It's not a true doll's eye.
It's a little hybrid I designed.
Once the poison gets into your
bloodstream, you'll start to see...
...the most extraordinary display
of blue objects.
This just isn't your week, is it?
Chief Anderton.
I'm not a killer.
You better drink this.
Soon you won't be able to swallow,
and then you'll be totally buggered.
All of it.
Okay, now take a minute
to right yourself.
Just what is it you think
I can do for you?
You could tell me how someone
can fake a prevision.
How would I know that?
Because you invented Precrime.
What's so funny?
If the consequences of several genetic
mistakes and science gone haywire...
...can be called an invention,
then I invented Precrime.
- You don't seem proud.
- I'm not.
I was trying to heal them,
not turn them into something else.
- Heal who?
- The innocents we use to stop the guilty.
You're talking about the Pre-Cogs.
You think they came from a test tube?
They are merely the ones who survived.
I was doing genetic research,
treating children of drug addicts.
This was 10 years ago,
when neuroin first hit the streets.
It was impure, not the engineered
cocktail popular among the educated.
All of these kids were born with severe
brain damage. Most died before age 12.
Those few who survived,
they had a gift.
I call it a gift. For them,
it was more like a cosmic joke.
They would wake up in the night,
curled in the corner...
...screaming, clawing at the walls.
Because when these children
closed their eyes at night...
...they dreamt only of murder
over and over, one after the other.
It didn't take for us long to realize
that the real nightmare was...
...that these dreams were about to come
true, these murders were happening.
You say some of the children died?
So many of them.
Despite what we did for them.
Or maybe because of what we
did to them. But it doesn't matter.
It's a perfect system now, isn't it?
I'm not going to commit murder.
I've never met the man
I'm supposed to kill.
And yet a chain of events has started
that will lead you to his murder.
- Not if I stay away from him.
- Can you avoid a man you've never met?
- You won't help?
- I can't help you. Nobody can.
The Pre-Cogs are never wrong.
But occasionally...
...they do disagree.
What?
Most of the time, all three Pre-Cogs
will see an event in the same way...
...but once in a while, one of them will
see things differently than the others.
Jesus Christ.
Why didn't I know about this?
Because these Minority Reports
are destroyed the instant they occur.
Why?
For Precrime to function, there can't
be any suggestion of fallibility.
Who wants a justice system
that instills doubt?
It may be reasonable,
but it's still doubt.
Are you saying
I've haloed innocent people?
I'm saying that every so often,
those accused of a Precrime...
...just might have
an alternate future.
Does Burgess know about this,
about this Minority Report?
I used to joke with Lamar that
we were the parents of Precrime.
Parents often see their children as they
want them to be and not as they are.
Answer my question: Does Lamar
Burgess know about the Minority Report?
Yes, of course, he knew.
But at the time, we felt their existence
was an insignificant variable.
Insignificant to you, maybe.
But what about those people that
I put away with alternate futures?
- My God, if the country knew...
- The system would collapse.
- I believe in that system.
- Do you really?
You wanna bring it down.
You will bring it down
if you manage to kill your victim.
That'll be the most spectacular public
display of how Precrime didn't work.
- I'm not gonna kill anybody.
- Hold that thought.
- Why should I trust you?
- You shouldn't trust anyone.
Certainly not the attorney general,
who wants it all for himself.
And not the young federal agent,
who wants your job.
Not even the old man who just wants
to hang on to what he created.
Don't trust anyone.
Just find the Minority Report.
You said the Minority Report
is destroyed.
The record is destroyed.
The original report still exists.
I designed it so the report is stored
in a safe place, but not declared.
What safe place is that?
The safest place there is.
Where is it?
Inside the Pre-Cog who predicted it.
All you have to do
is download it, darling.
That's all, huh?
Just walk into Precrime,
get into the temple...
...somehow tap into these Pre-Cogs
and download this Minority Report.
- If you have one.
- And then walk out.
Actually, you'll have to run out.
But yes, that's what you have to do.
You're insane.
Or you think I am.
I'll get eye-scanned a dozen times
before I get within 10 miles of Precrime.
Sometimes in order to see the light,
you have to risk the dark.
As a policeman...
Excuse me, as a former policeman...
...I'm sure that you know
all sorts of people...
...who can help you out
in this regard.
It's funny how all
living organisms are alike.
When the chips are down,
when the pressure is on...
...every creature
on the face of the earth...
...is interested in one thing
and one thing only:
Its own survival.
Find the Minority Report.
How do I even know which one has it?
It's always in the more gifted
of the three.
Which one is that?
The female.
We've got three men in a room.
The victim is here...
...John is here, and this
unidentified male, at the window.
The adjacent building suggests
public housing, which means...
- There's thousands like this one.
- They're everywhere.
But he doesn't go there to kill Crow
for another 22 hours.
This is Chief Anderton's space.
- He's not here.
- He'll be back.
I doubt that. I'm betting
he's somewhere in the Sprawl.
He's smart enough to go
where billboards can't ID him.
There's fewer consumers,
which means fewer scanners.
- Why won't he just run?
- Because he thinks he's innocent.
We concentrate on the Sprawl.
We do fly-overs in ships,
with two spyder teams on the ground.
Thermal scan the entire area. Read
anything with eyes and a heartbeat.
Where is she?
Started blowing buttons for no reason
whatsoever, and I knew that.
This damn cold.
Don't worry. I could cut open your
chest and sew a dead cat in there...
...you wouldn't get an infection. Not
with the antibios I'll shoot into you.
That's comforting.
You do understand I can't just
give you new irises?
Please, don't touch.
Because the scanners would read the
new scar tissue, alarms will go off...
...and large men with guns will appear.
What was that?
- It's anesthesia. It's all downhill...
- You always sneak up on your patients?
You wouldn't break the hand
of a violinist before the concert.
Please, relax.
All I'm trying to tell you is that I'll
have to remove your eyes completely.
I know.
- I have to replace them with new ones.
- I know. But I wanna keep the old ones.
- Why?
- Because my mother gave them to me.
What's it to you?
You can't resell them.
Whatever you say. It's your money.
Let me introduce my gorgeous
assistant, Miss Van Eyck.
- This is not a lot of money.
- It's all that I could safely move.
Okay.
- What did you give me?
- Smile medicine.
Tell you what, since we go way back...
...why don't I give you my old pal
discount? What do you say?
You don't remember me, do you?
- We know each other?
- Yes, we do.
From where? D.C.?
- Baltimore. The East Side.
- Baltimore? We go way back.
Solomon P. Eddie, M.D.
I was a plastic surgeon.
You remember? Specialized
in burn victims, mostly women.
- I put you away.
- Yeah, you did.
You made those tapes.
They were performance pieces.
- You set your patients on fire.
- I put them out.
Some not as quickly as others, but
let's change the subject, shall we?
The future's so much more interesting
than the past, don't you think?
Miss Van Eyck.
I'm afraid she's already smitten.
She only has eyes for you.
I know what you're thinking, John:
How can I do what I do now?
Let's say that I spent an awful lot
of time in the prison library.
That was a great way to avoid the more
unpleasant aspects of prison life.
Confinement was
a real education, a real...
...eye-opener.
For true enlightenment,
there's nothing quite like...
...well, let's say, taking a shower
while this large fellow...
...with an attitude you can't
knock down with a hammer...
...whispers in your ear, "Oh, Nancy. "
That was a lot of fun.
Thank you for putting me there...
...and giving me the opportunity to
get to know myself so much better.
And now to return the favor.
- This your work?
- Yes.
I like it.
- How do you take your coffee?
- Cream and sugar.
- I don't have any cream. Sorry.
- Just sugar then.
- You and John ever come here?
- We used to.
He's not here now, is he?
I had to ask.
- I don't have any sugar either.
- Thank you.
- He hasn't tried to contact you?
- No.
Did he ever mention the name
Leo Crow?
No, but I don't talk
to John much anymore.
- So you haven't seen his apartment.
- That was our apartment.
Have you been there recently?
It's full of these.
- How long has he been doping?
- Since right after we lost our son.
- You mean after he lost your son.
- It was nobody's fault.
But John was with him
at the public pool.
You said in your divorce papers
that John tried to kill himself.
- It wasn't a suicide attempt.
- What was it then?
The FBI found something
that belonged to my son, a sandal.
John was upset. He...
He took out his gun
and watched home movies.
- This is all in your statement.
- He shot a hole in the ceiling. So what?
You lose your son,
let's see how well you handle it.
Lamar thinks you left John because he
lost himself in Precrime instead of you.
I left him because every time
I looked at him, I saw my son.
Every time I got close to him,
I smelled my little boy.
That's why I left him.
And now you can leave.
Don't take the bandages off
for 12 hours.
If you take them off before then,
you'll go blind. Understand?
In the fridge, there's milk.
Greta made you a sandwich.
Make sure you drink a lot of water.
How do I find the bathroom?
The bathroom?
Now that's your right hand.
The kitchen is your left.
Don't scratch. Never scratch!
Seeing as we're being pals, I'll give
you a bonus that may come in handy.
This is a temporary paralytic enzyme.
You're gonna shoot this under your chin.
- What is this?
- It'll turn your pretty face into mush.
People won't even recognize you.
In 30 minutes, it'll tighten up again.
But it'll hurt like you've never felt.
I'm gonna put this in your goody-bag,
together with your...
...leftovers.
I'm setting up a timer. When it rings,
you can remove the bandages and leave.
- But not before then, or you will...
- Go blind. I know.
Don't scratch.
A little something from
a mutual friend of ours.
Don't take the bandages off
for 12 hours.
If you take them off before then,
you'll go blind. Understand?
- 25. 16 seconds. That's a new record.
- Is that a world record?
Is it a world record?
It's a personal best.
- Now I wanna time you.
- You gotta be kidding.
There's no way
I can beat 25. 16 seconds.
How long can a whale hold its breath?
For about 20 minutes.
- So we gotta beat the whale.
- Okay.
We gotta beat the whale.
Here you go.
It's gonna be 20 minutes. You sure
you don't wanna go for an ice cream?
Because you know
I'm gonna beat that whale.
- Ready?
- Give me the count.
Three, two, one, go!
Sean?
Sean.
Have you seen...?
I'm looking for my son. Have you
seen a boy in a red bathing suit?
You seen my boy?
He's wearing a red bathing suit.
Jad, we're ready to begin thermal scan
on all residences on North Powell.
You must really like me, don't you?
That's why you asked to partner
with me on this sortie.
You're swell company.
It's not that you don't trust me
to be alone with the chief, is it?
That you think I might, you know,
futz with him?
No, I just wanna watch him use your
body to sandblast another building.
Evanna, go.
I show 27 warm bodies.
Roger that. Confirmed, 27 warm bodies.
- Four spyders, one per floor?
- Let's do eight. I gotta eat.
Residents of 931 Powell, this is
Officer Fletcher of D.C. Precrime.
Under authority of P.C. section 6409, we
are deploying spyders into your complex.
Mom, I'm scared.
Mommy, I'm scared. Mommy.
That's gonna scan you.
Keep your eyes open. Stay still.
- It's okay.
- I don't like it.
Stay still. Stay still.
Come on!
You stepped out on me
for the last time.
I told you where I was.
You're a no-good liar.
I know you was with that ho.
You're lucky we...
Leave me alone!
We lost one.
Roger that. Maybe it was
a cat jumping through a window.
It's an awful big cat.
Fletcher.
I'll go check it out.
They're crying their eyes out.
You terrified them.
Keep your kids away from me.
The big cat's back. What do you think?
A drunk, maybe can't wake up?
Or a guy who doesn't want to get read.
Folks, be quiet, go back inside.
Be quiet and close the door.
We got an ID. It's not him.
- Standing down.
- Let's eat.
Fletcher, take a look.
There's four people in this room,
not three.
Four? There's Anderton, Crow
and the man in sunglasses.
The man in the sunglasses
is outside the window.
There's also someone here
in the mirror.
Definitely female.
The Precrime program began in 2046
with a federal grant.
And now, nine years later,
D.C. is the safest city in America.
Why? Because Precrime works.
Precrime has eliminated the need
for conventional detectives.
What happens now is the verification
and protection of future victims.
Can we see the Pre-Cogs?
They have such a powerful gift,
they're kept in peaceful seclusion...
...so as not to be distracted.
This display should give you some idea
of what their daily life is like.
The Pre-Cogs get over
8 million letters every year.
That's more than Santa Claus gets.
Each Pre-Cog has their own bedroom,
TV and weight room.
It's wonderful to be a Pre-Cog.
My mom's new boyfriend
came over again last night.
He's just not very intelligent.
My mom wouldn't let me eat upstairs.
I had to listen to him go on and on.
Shit!
Eye-dent: John Anderton.
Approved for entry.
- Which I told her I'd be able to do.
I'm so good at taking care of you.
But she thinks I'll be irresponsible.
It's ridiculous because...
You can't be in here.
What are you doing here?
Easy there, old-timer.
Who cleared you?
- You're not allowed here.
- Listen, Wally.
- Do I know you?
- I like you.
So I don't wanna have
to kick you or hit you.
But only if you promise to help me.
Hi, John.
Who does that look like to you?
I don't know.
It's Agatha.
He's coming here to get her.
- Are these all of her previsions?
- I'm rewinding her right now.
Just take me to the Leo Crow murder.
They don't come out in any order.
I'm getting them as she's giving them.
Can you see?
- He's inside.
- He has some kind of mask on.
- He sealed the door.
- Shit!
Nobody fires a weapon inside
the temple. Use bindfoam.
- Is there another way out of there?
- All the doors are covered.
John, move away from the tank.
Move away from the tank, John.
What does he want with a Pre-Cog?
So he can kill whoever he wants to
without anyone knowing.
Well, there's still the other two.
The other two can still function, right?
They're a hive mind. It takes all three
for their predictive abilities to work.
They can't see murders anymore?
Agatha, she's the key.
She's the one they listen to...
...the one with the most talent.
- She takes care of the other two.
- Jesus.
- Please bring her back.
- Every team underground, now!
- It doesn't matter. He wins.
- We'll stop him.
She's with him when he kills Crow.
She's already a part of his future.
Jad, put everything you've got into
finding that room, and we stop a murder.
- How much time have we got, Gordon?
- We've got...
...51 minutes, 30 seconds.
You cold? Can you understand me?
Are you cold? The shivers,
it's the drugs we gave you.
It should wear off soon.
I'm sorry. I need your help.
You contain information.
I need to know how to get at it.
Can you just tell me who Leo Crow is?
- Is it now?
- What?
Is it now?
Yes, this is all happening right now.
I'm taking you some place in public...
...which means you need
something else to wear.
I'm tired. I'm tired of the future.
Hello, Mr. Yakamoto,
welcome back to the Gap.
How'd those assorted tank tops
work out for you?
Mr. Yakamoto?
Miss Belfor, did you come back for
another pair of those chammy lace-ups?
- If it's ransom, where's the damn note?
- It has nothing to do with ransom.
It has to do with the information
inside of Agatha.
- He's trying to prove his innocence.
- He can't download her without support.
Your average consumer can't buy
any of this stuff.
It's been assembled and scrounged
from spare parts made to order.
Assuming Anderton ordered this,
who put it together?
Who's Rufus T. Riley?
What's your pleasure? We got it
all here: Sports fantasies...
..."Look, Ma, I can fly" fantasies...
...which covers everything from bungee
jumping to flying over the Grand Canyon.
You can experience sex as a woman.
Women come in to get laid
by their favorite soap star.
Or just some good, clean fun.
It's a big rush, but you come out
without a heart attack.
I wanna kill my boss.
Okay.
- You got some images I can work with?
- Rufus.
Yeah, being concertmaster
for the Philadelphia Symphony...
...is a popular choice.
- I wanna kill my boss.
- You sick bastard.
You make this a terrible world
to live in!
Detective, nice of you to come here,
seeing how every cop is looking for you.
- I need your help.
- Why'd you come here?
- I make house calls.
- I need your help with her.
Hello, honey pie.
I'm impressed. You're on the lam...
...and you still have the time to
slice off a little... jerky for yourself.
- She's a Pre-Cog.
- Oh, yeah, okay.
- That's right.
- She's a Pre-Cog.
You brought a Pre-Cog here.
Jesus Christ.
- Are you reading my mind right now?
- Get up.
I'm sorry for whatever I'm gonna do.
I swear I didn't do that stuff I did.
She has information inside her.
I need you to get it out.
No way. I wouldn't even know
where to begin.
Those thoughts about my cousin
were just thoughts.
- You've been busted for felony hacking.
- So?
So I need you to hack into her.
I do this, I get to keep
whatever images I get from her head.
- They don't belong to anybody.
- Take her to RadioShack.
You're gonna help me.
Agatha, I need to see. I need to see
what's gonna happen to me.
And then we'll go.
- She works.
- Slow it down.
How do I slow this down?
I should hit her on the head?
- Are you recording this?
- Shit.
Yeah, recording.
I know this already.
Come on. Move on.
Goodbye, Crow.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- I don't...
- Where's the rest of it?
- I guess that's all of it.
Where's my Minority Report?
Do I even have one?
- Do I have one?
- No.
- What?
What?
Agatha? What? What?
- Can you see?
- See what?
Anne Lively.
You want me to see who killed
Anne Lively. Are you recording this?
Yeah, but it's pouring
out of her backwards.
I like my life. Everything's good.
They're inside.
Who?
All your old teammates.
Kenny, left chamber.
Alan, straight across.
Negative!
- Negative!
I don't deserve that.
- You are the man.
- No, you're the man.
Can you see the umbrella?
Take it.
Take it!
A man in a blue suit.
He drops his briefcase.
You see a woman in a brown dress.
She knows your face.
Turn in here.
Let's go.
- Wait.
- No, we can't stop here.
Can you see the balloon man?
Wait.
- Wait.
- What are we waiting for?
Wait. Wait.
Wait.
- Please, Mommy, can I have one?
- All right.
Wait.
Thank you.
- Anybody got an ID? Anybody?
- Negative.
Scott, Ramos, take the east end.
Everyone else, follow me. Let's go.
He knows. Don't go home.
We've got eyes on.
They're working,
but they're standing on it.
Please! Please!
Have you got a quarter?
Drop some money.
Can't you put it in my hand?
May the Lord bless you.
May God take care of you.
Damn!
That's the guy.
The man in the window.
- Rooms are 95 a night.
- Mind if I look at the registry?
I mind.
How about now?
Help yourself.
He's here.
Anderton, leave.
You have a choice.
Walk away. Do it now.
I can't. I have to find out
what happened in my life.
Please.
Agatha, I'm not gonna kill the man.
I don't even know him.
- What room is Crow in?
- 1006.
Come on.
Wrong room.
Leave.
Oh, God.
This is Sean.
My son.
Every day for the last six years
I've thought about only two things:
The first is what my son would
look like if he were alive today...
...if I would recognize him
if I saw him on the street.
And the second is what I would do
to the man who took him.
You're right.
I'm not being set up.
You have to take me home.
You said so yourself.
There is no Minority Report.
I don't have an alternate future.
I am going to kill this man.
You still have a choice.
The others never saw their future.
- Leo Crow?
- Who the hell are you?
Six years ago, Baltimore...
...you grabbed a kid at Francis
public pool on the West End.
Did I? I don't remember
anything about that place.
Who am I? Who am I?
Do you know who I am?
- You're somebody's father.
- His name is Sean!
Sean!
I told him I was a policeman
and needed his help.
It wasn't so bad. I sang him a song.
I bought him a pretzel.
He was happy. He was happy.
Is he alive?
He's alive. Where have you got him?
Is he all right?
Tell me, you fuck, where is he?!
I put him in a barrel.
I sunk him in the bay.
He floated back up. I took him out.
I was gentle. I was gentle.
I was gentle.
I'm sorry.
I'm so very sorry.
How could you do that to my...?
You can choose.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say or do can be used
against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney...
...now and during any
further questioning.
If you can't afford an attorney...
...we will appoint one.
Do you understand these rights?
You're not gonna kill me?
- Do you understand these rights?
- You're not gonna kill me?
If you don't go through with this,
my family gets nothing.
You're supposed to kill me.
He said you would.
He? Who's he?
I don't know.
He called me in my cell.
He told me I'd be released if I went
along, and my family would be cared for.
If you did what?
If I acted like I killed your kid.
Okay?
If you killed my kid?
Look, you don't kill me,
my family gets nothing. Okay?
What about the pictures?
They're fake. He gave them to me.
Now, listen to me. You...
You tell me:
Who was it that set this up?
I don't know.
- Come on.
- I'm asking you again:
- Who put you up to this?
- I didn't see his face.
I tell you who,
and my family gets nothing.
- Who made you do this?
- Kill me.
- You can do this. Kill me.
- Tell me.
- Kill me.
- Leo, let go of the gun.
Let go of the gun. It's okay.
Let go of the gun. That's it.
Let go of the gun.
You're not gonna kill me.
- Goodbye, Crow.
- Anderton, wait a sec...!
- Did you see it?
- Stay back!
What's happening down there?
Murder!
Doesn't make sense.
If you were a child killer,
would you leave these photos out?
Anderton might have found them.
- What kind of cop were you before this?
- Treasury agent.
This will be your first murder scene?
I worked homicide before federal.
This is an orgy of evidence.
- Know how many orgies I had as a cop?
- How many?
None.
This was all arranged.
Today we saw the first murder in the
six years of the Precrime experiment.
Sadly enough, this failure was human.
The protection team
simply didn't get there in time.
But the murder itself happened exactly
as the Pre-Cogs predicted it would.
Today's event put a human face
on the Precrime system.
Danny Witwer's on the phone.
He says it's important.
Lamar?
- What?
- There's something wrong.
We're chasing the wrong man.
I don't wanna say over the phone.
Meet me at Anderton's.
We recovered that
from Leo Crow's hotel room.
I remember when I gave this
to him, back in Baltimore.
Please, sir.
Tell me what you have.
This is the murder of a woman
named Anne Lively.
John told me about this.
You got this from Containment?
Yes. This is from the twins,
Arthur and Dashiell.
Agatha's stream was missing.
This one is from the Cyber Parlor.
Anderton downloaded this directly
from Agatha. Rufus Riley recorded it.
- It's the same prevision.
- Not quite.
Look at the surface wind
across the water. Watch the ripples.
Moving away from shore.
Now the second image, the one from
Containment that Art and Dash saw.
Watch the water.
The wind's changed.
The ripples are moving the other way.
This murder's taking place
at two different times.
Anderton was watching this
right before he was tagged.
He told me about
the missing data stream.
- He was concerned you might find it.
- He was right. I did.
It was inside of Agatha.
So the question is, why would someone
want this erased from the data file?
Danny, just tell me
what you're thinking.
I'm thinking someone
got away with murder.
How?
Jad told me that sometimes the Pre-Cogs
see the same murder more than once.
- It's called an echo.
- Jad called it Pre-Cog déjà vu.
We teach the techs to identify
and disregard them.
Yeah, but what if a technician only
thought he was looking at an echo?
What if he was looking at a completely
different murder altogether?
I don't understand.
All you'd have to do is hire someone
to kill Anne Lively...
...like a drifter, a neuroin addict,
someone with nothing to lose.
Precrime stops the murder
from taking place...
...haloes the killer, takes him away.
But then, right then, someone else...
...having reviewed the prevision
and dressed in the same clothes...
...commits the murder
in exactly the same way.
Technician takes a look, thinks he's
looking at an echo, erases it.
It'd have to be someone with access
to the previsions in the first place.
Someone fairly high-up.
Do you know what I hear?
Nothing.
No footsteps up the stairs.
No hovercraft out the window.
No clickety-click of little spyders.
Do you know why?
Because right now,
the Pre-Cogs can't see a thing.
Can you see? It's beautiful.
- Where are we going?
- Someplace safe.
- Burgess.
- Lamar, it's Lara.
- Yes, Lara.
- You have to help him.
Is he there?
Is the Pre-Cog with him?
Keep them there. I'm on my way.
Please don't tell Danny Witwer.
I don't trust him.
I won't say a word.
You just don't let John leave,
all right?
He's no killer, Lamar.
I know.
It's cold.
Lara, this is Agatha.
You remember when I would read
Tom Sawyer to you and Sean?
He got so scared when Tom and Becky
were lost in the cave.
I gotta sit down.
I gotta figure this out.
They used Sean.
They wanted me to think
Crow killed him.
But he didn't.
He didn't.
Why would they set you up?
Because I found out about her.
About who?
- How could I not have seen this?
- Seen what?
Anne Lively.
Agatha.
Dr. Hineman once said,
"The dead don't die...
...they look on and help. "
Remember that, John.
Agatha.
Sean.
He's on the beach now...
...toe in the water.
He's asking you to come in with him.
He's been racing his mother
up and down the sand.
There's so much love in this house.
He's 10 years old.
He's surrounded by animals.
He wants to be a vet.
You keep a rabbit for him,
a bird and a fox.
He's in high school.
He likes to run, like his father.
He runs the two-mile
and the long relay.
He's 23.
He's at a university.
He makes love
to a pretty girl named Claire.
He asks her to be his wife.
He calls here and tells Lara,
who cries.
He still runs...
...across the university and
in the stadium, where John watches.
Oh, God. He's running so fast,
just like his daddy.
He sees his daddy.
He wants to run to him.
But he's only 6 years old,
and he can't do it.
And the other man is so fast.
There was so much love in this house.
I want him back so bad.
So did she.
Can't you see?
She just wanted her little girl back.
But it was too late.
Her little girl was already gone.
She's still alive.
She didn't die.
But she's not alive.
Agatha?
Just tell me...
...who killed your mother?
Who killed Anne Lively?
I'm sorry, John,
but you're gonna have to run again.
- What?
- Run!
I love you.
- It's okay.
- You'll be fine with them.
- No! No!
- Stay with me. Stay with me.
- John, no.
- Don't talk.
John Anderton.
By mandate of the D.C.
Precrime Division...
...I'm placing you under arrest for the
murders of Leo Crow and Danny Witwer.
That's it.
That's my girl.
I was so worried about you.
Did he hurt you?
I missed you so much.
It's okay. Wally's here.
Wally's here.
You're a part of my flock now, John.
Welcome.
It's actually kind of a rush.
They say you have visions...
...that your life flashes
before your eyes...
...that all your dreams come true.
This is all my fault.
There was nothing anyone could do.
I thought you might want
to have those.
I haven't worn this in years. I wanted
to make sure it fits before tonight.
You look great.
I knew he was having trouble
for some time, yet I did nothing.
- The guy from USA Today is here.
- Tell him not now.
- He just wanted a few minutes before...
- Not now!
- I thought you were retiring.
- Well, I was.
But this incident with John made me
realize the fragility of all this.
This is John's legacy
as much as it is my own.
Now I have an obligation
to protect that.
Lara, I know how difficult
this is for you.
But maybe you can find
some closure in the fact...
...that John finally found
the man who killed your son.
Who's Anne Lively?
- Who?
- Anne Lively.
John was talking about her
right before they took him.
I don't know who that is.
John said something about him being
set up because he found out about her.
- Well, we know why John was tagged.
- He also said Crow was a fake.
And Witwer? He was killed with
John's gun inside John's apartment.
Do you know the reason why
John came here to work for you?
- Sean.
- Yes.
He came here to work for you
because he thought...
...if he could just stop
that kind of thing from happening...
- I understand.
- No, I don't think you do.
Sir, they wanna start
the press conference in two minutes.
Lara...
...John was the best cop I ever knew...
...and, in some ways,
also the best man.
But the scars he carried around...
Well, I know he'd want us to honor
the good things we remember about him.
And I also know why he married you:
You're as stubborn as he is.
- Lamar...
- Do you know how to tie one of these?
Could you please give me a hand?
I'm all thumbs, as you see.
Listen, I'll tell you what I'll do.
First thing Monday,
I'll look over the Witwer evidence.
And I'll have Gideon
run the Containment files...
...see if anyone drowned a woman
by the name of...
What did you say her name was?
Anne Lively.
But I never said she drowned.
- Sir, the press conference is starting.
- I'll be right there.
We'll talk about this later.
Perhaps tomorrow,
I'll come by the cottage.
I'd like a word with my husband.
You're not authorized.
How did you get in here?
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, Lamar Burgess,
director of the new National Precrime.
On behalf of your staff,
we present you with this.
- Congratulations, sir.
- My God.
How did you get this?
I padded your expense account
for six months.
Revolvers like this one
were given to generals...
...at the end of the Civil War
by their troops.
The cylinders were loaded
with five gold-plated bullets...
...to symbolize the end
of the destruction and death...
...that had ripped the country apart
for five years.
Ladies and gentlemen,
with Precrime going national...
...maybe we can all look forward
to a time when none of us...
...will have to discharge
another firearm ever again.
Now enjoy yourselves.
Enjoy yourselves! That's an order.
Does this mean we can finally use
the lake house on weekends?
Hello.
Yes. Right away.
- Excuse me, so sorry.
- Excuse me.
- Sir?
- Yes.
Sir, you have an emergency call
on your private line.
Yes, this is Burgess.
Hello, Lamar. I just wanted
to congratulate you. You did it.
You created a world without murder.
Everyone wants your name on a hat.
Can you sign these?
All you had to do was kill someone
to do it.
A-room. Jad.
Jad, it's Lara. John needs a favor.
- What are you talking about?
- Agatha's mother, Anne Lively.
Just a junkie who had a kid once
and had to give her up, but surprise!
She cleaned herself up,
and she wanted her daughter back.
She wanted Agatha.
Jad, you getting this? It's from the
female only. No time or incident data.
It isn't the future.
It already happened.
And the problem was, without Agatha,
there was no Precrime.
She's the strongest of the three.
Without Agatha, you had nothing.
You wouldn't be where you are now,
standing there, signing autographs.
- What are you doing?
- What are you doing with that?
- What you up to, big man?
- Think before you send that.
Slow down.
Now you had to get rid of Anne Lively,
which presented a problem:
How can you kill her
without the Pre-Cogs seeing it?
Simple. Use a system
you control against her.
You hired someone to kill her, knowing
the Pre-Cogs would see that murder.
You lured Anne Lively
out to the lake...
... with the promise of reuniting her
with her daughter.
Where's my daughter?
Where?
Run!
When you were all alone,
you killed her yourself...
... in the same way the Pre-Cogs
predicted your John Doe would kill her.
You made the real murder
look like an echo...
... knowing the tech would do what
he was trained to do: Disregard it.
Anne Lively became
just another missing person.
So, what are you gonna do, Lamar?
What are you gonna do?
We got a Red Ball!
Think about the lives
that little girl has saved.
Think of all the lives she will save.
She could have saved Sean.
Don't you ever say his name!
You used the memory of my dead son
to set me up.
You knew that would
drive me to murder.
- What are you gonna do now, Lamar?
- How are you gonna...?
- Shut me up?
Forgive me, John.
Lamar.
It's over.
The question you have to ask is,
what are you gonna do now?
No doubt the Pre-Cogs have
already seen this.
No doubt.
You see the dilemma, don't you?
If you don't kill me, Pre-Cogs were
wrong and Precrime is over.
If you do kill me, you go away...
...but it proves the system works.
Pre-Cogs were right.
So, what are you gonna do now?
What's it worth?
Just one more murder.
You'll rot in hell with a halo, but
people will still believe in Precrime.
All you have to do is kill me,
like they said you would.
Except...
...you know your own future...
...which means you can change it
if you want to.
You still have a choice, Lamar.
Like I did.
Yes, I have a choice...
...and I made it.
Forgive me, John.
Forgive me.
Forgive me, my boy.
Lamar!
In 2054, the six-year Precrime
experiment was abandoned.
All prisoners were unconditionally
pardoned and released...
... although police departments
kept watch on many of them for years.
Agatha and the twins...
... were transferred
to an undisclosed location...
... a place where they could
find relief from their gifts...
live out their lives in peace.