While most of President
Eisenhower's advisors...
Today are ominous.
Washington...
If you have just tuned in
to this special bulletin,
Washington has confirmed
that, yesterday,
on the fourth
of October, 1957,
the Soviet Unión
successfully launched...
history's first
man-made satellite...
into space orbit
around the Earth.
The satellite which the Russians
have dubbed Sputnik...
is being hailed
as a milestone in history.
No one in our nation's capital
could deny that the satellite...
has ushered in a grim
new chapter in the Cold War.
And indeed,
a wave of national anxiety...
already seems
to be sweeping the country.
Still maintaining its speed
of 18,000 miles an hour,
completing an orbit of the Earth
every 96 minutes.
Doctor Wernher von Braun,
Chief Engineer of the Army
Ballistic Missile Agency,
expressed the hope
that the United States...
would soon be following
the Russians into space...
with our own
artificial satellite.
Doctor von Braun confirmed...
that there has still been
no actual sighting
of the Soviet satellite,
but the U.S. Expects
to be tracking it very soon.
We are told that Sputnik will be
visible to the naked eye...
about an hour after sunset
and an hour before dawn,
as it traverses the October sky
over the United States.
What the beeping signal means
we still don't know.
It may be nothing more...
# Warden threw a party
in the county jail #
Let's go, Roy Lee.
It's almost 9:00.
Sure are in a hurry
to get yourself killed.
No kiddin'. There are easier
ways to commit suicide, Homer.
Will you just step on it,
Roy Lee?
I am steppin' on it.
#Everybody
in the whole cell block #
# Was dancin'
to the jailhouse rock ##
Okay, Maguire,
Longstreet, Hickam.
Let's see what you got.
Hey, take it easy on my kid
brother. Make him look good,
all right?
Let's go! Hut!
Hut two!
I thought I told you
to take it easy on him.
I did take it easy on him.
Set!
I'm gonna run right over you,
you son of a bitch.
You hear me?
Hut one! Hut two!
Homer, you sure got guts,
but you gotta know
when to quit.
Okay, Miller!
You're up!
#Someday we'll all be blue #
# Well, that'll be the day
when you say good-bye #
Why should
the damn jocks be the only ones
gettin' scholarships?
They're also the only ones
that get the giris.
This burns my ass.
# That'll be the day
when I die ##
What do you boys think
about this?
Isn't that something?
Let 'em have outer space.
We got rock 'n' roll.
I'm with you. We got enough
to worry about down here.
Homer, your dad say anything
about the layoffs?
No.
- Have they pulled
any more pillars?
- Uh, he didn't say.
Does he talk at all?
Oh, yeah. He talks.
Damn it, Jake! Didn't
I tell you to put some men
to work on those roof bolts?
Was I talkin' to the wall?
I'm sorry, John.
We was just tryin' to get...
Make sure the hoot owl shift
sets those timbers by the vent!
Two more days on that block,
we're gonna be down to the bone.
I guess that's...
Jensen!
Get out of the way!
Jensen, look out!
Come on. Come on, Jensen.
Come on back.
Come on.
What happened?
Whole damn mountain
'bout fell on your head.
And John here...
he saved your life.
That's my dad.
I want you out of this mine.
Don't come back, you stupid
son of a bitch.
Didn't I tell you
to watch the roof, huh?
Now we could've all been killed
'cause you didn't have the sense
to look up!
That's my dad.
Homer.
Well, how'd it go?
Well, I told you. You spend
the summer shovelin' coal,
and you'll be playin'
linebacker next fall.
What's the matter, Homer?
Not cut out for mining coal?
Me neither.
Hey, let's get that mess
cleaned up!
Let's get some cribbin'
on that roof!
Buck up, Homer.
You're a Coalwood boy.
When you get down in the mine,
get that coal shovel
in your hand,
feel just as natural to you
as a tick on a dog.
And get that slate
off the loader!
It's
the radio signal transmitted
by the Soviet Sputnik.
Listen now for the sound
which forevermore separates
the old from the new.
That's it?
That's the Sputnik?
- That's Sputnik.
- Well, big deal.
Big deal?
What you fail to grasp...
is that the sound you're hearin'
is bein' transmitted...
by an object that is travelin'
at 18,000 miles per hour,
559 miles high,
a- a-a-and orbitin'the Earth
e- e-every nine...
Shut up!
Boys, not in my class!
Thank you, Quentin.
Now Quentin's right, y'all.
Sputnik is a milestone
in history.
Things'll never be
the same again.
What do you think
about that, Homer?
Well, yes, ma'am. Uh...
Cat got your tongue?
We were talkin'
about bein' in orbit,
hundreds of miles
away from the Earth.
You know anything
about that?
No, ma'am.
I got my eye on you, boy.
Now who can tell me
why Sputnik is so important?
We ought to just shoot
the damn thing down.
It's got one of them
little spy cameras in it.
It takes pictures of every one
of our missile bases.
This country'd better get on
the ball before it's too late.
All I know is this Sputnik
had better show up soon.
I'm gettin' a crick
in my neck.
All right. What you need to do
is take her to the movies.
Somethin'scary, like
Frankenstein Meets the Wolf Man.
Then you take your arm
and put it up round the back
of her chair, like so.
Now when it gets real scary,
and she ain't payin' attention
to nothin' but the movie,
you sort of let your arm sort
of slide on down her shoulder,
real nice and slow
and easy...
until...
Hey! Hey!
I see it!
Right there!
Where? Where?
You seein'things, Carl?
I see it.
Where do you see it?
It's right there.
Wow.
Son ofbitches
gonna be droppin'bombs
on us from up there.
Don't know why they'd drop
a bomb on this place.
Be a heck of a waste
of a bomb.
The first game against Welch...
that's the one that's
gonna draw the scouts.
Yeah. Welch knows it too.
They're gonna be coming
after us.
Well, y'all be careful, Jim.
Last year, those two boys from
Welch got their arms broken.
Well, they started it.
It don't matter much
who started it.
I don't call that football.
You don't worry about Jim.
Ain't nobody on the Welch team
that can catch him.
I wish the scouts could've seen
that first game with Bluefield.
I'm gonna build a rocket.
Like Sputnik.
Well, I'm not sayin' it's gonna
go up in space or anything,
but I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna build a rocket.
Well, just don't
blow yourself up.
More eggs, anybody?
Nice rocket, Homer.
How high do you think
it will fly?
Well, I got it packed with
the powder from 30 sky rockets.
Three, four miles.
You ready?
Yeah.
Ten, nine...
Eight, seven, six...
Should we get behind somethin'?
Wh-What happened?
My rocket blew up.
- Are you okay?
- I guess.
- My heart's poundin'.
I thought the mine blew up.
Oh, Homer.
I waited six months for
the company carpenter to get
around puttin' up that fence.
Didn't I tell you
not to blow yourself up?
Yes, ma'am.
Then let's not.
Elsie.
It's all right, Ms. Fields!
It's all right.
Dear Dr. Von Braun,
Six, five, four, three...
My name is Homer Hickam.
Two, one...
I'm 17 and I live in a small
mining town in West Virginia.
Ignition.
Liftoff. Liftoff.
I'm writing to offer
my condolences to you
and your team...
on your recent attempt
to launch the Vanguard rocket.
I also had a disastrous
occurrence during the launch
of my own small rocket.
Since here in Coalwood,
everyone's much more
interested...
in what's down below the earth
than what's above it,
there isn't a whole lot
of material to be found
on the subject of rocketry.
So I've been kind of stumbling
around in the dark.
#Don't you give me
no dirty look #
# Your father's hip
He knows what cooks #
#Just tell your hoodlum
friend outside #
# You ain't got time
to take a ride #
# Yakety yak
Don't talk back #
# Yakety yak, yakety yak ##
You can't be seen
with him, Homer.
He's a weirdo.
You go ahead,
but you can kiss
your social life good-bye.
Hi, Homer.
Hi.
I don't let anybody
copy my homework.
I don't wanna copy
your homework.
Um,
do you know anything
about rockets?
Of course I do.
Uh, you wanna come with me
over to the library?
No.
What do you wanna know
about rockets?
Everything.
Well, rocketry was actually
invented by the Chinese
as early as 1,000 A.D.
And, supposedly,
they were quite sophisticated.
Potassium chlorate and sulphur.
Uh, well,
what'd you use?
Uh, somethin' like that.
Hey, Quentin, this is great.
This is exactly... We have
everything we need in here.
Roy Lee,
drive me to my house.
We can use my basement.
Yeah, at least nobody'll
see us down there.
Go, go, go.
Come on.
You got a loose choke cable.
You hear that?
The butterfly valve
isn't closin' all the way.
Uh, last year I built
an internal combustion engine...
and entered it
in the science fair.
Yeah, well, you wouldn't happen
to have it on you, would you?
# Gonna find her #
# Yeah #
#I've been searchin'#
# Uh, I'm searchin'#
# Oh, yeah, searchin'#
#Every which way #
Ow!
# Oh, yeah #
I'm sorry.
#Searchin'#
#I'm searchin'#
You missed a spot.
#Searchin'every which way #
#But I'm like that... ##
This thing's startin'
to look like a rocket.
Listen to this.
"Weld the washer
to the base of the rocket body,
creating a combustion chamber
and nozzle."
We don't know how to weld.
Weld.
Homer,
your brother's in metal shop.
Maybe he could, uh...
- Do we really need
this nozzle thing?
- For cryin'out loud,
the nozzle's
the most important part.
It directs the flow
of the hot gases!
Hey, cool it, Quentin.
Man, talkin'about
your hot gases.
I don't think your father
would like you sneaking up in
the middle of the night in here.
And I know that he wouldn't
like me welding for you
on company time.
Well, what if I paid
the company for your time?
Homer, I can't.
I would lose my job.
I'm sorry.
Did you see Sputnik go over
the other night?
Nah.
'Cause it was beautiful.
I stood there and watched it
streak across the sky.
And anywhere in the worid,
someone could look up
and see exactly what I saw.
For once, it felt like Coalwood
was part of the outside worid.
Homer, believe me,
there are much worse places
than Coalwood in this worid.
Besides, this is just
a flying piece of steel.
You know, a rocket
took it up there, Mr. Bykovsky.
I don't know. L...
When I was workin'
on this rocket, I felt like,
I felt like I was,
like I was Wernher von Braun.
Let me see.
Homer,
it will be our secret.
Mr. Bykovsky did
a dang good job on this.
Yeah, well,
he used a washer for the weld.
Man, it looks just like it did
in the picture.
Prodigious.
When, uh,
when do we go?
Give me that.
Uh, Saturday...
What is this,
a weapon of some kind?
No, sir. It's a,
it's a rocket.
I don't allow dangerous devices
on school grounds.
Mr. Turner, I asked Homer
to bring that to school.
To show it in class.
You know, the boys are
thinkin' about enterin'
that county science fair.
Be careful, gentlemen.
I'm gonna have my eye on you.
Thank you, Mr. Turner.
That science fair is rigged.
All the judges are from Welch,
so only the kids from Welch
ever win.
And besides,
science fairs are for geeks.
No offense, Quentin.
Well, it's too bad
you feel that way.
You know, the winners go on
to the National Science Fair
in Indianapolis,
and colleges from all over the
country hand out scholarships.
It's great.
Have a good lunch, boys.
College scholarships
for winning a science fair?
Well, maybe
it's not for you.
W- W-Well,
what do you mean?
Homer, you got a great mind.
But science requires math,
which has never been one
of your favorite subjects.
Can't just dream your way
out of Coalwood, Homer.
Auk I.
Stroke of genius, Homer.
It won't fly unless somebody
lights the fuse.
What the hell is auk?
It's a bird that don't fly.
What, kind of like
a parakeet?
Ready?
Well, Youngstown's
always been fair, Otis,
But you're askin' me to lay off
damn near half the town.
The mine
is just not producin'...
the way it was
ten years ago, John.
We're payin'the same labor
for half the tonnage.
What if we were
to open up a new shaft?
That coal is down there, Otis.
You just, you just
let me go after it.
The Coalwood mine
is givin' out, Mr. Hickam.
Move!
Ten...
Nine, eight,
seven, six, five,
four, three, two...
Uh-oh.
Holy shit,
it's headed for the mine!
- I told you we didn't know
what we were doin'!
I told you!
Oh, no. Oh, no.
I don't believe this.
Go ahead.
God in heaven, I thought
it was a guided missile!
I thought the damn Russians
were attackin'us.
The boy's in trouble now.
So this is what you been up to
in the basement, huh?
Yes, sir.
Damn, Homer.
You could've killed somebody
with this idiot thing.
I know, sir.
I'm sorry. I was...
Well, Homer here
wants to be a rocket scientist.
Is that it, John?
He has no idea
what he wants to be.
But I know what he is.
He's a menace,
and he's a damn thief.
Dad...
And so is whoever
helped you.
Ike Bykovsky did this,
didn't he?
Don't you ever
let me catch you...
with these fool things
on company property again,
you understand me?
Yes, sir.
Then go home.
Yeah?
What's your tunnel number?
He called me a thief, Ma,
in front of everybody.
I mean, how could he do that?
He was dead wrong
callin' you that.
He'd never have done that
to Jim.
They could catch Jim
stickin' up the company store,
and Dad would probably laugh
and say, "That's my boy."
I know he's hard to understand
sometimes, Homer,
but you have to know
he loves you.
He loves the mine...
more than Jim even.
More than you.
You hush up.
What's it given him back?
Nothin' but a spot on his lung
the size of a damn quarter.
You don't know
what the mine gives me.
'cause you're still a boy.
But, by golly, you're gonna
find out soon enough.
I'm never goin' down there.
You better have a talk
with your son, Elsie,
'cause he's out of control.
Where's my rocket stuff?
Right where they belong.
Quentin, you know, that rocket
went up at least 100 feet.
More like 200.
God...
Man, will you cut it out,
Roy Lee?
Die, you son of a bitch.
Come on.
My turn now.
Hey, man. What's with you?
Man, we should be tryin'
to get in that science fair...
instead of sittin' around here
like a bunch of hillbillies.
I got some really
bad news for you, Homer.
We are a bunch of hillbillies.
Besides, um, didn't your dad
say no more rockets?
No. He said no more rockets
on company property.
Do you realize
how far we'd have to go
to get off company property?
Yeah. We have
to go to Snakeroot.
Snakeroot?
That's eight miles.
It's not that far.
I mean, we could walk
if we have to.
Oh, walk.
That's a fantastic idea.
Let's go! Come on!
Wake the hell up,
will ya, Homer?
I got about as much chance
of winnin' that science fair...
as you do winnin'
a football scholarship.
I know I'm gonna be
a miner.
I've known my entire life.
What the hell's so bad
about minin' coal?
Nothin', Roy Lee.
Coal minin's great.
That's why your stepdaddy's
the biggest drunk
in West Virginia.
I mean, come on, guys!
You know the mine'll kill ya.
Did you ever hear the story
about how O'Dell's dad died?
- Homer,
will you forget it, man?
- Shut up, Homer.
Apiece of slate
caught him right in the neck
and cut his head clear off.
Bitch! Come on!
O'Dell!
Get off of me!
Hey, fellas.
We're lookin' for U.S. 52.
Uh, fellas?
Uh, just, uh, stay left
at the fork. It's about another
five miles straight ahead.
Thanks.
You fellas see the way
she was lookin' at me?
Man, you all wanna
be coal miners,
you all go ahead
and be coal miners.
There. There.
God's honest truth, Homer,
what are the chances...
of a bunch of kids
from Coalwood...
actually winnin'
the National Science Fair?
A million to one, O'Dell.
That good?
Well, why didn't you say so?
Come on. Give me that.
Quentin.
What?
We hiked eight miles
for this?
Oh, it's great.
What should we call it?
How 'bout a slack dump?
What about "No Man's Land"?
Cape Coalwood.
I mean, it's perfect.
We could build a blockhouse
over there...
and, and a, and a,
and a launchpad.
And we could even build
a test stand!
Dear Dr. Von Braun,
our launch site,
which we've named Cape Coalwood,
is nearing completion.
Thanks to the generosity
oflocal businesses.
# Come on, baby #
#Let the good times roll #
# Come on, baby
Let the good time roll #
#Roll all night long ##
Inspired by our efforts,
everyone is anxious to help
by donating materials.
We've been fortunate to have
the support of our classmates.
And the whole community
here in Coalwood is behind us.
Hey, rocket boy.
Mars is that way.
But no one has been more
encouraging to our efforts
than my father.
No, the company doesn't have
any cement left over
for launchpads.
I just thought I'd ask.
Besides, I told you
no more rockets.
Uh, you said no more rockets
on company property.
And Olga
doesn't own Snakeroot.
So, you walk eight miles?
Yes, sir.
Well, tell me something,
Homer.
Uh, what exactly is
this Wernher von Braun...
and the rest of those Germans
accomplishin' anyway?
'Cause if you ask me,
it's nothin' but a stunt.
You think, you think catchin' up
to the Russians in space
is a stunt?
When the novelty wears off,
they're all gonna be
sent packin'.
Maybe then they'll have
to find themselves a real job.
Like minin' coal?
You listen here.
The coal we mine
makes steel, Homer.
And if steel fails,
this country fails.
If you had half a damn brain
in your head, you'd know that.
Well, who's down there now?
Hold on just a second.
Hey, listen here.
I had an engineer estimate
a new walkway.
They had some cement left over,
so it got caught in the rain...
it's probably ruined.
But if you wanna haul it out,
it's all yours.
Thanks, Dad.
I'll be down there
in a minute.
And Miss Riley wanted
to make sure you document
your results.
You will be graded
when she returns.
You have one hour.
Potassium chloride
has a potassium atom.
If we mix it with sugar
and add heat,
we'll get three parts oxygen,
two parts carbon dioxide,
along with some
other by-products.
In other words, lots
of good expanding gases.
It should make
an excellent propellant.
It smells like candy. Ooh!
Better get started.
All right, quick.
Get rid of it.
# Only you #
Mr. Bolden, have you seen
Mr. Bykovsky around?
He's not in the shop anymore.
Your dad sent him down
to the mine.
#For only you ##
He's takin' it out on you
because you helped me.
That's enough of that.
Your father is a fair man.
If he's strict,
it's because he has to be.
Besides, he did me a big favor,
transferring me from
the machine shop.
What are you talkin' about?
I can make twice
as much money down there
working the high coal.
You can?
I've got relatives in Europe
who've had hard time recovering
from the war.
They depend on me
for whatever I can provide.
So, believe me,
I can use the extra money.
I'm just sorry
I won't be able to weld
any more rockets for you.
That's for good luck.
May-Maybe you could teach me
how to weld.
Welding
is very difficult, Homer.
I could learn.
You don't give up,
do you?
I can't.
Come on, son.
Hi, Mr. Bolden.
Hey, Homer.
I heard you tellin' Ike...
you were gonna be shootin' off
another rocket up here today.
I, I thought that might
be somethin'we'd like to see.
Whoa!
Eight, seven,
six, five,
four, three...
Hey, look out!
Mr. Bolden!
Mr. Bolden,
are you okay?
I'm all right.
I'm sorry about that, sir.
Oh, that's all right.
That's all right.
Homer, I flew with the Red Tails
in Worid War II.
And seein' that rocket
come at me...
it almost
took me back there.
Hey, let me have
a look at that thing.
That's a good job
on the weld, Homer,
but the heat from the exhaust
melted the washer.
It's referred to
as a nozzle... uh, sir.
Son, you can call it
whatever you wanna call it,
but you're gonna have to have
a better steel that can take
the heat.
Now I'd say S.A.E. 10-20 bar
stock ought to do you fine.
And I can order it for you.
Well, that'd be great,
Mr. Bolden.
But it's kind of expensive.
Um...
Twelve miles of scrap iron,
and all we gotta do
is pop it loose.
Yeah. Now what are we gonna
tell the railroad when they
catch us pryin' up the track?
It's abandoned.
See, the county's covered
with abandoned spur lines.
A mine shuts down,
the track just rusts over.
$8.20.
This is worth eight twenty?
A ton.
Come on.
Go, go!
This thing weighs a ton
all by itself!
Four-hundred pounds.
Four-hundred pounds?
All right.
O'Dell, you're sayin' this thing
is worth a buck 65?
Woo-hoo!
Whoa.
O'Dell?
L- It's abandoned.
Uh, look at the rust.
Caretta number two
shut down in '51.
Shit!
Get it up! Get it up!
Just get it up!
Give me a hand, man.
Come on!
Forget it! Forget it!
Just stop the train!
Roy Lee!
Stop!
Stop! The track's out!
Stop it!
Stop!
The track!
# You made me cry #
# When you said good-bye #
#Ain't that a shame #
#My tears fell like rain #
S.A.E. 10-20 bar stock.
#Ain't that a shame #
Then go 30 degrees crucial.
When the fuel combusts,
i- it creates
a controlled explosión.
The nozzle directs
a, a, a river of hot gas...
tha-that can reach th-the speed
of sound when it hits
the mouth of the nozzle!
Hey, Quentin.
Sorry.
#Ain't that a shame #
#My tears fell like rain #
It's called a tapered bore.
A tapered bore.
Now he's takin' off
just a little bit at a time.
# You are to blame #
# Oh, well #
# Good-bye, although #
#I'll cry #
#Ain't that a shame #
#My tears fell like rain #
Good deed, good deed.
#Ain't that a shame #
# You're the one to blame #
I'm concerned that the mass
of the added propellant...
compared to the mass
of the empty rocket
will be too little.
Uh, he's afraid
it'll be too heavy.
Why don't we just
make it longer?
Longer would allow increased
volume for the propellant
without much additional mass.
Great idea.
# Well, you made me cry #
# When you said good-bye #
#Ain't that a shame #
#My tears fell like rain #
# You're the one to blame #
Yeah.
We got one!
# Oh, well #
# Good-bye #
#Although I'll try #
#Ain't that a shame #
#My tears fell like rain #
# You're the one to blame ##
My guess is, is we're gettin'
air pockets in the body
of the propellant.
When the fire hits 'em,
they act like little
combustion chambers.
I think we're gonna need
a liquid binder of some sort.
What about gasoline?
That's a good idea.
"Four unidentifiable
high school students...
Iost their lives
earlier this mornin'
when their toy rocket exploded."
Alcohol.
I mean, alcohol's stable.
And it'll evaporate quickly.
Yeah, but it'd have
to be 100% undiluted.
None of that watered-down stuff
they sell at the company store.
I have no idea
where we could find that.
Listen. I know these fellas,
so let me do all the talkin'.
I'm not gonna say a word.
#Now they often
call me Speedo #
#But my real name is Mr. Earl #
Is that rocket fuel or what?
#Now they often
call me Speedo #
#But my real name is Mr. Earl #
# Well, now some
may call me Joe #
#Some may call me Moe #
#Just remember Speedo
He don't ever take it slow #
# Well, now they often call me
Speedo #
# 'Cause I don't believe
in wastin'time ##
Great.
How'd they find out
about it?
My brother.
You know, we poop out this time,
the whole county's gonna be
laughin' at us.
Who cares
what any of them think?
Easy for you to say, Quentin.
You're used to people
makin' fun of you.
All right now.
Quentin's right, y'all.
Homer, you don't have to prove
anything to anybody.
You remember that.
Now go launch yourself
a rocket.
Come on, boy.
Homer!
Hello, Dorothy.
Is that thing
really gonna fly?
Well, it, uh...
That thing had better fly,
or you can kiss your chances of
losin' your virginity good-bye.
Hey, couldn't you guys
find somethin' better to do?
Hey, listen. There's
no practice on Saturdays.
You little sisters
are the only entertainment
in town.
Yeah, we were gonna
drive over to War,
but then we thought,
hey, let's go see Homer
blow himself up.
That's real funny, Jim.
Hey, Homer. Come on.
We don't got all day.
Shut up, Jim.
Homer, everything ready?
Wait, wait.
What?
What do you mean, wait?
Where are you goin'?
Hurry up, y'all.
All right. It won't fly unless
somebody pulls the string.
Ten...
Nine, eight,
seven, six,
five, four...
Oh, my God!
That's great!
Homer,
that was unbelievable!
Let's go, Dorothy.
I'll tell you
what's unbelievable...
the captain of the football team
bein' jealous of you.
What you think about gettin'
in that science fair now?
I think we got a chance.
Well, bless her heart.
Aunt Joanne hasn't seen you
in about a year and a half.
You look like a sausage.
- He does not.
Happy birthday, Homer.
It'll stretch some
when you wear it.
You be sure and send her
a nice thank you note now.
All right.
John?
Huh?
Oh, happy birthday, Homer.
And I got this in the mail.
Must be a present
from Grandma.
What's this?
Oh, it's
an autographed picture.
Of Grandma?
Rather get socks.
Wernher von Braun.
Well, wonder how he knew
it was your birthday.
I don't reckon he did.
"Dear Homer, congratulations
on your rocket building.
Continue your education
and maybe one day..."
Boy, you better take an interest
in your own damn town.
Instead of wastin'your time,
worryin'about Wernher von Braun
and, uh, uh, Cape Canaveral.
John, it's his birthday.
All right, Homer. Uh...
Yeah?
Homer, there's strike talk
startin' up again.
Your father's...
Yeah, he's got a lot
on his mind.
Yeah, well,
I don't give a damn.
"Principles
of Guided Missile Design."
I had
Miss Waters order it for you
a while back, and it just came.
I know the math
is too advanced for you.
It is for me too.
There's calculus,
differential equations...
No, I'll learn the math.
This is great, Miss Riley.
I'll learn everything.
It's the best present
that anyone's ever given me.
Thank you.
I'm gonna show the guys.
Well, Quentin
will probably go cra...
Goodness gracious, Hickam.
Watch where you're goin'.
Just...
- Where'd you get this?
- I gave it to him.
Bye, Miss Riley.
Miss Riley, our job is to give
these kids an education,
not false hopes.
False hopes?
Do you want me to sit quiet,
let 'em breathe in coal dust
the rest of their life?
Miss Riley, once in a while,
a lucky one will get out
on a football scholarship.
The rest of'em
work in the mines.
How about I believe
in the unlucky ones, hmm?
I have to, Mr. Turner,
or I'd go out of my mind.
It's good, it's good.
Hey, Homer.
Happy birthday, son.
Got some good news
for you, Homer.
Say hello to Fred Smith from
the University of West Virginia.
Hello, Homer.
Hi, sir.
Mr. Smith wants Jim to play
football there. He's offerin'
him a full scholarship.
Well, congratulations, Jim.
Do you play ball, son?
No, Homer shoots off rockets.
Whoosh and all that st...
Well, rockets
are not exactly my field, son,
but maybe if you work hard,
you'll go to college too.
Yeah, on a science fiction
scholarship, maybe.
Jim.
Dear Dr. Von Braun,
thank you
for the autographed picture.
It will only further inspire me
to keep working...
toward our all-important goal
of entering that science fair
this spring.
We're shootin' off
a rocket today.
I th-thought you'd like
to come see it.
I gotta catch up
on some work.
Ho-How come,
how come you never have work
when Jim plays football?
You never miss a game.
What time
are you gonna do it?
About 4:00.
Uh, I can't promise you...
Somebody pulled a pillar
too close.
Yeah?
Well, thank God for that.
Yeah, right now.
Nobody hurt.
# Go, Rocket Boys ##
Ten!
Nine, eight, seven,
six, five,
four, three, two,
one, liftoff!
You got it?
Can you see?
Uh, no. Yes.
See it?
Yeah, I see it.
What's the time?
Looks like 12 seconds.
Which one of you fellas
is Homer Hickam?
Um, it's me, sir.
I'm Basil Thorpe
with the Bluefield Telegraph.
Can I ask you
a few questions?
Sure.
"The silvery cylinder
burst forth in a fiery column
of smoke and flame,
"racing the very wind
as it soared into the sky,
"a messenger of these
Rocket Boys of Big Creek...
"these boys who use
their brains, not brawn,
who play not football,
but with Apollo's fire."
Hi, Homer.
Hi, Dorothy.
Would you please sign
my newspaper?
Sure.
I just know you're gonna be
really famous someday.
H-O-M-E-R.
Which one of you fellas
is Homer Hickam?
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Which cost the taxpayers...
What in the worid
is goin' on?
Miss Riley,
this does not concern you.
You have these boys
in handcuffs.
in handcuffs in a high school,
Mr. Turner.
You probably heard
about the forest fire last week
over by Welch.
A lot of timber went up.
Mr. Turner, you take
these handcuffs off these boys.
They found a rocket
on the side of the road.
We knew it started the fire,
ma'am. What we didn't know
is where it came from,
till this morning.
Mr. Hickam, can you account
for all your rockets?
No, sir. I can't.
If you weren't a minor,
you'd be in the state penitentiary.
I know, Dad. L...
Homer, I've been
confused by you,
I've been mad as hell
at you.
But, boy, it's the first time
in your life I've been ashamed
of you.
You couldn't stop, man.
You couldn't!
Get in the car, Homer!
Homer, get in the car.
Idiot! I ought
to goddamn kill ya.
We ain't at the mine now.
This ain't your business.
You get in the car
with Homer, son.
You listen to me,
you drunken son of a bitch.
If that boy's father was alive,
he'd kick your ass.
So I'm gonna
have to do it for him.
If I see him with a bruise,
you get a scar.
If I see him with a limp,
you get crutches!
You hear me?
Do you hear me?
You know,
I'm reportin' you to the unión!
Screw you
and your damn unión.
Your father was
one of the best men
I ever had workin' for me.
I was lucky to know him.
Come on.
Let's go have some fun
for a change.
#In love #
# Why does my heart #
#Skip a crazy beat #
#For I know
it will beat, beat, beat #
# Tell me why #
They watched us get arrested.
We're practically ex-convicts.
They'll never dance with us.
Jesus, Quentin.
You don't know anything
about women.
# Why do fools #
I heard she broke up
with that dumb jock.
#Fall in love ##
See you later, hopeless.
#Many a tear has to fall #
#But it's all in the game #
#All in the wonderful game #
# That we know #
#As love #
Hi, Homer.
Hi, Dorothy.
- # You have words #
- Jim, look who's here.
Yeah, ain't it past
your bedtime?
#And your future's looking #
Let's go.
Hey, Jim.
#Dim #
#But these things #
Way to go.
# Your hearts can rise #
#Above #
# Once in a while
he will call ##
# When the twilight is gone #
#Ah, ah #
Hi, Valentine.
#Ah #
I'm glad you didn't
go to jail.
# When the twilight is gone #
#Ah, ah #
# You come into my heart #
#Ah #
#And here in my heart
you will stay #
It sure was exciting
watching your rockets
go up.
#My prayer #
#Is to linger with you #
#At the end of the day ##
You ever see that movie,
Frankenstein Meets
the Wolf Man?
Homer!
Down here!
Homer! Homer!
What is it?
Mom! Mom!
Mom?
Your father always has to be
the big hero.
I swear to God,
if he gets killed,
I won't shed a tear.
It's comin' up!
Who-Who is it?
It's Ike Bykovsky.
Bykovsky.
It's John Hickam!
Dad, Dad!
The cable snapped.
May have fractured
his skull!
Get out of the way.
Move back, folks!
Let us through here!
Tell you what, Homer.
A dozen men would've died today
if it hadn't been for your dad.
Thank you, doctor.
Mm-hmm. Bye-Bye.
The, uh, doctor
says...
there's a chance your dad
could lose his eye.
He has to go to the hospital
in Charleston,
and Olga won't pay
for all of it.
I'm gonna go down to the mine
and ask Jake Mosby
to sign me on.
You can't do that, Jim.
You've got school.
Olga owns this house, Mom,
and half the furniture in it.
If you drop out,
you'll lose your scholarship.
- Homer, I'm the oldest.
It's my responsibility.
- I'll work in the mine.
Here you are,
Mr. Turner.
Thank you, Miss Wade.
Mining coal
is an honorable trade,
Mr. Hickam.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
Miss Riley!
Turn your light on, boy.
Remember when you
gave me these, John?
Carbon crystals
from the mine.
Yeah. Honeymoon.
At Myrtle Beach.
And you said,
"You always wanted diamonds.
But these are
the best I can do.
I wish they were real."
John, I never
wanted diamonds.
This whole year...
has been pretty rough going
down at the mine.
Bad tempers...
and a lot of strike talk.
An accident
makes things worse.
In a way, I guess,
I'm the one who's responsible
for what happened
to Mr. Bykovsky.
Listen to me, Homer.
Last month,
I gave Ike the chance
to go back to the machine shop,
and he turned it down.
Yeah, he stayed in the mine
'cause the money was better.
That was his decisión.
You understand me?
Yes, sir.
Well, is mining coal as terrible
as you figured it'd be?
I guess not.
But almost.
Everybody says to say hi.
Michael and Billy.
Valentine Carmina.
How about Miss Riley?
She ain't been around much.
She got some new boyfriend
over in Welch.
So, uh, what's it like
down there?
You get used to it
after a while.
Besides, shoveling coal
has got its advantages.
Check this out.
Man, no wonder my stepdad
can slug me so good.
After a month down there,
you'd be able
to knock him out.
Well, I ain't
in no hurry.
See ya all later.
See ya, man.
See ya, Homer.
In Christ's name,
we pray. Amen.
Amen.
We appreciate the sacrifice
you made here, Homer.
But pretty soon,
you'll be able to go back
and finish up the school year.
I'm not going back
to school.
A few weeks left in the term,
I'll just stay put.
Well, I think you ought
to finish high school.
Well, tell him, John.
Homer's not a boy anymore.
I don't think
I can tell him anything.
All I'm saying, John,
is the cutoff was not done
proper according to contract.
Well, the company did
what it had to do.
Well, you know the unión
won't put up with it.
Just give it a rest, Jake.
It's my first day back.
Hey, Lenny,
how's he doing?
He's a chip
off the old block, John.
It's good
to have you back.
Thank you.
Hi.
I'm headed toward the face.
You wanna come along?
Even though I don't have
that piece of paper...
the thing from college...
they listen to me.
You know why?
'Cause you know more
than they do.
You bet your life
I do. Homer.
I know the mine
like I know a man.
Heck, I can take
one look around here...
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm not afraid
of a little coal dust.
Hell, Homer,
I was born for this.
I guess
it shouldn't surprise me
that you were too.
Let's go watch 'em
shoot some coal.
Elsie, hold dinner
for a while, will you?
I have to make a call.
Homer,
I was in the store today,
and I heard some talk.
Boy, it's sure hard
to keep a secret in this town,
isn't it?
But I guess I did
a pretty good job.
You know, there's a rumor going
around that I been sneaking off
to Welch to see some beau.
I wish that rumor'd
been true.
Yeah.
They told me Hodgkin's
can go into remissión,
so I might have some time.
Is there anything I can do,
Miss Riley?
You can accept
my apology.
For what?
My life's work
is teaching.
And I believed
that if you boys won
that science fair,
got scholarships, went off
and did something great
with your lives,
somehow my life
would have counted
for something.
Homer.
You know what?
Sometimes you really
can't listen to what
anybody else says.
You just gotta
listen inside.
You're not supposed to
end up in those mines.
You know why?
'Cause I think
you made other plans.
I want you
to know something.
I'm proud of you.
I am.
Whatever you choose.
Excuse me, ma'am,
is Quentin home?
Quentin.
Homer, y-you figured
this equation out
by yourself?
Well, if I did the math right.
It proves that you can't...
l- It proves we didn't
start that fire!
Quentin, what're you doin'?
Now, the AUKXIII was
the only one that we couldn't
find that day.
And our best guess
for fall time
with the AUKXII,
which is exactly identical,
was about 14 seconds.
If you help me
with the trig part,
Quentin,
we should be able
to make a good guess
where that rocket landed.
Six thousand,
three hundred
and twenty-eight feet.
One point two miles.
Homer?
Yeah?
Are you gonna tell
Roy Lee and O'Dell
where I live?
It wouldn't matter
if you lived
in the governor's mansión,
they'd still think
you're weird.
I'll see you at dawn.
Don't you have to go
to the mine?
I don't work there
anymore.
One.
Two.
Ninety-nine.
A hundred seven.
One hundred
and twenty-six.
That's 6,300 feet.
It's gotta be
around here somewhere.
What'd we do wrong?
I don't know.
L- I'll check the math again.
Was there a wind
that day?
L- I don't remember.
'Cause if there was,
the wind probably came
from the west...
which means that
it would've pushed
the rocket...
right there.
Prodigious.
...associated...
Mr. Hayes,
where you off to
in such a hurry?
Okay, everybody,
back in your seats.
Miss Stanton, Miss Blue,
let's go, back in your seats.
Mr. Hancock.
That goes for you too,
Mr. Wilson.
Miss Riley,
what's going on in here?
They didn't start
that fire, Mr. Turner.
In the first place,
you are not a member
of this classroom.
Neither are you,
Mr. Turner.
Why don't you let the boy
defend himself?
And in the second place,
this rocket proves nothing.
You've already admitted
having lost a number
of your rockets.
You cannot prove
conclusively...
that another one of them
didn't start that fire.
Yes, I can.
Are we to conclude,
Mr. Hickam, that
since leaving school,
you've not only become an expert
in rocket science, but in
the field of trigonometry?
I didn't say
that I was a rock...
Obviously, you learned more...
in the coal mines
than you did in high school.
Let the boy talk.
Go ahead, Homer.
Now, that fire was near Welch,
just under three miles
from our launchpad.
And at the time of the fire,
the best that we could do
was 1.2 miles...
which is exactly where we found
that rocket, Mr. Turner.
See, Mr. Turner, that rocket
fell for about 14 seconds,
which means...
that it flew to an altitude
of 3,000 feet...
according to the equation...
"S" equals one-half"A"
"T" squared...
where "S"is the altitude,
"A"is the gravity constant...
or 32...
and "T" is the time
it took for that rocket
to come back down.
Velocity equals
acceleration times time.
Get him, Homer, get him.
Are you following this,
Mr. Turner?
All right,
we're all duly impressed.
But do you mind telling me,
if you did not start that fire,
who did?
What is it?
Whatever it is,
i- it's ingenious.
The fins are spring-loaded.
That isn't a rocket
at all.
It's an aeronautical flare.
There's an airport here
in Welch. It's right above
where the fire started.
Mr. Hickam,
report to my office as soon
as we return to school.
You do intend to enter
the county science fair,
do you not?
Yes, sir, we do.
Well, if you intend
to represent Big Creek,
you're gonna have to be
enrolled as a student
at Big Creek.
"Prodigenous."
Do you think
you can draw well enough
so Mr. Bolden could build it?
Yep.
Let me see.
Yeah.
Hey, Homer.
- Hi, Dad.
- What's this stuff doin' here?
Mr. Hickam, we didn't
start the fire.
The troopers gave it back to us.
Yeah, it wasn't even
one of our rockets.
It was an aeronautical flare.
Y'all go on home now.
Yes, sir.
This the reason
you skipped work today?
Yes, sir.
I thought you put
all this nonsense
behind you, Homer.
I thought you weren't
gonna be doin' it...
Dad, it isn't nonsense.
L- I don't wanna
argue with you.
Look, son,
I can't even begin to tell you
how proud of you I've been
these past weeks.
I mean, you've just been
doin' a hell of a job
in that mine.
You keep goin',
you're gonna have
my job someday.
Everybody says so.
You got any idea how proud
that would make me?
Dad, what l...
I guess what I'm sayin' is,
is that if this rocket stuff
is so important to you,
then so be it,
as long as you're careful.
Guess there's worse hobbies
you could have.
But skippin'work,
that's out ofline.
And you gotta know that.
So let's go
and get you right
with Jake.
Tell him you'll work
the hoot owl shift tonight.
No.
The coal mine's your life.
It's not mine.
I'm never going
down there again.
I wanna go into space.
Homer Hickam, Roy Lee Cook,
Quentin Wilson...
and Sherman O'Dell
of Big Creek High...
for their ingenious display
of amateur rocket-building
techniques.
I can't believe
we beat the kid
with the robot dog.
And I thought
the see-through ear
was gonna win.
I got Miss Wade workin'
on your travel arrangements,
so you boys are gonna
have to decide who's goin'
to Indianapolis.
We're all goin'.
Yeah.
Son, I wish you could,
but we can't afford
to send all four of you.
Only one. Let me know
what you decide. I'm gonna
have to know by Friday.
You boys did
a fine job today.
I need to borrow a suitcase,
and I'm gonna need
you guys' addresses...
because I'm gonna
write some postcards.
Oh, you shut up, Roy Lee.
Come on, you dope.
You know, you're goin',
Homer.
Yeah.
Say hello
to the outside worid
for us.
Do we know
what we want?
Yeah!
Are we gettin' it?
No!
All right!
All in favor of goin' out
on strike, say "aye"!
Aye!
All right, let's go!
All right, shut 'em down!
Let's go!
Strike! Strike!
Strike!
Well, they sure are
gettin' themselves
worked up.
Everybody's sayin'
this one's gonna be
a long one.
And it will,
if I have anything
to say about it.
Ungrateful
sons of bitches.
Mom, have you seen
the big green suitcase?
Did you look in the attic?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, I don't know. John,
you know where the suitcase is?
How the hell should I know
where the suitcase is?
I don't know, sug.
- John!
- Y'all stay inside!
Vernon!
I'm gonna kill
that son of a bitch!
Oh, don't be
a damn fool.
All right, well,
what are we gonna do?
Nothin'.
Drunken bastard couldn't hit
the broad side of a barn.
He tried to kill you, Dad.
Yeah, Dad,
you can't just stand...
Hey, hey, don't
trouble yourself, Homer.
You got
more important things
to worry about.
Just go look
for your suitcase.
Forget about it, Homer.
Shut up, Jim!
Listen, I'm sorry about
what's goin' on around here,
but it isn't my fault!
What do you want
from me anyway?
Better watch yourself, Homer!
If I win at Indianapolis,
maybe I can go to college,
maybe even get a job
at Cape Canaveral!
There's nothing here for me!
The town is dyin'!
The mine is dyin'!
Everybody knows it here
but you!
You wanna get out of here
so bad, then go! Go!
Yeah, I'll go!
Go, go!
I'll go!
And I'll be gone forever!
I won't even look back!
Welcome to Indianapolis!
Visitors to the fair
will include prominent members
of every branch...
of the national
scientific community.
The fair will be open
to the public
over the next two days.
The following day,
the judges will arrive
to select the winners.
By timing the rocket's descent,
we would be able to figure out
just how high the rocket flew.
Would you like to see?
This is a Delaval nozzle.
Do any of y'all know
what a Delaval noz...
Two, please.
The judges always go
for the most expensive exhibits.
That guy with
the biosphere's gonna win.
I don't think so.
My money's on the kid
with the rocket display.
Have you seen it yet?
It's really cool.
Mr. Owens,
to the security office.
to the security office, please.
It's not like we got a hell
of a lot of time, Roy Lee.
The judging is tomorrow.
There's nothin' we can do
without Mr. Bolden.
And he can't get anywhere
near the machine shop.
They even took my picture
of Dr. Von Braun.
They stole everything.
Leon, what are you doing
back here?
You know you shouldn't
be seen back here.
I know, Elsie,
but Homer's in trouble.
Elsie, I don't have the power
to settle this strike.
The bosses listen to you.
They'll do what you tell 'em.
I am not gonna crawl
on my belly...
in front of those
miserable unión rats.
Is that what this
is about, John?
Is this about your pride?
No, it's about what's best
for Coalwood.
If this mine
doesn't produce,
then the town dies.
Think the unión gives
a good damn about that?
They're nothin'
but a bunch of greedy
sons of bitches that...
Shut up, John.
Just shut up.
Homer once said
you love the mine more
than your own family.
And I took up for you
'cause I didn't wanna
believe it.
Homer has gotten a lot of help
from the people in this town.
They've helped him build
his rockets, they've gone out
there and watched him fly 'em.
But not you, John.
You never showed up.
Not even once.
Now, I'm not asking you
to believe in him,
but he's your son,
for God's sake, John.
And I am askin' you
to help him.
If you don't,
I'll leave you.
I'll find work.
I'll do whatever it takes
to get away from here.
I'll live in a tree
to get away from you.
Don't you think I won't.
Where would you go?
Myrtle Beach.
I guess we all know
this isn't gonna fix things,
uh, at least not for long.
We know you did
what you could for us.
Jake.
Thanks.
Leon.
Yes, John.
Don't you have
some work to do?
It's packed and shipped
and on its way. Be at
the bus station, 8:00 a.m.
Okay, Mom,
but how'd you...
Your father, Homer.
It was your father.
Give 'em hell, Homer!
- Good luck, sweetie.
- Bye.
Thanks, Dad.
When
the rocket propellant burns,
it produces a river of gas...
which flows through
the convergent section
of the nozzle.
If the river continues
through the nozzle,
but through the throat
at less than sonic speed...
that is to say, less than
the speed of sound...
it becomes compact in the...
compacted in the divergent
section,
bound in turmoil
and inefficient.
Lyle Wells and Jean Cooper,
Schrader High School,
McMinnville, Oregon.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
the big moment.
The Highest Scholastic
Achievement Award
for Science.
The National Science Fair
first prize gold medal...
goes to Homer Hickam,
Quentin Wilson, Roy Lee Cook
and Sherman O'Dell,
Big Creek High School,
McDowell County, West Virginia.
Tom Webster of Virginia State
College. I wanna talk to you
about a scholarship.
Jack Palmer, Virginia Tech.
We got the best science program
in the state, buddy, okay?
Congratulations, son.
Good luck to you.
What did he say to you?
What did who say?
Von Braun.
That was Wernher von Braun.
You just shook his hand.
Oh, Homer,
I'm so proud of you.
Thanks, Mom.
He's not here, hon.
Where's Miss Riley?
Hello, Miss Riley.
Hi, Homer.
Hi.
Oh!
You did it!
I knew you would.
The Rocket Boys
are goin' to college.
We all got scholarships.
And you know what?
From now on,
every school year,
I'm gonna brag
to all my new students...
about how I taught
Homer Hickam
and the Rocket Boys.
Maybe one day,
one of them'll feel
like they can do
what y'all did.
You know, just,
stuff like that
takes time.
Will you let me out?
What are they doin',
charging Olga for that.
Hell, I'm going to salvage
something up here?
Hey, Dad. Hi.
Hello, Homer.
I just wanted to tell you
how much I appreciate
what you did for me.
I know it wasn't easy for you,
so thank you.
A- And we're shootin' off
our last rocket today at 5:00,
so if you'd like to come
see it...
I got a lot of work to do.
All right. Well,
I just thought I'd ask.
Hear you met
your big hero.
Didn't even know it.
Look,
I know you and me
don't exactly see eye to eye
on certain things.
I mean,
we don't see eye to eye
on just about anything.
But Dad, I come to believe
that I got it in me to be
somebody in this worid.
A- And it's not because
I'm so different
from you either.
It's 'cause
I'm the same.
You know, I can be
just as hardheaded
and just as tough.
I only hope I can be
as good a man as you are.
I mean, sure,
Dr. Von Braun's
a great scientist,
but he isn't my hero.
It's our last rocket.
Yeah, let's do it.
Wire it up for me, will ya?
I gotta do something.
Yeah.
Hi, Homer.
Hi.
Congratulations
on winning
the science fair.
It's gotta be the most
exciting thing that's ever
happened around here.
Um, I was thinking,
Homer, if, if you've
got some time...
Excuse me, Dorothy.
Hi.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Hey, everybody, can we have
your attention, please?
Come on, Homer,
let her fly!
We're gonna launch the rocket
in a minute, but we'd like
to say thank you first.
If it wasn't for y'all,
we'd never have gotten
into any science fair.
We'd probably never have
gotten past blowin' up
my mom's fence.
But we did...
because of your help
and support.
And this is for Coalwood.
There are a few people
who believed in us
even before we did.
We'd like to dedicate
this rocket to them.
To Ike Bykovsky.
To Mr. Bolden,
who helped us so much.
To the person
who first inspired us,
our teacher, Miss Riley.
And, finally, I'd like
to dedicate this rocket
to my mom and to...
my dad.
You know, it, uh, won't fly
unless somebody pushes
the button.
It's yours,
if you want it.
Ten, nine...
Eight,
seven, six, five,
four, three, two, one.
Look at it go, Homer.
This one's gonna go for miles.
#Many a tear
has to fall #
#But it's all #
#In the game #
#All in the wonderful game #
# That we know #
#As love #
# You have words #
# With him #
#And your future's #
#Looking dim #
#But these things #
# Your hearts can rise #
#Above #
# Once in a while
you will call #
#But it's all #
#In the game #
#Soon he'll be there
at your side #
# With a sweet #
#Bouquet #
#And he'll kiss #
# Your lips #
#And caress #
# Your waiting fingertips #
#And your hearts #
# Will fly #
#Away #
#Soon he'll be there
at your side #
# With a sweet #
#Bouquet #
# Then he'll kiss #
# Your lips #
#And caress #
# Your waiting fingertips #
#And your hearts #
# Will fly #
#Away ##