Fabinho, look who
came to play with us.
Maggie. Where's Maggie?
-Little  Maggie
-Little Maggie.
Come, now you will
see the greatest champion.
Come see. Come see.
The greatest Olympic champion.
Let's go to the pool.
Come to the pool.
Go.
Oh, the animal's going to drown, Ok?
I want to see if you'll
save him. Come on.
Oh, poor thing.
-It's cold.
It's cold? what are
you talking about?
Stop being a pussy, boy.
It's hot. Let's go.
-Will you watch me?
-I'm watching!
-Swim with me!
-Me? Swim?
I don't have a
bathing suit to swim.
-Look!
-I'm looking!
I see you very well.
Convince her.
Tell her mommy misses her.
Oh, my love.
Oh, mom's precious thing.
Are you doing everything
you're supposed to?
Are you obeying Sandra?
Alright.
Don't talk like that.
Talk straight with your mom.
I only called to give you a kiss.
Ok, go.
Go.
Listen, I love you. Hear me?
Bye.
Who did you say that you love?
My daughter.
Where is she?
Oh, she's very far away.
And my mom? Where is she?
You're mom is working, love.
What time is she coming back?
I don't know.
Oh, my gosh.
The Second Mother
Fabinho?
Fabinho..
Go away, go away.
You're going to wake them up.
I'm getting some ice,
because this juice is too hot.
There had to be another one here.
I can't believe something like this.
How is it that someone
takes away the ice
and puts the tray
back in the freezer, empty?
They have to be very bad.
This upsets me.
And take into account I
am a free spirited person...
very nice.
But when I see
It's a bad person who
does that kind of thing.
You know?
Val?
Remember that girl Bruna
I told you about from school?
Cute.
Here.
She dumped me with two
messages. Again.
-There are stupid women
in this world, huh?
Will I die a virgin?
Who's stupid idea is that?
That Bruna.
A handsome guy like you.
Look, There is no boy like
you in Brazil.
A handsome boy
with those big blue eyes.
You look like the prince of England.
What's the youngest one's name?
Dr. Carlos,
It's already eleven, you know?
Won't you stop with
the renovations, Tony?
I'm not going to give
you lunch, you hear me?
Oh, my goodness val.
Does that man eat?
take away that dropping
from him, then he will work.
At home he's a saint.
He goes to school and he looks
like the devil's
inside his body.
I don't know. He bites the kids,
Now, he hasn't been
shitting for five days.
You only give him Mucilon,
Mucilon, Mucillon
You can't give him only Mucilon.
You have to give him a fruit, a food.
Poor thing, when he
comes at night, he eats
what he likes, makes him happy.
What he likes...
A child doesn't get to want something,
You spoil him too much.
It's easy for you to say,
it's hard to raise a kid on your own.
At night,
I want to see his face, laughing.
I'm sorry.
-Are you done?
-I'm done, thank you.
Would you like anything else?
I'd like another Guaraná, please.
You don't want anything else?
-No, thank you.
-My food wasn't good
at all, you didn't eat anything.
Didn't eat anything.
It was...No, it was Guaraná.
Guaraná.
Are you going to take
the medicine with sugar?
$250 Reais to get prescription..
..for some creams.
-For the love of God.
-I don't know why you have a dog.
-Security,
What? Security? A slow dog like that.
-Can I eat another one?
A thief comes and she'll lick
him and will leave wagging her tail.
-Only one?
Put more onions here.
-He wants two steaks.
-Of course.
I don't eat this salad. I
don't eat purple things.
Put it there.
Go away, dog! The dog is licking
everything. I'm disgusted.
My baby...
Get the farofa, Val.
Val?
I'm leaving.
Ok, hon.
Smell.
-Go safely.
-See you Wednesday. Amen.
-Is it yours, Carlos?
-Val bring an ice cream, please.
-Yes, ma'am.
-So it's yours, right?
-Of course not.
No, we've smoked pot. You think your
father and I, we never smoked pot?
Of course we smoked pot,
but we...right?
I wouldn’t get crazy, I wouldn't
use it in this absurd quantity.
Don't believe me then.
What can I do about it?
If you're saying it's not yours,
then I believe you.
-So you believe it's not his?
-Yeah.
But we're having a cool conversation.
That's right, I'm giving him an
opportunity to talk
You want to smoke pot, you can
you just don't need to smoke this much.
If it were mine, I'd say it.
Maybe some friend of his
put it there as a prank.
A friend, huh?
Pour some for me, please. A friend.
Alright. So you're going to
continue to tell me it's not yours.
Then I will throw it away.
Can I do that?
It's not yours, it's
not Carlos', it's
not mine either, so
I'll throw it away.
Go ahead and throw it,
if you think it's best.
Don't complicate things.
I believe you.
You believe me?
Let's make it alright, please?
It's delicious. Are you hungry?
Do you like it, Fabinho?
I'm going to get the
syrup for the desert. Excuse me.
Val!
Um..is there syrup?
Over there.
Can you get it for me, please?
You have nothing in your mind.
window, little window,
door, doorbell.
I'm already a big man, Val.
He is very adorable, he is
Very funny
He is
little Val's, he is...
very adorable...
He is...
very funny...
Ah Ok, you learned how
to wash behind your ears.
We are back with
"I want to be cute too."
Well, as we saw in one
of last block's subjects,
fashion is really very democratic.
For example,
today I was leaving home
And I was focusing in Marginal street
there was a group of
teenagers at the bus stop
and it was really a...it was a party.
it was colorful clothing,
the sneakers each one
different from the other,
But at the same time
there was harmony, you know?
Yes.
Hi.
If I were to show you guys,
you'd be able to see
Hello?
They mix together,
it becomes so cool, you could
cite the clothes,
I have a man...
Hi!
Who is it?
I can't hear...
Jessica, is that you?
Hi, my daughter.
Hi.
What happened?
Oh man!
It's not.
You're going to Sao Paulo?
Don't do this to your
mom. You got to be kidding me.
No, I like it. I think it's good.
But there's no...
Listen, there is no more time.
How long has it been since
Fabinho registered?
in the internet?
You can do that?
-I'm going.
-Where are you going so gussied up?
Fabinho, go take care of your life.
Respect is good and I like it.
Mrs. Barbara...
Hi.
I've been needing to talk to you
Wow, you smell good!
Oh, my goodness.
Ok, you can talk. Did
you leave the lasagna there?
I left it there inside the oven, because I couldn't
put it in the freezer because it was too hot.
Ok. Ok. Thank you, love.
Come earlier on Monday,
Ok? It's my birthday dinner.
-How would I forget?
-Ok? Thank you. Kisses.
And uh...
..Kisses, love.
-Bye.
Go away, Maggie. Maggie.
Maggie, honestly, Maggie.
How long has it been?
That Pamela has been living,
has been living with you?
Four years!
Oh, my gosh! That long?
And is it working out?
Fabinho.
Fabinho, it's almost seven AM.
-Hi.
Please, we are recording here,
can you make a little less noise?
Thank you.
You are a  woman who
dictates style, a trendsetter,
Yeah, a little.
Define style for me.
People, style has no secrets.
You know?
You can't make anything up.
Style means getting to know yourself.
You assume yourself and...
That's why I believe style
is being who you are.
You know?
-Marvelous.
You really are awesome.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, dear.
-Pleasure.
-The pleasure is all mine.
And happy birthday.
-Thank you.
And cut.
Thank you, everyone.
-See if you can come tonight.
-Ah, alright..
-Thank you.
-Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Will you call Janaina
and let her know when you go there?
Of course, of course. We are only
going to clean up here
-No, make yourself at home.
-Thank you.
Congratulations, Mrs. Barbara.
-Oh thank you, Val, thank you.
-Wish you the best.
A very great year to you, Mrs.
-Oh, I need it.
-Ah, please excuse the mess.
You bought me a present? Thank you.
Can I open it?
-Yes, please.
Ah, let's see, let's see.
the lady at the store says
it is selling lots of them.
-Oh yeah, it is selling lots of them?
-Yeah, people are using it a lot.
Oh, look! Awesome!
How pretty! Fantastic!
-You like it, didn't you?
-I did.
Let's put it away, Ok?
Let's put it away to use it in a
special occasion. In a moment...
-It's Ok.
-Ok? Take it for me and put it away.
Mrs. Barbara?
I'd like to have a conversation with you.
-Go ahead.
-Jessica called me on Thursday.
-Who's Jessica?
-My daughter.
-Ah, your daughter.
-And Jessica wants to...
-Wait just a minute, just a minute, val.
Hello.
Hi, Leo, how are you?
I don't know, love.
No, you call Janaina
check with her.
It's true.
Thank you, thank you, dear.
Kisses
Bye. Bye.
Ok. Jessica...um...
wants to come to São
Paulo to stay with me.
Are you kidding?
How wonderful, Val.
how great!
Right? What is she going to do here?
She's coming to apply
for college admission.
What is she going to study?
-I don't know. No, madam.
-No?
I don't know, madam.
But I wanted to see with
you, if in the very beginning,
just in the beginning, if she could
stay with us until I find a place.
Of course she can!
Of course, sweetie. You are
practically a part of the family.
You helped me take care of Fabinho.
Something so badly resolved.
How long has it been since
you've seen each other?
It's been more than ten years.
Wow!
In the beginning I wasn't
able to go see her,
You remember the problem with
her father. I couldn't go
but even then, after I got rid
of that pain in the ass,
I was struggling, calling, calling
she didn't want to talk to me,
She never wanted to talk to me,
she would
and would say "It’s Val, your mom."
"She went out, she went out."
It's been more than three years
since I don't speak to her. I
found it strange when she called
saying she wants to come.
But are you looking for a place
for you both to stay?
Yes, I've been asking about
who has a little place here..
..to rent, right?
-No, no.
I'm not asking you
this for a reason.
You can stay here for as long
as you want, there is no problem at all.
Thank you very much. I'm going to
get a mattress to put in the room,
Ok, buy a very good one.
Buy a good one because I
insist on paying for it.
Ok? Tell me how much
it is so I can give you the money.
You're wonderful, Mrs. Barbara,
you're like a mom to me.
What? Mom? here,
don't forget the moose cake.
Ok? Double recipe. Kisses, sweetie.
Bye!
-Bye.
Trix Casa.
Contains six tea cups,
with saucers and a tray.
It goes this way.
But it's mismatched
One black...
and one white.
And then the white
with the black,
And then the black
There.
Oh, how pretty.
And here
Yeah, it's mismatched.
A white
They like it like this, right?
It's the thermos'
It has a thermos.
Where's the thermos?
Oh my!
My god!
The thermos is...
So I have to take out one.
So if I put the thermos,
I have to take out the tea cup?
Maybe it's with the thermos like this.
But then it wouldn't be presentable.
In the photo...
No. It's with the thermos.
The right way
is with the thermos.
I'm going to hide this tea cup.
I can't stand it anymore.
For the love of God,
give me something.
I'm not going to stand it.
It's only one, you hear me, Skull?
You're going to deny to your fiancé?
It's only one. Show some respect, Ok?
Go cut your hair!
It really is good, right?
-What's wrong, Mrs. Barbara?
-Val, for the love of God, not this one.
Where did you get this one?
I told you that this one
we're taking to Guarujá.
-But...
-You get that one made of...
of white wood that I brought from
Sweden, for the love of God, Ok?
But you said it was
for a special occasion.
Oh, Ok.
Good night.
Let's get going.
Val?
Look. A little gift for you.
You are pretty, pretty,
pretty, pretty, pretty.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
Look at that.
Are you hungry, my daughter?
-No, it's alright.
You got scared, did you?
No. I have a little something
here that Sandra sent you.
Do you want to take it already?
-What is this?
It's better to give it to
you now, or I'll forget
She told me to
give it to you. It's coconut sweet..
-Oh, I love this coconut sweet..
-It smells good.
It's the jawbreaker.
I know which one she sends.
Let's go?
-let's go.
Let's go home. Let's
go, let's leave.
You don't want to eat anything?
You're not hungry?   -No.
- I'm fine.
- Are you sure.
- Do you want me to carry
anything? Do you
want me to push?
No. No carts.
You're so cute.
Your father?
What about him?
Your father. How is he?
He's not speaking to me.
What did you do?
Just bullshit of his.
It wasn't bullshit for
your dad to stop talking to you.
Are you liking it?
Yes, what place is this here we are now?
It's Marginal Tietê. It's the Tietê River.
Oh, I see.
Alright, there, over here,
look, is the Largo da Batata.
Oh, I've heard about
this place already.
That there are more
north-easterners
here than in the northeast.
Isn't there a story like this?
There only were
north-easterners.
But now to put a subway here,
look, they paved everything.
It's looking like, I don't
know what, it's not a square,
because there isn't
a bush walk here.
They cemented everything and took away
everything. There was a lot of forró here,
All this was full of crowds.
A little bar, many
good stores, but now,
-You used to come here a lot? Walk here?
-I did. Raimunda and I.
Look, what is that? it's not a square.
It's not...I don't know what that is.
Will it still take a while for us to arrive?
No, it's very near. It will
be about ten minutes.
They are very excited to meet you.
They are very anxious.
They? Who?
Barbara, Dr. Carlos,
right?
Fabinho,
everyone.
Later we can plan some time
to go there, right?
No, we're already going.
I just arrived. I'm tired.
We can plan to go later.
No, we're going there now.
I still live there.
What do you mean
you still live there, Val?
Are you taking me
to your bosses' house?
I live at work. I already said that.
I live at work.
You live in tiny room in
the back of their house?
You're going to love Fabinho.
For the love of God,
I'm not believing this.
-Calm down. Calm down.
-You're taking me to someone else's house?
Alright.
This here is my little corner.
You see? Look.
Television, everything in
the right place.
Ah, let me show you.
The brand new mattress
that she brought for you.
First class.
Here, look.
bed linen, towel,
everything you need.
You hear?
I don't know if the
mattress will fit here.
Of course it will. Look.
Let me open here to aerate.
I'll pull it now.
-Afterwards, we'll tidy up.
-No. It fit. It's done.
Ok, now all we need to do is cover it.
Now...
Ah, you're looking at it.
You liked it, did you?
This here, is a juicer.
This is a...
it's an electric fan,
a good one,
not this crappy one here,
All this I bought for you and I.
Where am I going to study here?
They're home. They're home!
Are you done, Fabinho?
Fabinho?
-Yes, I'm done.
-Carlos, are you going to eat more?
-No.
-Val!
-Yes?
You can clean the table, please.
I'm going.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Where is she, is she here?
-Jessica? Yes she is ma'am.
-Oh, yeah?
-Let me see that, Fabinho.
-Bring her here for us to meet her.
She's coming.
-Thank you, Val.
I'm curious.
-I'll go call her.
I'm going.
Jessica?
She's so happy. How cute.
Come, my daughter.
Look, Mrs. Barbara.
Oh, how beautiful.
Look, this is for you.
Oh, my goodness.
Welcome.
What a pleasure. Thank you.
We like your mom very much.
Your mom is very important to
everyone in this house so are you.
How is everything, Jessica?
Ok? Make yourself at home.
Dr. Carlos, and Fabinho...
How's it going?
Have you been to Sao Paulo before?
No, only in the pictures.
The internet, the movies...
She talks just like Val.
What is that?
-Very similar.
-Oh, yes.
Jessica brought a coconut sweet.
-Oh, nice...
-Actually, we call it jawbreaker.
I'm going to get a piece.
No, I don't even want...
it just...
I can't even get
near that, because
it fattens you just
by looking at it.
It's delicious.
-It's pretty.
Very delicious.
Your mom says you're applying for
college admission, is that right?
-Yes.
-What will you be studying?
Architecture.
-Architecture?
-At FAU?
Yeah, at FAU.
What is it, Mrs. Barbara,
what''s the problem?
None, it's just that FAU is one
of the hardest colleges
to get admission to.
-Is it true, Mrs. Barbara? Is it difficult?
-Yes, it's very competitive.
I'm aware.
But the school there,
where you went to, was it good?
-The teaching there?
-Yes.
No it wasn't very good.
Oh, poor thing.
But I always had help.
Right? And I met a history professor,
João Emanuel, who helped me a lot.
He helped you how?
How did he help you?
Oh, he...had a very criticizing
vision of things
So he gave us lots of important
things for us to think.
He put our minds to work,
putting together a theater group...
And why architecture?
Why did you choose Architecture?
Ah, there are many things, I think.
I always liked to draw,
so that's already a readiness,
and I have an uncle who is a contractor,
Uncle Adejado.
Yeah, Adejado, Evicto, and Adejá,
they are three siblings.
And then I helped him and
I learned many things, too
at the same time. And
then I made floor plans.
I made a floor plan of a house
there, a townhouse that
they even ended up building,
Look at that.
I think it's important I have a diploma,
-Of course.
-And I believe that architecture
is an instrument
for social change
You see?
The country is really changing.
-Would you look at that?
-Awesome.
-Very good.
Good luck.
The house is a bit modernist, right?
But not being exactly modernist
Wow, your daughter's intelligent, Val.
You should see her report card.
It's all A's from top to bottom.
Val, will you bring a cup
of water for me please?
Yes sir.
I'm not intelligent, I'm curious.
Isn't that the same thing?
I really wanted to read this book here,
I was even looking for it.
And you have time
to read other things
besides studying for
the entrance exam?
-I like to read.
-Thank you.
Then take it, take it to read.
-Can I?
-Of course.
Come see the pool.
Val, would you turn on
the pool lights, please?
A beautiful thing, isn't it?
It's beautiful.
I like to read, too.
Yeah. Fabinho is also a very
good student. Aren't you, Fabinho?
Right, Dr. Carlos?
-Good student.
Let's go see Fabinho's room?
They are all suites, right?
Look, Jessica.
Fabinho.
Fabinho was like this when I first came.
Ah, so cute.
The famous Fabinho.
And you are the famous Jessica.
What about that door over here?
-Over there is the guest room, right?
-Yes, the guest room.
You want to see?
Another suite.
Look, what a comfortable mattress.
-Jessica.
-I'm sorry, sir
-Such a great mattress and no one sleeps here?
It's the guest room.
So it's where I'm going to stay.
Did you lose your mind?
For the love of God, for the
love of God, for the love of God.
-Do you want to stay here?
-Yeah, I think it would be good to study here.
It wouldn't have any interference.
-No, Jessica. You'll stay in my room.
-Did you lose your mind?
-What happened?
Jessica is going to stay here.
-It's Ok.
-I think it's better if she stays in my room.
It has already been
arranged that way.
Mrs. Barbara even bought a mattress.
Very comfortable.
-No, Doctor Carlos, there's no need.
She can stay there
with me, won't
bother anyone.
-Alright. I'm going to get things. I'll come in a bit.
-Jessica stop being pushy!
-Pushy? But he's inviting me.
-But it's only because you said "It's here I'm staying."
Ah.
It's you.
I can't sleep, Val.
Fabinho, I'm tired.
-Ok. I'm to sleep here, alright?
-Alright, but we're not going to keep chatting.
Because tomorrow I wake up early.
What's gotten into you?
I can't sleep.
I'll stay here with you.
Do some caress here.
Fabinho.
What?
And Jessica?
What about Jessica?
What do you think of Jessica?
A little strange, right?
Strange how?
I don't know.
Too confident about herself.
She is too confident.
That's it. She's confident.
Her eyes.
She looks at everything.
Looks like the president.
Fabinho?
Huh?
Val?
Good morning.
Were you with your mother?
I haven't seen her today.
Do you know where she might be?
She's probably sleeping.
It's strange, because I went to her room,
knocked and she didn't answer.
Have you eaten?
I just woke up.
Do you want to eat?
Oh, let me see.
Excuse me. There is...there's bread...
There's white bread, there's wheat bread,
Let me get a cloth for you here.
Sit down.
What do you want to drink?
What kind of juice is that?
it's Palestinian Sweet Lime.
You're not going to drink that?
No, I'll make one for
you. Do you want one?
Sure.
Is it good? Did you like it?
-I liked it.
-It's good, right? It's so good for you.
Jeez.
Oh, Mrs. Barbara,
this never happened to me before.
I think the alarm didn't go off,
I completely lost track of time.
-It's Ok.
-What do you want? A toast?
-No, I already ate.
-No, I'll make a toast for you.
You don't need to. I'm
already leaving, Val.
-For the love of God, Mrs. Barbara.
-Oh, your daughter loved the jelly.
Bye.
What was that?
Jessica...
Who put the breakfast table?
It was Barbara.
Goodness, it's not "Barbara"
it's Mrs. Barbara.
You sound like you're...crazy.
Barbara.
And you can't sit at their table.
-Which one is their table?
-It's that one.
And where's the other
one? I don't see it.
Am I going to eat standing?
She was the one who told me to sit here.
Get off that table.
I'm eating. Hold on.
-Get off the table!
-I'm eating, Val.
Let me finish.
Blessed Mary.
What were you thinking?
The housekeeper's daughter
sitting at the bosses' table.
They aren't my bosses, Val.
Come on. Val? Can't
you call me mom?
-I can.
-Thank you.
There, I'm done.
Blessed Mary, I have
never seen this before.
You're crazy. You have
no idea about anything.
Leave that for me to wash, go. go.
-I'm going to my room to study.
-That's right, go.
Hi, son.
What do you want, sweetie?
Juice.
Do you want a grilled cheese?
Yes.
Go ahead and put the
ladder next to the plant.
There.
Now. Faster, Edna.
Here.
Pay attention.
Pretend you are trimming and
I'll pretend that I'm watering.
And keep spying.
Pretend you are trimming and
I'll pretend that I'm watering.
Do you understand? Understand?
This is unbalanced. Hold it for me.
She's reading..
-What is she doing?
-She's reading. She has the book like this
-Reading?
-Yes. She's seated.
She must be studying.
She could be sleeping, I don't..
..see her face.
-She is studying.
She got up.
She lay on the bed,
Pretend you are trimming and
I'll pretend that I'm watering.
-And now, what is she doing?
-I don't know if she's going to bed
She grabbed the book.
Don't let her see you. Don't.
Get down. Get down.
-Get down.
-The whole day.
Get down, get down.
-The person gets crazy reading all day.
Get down the ladder.
Give it to me. Give it to me. Give me.
Jessica?
Hold on.
-It's mom, Jessica.
-Hold on.
Ok. This here is Edna.
She works with me. She's
a little sister I have her in São Paulo.
-Pleasure.
-Likewise.
-She looks like you, huh?
-Yeah.
You think so?
I think she looks like her father.
Pretty, but she looks so thin, though.
So, uh...
Edna wants to come in for a bit.
To vacuum, clean the room.
No worries. I already tidied up.
Everything is in the right
place all cleaned up.
-So...
-No, it's that Mrs. Barbara, she...
She's very picky about this, so
I have to vacuum.
Yeah, she...
-Does she really check everything?
-She passes her finger
-Get your things. Let's go upstairs.
-It's just that I'm studying, Val.
Everything is all here.
No, let's go.
Grab your book and
let's go study in the
kitchen with me.
-It's cool there, right?
-It's just that Edna is going to vacuum.
I'll go get the rest of my things.
I don't know what's worse
Clodomil or Pingulim.
I didn't like it, either.
But Pingulim sounds nicer.
Don't you think?
-Poor thing.
Each one worse than the other.
Yeah.
So, are you enjoying São Paulo?
I arrived only yesterday.
Aren't you going to help
your mom with the work?
Shh...
I can help.
What do you want me do do?
Keep drawing, keep drawing,
keep drawing, my daughter. Keep drawing.
Hi, girls.
Hi, Mr. Carlos.
-Hi.
-What do you want in my fridge?
-I want a Guaraná.
-Guaraná.
Did you have fun at the club?
-It was really hot, right?
Very hot.
-It's about to rain a lot.
-Thank you.
-It's hot.
Mister, come see.
-She's very good at drawing.
-No, I already told you it's not done, Edna.
Let me see, let me see.
Let me see.
-Look, it's not done yet.
-Look at that.
Very good. Did you
take any classes?
-No, I didn't.
-That's why you draw well.
Let's go see my studio.
Can she go, Val?
-Let's go.
-Can I?
Let's go?
Val, can you serve lunch?
Yes, sir. I'll do that now.
You're in trouble.
One time I spent six
months with one pallet.
To create each color like that?
-Yes, to come up with these colors.
-it's very beautiful.
-Beautiful?
-Very.
It's a pity you have it stored away.
You have to hang it on a wall.
Put it on yours.
-Really?
-Yes.
Did you like it?
-This one?
Yeah.
-I'm giving it to you as a present.
-It is too lovely.
-For me?
-Yes.
How am I going to carry this?
You have to use Dante's car.
Thank you.
Wow, I don't know
how I'm to wrap this so.
I'll help you.
I fell in love with this one.
-Yeah?
You fell in love?
Very beautiful.
And why did you stop painting?
I stopped painting because
I stopped smoking.
No, I'm just kidding.
There are some more pictures here.
I think there are pictures of your mom.
Here, it's Val.
Awesome.
She looks like those babysitters
in advertisements, looking so nice.
I stopped because
everyone said I was
the best, you know?
And I believed them.
I don't know,
a lot of things happened,
I ended up stopping to paint.
-You stopped working?
How do you get money?
Does Barbara provide for you?
-Barbara provides for us?
-It's not?
Uh-uh.
I know it doesn't look like it
but the cash is mine.
My dad worked a lot,
saved lots of cash,
and I inherited it.
Everyone dances,
because I choose the music.
Excuse me.
Hi, Val.
I already set the table for lunch.
Can Jessica have lunch with me?
-Jessica?
-Yeah.
-Are you the one inviting her?
-Of course I am inviting her.
Can you put another plate on the table?
-Yes sir.
Sorry?
Oh, Ok.
Ah, and don't tell her I am smoking
on my job or I'll be in trouble. You know.
No worries. No worries.
Later we'll return.
We'll come back.
Have you been there? No?
Now I think it has eleven,
twelve, thirteen stories.
And it's the  superintendency of
the development of the northeast.
And it's a building that
is very similar to Copan, I think.
It is a bit modernistic
I'd like to see Copan.
Yeah, we need to go.
Let's go there.
-Let's go?
-Of course.
Of course. You have to see it.
You have to see that
one about the movement.
Val?
Yes?
-Val?
-I'm going.
Will you clear the table?
It was very good, wasn't it?
Let me help you.
No, no, no, let Val clear the table.
No, no, Val clears it.
The Sugar loaf Mountain,
have you been there?
No, just pictures.
Will you bring a coffee for us, Val?
Are there any sweets, Val?
Bring an ice cream.
What do you think?
Wonderful.
Although I find it a bit strange.
-It's very good. It's very good.
-Very good.
Thank you Val.
Oh, Val, it's not this one.
It's that one, the one
that's almond chocolate.
Fabinho's?
It's not Fabinho's.
It's ours, it's Jessica's,
the other one. Almond chocolate.
-Fabinho's ice cream?
-The almond chocolate ice cream.
-Have you been there? Brasilia.
-Yes, Brasilia is very nice.
Now when Fabinho wants
the ice cream,
-The bean broth was excellent.
-There's no way to eat without beans.
Let me serve, Val.
Look how beautiful.
It looks tasty.
This is mine.
Thank you.
-Is it this one?
-No, let me serve.
Did you ever eat this before?
Never. not in this little container.
Are there no sweets?
She asked  "Are there no sweets?"
She doesn't even get up
when you go in the kitchen.
Edna.
Please. I'm the one talking about Jessica.
It's not for you to talk about Jessica,
I'm talking about Jessica.
"Are there no sweets?"
And bla bla bla.
Nobody deserves that.
Visit I don't know what,
I don't know what else, with Dr.Carlos.
It's like she doesn't...
...have any notion
about anything in this life.
Gosh!
Edna!
Look at that.
I went with so much force that
You're very nervous. Let me fix it.
These old stuff.
The hallway...there's the dining room,
the bigger room, you see?
The things here of this floor.
Over here.
And down over here,
in the inferior is your room,
And why is this called a plant?
Good question.
I don't know.
-You don't know?
-No.
-But is that what you want to do?
-Yeah, more or less.
-Val?
It's not just this.
-I'm going.
Will you clean the table, please?
Val, will you bring
the ice cream, please?
Can you give me a little bit, Val?
This ice cream is Fabinho's.
But he said I could have some.
When they say that,
when they offer something
that is theirs,
it's out of politeness.
It's because they're sure
that we're going to say no.
Thank you.
-Do you want mine?
-No.
If you're going to have ice cream,
eat this one, that's ours.
It's very impressive, isn't it?
it seems like the buildings
don't end. We keep looking there,
But there is something
that I am thinking
that I found very awesome
in the television,
It was a show that talked about
the possibility
of us not existing anymore.
And then it said that
in one-hundred years
everything would be taken
over by jungles.
Everything would be back
and I keep thinking about it.
I think that's interesting.
-One-hundred years?
-It's a small amount of time, isn't it?
I don't know if it was one-hundred.
I don't remember.
Thank you for the trip. I really liked it.
No problem.
I'm sorry, Jose Carlos.
I'm sorry.
Hello?
Hi.
Hi Janaina.
What?
But what...is it serious?
But what happened?
Ok. Is she alright?
Ok. I'll be right there.
Barbara had an accident.
-Was it serious?
-It doesn't seem so. It seems she's Ok.
-No, we're going. Of course.
- I have to go there
Barbara hit her head.
She hurt her forehead?
-Holy Mary.
-And her shoulder?
She hurt her forehead.
Her forehead and her shoulder,
and they said she was nervous...
Mrs. Barbara is nervous?
Yeah, she hit her car, right?
It scared her.
-What a scare, oh, my god.
What do they do to keep
the water so clean, Val?
Don't keep looking at that pool, Jessica.
That's not for you.
-I didn't say anything.
You didn't say anything but
you thought something, I know.
You hear me?
You never swam here before?
I am going to swim at someone
else's pool in someone else's house?
-Never?
-Never.
And if one day the ask you
to swim in this pool you'll say "I have
no bathing suit, I can't." Understand?
-I understand.
-Hey, val.
Val!
Don't do that, Skull. Ow, Skull
Get out of there with that hair!
That hairy dude is Skull.
Go comb your hair to talk to my daughter.
-How are you?
-It's Jessica.
-Nice to meet you.
-Are we going to swim or what?
That boy's got nothing in his head.
How about you, Jessica?
You're not going in?
It's very good.
I have no bathing suit.
-Come in with those clothes, Jessica.
-No, I'm wearing clothes.
I think your mom is coming.
It's Mrs. Barbara.
Go away!
Stop, stop, stop.
Stop, stop, no. No! Stop!
-You want to sit up a bit more, right?
-Yes.
-Who's in the pool? Fabinho?
-Fabinho and Skull.
-Oh, Ok.
-Them both, the both of them.
But there is someone else;
who is it? Jessica?
No, Jessica is only there waiting
for me. She was just looking.
But...I'm going to see
what this racket is.
Excuse me.
Go away! No!
Stop that!
-Jessica!
Get out of there, Jessica!
Jessica, get out of there, now.
Dr. Carlos is here, Jessica.
Fabinho!
Jessica. I don't know what
she's thinking. to go in...
I'm going there, Dr.Carlos.
Look at the contractors
there looking. Fabinho!
Carlos?
Carlos, help me.
Jose Carlos, help me!
Oh, Fabinho!
What a stupid prank, Fabinho.
Take her out of there.
-Jessica, get out of there!
Get out of there!
-I'm going!
Get out, Jessica!
Can you obey your mother?
She's talking to you.
-Get out if that water!
-Obey your mother.
She's going to catch a cold.
Obey Dr.Carlos, Mrs.Barbara.
-I'm going.
-Have you lost your mind?
Get out of that pool.
Jessica!
Look.
-I'm going, Val.
-You are taking too long.
Come, come...come!
-You don't need to grab me like that.
-Come, Jessica!
I'm going to get the towel.
Where's the towel?
Wait, you're naked. Are you crazy?
-Fabinho?
Fabinho! Get out of there,
I want to talk to you.
Mom, you're humiliating me.
-Now, Fabinho.
-Dad, look...
-Now, Fabinho!
-Listen to your mother, Fabinho.
-I'm going.
Are you drugged?
Did you smoke today?
Drugged? What are
you taking about?
What am I talking about?
Fabinho, I was in an accident.
Did you know that?
That I was unconscious?
That the ambulance took me to the hospital?
I'm all busted?
-but the doctor said that everything's OK.
Is that why you don't
even come to see me, Fabinho?
You don't even come to see me, man.
You don't care one bit about me.
You don't even come see me.
Calm down, mom.
Calm down? Calm down is great.
It's terrible.
-May I go?
-yes, you can.
-Ok, bye.
Do you have Carlos from
the pool's phone number there?
Call him, please.
Do you have it in your phone?
-Yes.
Give it to me. I'm
going to talk to him.
Press Talk.
Claudio?
Hi, it's Barbara from the Morumbi.
I know. But I need
you to come tomorrow. Can you?
Yeah, something went wrong here.
Go on, Maggie. Stop with that sniffing.
Poop quicker, Maggie.
Today, I don't have any
patience even for you, you hear?
But you did everything
to make him throw you in the pool.
You weren't even looking, Val.
You don't know what you're saying.
I'm telling you I want to leave
this place, you understand?
-it is better if you do.
-Didn't I say that since the beginning?
-This is not working.
-It really isn't.
And I told you so.
I don't know where you
learned these things.
You keep saying "You can't this,
you can't that"
Was it ever written in a book or
something? How is it? Who taught you?
When you arrived here were
they explaining these things to you?
Those things people don't need to explain.
People are born knowing it.
What you can do and what you can't.
You seem like you're from another planet.
-I know.
We are born knowing it.
-How are you?
-I'm good, dear.
-What's up?
-So, did you find out the price
of that room in Campo Limpo?
I already talked to them, Ok?
I talked to Adneia,
and everything is alright.
Isn't the price good? -400.
It's great.
We're going now, right Val?
Ok. It's actually better.
Tomorrow I'm coming.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah, because things aren't working out there.
-Why? Want happened?
-You can't imagine.
-Nothing.
-I'll tell you later. She went to the pool...
-Let's go, Val.
-Holy moly.
At Mrs. Barbara's pool?
Later you come here, Val. For us to talk.
-Raimunda I'm almost going crazy.
Ok, Bye.
So let's do this: I'll take the pictures,
I'll choose the best ones
-Ok.
-Because I don't want you tiring yourself now..
You have to look beautiful and marvelous.
-Ok.
-Mrs. Barbara, we're leaving.
You decided to find
your own place to stay.
-Technically.
-Ok. Did you leave the pie?
Yes, ma'am.
-Thank you very much, Ok?
-You're welcome.
So we're leaving. Excuse me.
Good luck on the college admission test.
-So, let's continue.
-Dr. Carlos...
Hi.
Thank you.
Good luck.
It was a pleasure.
Pleasure.
Ok let me...
-No, Dr. Carlos, for the love of God.
-No, have a little treat. Please.
For the love of God,
I'm going to be embarrassed.
-No worries.
-Thank you.
-See you later.
-Bye.
Bye.
-Is everything Ok over there?
-Uh-huh.
Here, guys, come on in...
Take a quick glance.
-Is it here?
-Yes, here.
That's strange, this doesn't
look like a home.
Is this a person's house?
It is more like a parlor.
Yeah, it used to be a parlor before,
but the person who lived here made a little parlor.
There's even this huge mirror.
Raimunda, I think these walls are
too red. Don't you think it's a bit showy?
It's not. That's what makes it pretty.
-Just paint it, Val.
-You think so, Jessica?
-Yes, you can paint it.
-Look here. There is this window
that brings this fresh air every afternoon,
And it's also gated. It is totally secured.
The shower is brand new,
and it's also very good.
Yeah, we're going to stay.
-Ok.
-Did you like it?
It's good, Val.
We'll make do.
Let's talk to Pedro downstairs.
Talk nicely, and I
think it will work out.
Let's go talk to him.
We'll talk nicely to him.
I said that I wanted...
Just a moment, Raimunda,
didn't you tell him that I was
working it out?
I thought everything had worked out.
Raimunda, look.
-The problem is that
there was no deposit, understand?
Deposit for what if
I didn't see the house?
How is someone going to deposit money
if there is no one home?
-Ok, let's do this:
I'm going to turn things around
-I am going to find you a house.
-Is there something to see today?
-Not today, but...
-I waned to stay here already.
Let me stay at your house today, Bruna.
But this week? This week?
Edimilson is coming today.
-It's only for tonight that I'm asking.
-I can't.
Edmilson only has one free day each week,
it's just for tonight.
He only has one free day.
He's arriving.
Calm down, Jessica.
-I didn't want to go back there.
It's only for one week, Jessica.
-We had agreed to stay here already.
-It will be over soon.
-Are they treating you bad?
-No, it's not this.
Dr. Carlos? Fabinho?
Do you have a crush on Fabinho?
-I'm not saying that.
-Dr. Carlos is even cherishing her.
Carlos?
José Carlos!
Yes?
Her gracious little daughter is back.
Right, Val?
Yes, Uh, Dr. Carlos?
it's only for one week.
Val, there's no problem at all.
I thank you so much, but
I gave my word.
You stay as long as
you need, no problem.
Thank you.
-It won't be for long, Mrs. Barbara.
-Oh, Ok.
Hey, you know what I saw in the pool?
A rat, Val.
-No
-Can you believe it?
-Really, Mrs. Barbara?
A rat. I screamed from up here.
You came back.
The room didn't work out?
-No, it didn't.
Do you want one?
I have one here already.
You know this house here is
almost as if it were yours
Anything that you'll need
The house even got a bit
empty, you know?
Thank you.
Do you believe in reincarnation?
I don't know.
I never thought much about it.
-I don't believe it, I don't  believe it
because It think it's only this time,
you know?
So...
sometimes we say
things that may seem
crazy, you know?
But if I don't say it,
Maybe it is crazy if we
only have this one time.
You know? Uh...
Do you want to marry me?
Marry me.
I'll take you anywhere you want.
Uh...
It's hot, isn't it?
Sorry, José Carlos.
-No, I'm sorry.
-I don't know what to say.
It's yes.
Say yes.
Marry me.
-No,
-Sorry. I am...
-I don't...
I don't understand.
-I'm sorry, it's...
I was just kidding.
I was kidding.
-You were kidding?
-I was kidding. It was a joke.
-Wow, you scared me.
-I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
She's coming to São Paulo,
she never comes, and
since Jessica has vacated the guest room,
I told her she could stay here
in my house, so
she is coming
and I will need you to
help Jessica move to your room.
-Of course.
-Ok?
She will go to my room
Great. Tell her to leave the room today.
-Yes ma'am
-Then it will be enough time to
organize everything.
-Don't worry.
-Ok, thank you, Val.
But tell her to leave the room today, Ok?
-Ok, yes ma'am.
-Alright, thank you.
Let me go, because I've
got a pot on the range.
Can't you open the window, Val?
If I open the window, It'll be
as hot, the only thing that
it'll do is bring
in more mosquitoes.
Sincerely, Val,
I don't know how you can stand it.
How I stand what?
To be treated this way,
like a second-class citizen.
This is worse than India.
Don't go talking this
difficult subject of India,
because you are snobby,
that's what you are.
-This is all too shitty, that's what it is.
-Stop swearing.
Because I don't like swearing.
You think you're all that.
You think you're better than
everyone, you are
superior to everyone.
-I don't think I'm superior, Val,
I just don't think I'm inferior, understand?
It's different.
-You are going to make me lose this job.
-Oh, fuck it.
-Watch your language.
Go wash your mouth with soap.
Respect me because I'm your mother.
-Oh, no, you're not my mom.
-Sandra is the one who raised me.
You have nothing to do with this.
Look down. Sandra raised you
with the money I sent her
every month
to pay for your school, pay
for your dentist...
Sandra got the easy part.
Sandra was with you,
and I was here, only working,
working hard.
Sandra is your mom,
Sandra is...Sandra's bill, you
know who sent her money every month.
I'm tired, you know?
Of hearing this kind of thing.
Tired. Tired.
No, everything's
alright. I'm studying...
But let me ask you.
How is he, huh?
Is he asking about me?
really?
Wish I'd seen it.
Look, I'm going to
let you sleep, Ok?
Later we'll talk more.
Ok, kisses.
Do you want to smoke?
Yeah.
This one's one of the good ones.
They asked to drain out the pool,
did they?
Yeah. My mom said
she saw a rat here.
I don't know. It might be
dangerous. We might catch a disease.
Alright.
Are you a virgin?
What kind of question is that?
Do I look like a virgin?
I don't know.
The look...
-You look like a virgin.
-Me?
You do.
In this face?
I'm not. Are you?
Of course not.
You think I'm a rat.
What?
-I think I know already.
-Already?
-You know?
-Ah, I think I know.
-I don't know.
-You don't?
I don't get it.
Ah, there.
FAU. -It's FAU.
Ah...
This is where you'll
be studying, right?
Yeah.
I want to, right?
It's pure town planning.
I'm going to put Maggie
down there. Come, Maggie.
Come, Maggie!
Maggie.
Come, Maggie.
Come.
She's must be smelly because
she fell in the pool and didn't dry well.
That's why Fabinho's
ice cream finishes.
I already said that this
is Fabinho's ice cream.
You are so stubborn.
Forgive me for that, Mrs. Barbara.
I have already said it, and said it again.
Since when is my great-grandma's
tray broken?
Val, it may not appear to be,
but this house is still mine.
Come here.
I want to talk to you.
Mrs. Barbara, If you'll tell me
where I can get...
this silver tray fixed, I’ll take it there
I'll do everything, pay for everything...
-Val, it's not that.
Val, that's not it.
That's not the problem.
The college admission
exam is tomorrow, right?
-Yes, ma’am.
-After that, she'll leave, right?
She will go, yes, ma'am.
So while she's still here,
I'd want you to
make sure she doesn't pass
the kitchen door, Ok.
Yes, ma'am. She won't
pass the kitchen door.
Yes, from the door of the kitchen out.
You can go, thank you.
You know she lives far away,
how are you going to get there now?
You can't leave now.
-I'll make it work.
-Oh stubborn girl, don't go, Jessica.
I have no guts for that.
to endure this.
We'll talk about this later. Tomorrow is
you exam, my daughter.
I'd rather think about what to
then to keep tolerating this bullshit.
If you have the guts to stay
here, then stay, but I can't stand it, Val.
I can't stand it.
-You should have defended me!
Jessica, don't go...Don't
go with this rain! Holy Mary!
-How will you go?
-I'll find a way. I'm not scared of water.
-Where are you going?
-Let it be, Val, let it be because it's no use!
-Have you lost your mind?
Who goes out on a storm like this?
-Forget it, Val. Go back home!
Tomorrow's your exam.
You'll miss it, Jessica.
Good luck, my daughter.
Go with  the boy Jesus on your lap.
-Let's go? Let's go.
I'm worried.
What about the traffic? No, no, let's get
going downstairs and I'll call him.
-At least drink coffee. It's still very early.
-But I think it's better to be early than late.
What if we have an accident or there is traffic,
or something? We'd better go.
Right? Let's go.
Did you get a cereal bar or
something else to eat?
I got. Got it.
Good luck.
Very difficult.
But do you think you think you did well?
We don't know yet.
The answers have been posted.
-it has been posted already?
-Was it hard?
-yes. Hold on, let me get it here.
Which one was yours? There's A...
-it was Q, mom.
-Ok, let me see here.
And Jessica, Fabinho?
Have you seen Jessica?
Crap, Val. I don't
have any news about her.
Let's see? Val, can you excuse us, please?
Ok...Can I start?
-Let's go. You can start.
-One- C.
-Yeah.
-Did you get it right?
-Yes.
-Two - D
-I got it right.
-Yeah.
-Three - B,
-Four A,
No?
Mom, keep going. In the end, we'll see.
Five A,
You got nervous.
You knew all the answers, didn't you?
Val, I was two point away.
That's unfair.
Let's move on.
Fabinho,
Next year, you'll try again.
Excuse me.
-Look how bad he is.
-You will continue to be like this, son?
Now there's no use.
Hey...
Get your hopes up.
It's over now.
Come here.
Hey, Fabinho...Val can hug you and I can't?
-Val thinks I'm intelligent.
You think I'm dumb.
-I don't think you're dumb.
I don't think you're dumb.
I think maybe...
You didn't pass because you
don't know what you want...
You have doubts...
Excuse me, Mrs. Barbara,
Mrs. Barbara, I'm so nervous
I can't even talk to you.
-What happened?
-Holy Mary, Jessica called.
-Yeah?
-Do you know how many point Jessica got?
-How many?
Do you know how
many points Jessica got?
68 points!
-68?
-Jessica passed the exam.
-Jessica passed.
-Wow, 68?
-Look, I'm so nervous.
-Congratulations, Val.
-Thank you.
-Holy Mary!
-68?
-I still can't believe it.
-Yeah, I can't believe it, either.
It's incredible, isn’t it?
-So...
-Impressive. very good. 68.
-It's very good.
-She said 68.
-Val?
Yeah...don't get too excited.
It was only the first round.
-I know, yes, ma'am.
There'll we another exam, the second
round is a lot harder,
-I can't believe it.
-I know.
So...
She said she got 68
points and 68 points is...
No it's very good, but...she
has to pass the next round.
It won't matter if she doesn't
pass the other round.
-But if God wants to help,
she'll pass the next round.
-Yes, she will.
-Right, and so will Fabinho for the next year.
They'll pass, right, Fabinho?
Don't be so sad like that,
my precious.
Well, get your hopes up, Fabinho.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
68...
-That's a lot, right?
-Yeah.
She studied, right?
She didn't do anything else,
she only studied.
You have to study to pass.
You have to study.
I'm leaving.
Jessica?
My daughter.
Hi it's mom.
I'm calling to say good night.
To say I'm very proud of you.
Now...
Guess where I am.
Look...
Can you hear?
I'm in the pool!
Yeah.
Yes, I am.
I'm very happy.
You hear me?
A kiss...look...
Mom loves you.
A kiss.
Dr. Carlos, it's eleven O'clock.
-Come in, Val.
-Excuse  me.
-Have you taken your medicine?
-I did. I want to congratulate you.
for Jessica.
-Goodness.
You raised your daughter very well.
Me?
I also want...
To apologize to you.
Apologize for what?
You know.
I'm going...to
stay here a little bit more.
But...
What can I do? Do you want anything?
I want to sleep.
Huh.
-Tell her the news.
-Didn't I tell you?
I'm going to live overseas
six months by myself.
-Overseas? Where?
-in Australia, Val.
Holy Moly, how far!
There is an incredible
English school there.
it's good for him to
stay there, study...
I didn't like this. I'm going to miss
you very much. Six months without him?
-Look at this beach here.
-Oh my goodness.
-Look how pretty.
-Very pretty.
Yeah, we're still seeing where
he is going to stay...
It's very far, guys.
Oh my goodness, it's so far...
-Look.
-It looks like Recife.
Look how cute.
It's crochet. I bought it from Joelma.
She lives near Pamela.
Look at how everything is tidying up.
God writes straight
with crooked lines.
This house is much better
than that one, isn't it Jessica?
Jessica, you're still mad at me.
You have to understand my side
of the story, my daughter.
And you should have defended me.
Didn't I defend you?
I'm not going to talk
about this because I don't want to fight again.
Mother of God.
They thought you were so pretty.
All rich, full of things, when you
used to go by and visit.
They don't know how much
I suffered because of you.
You don't know how much
You suffered because you wanted to.
You always went  there
carrying many presents
telling me this, telling me that,
and then leaving me there like an idiot
asking "When does my mommy return"
"What time does she return?"
You don't know half of it.
One day I asked your dad.
Fuck that, Val. Ten years!
Why didn't you come back?
You don't know what I went through.
The longer I stayed the more I wanted to go back,
but the time passed and I didn't go back,
but even if I didn't go back...
I'm going to tell you
something: one day
God forbid, God forbid,
but one day
you will understand your mother very much.
Who is this boy?
Jessica, I am asking
you who this boy is.
Jessica, why doesn't your
father speak to you?
I don't understand why your
father doesn't speak to you.
Jessica, I'm asking you. Who
is this boy, Jessica?
It's Jorge.
I don't know who Jorge is
-He's my son.
-Oh, my God.
Jessica, I can't believe it, Jessica.
And why didn't you
ever tell me, Jessica?
-Because we weren't even talking.
How would I tell you something like that?
-And you left the boy there?
You left the boy there?
-I did, Val. How was I going to study, do the exam?
Would I bring the boy with me?
Oh, my God.
And you won't bring the boy?
Yes, I will.
As soon as I can I will.
-So cute.
-When?
-When I can, Val.
-Oh, Thank you, Val.
it's alright.
Oh, my god, send a a man like this to
that end of the world
My little boy, my precious.
Love of mine.
My boy.
-Let's go, son?
We're late.
Ok? Bye, Val.
-Bye bye.
-Kisses.
Don't eat any junk food.
Take care.
Ok, my love?
Love you.
Oh my.
-But Val...but why?
Are you mad at me?
No, I'm asking my resignation.
I'm resigning.
But why so sudden?
Was it something I did?
Are you mad at me?
-No ma'am.
-me?
No, Mrs. Barbara. It's...
It's not you, it's me.
Are there being Gossips? is Vandre
the driver whispering things to you?
No it wasn't Vandre.
It wasn't, ma'am.
This is...
This is my thing.
I know.
This, Mrs. Barbara,
Do you want a raise?
No ma'am, it's not about money.
We can see. We can get you a raise.
No, Mrs. Barbara,
it's not because of money.
No ma'am it's not because of money.
It's that...
I think I am...
I need...
...to stay with my daughter.
To take care of my daughter,
to be with my daughter.
Yeah.
You're right.
-Right?
Oh, Val.
Alright.
People'll stay there until 9:30,
I will lose track of time,
and then, you guessed it,
I have to go to Vila Romana
over there, close by
go down behind there, cut through it,
go to Moema,
and on top of that I still need
to buy the kids' Christmas presents.
It's not easy.
-But we need to have hope, Vitor,
what do you intend
on doing next year?
If I could choose, you know
how it's so hot,
sometimes it rains too much
and I have to close the truck's window,
and I would like to ask a favor here...
Here.
-Put this one with the other...
-No, that's Ok.
-Thank you, Andre.
-Your're welcome.
-Thank you.
-If you need me, call me.
Good bye, you two. Wish you the best.
-Bye.
What are you doing here on a Thursday?
Goodbye.
I resigned.
You're kidding, Val.
-No. I'm serious.
-Really?
Not even I can believe it.
That's not good.
Go boil some water.
Now we're going to drink coffee.
Let's.
And now? Have you
thought about what you're going to do?
I don't know.
I'll figure it out.
I'll do a massage specialization class,
Doesn't Fabinho say I'm
the best masseuse in the world?
Who knows?
It's a good idea.
Look how beautiful.
I like it.
-Modern right?
-I see it.
All this is different, look.
The black on the white,
the white on the black,
It's different, like you.
Beautiful.
-Modern.
-Yeah.
Look at thermos, how beautiful.
So beautiful, so beautiful.
Fancy.
Why?
I stole it from Mrs. Barbara.
You're lying, Val.
You swear?
Jessica, now that...
I spend more time at home,
that we're home,
I was thinking.
Go get Jorge.
Bring my grandson.
I'll pay for the trip.
By plane!
Go get your son.
Go.
Aren't you in a hurry?
You already want to get
ahead of yourself, huh, Val?
Will you take care of him, mom?