(BIRDS SCREECHING)
(MEN SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SCREECHING)
(HOOTING IN PANIC)
(SCREAMING)
Okay, okay. Here you go.
And let's go again.
Which one is this? Number nine?
Yeah, this is number nine.
Bright Eyes, we call her.
Are you watching this?
This is unbelievable.
Oh, my God.
-How many moves was that?
-20.
Yeah, a perfect score is 1 5.
Doc, what are you giving her?
Hey, give me that video!
Chimp number nine, just one dose.
Aren't l seeing you later?
We are good to go.
l'm going to call you back.
Yeah, all right. Thanks. Bye.
WlLL: The 1 1 2. lt works.
On just the one primate.
One is all we need.
Full cognitive recovery. We're ready.
Look, are you sure you're not rushing this?
l've been working on this
for five and a half years.
The data is clear.
We're ready, Steven.
All l need is your approval for human trials.
For this, you're going to need
the board's approval.
There's a lot of money riding on this, Will.
You only get one shot.
One shot is all l need.
(SlGHlNG)
All right. But l'll need to see
-all the research.
-You got it.
-And, Will...
-Yeah?
Keep your personal emotions out of it.
These people invest in results, not dreams.
Okay.
Meet chimp nine.
Here she is tasking at what is called
the Lucas Tower,
the object of which is to move the tower
from peg to peg,
without placing a larger block
on top of a smaller block.
As expected, she was unable
to complete the puzzle at all.
Then, we gave her what we call ALZ-1 1 2,
a gene therapy that allows the brain
to create its own cells
in order to repair itself.
ln biology, this is called neurogenesis.
Here at Gen-Sys,
we call it the cure to Alzheimer's.
(ALL MURMURlNG)
FRANKLlN: Donnie, you get her ready?
She's got stage fright.
ls that what it is?
(HlSSlNG)
Hey! Hey!
She is going to break my hand!
Let go. Bright Eyes, let go!
Are you all right?
We're ready to move on to the next phase.
Human trials.
FRANKLlN: Here you go, Bright Eyes.
lt's your favorite fizzy soda, come on.
Let's go, Donnie.
We should have her downstairs already.
Okay? Good girl.
Come on out, girl. That's right.
That's for you.
Around the neck, Donnie! Around the neck.
Around the neck! Jesus!
(SCREECHlNG)
Donnie, do it now! Open up!
Donnie!
l'm going to sedate her.
-No, no, no, no!
-DONNlE: Door! Get the door! Bright Eyes!
(SClENTlSTS CLAMORlNG)
(ALARM SOUNDlNG)
No, no, no, no.
MAN: Close it down. Close it down now!
Go get help. Donnie! Donnie! Come on.
There have been absolutely no side effects
associated with 1 1 2.
With one exception.
For some reason,
the chimps' irises exhibit flecks of green.
Actually, we first noticed it in chimp nine.
Hence her nickname, Bright Eyes.
You will see when we bring her in.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
MAN: Watch out!
ln theory,
this therapy can be used to treat
a wide range of brain disorders.
lt is virtually limitless.
As are the potential profits, which is why
we are confident that
you will vote to approve human trials.
(SHRlEKlNG)
No! No!
Mr. Jacobs? Mr. Jacobs, l am begging you.
l am begging you not to do this.
Look, it would cost a small fortune
to run lab work-ups on all of those chimps
only to tell me what l already know.
That they are contaminated.
There are lives at stake here.
These are animals with personalities,
with attachments.
-Attachments?
-Yeah.
l run a business, not a petting zoo.
Find the most cost-effective way
to put those apes down.
-l can't do that.
-You're the chimp handler. Handle it.
WlLL: Steven?
-Well, that was fun.
-They've taken the 1 1 2.
The board have rejected your proposal.
They've chosen to advance other programs.
Well, there must be something
that you can do.
Yes, there is. l could fire you.
Believe me, we talked about it.
We have five years of conclusive data.
Parade all the data you want,
you will never convince anyone
to invest another dime.
(CAR LOCK CHlRPS)
This drug has the potential to save lives.
To bankrupt this company, more like.
l swear, you know everything
about the human brain
except the way it works.
(SlGHlNG)
Go back to the drawing board on the 1 1 2.
Start again in molecular development.
Find a way to get there
before someone else does.
And clean up this mess.
(ENGlNE STARTS)
Franklin?
(SOFT COOlNG)
FRANKLlN: They carry small.
She must have been pregnant
when they brought her in.
So that's why...
She wasn't being aggressive,
she was just being protective?
She thought
we were going to hurt her baby.
Come here.
l'd take him myself, but my brother-in-law
works for security.
He'd rat me out in a second.
What, you want me to take it home?
l can't take care of a monkey.
-He's not a monkey, he's an ape.
-Franklin, l...
lt's just for a couple days, until
l find a sanctuary. That's all l need.
Franklin, no.
Look, this isn't my responsibility.
This is company property.
Okay. l'm going to tell you what, Doc.
Jacobs made me put down the other 1 2.
l'm done.
Be my guest.
(CLAIRE DE LUNE
PLAYlNG ON PlANO)
(CHlMP SQUEAKlNG)
-Hey.
-Hi.
-Oh, you look beat.
-Yeah.
How is he doing?
Well, he has good days and bad days.
Today, not so good. Although,
he has been quoting Shakespeare.
(CHlMP SQUEAKlNG)
Oh, you got a pet.
Just a temporary house guest.
Oh. Well, it might be good for him.
-Yeah.
-Good night.
Hey, Dad.
-Dad?
-Will!
(CHUCKLlNG) Hi. l didn't hear you come in.
Today is the day, right?
You thought l'd forget.
You have a big test today, right?
Chemistry?
Hey, Dad, do you want to see something?
What?
(GASPlNG)
What is that? ls he injured?
No, l think that is a birthmark.
"But as for Caesar,
"kneel down, kneel down, and wonder."
Yeah, don't get too attached.
He is a cute little guy, isn't he?
(FAlNT SCREECHlNG)
(CHlMP COUGHlNG)
(COOlNG)
Where are my car keys?
-My car keys! Where did you put them?
-Dad.
You don't drive anymore.
l know that.
Here,
why don't you feed him?
-Can you do that?
-Of course l can.
(SQUEAKlNG EXClTEDLY)
Will, look at this.
How old is he? A day old? Two days old?
Yeah.
Well, he is a smart one, isn't he?
What are you going to name him?
l don't know.
(CHARLES LAUGHlNG)
WILL: Right away, Caesar displayed
signs of heightened intelligence.
So l kept him and brought my work home.
By 18 months,
Caesar was signing up to 24 words.
By age two,
Caesar was completing puzzles and models
designed for children eight years and up.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
At age three,
Caesar continues to show cognitive skills
that far exceed
that of a human counterpart.
Home. Home.
He completed the Lucas Tower
in fifteen moves,
a perfect score.
l maintain my hypothesis
that, A, the green in his eyes
indicates that the ALZ-1 1 2
was passed genetically from mother to son
and, B, that in the absence
of damaged cells that need replacing,
the drug in his system has radically
boosted healthy brain functioning.
And,
he plays chess pretty well.
-CHARLES: lt's my lamp! And my room!
-(lRENA ARGUlNG)
Dad?
-CHARLES: l don't need you here.
-lrena, l'm sorry.
l can't do this anymore.
He belongs in a home.
This is no way for him to live.
CHARLES: Yeah, and no way to live.
No way to live.
Now, it's my lamp. l'm always...
(SOFTLY) lt'll make you better, Dad.
(CAESAR HOOTlNG SOFTLY)
Shh!
(COOlNG)
(LlVELY PlANO MUSlC PLAYlNG)
Dad?
NElGHBOR: Todd!
Come inside for breakfast!
(GRUNTlNG EXClTEDLY)
l'll need to keep track
of what l take from the lab.
Although, l don't foresee you needing
more than one treatment a month.
-Something amazing has happened.
-Yeah.
l'll need a blood test,
and a scan and the dosage.
-You'll have to be carefully monitored.
-Will...
Now if l can sneak some...
-Will!
-Yeah?
l'm not sick anymore.
lt was nothing, Dad.
Caesar. Where's Caesar? l want to see him.
Caesar?
Caesar!
All right, he can't have gone far.
Daddy? Daddy!
Caesar!
-(CAESAR SCREECHlNG)
-NElGHBOR: Get out of here! Get out!
Get out! Get out of here!
Hey, hey, hey! Enough! Enough!
The hell is the matter with you?
lf l see that animal anywhere
near my house or my kids again...
He's not dangerous.
-lt won't happen again.
-Damn right, it won't.
WlLL: Come on, Dad.
He just wanted to play.
NElGHBOR: Stay in the house.
Daddy's got it.
l told you not to go out without us.
Oh, God. lt's okay.
How bad is it?
l don't know.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
(CHlMPS SCREECHlNG)
(COOlNG)
He likes you.
Mmm-hmm.
Don't worry.
lt'll be over soon and we can go get a treat.
l'm thinking ice cream.
(GRUNTlNG EXClTEDLY)
Good idea.
You taught him to sign?
Just a handful of things.
Basic stuff.
What's he saying?
Nothing.
So, when do you think
we should come back?
Well, you won't need to come back
because the stitches are dissolvable.
l would just say
watch out for signs of infection.
Fever, redness.
Okay. What's he saying now?
Well, he thinks that you and l
should have dinner together.
(CHUCKLES) l know.
WlLL: Hey, Caesar. Come on.
Good to see you again, Caroline.
You coming, Caesar?
So, what's your secret?
l can't take any credit. lt's in his genes.
l think you're being very modest.
He's pretty amazing.
l think you've built a pretty good home
for Caesar here.
-But?
-(CAESAR GRUNTlNG)
He won't stay this way for long.
He's gonna soon grow
into a large, powerful animal.
Come here.
(CAESAR CHATTERlNG)
How has he been doing?
Okay. l think.
l love chimpanzees. l'm also afraid of them.
And it's appropriate to be afraid of them.
Caesar would never hurt anyone.
Hey! Hey!
He's happy here. Come on.
Yeah, l can see that.
Can we at least give him some open space?
Yeah. That probably would be a good idea.
l know a place right across the bridge.
The redwoods. lt's paradise.
(CHATTERlNG)
Come on. Come on.
Come here.
He doesn't need a leash.
He'll be fine. Come on.
WlLL: Just to be safe. Come on.
CHARLES: Come on, Caesar.
This is the redwoods.
Caesar? All right.
lf l take this off, you cannot leave my sight.
l would never find you again. Okay.
-What is this?
-What's he doing?
CAROLlNE: l don't believe that.
-What?
-He's asking your permission.
lt's a supplicating gesture.
lt's okay.
CHARLES: Come on, Caesar. Off you go!
(CHATTERlNG EXClTEDLY)
(CHARLES CHUCKLlNG)
Look at him go.
WlLL: Caesar!
CHARLES: Caesar!
-Caesar!
-CHARLES: Caesar!
WlLL: Caesar!
(SlGHS)
There you are.
CHARLES: Caesar?
Go on, Caesar. Climb!
WlLL: Go higher.
CHARLES: Climb!
WlLL: Just be careful.
Caesar, be careful!
(BOTH CHUCKLlNG)
Hi.
What's going on, buddy?
You get some love, too.
Come on, honey.
ls that a chimpanzee?
Hi.
(GROWLlNG)
(DOG BARKlNG)
WOMAN: Come on!
Come on.
(ROARS)
(WHlMPERlNG)
WlLL: Caesar? Caesar.
Come on.
lt's all right. Come on.
All right, come on.
Let's go. You getting in?
Caesar?
You okay, pal?
Are you a pet? No.
You're not a pet.
l'm your father.
What is Caesar?
Okay.
Caesar, this is where l work.
This is where you were born.
Your mother was here
with other chimpanzees.
But she's not here anymore.
So,
that's why l took you home to live with me.
Yeah.
Your mother is dead.
The thing is, she was given medicine.
Like the medicine l give to Charles.
She passed it on to you.
That's why you're so smart.
Let's take him home.
Okay.
Come on, explain it to me.
All right.
l snuck him out of the lab to save his life.
l had no idea that the effects had been
transferred vertically from his mother.
But since then, he's been displaying
incredible signs of intelligence.
l designed the 1 1 2 for repair,
but Caesar has gone way beyond that.
Here is his lQ from last year.
Since then, it's doubled.
This is wrong, Will.
My father was gone.
This drug brought him back.
You never saw how bad he was.
-He has his life again.
-And what about Caesar?
-What about him?
-Where does he fit in?
With me.
With us.
Listen,
l know it's been hard for you,
but you're trying to control things
that are not meant to be controlled.
WlLL: The 1 1 2 works.
CAROLlNE: Do you realize how you sound?
WlLL: All l'm saying is, this is a good thing.
Caesar is proof of that. So is my father.
Caesar, eat your food.
Dad, are you okay?
Yeah, l'm fine.
WlLL: Antibodies.
His system has found a way
to fight the 1 1 2 virus
so that it can't deliver its therapy.
My father's disease
is going to return with a vengeance.
NElGHBOR:
Honey, have you seen the car wax?
CHARLES: lt's a Mustang.
(GRUNTS)
lt's looking great. What did l do...
Stop!
NElGHBOR: You stop right now!
Hey! Hey!
Get out of there! Get out of that car!
What the hell are you doing?
Get out of my car!
l said get out of my car!
l'm a pilot! l got to get to the airport!
How am l going to get there now, huh?
Answer the goddamned question!
What were you doing?
(STAMMERlNG) l have a carjust...
Well, it's not obviously...
That's it, l'm done.
The police can handle this.
You stay right there!
You are going nowhere, mister!
You or your son are going to pay for this!
But l sure as hell am not going to!
This is your problem! You made the mess!
(HOOTlNG ANGRlLY)
-l'm sick of the two of you!
-l'm not going...
You stay right there!
No!
(CAESAR SHRlEKlNG)
(HONKlNG)
(SCREECHlNG)
No!
No! No!
CHARLES: Caesar! Stop!
(NElGHBOR SCREAMlNG)
Daddy!
(NElGHBOR WHlMPERlNG)
No, no.
CHARLES: Caesar!
lt's okay.
lt's okay. You didn't mean it.
(SlRENS WAlLlNG)
Hey. Take that thing off of him.
Will you take that thing off of him?
Come on.
Look. l'll take him in. Okay?
No, he's under court orders.
You can't do that.
LANDON: lt's fine, let him.
Bring him in when you're ready.
-Take it off.
-Thank you.
Caesar, Caesar, Caesar, Caesar? Caesar.
(GRUNTlNG)
Not right now. lt's gonna be okay.
Let's just see what it's like inside. Okay?
(GATE OPENlNG)
Come on, Caesar. Let's go.
Come on. Trust me.
lt's okay.
Go on.
(GRUNTlNG)
(HOOTlNG)
He hasn't spent any time
with other chimps.
We're used to that.
He'll be a little skittish at first,
but we'll integrate him.
You'd be surprised how quick they adapt.
We provide a stimulating environment.
He's going to thrive here.
Come on, let's do some paperwork.
Oh, and make sure you lock that door
when you come in.
(GRUNTlNG NERVOUSLY)
(DOOR LOCKS)
(CAESAR SHRlEKS)
Caesar.
lt's gonna be okay.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Don't be scared.
You're gonna stay here now.
No.
We're not going home right now.
(SOFTLY) lt's okay.
ln our experience,
the longer you drag out the goodbyes,
the harder it is.
Can l just sign that later?
You'll probably miss him
more than he'll miss you.
Best give him a couple of weeks
to get used to the place.
CAROLlNE: Will, we have to go.
We have to go home.
l'm coming back soon. Okay?
Just call ahead before you do.
DODGE: Hey, over here!
Hey, l can get you out!
Come on. Over here.
Come on. Hey. Down here.
(CHATTERlNG)
(MlMlCS CHATTERlNG)
(LAUGHS)
Stupid monkey.
(ALL SHRlEKlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
ls that all you got? Come on!
lt's a madhouse!
Court order hasn't been filed,
so it's not in the system.
Once it comes through,
it'll take about 90 days
before you receive an appeal date.
-90 days?
-Yes, sir, 90 days.
-You'll be notified by mail.
-Hang on.
Right. Here's what's gonna happen.
You're going to go back on your computer,
you're gonna shift things around,
and you're going to get me a date
for my appeal this week. You got it?
l can't help you.
All right, then we have a problem.
Because l'm not moving until you do.
90 days, sir.
Be thankful
you're talking about court dates.
You're lucky
they didn't put that animal down.
WlLL: l promise to get him back soon, Dad.
Dad?
WILL: My father's immune system
continues to reject the 1 12 virus,
rendering the gene therapy obsolete.
His health is deteriorating,
and the disease is progressing rapidly.
l need a more aggressive virus strain.
A faster delivery method.
Because at this rate...
(SlGHS)
l can't lose them both.
l won't lose them both.
Hi. Can we talk?
Make it fast. l've got a meeting.
ln the 1 0 years
you've been running Gen-Sys,
how many drugs
have come down the pipeline
that could save millions of lives,
that could change everything?
What are you talking about?
The ALZ-1 1 2.
(SlGHS)
What happened to you, Will?
You used to be the star of this lab.
Now you hardly ever show,
and when you do,
you waste your time and that
of your team's fixating on a drug that,
after what happened, is never,
ever going to get approved.
The 1 1 2 is dangerous, Will,
and it doesn't work.
l treated my father with it. lt does work.
You did what? You did what?
WlLL: He beat the disease.
Like we predicted.
-Bring him in.
-There's been a complication.
Well, does it work, or doesn't it?
My father's disease
eventually outran the cure.
For goodness sake.
His immune system produced antibodies
that beat the viral component,
but it will work.
l've already developed a virus strain
that l think will be more aggressive.
You think?
Just let me test it.
You're wasting my time.
There's more.
The applications go beyond the disease.
There are indications that show
that therapy can improve
cognitive functioning, memory quality...
(STAMMERS) What are you saying?
My father didn't just recover. He improved.
You mean increased intelligence?
lt's not conclusive, but yes.
l want you to start testing
the revised 1 1 2 on chimps ASAP.
-Okay.
-l'll give you whatever you need.
Absolutely.
DODGE: Dinner time!
(APES CLAMORlNG)
Mmm.
Grade A primate chow.
Go on.
Don't you know food when you see it?
(SNlCKERS)
(RODNEY CLEARS THROAT)
You think that's funny, huh?
(SNlGGERlNG)
l'll show you something funny.
He'll learn who's boss soon enough.
-RODNEY: What about his clothes?
-What about them?
l don't know.
lt might cause problems
with the other apes.
(SCOFFS) Good.
(CHlLDREN LAUGHlNG)
FRANKLlN: l've counted 1 0 apes. Correct?
Yep.
FRANKLlN: Good. All the way to the back.
Okay.
You guys are moving really quick on this.
What's the big rush?
First day back, and you're still complaining.
(CHlMP GRUNTlNG WEAKLY)
Koba. Hi, l'm Will.
(GRUNTS)
Okay. This one.
He's very calm.
Yeah, this guy has seen the inside
of a whole lot of labs.
He knows the drill.
(KNOCKlNG ON WlNDOW)
Thought l'd join you.
Watch our progress.
Get him prepped.
(FRANKLlN CLEARS THROAT)
LAB ASSlSTANT: Tighten your masks.
WlLL: Pass me the 1 1 3.
FRANKLlN: Pulse-ox is good,
blood pressure steady.
LAB ASSlSTANT: Aerosol delivery in place.
Releasing the 1 1 3.
(BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
(ALL SHOUTlNG)
Franklin, get your mask on!
(PANTlNG)
-Got it?
-Yeah.
STEVEN: Tighten the straps.
WlLL: You okay?
Yeah, okay.
Move it! Let's go!
Get up and exercise, you lazy baboons!
(SNlFFS)
(ROARlNG)
(CHATTERlNG)
(GRUNTS)
(HOOTlNG)
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
(PANTlNG)
(KOBA BREATHlNG DEEPLY)
(CHUCKLES)
WlLL: lntelligence results are remarkable.
No adverse effects.
FRANKLlN: Apes have amazingly strong
immune systems.
Yeah. All right, keep an eye on it.
Okay. (SNEEZES)
Sorry about that.
These guys are more resilient than l am.
Excuse me a sec.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hurt bad?
You know sign?
Circus Orangutan.
-(GUN CLlCKS)
-(THUD)
He's good.
Careful. Human no like smart Ape.
l want you working late tonight.
Gen-Sys needs three more of them.
(CLATTERlNG)
Hey. Hey. Hey! (LAUGHS)
-Hey.
-Hey, Caesar. Hi.
Are you hurt?
Show me.
CAROLlNE: Caesar. Give me your hand.
Give me your hand. lt's okay.
Sometimes the new kid on the block
gets picked on.
CAROLlNE: Don't worry.
God, what have they done to you?
That's bullshit. What the hell did you do?
-Let go, man.
-Hey! What's the problem here?
l'm taking him out of here. Right now.
Not without a court order, you're not.
He's not yours anymore.
l promise, if l find out
he's been mistreated in any way,
l'll have this place shut down.
Go on.
Hey. Hi.
Hey.
No.
No, we're not going home right now.
But l'm going to get you out of here.
l promise.
You have to trust me.
Caesar, you have to trust me. Okay?
l think this visit is over.
Trust me. lt'll be okay.
(CHATTERlNG ANGRlLY)
(PANTlNG)
(CAGE DOORS BUZZ)
DODGE: Come on! Move it! Let's go!
(BUCK ROARlNG)
(CAGE DOORS BUZZ)
WOMAN 1 : Wow! There's hundreds of them.
WOMAN 2: This is like your own private zoo.
MAN: More like a prison for hairy dudes.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
WOMAN 1 : They watch TV?
We call it enrichment.
This one's so cute!
What's his name?
The name is Cornelia. lt's a she.
(WOMAN 1 SHRlEKS)
-Oh, my God!
-DODGE: Don't get too close.
WOMAN 1 : This one scared me
half to death.
DODGE: Yeah. That big guy's called Maurice.
No fun.
Here, l'll show you something fun.
Check this out.
(BOTH SCREAMlNG)
MAN: Are you insane?
(STAMMERlNG) You shouldn't be in here.
Hey, you're next!
(DODGE AND MAN LAUGHlNG)
Come on, let's go.
l spend too much time in here as it is.
Come on.
Check out this guy.
DODGE: Hey, that one is a pain in the ass.
Thinks he's special or something.
Freaky.
Hey, come here.
lt's like he's thinking or something...
WOMAN 1 : Oh, my God! He's got his throat!
-Let him go!
-DODGE: Let go!
WOMAN 1 : Are you okay?
MAN: l'm okay.
l told you not to get too close, man.
Come on, guys. Let's get out of here.
(THUNDER CRASHlNG)
(CLlCKS)
(GROWLlNG)
(EXCLAlMS)
(ROARlNG)
(GRUNTS QUESTlONlNGLY)
(PANTlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
(MOANS SOFTLY)
(GRUNTS)
(NEWSCASTERS CHATTERlNG ON TV)
(SlGHS)
Hey.
Some things aren't meant to be changed.
You need to accept that.
Hey!
Hey! What's going on here?
More 1 1 3 trials. We're just prepping...
No, we have to analyze
Koba's blood work first.
Franklin knows this. Where is he?
He's been out sick for two days.
Well, l didn't authorize this.
STEVEN: No.
l did.
We agreed to test sparingly on one subject.
And that one subject is stunning.
lt's a virus,
we don't know the human-related effects.
The drug works, Will. Tell him, Linda.
For starters, Koba scored a perfect 1 5
on the Lucas Tower.
Every test result verifies its effectiveness.
-No more tests.
-What are you...
Not until we have a better understanding
of what we're dealing with.
Look, l'll tell you exactly what we're...
Look. Just give us a minute.
Excuse me, put the ape back in the cage,
and be gentle.
Will, l'll tell you exactly
what we're dealing with here.
We're dealing with a drug
that is worth more than everything
else we are developing combined.
You make history, l make money.
Wasn't that our arrangement?
WlLL: No, there are risks.
Don't talk to me about risks.
You gave your own father
an experimental drug.
l could finish your career
with one phone call.
l'll save you the trouble. l quit.
We will proceed without you.
Look, you don't know what you're doing.
These tests need to be contained.
You have no idea if the 1 1 3 is stable,
what kind of damage it can do to people.
Yes. Well, that is why we test it on chimps.
lsn't it?
(KNOCKlNG)
Dr. Rodman, it's me, Franklin!
l need to talk to you!
Can you come to the door?
(COUGHlNG)
(PANTlNG)
Doc?
-Who the hell are you?
-(SNEEZES)
(COUGHS)
Get out of here!
l'm sorry. l'm sorry.
You wouldn't be trying to entrap me,
would you?
Well, l can't say l approve.
They're not people, you know.
You gonna let him go or not?
Caesar? Hey, come on.
Come on, we're going home.
Home.
Come on, we're really going.
Come on. Let's get out of here.
Yeah.
Come on.
Caesar?
l guess he likes it better here
with his own kind.
(HOOTlNG)
(APES CHATTERlNG)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Why cookie Rocket?
Apes alone...
weak.
Apes together strong.
(CAGE DOORS BUZZ)
Apes stupid.
DODGE: Damn it, Rodney!
You leave the hose out in the atrium again?
RODNEY: What? No!
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG ON TV)
(lNSECT BUZZlNG)
(ALARM BLARlNG)
(CAGE DOORS BUZZ)
Come on! Let's go!
Come on, get up!
REPORTER: Eight months after its launch,
Earth's first manned space flight to Mars...
RODNEY: l swear, Dodge,
l'm telling the truth.
Yeah, well, if you didn't take my cookies
then who the hell did?
-l don't know.
-Hey!
Will you two morons knock it off?
l'm going home.
l get more peace
in the goddamn ape house.
DODGE: Dad, l'm sorry.
-Well done, Rodney.
-RODNEY: l swear...
(APES GRUNTlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
(APES GRUNTlNG lN REPLY)
Mr. Franklin? lt's Dottie.
(lNDlSTlNCT CHATTER ON TV)
Mr. Franklin?
Hello?
(GASPS)
(CAGE DOORS BUZZ)
What the hell?
MAN ON TV: God said, "Let the waters
bring forth moving creatures..."
DODGE ON RADlO:
Rodney, get to the platform now.
Rodney!
What the hell do you think
you're doing, huh?
Get!
Go on. Get back in your cage.
l'm warning you.
Go on, get!
That's it.
See? That's what you get! Now get back!
What's wrong with you?
Dumb monkey!
(APES CLAMORlNG)
Take your stinking paw off me,
you damn dirty ape!
No!
No! No! No!
No! No!
No!
(ROARlNG)
(SCREAMS)
No!
(GROANlNG)
l swear l'm gonna skin
each and every one of you!
(PANTlNG)
(APES SHRlEKlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
Caroline, have you been up
to Caesar's room?
(PHONE RlNGlNG)
(SlGHlNG)
No one is answering.
WlLL: Landon?
Will?
Will!
What happened?
(STAMMERlNG) He spoke.
What do you... What?
RODNEY: Your ape.
He spoke.
(PANTlNG)
(CHATTER ON POLlCE RADlO)
COP: What in the hell?
l don't believe this.
DODGE ON TV: ...I'm gonna skin
each and every one of you!
l need someone to coordinate
with the SFPD. Tell them we got a fatality.
-What is it?
-l know where he's headed.
(PEOPLE EXCLAlMlNG)
Len?
SECURlTY GUARD: Let's go.
(APES SHRlEKlNG)
(CAR LOCK CHlRPS)
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
-Jacobs.
-Mr. Jacobs, it's Linda from Will's team.
Something horrible has happened.
Franklin is dead, from a viral infection.
The hell are you talking about?
He was exposed to the 1 13.
lt does something to people
that it doesn't do to apes.
WlLL: He'll have to go through the city
and across the bridge.
LINDA: Mr. Jacobs? Mr. Jacobs, are you...
What the hell?
(STEVEN YELLlNG)
Steven Jacobs!
This is my facility. We've had a breach.
We need to get up in the air
and track them down
and destroy them! Okay?
Wait a sec! Wait a second.
Look. You've got to trust me on this! Okay?
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY)
(APES CHATTERlNG)
FEMALE GUlDE: You guys might want
to get your cameras ready.
Normally these guys are quite shy.
(ALL SCREAMlNG)
They just tore through a park
on the north side.
-They're being led!
-Got to hold the button!
-What?
-The button!
They're being led!
These apes are smarter than you think!
We've got to kill the leader!
(SHRlEKlNG)
(PEOPLE SHOUTlNG)
(PEOPLE CLAMORlNG)
(ROARlNG)
(HORNS HONKlNG)
No, you do not tell them
l am stuck in traffic.
You make up something smarter! Hold on.
(PEOPLE SCREAMlNG)
What the...
They're on the bridge.
They're trying to get to the redwoods.
SFPD Police One, this is Air Ops.
Seal off the south end.
What's the status of the mounted units?
OFFlCER ON RADlO: Good to go, sir.
All right.
As soon as they reach you, push north!
(PEOPLE CLAMORlNG)
OFFlCER 1 ON RADlO: North side,
we're going to push them right to you.
OFFlCER 2: No probIem,
we're ready for them.
North side is locked.
They'll never get through here.
As soon as they hit the gap,
we'll take them out!
-You're going to shoot them?
-Like shooting fish in a barrel.
Good.
Turn that thing around. Keep moving.
Get off this bridge, sir.
-No, you don't understand.
-You don't understand!
Get off this bridge now!
This is an evacuation. Get out!
-All civilians clear.
-MAN ON RADlO: PIease confirm.
Get these people off the bridge!
Wait!
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
Go up.
Get under.
Stand by to send in mounted units.
They're gonna slaughter them.
-l'm going to get Caesar.
-Hey. Hey, hey.
Listen.
You be careful.
Hey!
Get down from there.
You're not allowed up there.
But l have to get to my car! Let go of me!
l've got to get to my car. lt's important!
Hey!
OFFlCER: Push them north!
Get out of the way!
(SNARLS)
(ROARS)
(GRUNTlNG)
No!
STEVEN: Quick or you'll lose them
in the fog!
Do it!
(SCREAMlNG)
Where are they? l can't see them.
CHP North, do you have a visual?
No, sir. Negative.
(APES GRUNTlNG)
Safeties off!
(RlFLES COCKlNG)
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
(HORSE WHlNNYlNG)
(ROARlNG)
(EXCLAlMlNG)
(SHRlEKlNG)
OFFlCER 1 : Get back! Get back!
Everybody, pull back!
(SCREAMlNG)
(ROARS)
Caesar!
(PANTlNG)
(HELlCOPTER APPROACHlNG)
That's him. That's the leader.
DlSPATCHER: 255, come in! Are you there?
(BOTH GRUNT)
(ROARlNG)
(GROANlNG)
STEVEN: Help me.
Help me.
(GROWLlNG)
Take my hand.
Come on. Come on.
(SCREAMlNG)
Come on.
No.
Not you.
No! No!
Stupid monkey!
Caesar!
Caesar?
(SNARLlNG)
(GRUNTS)
Caesar.
l'm sorry. This is my fault.
This has to stop. This isn't the way.
You know what they're capable of.
Please come home.
lf you come home, l'll protect you.
Caesar is home.
Okay.
Go.
(EXHALES)
RADlO ANNOUNCER: An unknown group
have caused a major disturbance
here in the Bay Area,
including the City Zoo
and the Golden Gate Bridge,
causing widespread damage
and some reported injuries.
Eyewitnesses have also reported
seeing apes running through the city.