Encoded by m@husni
the year was 1891
storm cloud were
brewing over Europe.
France and Germany were
at each other's throats
the result of a
series of bombings
some said it was nationalists
others, the anarchists
but as usual
my friend, Sherlock Holmes
had a different
theory entirely
bombing in strasbourg,
read all about it!
Thank you - anarchists suspected
in strasbourg bombing!
When did you start working
for the postal service?
That was you back there?
It's shame your activities
have landed you in the gutter
a curious parcel? Who's
the intended recipient?
Why don't we discuss that
over dinner tonight?
- I'm free for lunch.
- Hmm.. I'm not
how about at savoy,
eight o'clock?
Splendid
and will you becoming
as yourself?
Most likely
three men have been following
you for the last half mile
their motives highly unsavoiry
no
oh, and by the way,
they're not pursuing me
they're escorting me, and instead
of three, there seems to be..
Ah.. Four
steady hands with that Irene
oh, I don't think it's my
hands you've to worry about
now, be careful with the face boys,
we do have a dinner date tonight
don't fill up on bread
I've got the rest of it
uhh, it's coming back now
hey, youths!
Now comes to lot 34.
Egyptian sarcophagus of
outstanding Providence
retrieved from the
valley of the kings
your payment, doctor..
He sends his thanks
who will bid, one
hundred pounds?
One hundred pounds!
Please give this to
him, he's expecting it
tell him our friend thinks I
delivered it to his sister
ah, stay
while I check the contents.
- I was assured full payment would be there.
- Yes
but assured by whom? Have
you ever met him in person?
All likely...
Hold it, hold it, hold it...
Don't move it!
Judging from its size and weight,
it's not payment you were expecting
I'd wager the contents are
rather more incendiary
- who is this?
- It's..
Hello, darling.
Oh dear... I told
you not to move it
it seems a secondary
charge has been activated
sweet thing, I might need your help
in the disposal of this parcel
1600, 1700..
- 1800..
- Well, good luck!
One million pounds!
Oh... and uhm... by the way, fire..
Fire!
Leave my side and you'll
be dead within an hour
and don't be late for dinner
I expect that my schedule be quite tight
because of these activities here.
- I'm never late in my life, only early.
- Passionately
hmm... hmm... very witty, so
confident even in retreat
I'll hold on to that.. We'll
read it together during aperitif
all right..
Dinner and a show
stay! Trust me.. This is
what I do for a living
hey hoffmanstahl, you
should count yourself lucky
this faceless man with whom
you find yourself in business
is no ordinary criminal
he's the Napoleon of
crime, fortunately..
You now have me as an ally
I'm a consulting detective
of some repute...
Perhaps you've heard of me..
My name is Sherlock hol..
Holmes..
Ah.. Fresh pot of tea,
thank you, George
yes, miss adler
fine choice, this place
do you have the letter?
It was taken
taken? Now that is unfortunate
during the chaos created
by your package
perhaps if you had
shared your plans
you wish to know my
plans now, do you?
Did you imagine miss adler, that
something would happen to you?
Is that why you chose to meet
here, in a public place?
Your favorite restaurant
I don't blame you
I blame myself
it's been apparent me for some time that
you had succumbed to your feeling for him
and this isn't the first occasion
mister Holmes has inconvenienced me
in recent months
the question is
what to do about it?
But
that's my problem to solve now
I no longer require
your services.
Mrs. Hudson?
Ooh, Mrs. Hudson?
Holmes, you in there?
Your hedge needs trimming..
Where am I?
Okay, where you are,
as long as you ready.
I'm waiting..
I'm not going to play this game
remember I have to
catch the last..
Train
- o oh..That's you there, I'm afraid..
- You win
I lose.. Game over
still don't see me?
(French) What a surprise
I'm not going out with
you dressed like that.
Would you prefer I joined you in the fashion
folk pathway and fine military dress...
With that hedonist hand-made scarf..
Clearly, one of your fiancé's early efforts?
- Oh... how I've missed you, Holmes.
- Have you?
Why?
I've barely of noticed your absence..
Then again I'm knee deep in research
extracting fluids from the
adrenal glands of sheep
and designing my own
urban camouflage
all the while verging on a decisive breakthrough,
in the single most important case of my career
perhaps of all time.
Mrs. Hudson, how are you?
Ohh.. I'm so pleased to see you, doctor..
Thank you for inviting me tomorrow
and thank you for
looking after gladstone
dear... dear sickly sweet nanny
might I have a word?
Yummy..
Feed the snake, woman
you feed it!
Touchy touchy.
Doctor, you must get
him to a sanatorium
he's been on a diet of coffee,
tobacco, and cocoa leaves
he never sleeps
I hear multiple voices, as
if he's rehearsing a play
leave him to me
don't you have a goat
that needs worming?
Oh, how kind of you to remind me
so much to look forward to..
What would I do without you?
Good luck on patient, doctor
why are you here?
I'm getting married, tomorrow?
Oh, embrace me!
Watson's getting married
- you lost a few pounds.
- Less than you picked them up
nurturing on Mary's
muffins no doubt
pour us a Brandy..
Stag party has begun
it's our last adventure Watson
I intend to make the most of it
I see you've made good
use of my old office
- do you like my spider's web?
- Is that what you call it?
Follow that strand
question..
What do a scandal involving
an Indian cotton tycoon,
the overdose of a
Chinese opium trader..
Bombings in strasbourg
and vienna,
and the death of a steel magnate
in America, all have in common?
Well, according to your diorama
Professor James moriarty
indeed
mathematical genius
celebrated author and lecturer
boxing champion at Cambridge,
where he'd made friends with
our current prime minister
do you have any evidence to
substantiate your claim?
Hmm.. This..
Now do you see?
Doctor hoffmanstahl's death?
Yes, I've heard you speak of
him extolling his virtues
oh, hoffmanstahl was at the forefront
of medical innovations, a true pioneer
just the other day, I averted an
explosion that was intended for him
it says here, he
died of heart attack
has all my instruction
been for naught?
You still read the offical
statement and believe it?
It's a game dear man, a shadowy game..
We're playing cat and mouse,
the Professor and I..
Cloak and dagger..
I thought it was spider and fly
I'm not a fly, I'm a cat
not a mouse, but a dagger
you're drinking embalming fluid
oh yes.. Care for a drop?
- You do seem..
- Excited?
- Manic.
- I am!
- Verging on..
- Ecstatic?
Psychotic.
- I should've brought you a sedative.
- I'll give my life to see his demise
he must be stopped.. Before his evil
machinations come to a crescendo
and how will you do all that?
Don't be a dingy bird, bad people
do bad things because they can
no one.. Not the victims, the police,
the governments, not anyone!
- Except the great Sherlock Holmes.
- Correct
on this diet, will
work it all out
right
- or thereabouts.
- Thereabouts - not quite that
here's to your good health
dingy bird!
What you did to gladstone now?!
Ricinus communis the
fruit is highly toxic
he's barely breathing!
It was an excellent opportunity..
This may be just the thing
I hope you don't mind terribly
if I tried my adrenal extract
how many times are you going
to kill my dog, Holmes?
He took off like a
monkey from a box!
- I may need one of those in a few hours.
- Consider it a wedding gift
Watson, might we use
an alternative exit?
- Is there something different about you?
- I'm under observation
- as you should be.
- You drive
will your beard, be
with us all night?
I'll remove it once we're
South of trafalgar square
if you believe moriarty has
you under observation,
isn't this a bit conspicuous?
It's so overt, it's covert.
Trafalgar square
we must be safe by now
why are you looking at
me with such concern?
I'm so very worried
your vitality's been
drained from you
- marriage it's the end, I tell you.
- I think of it as the beginning
- armageddon!
- Rebirth!
- Restriction!
- Structure!
- Answering to a woman?
- Being in a relationship
a life in matrimony, the
possibility of a family,
who wants to die alone?
So, we'll have a good old fashioned romp tonight,
you'll settle down have a family.. And I'll...
Die alone..
Yes that's about it
perhaps it's better for one to die alone than to..
Live life in eternal purgatory
anyway
not bad, that
so, where are we going?
(Mycroft) In the future, there will be one
of those machines in every town in Europe
loitering in the
woodshed again..
- Are we, my king?
- Good evening, Shirley
I see your boot maker
is ill, dear brother
as I detect that you've recently changed
the brand of soap, with which you shave..
May I point out the chimney in the front room of Baker
street, is to the need of a damn good sweeping out..
Are you aware that the hackney carriage by
which you arrived, had a damaged wheel?
Yes, the left
and it's plain to the meanest intelligence that
you've recently acquired a new bow for your violin
same bow, new strings
and may I deduce, mycroft..
- Good evening, by the way.
- No!
He doesn't
may I deduce, that you who
rarely strays from the path..
Runs from your home to
the diogenes club..
And never on a Monday.. When they
serve your favorite potted shrimps..
Must be here for some far more
important reason than my stag party
you know, he's nothing like as slow-witted as
you've been leading me to believe, Shirley
you're quite right,
doctor Watson
but with all the conflict
in Europe at the moment..
The whole situation could..
Excuse me, suddenly erupt..
I'm here, to avoid
a dire catastrophe
if the concerns of two nations
which shall remain nameless..
But I can tell you they
speak French and German
are not dealt with tonight I shall
be forced to go to Switzerland
to attend a ghastly peace
summit in richtenburg
first thing about the Switzerland
is the altitude...(Fading)
I'm so glad you invited
your brother..(Sarcasm)
- This looks promising.
- And your poison of choice gentlemen?
We'll start with the champagne,
we may need several more chairs
perhaps a good cigar
and uhm.. Don't bother
with the chairs
what is it your brother does exactly?
- He is the keeper of the broom covet of state,
no ambition, no energy
and I'm repeatedly told,
that he's indispensable
to the British government
particularly the foreign office..
I would like to propose a toast
really?
To my dear friend, doctor John..
Ummm... Hamish.. Watson..
- I'm right here.
- On the Eve of his wedding, he...
- Has been the best of companions.
- Shouldn't we be waiting?
- For the boys from my rugby club?
- He's always kept us
- they could've attend flat footed on the ground.
- All of them?
- Hmmm.. What about the chaps from my medical school?
- I attempted they declined
- the lads from.
- There's no man better
- who is it your looking for?
- Worth having at your side.
- I don't know a single damn person here, do I?
- There's no need for hysterics
you know me, and
you know mycroft..
Don't be a pounce, Watson
pounce?!
You completely forgot about
my stag party, didn't you?
- Why are we here?
- Your in very good health doctor
shame none of your
friends could make it
I'm going to the gaming tables
I refuse for this night to be a
total loss, give me my money!
Happily... give me
the wedding ring!
Oh... now you are interested
in being the best man
you're suppose to
keep the ring anyway
just as you're supposed
to organize my stag party
you don't want to lose
it on a bet John...
And invite my friends, which
by the way, there are many
you're the one with no friends,
surely no mates..
He's all me, me, me, isn't he?
Please sit
put your money on the
table and we will begin
welcome, I'm madame simza
cards can illuminate your past
clarify your present,
and show you the future
if you have a specific
question, hold it in your mind
- hold it.
- Let me know when your ready
actually, I prefer to read..
Your fortune
temperance
inverted..
Indicative of volatility
a woman who recently
taken a confident drink
from what does she seek solace?
What does she wish not to see?
Ah, a fool embarrassing himself?
Oh, yes the fool
someone had been led astray, involved
in something without their knowledge
not bad, but um.. You have
to make me believe you..
I have to see it in your eyes
I can do better
the two of cups, a powerful bond..
But between whom?
A brother and a sister perhaps?
And I see a name.. Yes it's..
Rene
what do you want?
The devil
why are we playing this game?
- Where did you get this?
- I stole it from a woman in an auction room
but I believe it was
intended for you.
SIM my love, remember my face
as you never see it again..
That is the price I must pay, to
change the course of history..
I have finally found
my purpose in life
so the question I've been holding is,
what purpose is rene fulfilling?
Time is up
I have other clients
though you may not have detected
the wisp of astrakhan fur
snagged on a nail
from my left shoulder
you couldn't have failed to notice the
overpowering aroma of herring pickled in vodka
in tandem with a truly
unfortunate body odour
there's a man concealed
in the rafters above us
a cossack, renowned for the
invisible acrobatic abilities..
And are notorious for their
hunting, as assassins
so it's safe to presume that your
next client, is here to kill you
anything else? No?
First, pillage the nest
clip wings
now blunt his beak
crack eggs
scramble pinch of salt
touch of pepper
flip the omelette
additional seasoning required
breakfast is served
come with me I need
you alive, now!
Didn't see that in
the cards, did you?
Carry down folks, carry down..
Looks like we get ourselves
our next cock fight
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.. Let him go!
Get after him!
All mine?
Now, wait a minute
- you're right, it is sting.
- Hey, you you run, where, where's you...?
Just had a fight!
- You just had a fight?
- Yes
where were you?
I am glad to see you're taking your
best man duty so seriously, Sherlock
I was on my own.. You're
not gonna get my moneys!
She was biting my leg
I'll have carruthers put some fuel into that motor
carriage of yours.. You do have a wedding to attend..
Oh, I'll drive..
- Another drink?
- I don't know, I think you've had quite enough
I've been to a
wedding here before
a funeral too
the Professor wants to meet
I'd expected to hear
from him sooner..
In light of recent events - and he was wondering if it
would be convenient for you to come by the college ..
This afternoon.. His lecture
concludes at four..
Looking forward..
One side chumney.
Fischerweise... schubert, 1826
(speaking German)
- Give up your foolish trickery.
- This fish you can not cheat..
I hope I'm not intruding
ahh, excuse me.. Please take
these up to Mr. Williams
and make sure he packs
my white tie and tails..
I'll take care of it Professor
I do apologize, I'm off
on a blasted lecture tour
- would you care for some tea or coffee?
- Neither..
- Something stronger perhaps?
- No, but...
Might I trouble you
for an inscription?
The dynamics of an asteroid & lecture
notes by Professor James moriarty
I read that the good doctor
was to be married today
- how was the service?
- Definitive
he'll no longer be party to my investigations,
he's out of the equation, I..
Trust you'll take this
into consideration?
The art of domestic holticulture and
what considerations will you grant me?
- Have you actually read the book?
- I found it compelling
though, I'm primarily intrested
in your more recent, endeavors
I take that as a compliment
I have the utmost
regard for your times
it's a pleasure..
To finally meet you
officially
are you familiar with the
study of graphology?
I've never given it any
serious thought, no
psychological analysis
of handwriting
the upward strokes on the p,
the j, and the m, indicate..
A genius level of intellect
while the flourishes on the lower zone, denote
a highly creative yet meticulous nature
but, if one observes the overall
slant, and the pressure of the writing
there's a suggestion
of acute narcissism,
a complete lack of empathy, and a
pronounced inclination toward..
- No!
- Moral insanity
an answer to your previous request, regarding
doctor Watson, not being involved..
The answer is.. No
the laws of celestrial mechanics
dictate that when two objects collide
there is always damage
of a collateral nature
(speaks Latin) For example..
Two gentlemen, find themselves
at cross of purposes
a young woman torn between them
the strain proves
too much for her
and she suddenly falls ill
with.. Tragic consequences
a rare form of tuberculosis
she succumbed in a
matter of seconds
now
are you sure you want
to play this game?
I'm afraid you'd lose
rest assured
if you attempt to bring
destruction down upon me
I shall do the same to you
my respect for you, Mr. Holmes..
Is the only reason
you're still alive
you've paid me several compliments..
Let me pay you one in return..
When I said if I were assured
of the former eventuality
I will cheerfully
accept the latter
I'll be sure to send my
regards to the happy couple
another time then..
All aboard!
- Which cart are we?
- We should be just... here
first class!
All aboard! All aboard!
Hurry up doctor Watson,
your wife needs you
coming Mrs. Watson
first class champagne.. You do know
how to spoil a girl, Mr. Watson
you're not just any girl
I'm sorry madam, but you can't use the
lavatory while the train's in station
you're Mrs. Watson
give me that bottle
John, there is no where else
in the world I'd rather be
there's no one I'd
rather be with
why do you have a gun stuffed
down the back of your trousers?
Old habits
come in!
- Oh yes, please.
- We didn't order that
- with our compliments, sir.
- Thank you, put it there
open the door, John!
I think it's time
for you to leave
sit down
I agree it's not my best
disguise, but I had to make do
- my God!
- They'll be back
- ohh.. John, shut the door!
- They'll only shoot through it my lovey
- he's right.
- Oh my God!
- I understand.
- Do you?
Terribly inconvenient
we don't have much time!
- How many are we expecting?
- Half a dozen - who are they?
A wedding present from moriarty
lovely ceremony by the way,
many a tears shed in joy
oh John!
- Just a minute, darling.
- Do you trust me?
No
well, then I should have to
do something about that
no...!!
Who's up to bat
next you bastards!
Send out the fastballer!
John, do shut the door!
It had to be done
she's safe now!
In my own defense, I
timed it perfectly
did you killed my wife?!
Did you just kill my new wife?!
Of course not!
What do you mean?
How do you know that.. When you
just threw her off the train?!
I told you I'd
timed it perfectly
what does that mean?
- Calm down!
- Explain!!
By the time I'd explain
we'd both be dead!
I'm sorry madam but you can't use the
lavatory while the train's in station
caution! Phosphorus
highly flammable
that was no accident
it was by design
now, do you need
me to elaborate?
Or can we just crack on?
Come on!
Don't worry old boy, she's as safe
as houses, she's with my brother
I'm on my honeymoon!
Why did you lead them here?
- Why did you involve us?
- There not here for me
there here for you!
Fortunately
so am I
now mind the door!
Good evening
I think you'll find second
class is more comfortable,
the coast is clear
to the South! Quick march!
- Lie down with me, Watson!
- Why?!
I insist
- what are we doing down here?
- We are waiting, I am smoking
- patiently waiting.
- For what?!
Your window of opportunity
make it count!
I said make it count!
How many windows must I provide?
Who'd have known that honeymooning in
Brighton was such a dangerous notion?
Is that all this is about?
By your own admission,
you've never enjoy it there
I've never been to Brighton
or... your just too fragile
to remember at present
tell me that my wife's safe!
I can't do both
I promise
as I said, I timed it perfectly
over here, madam!
I believe congratulations
are in order Mrs. Watson
I'm the other Holmes
you mean there's two of you?
Oh how marvelous, could this
evening get any better?
Why were Mary and I
targeted at all?
Excellent question
the answer is two fold
he's after us
because of you!
I'm afraid you must bear
half the responsibility
here it comes..
Had you and Mary had not been
so hellbent on your wedding,
we could've already
solved this case
there it is..
It's my fault now
all I'm saying is that
the argument could mean
no, it couldn't
that your nuptials were
rather poorly timed
thus
our relationship
relationship?
Very well, partnership
has not yet run it's course
my dear fellow if you could be bothered
to see this through to the end,
I shall never again
ask you to assist me
once more until the bridge
that's the spirit!
Now to the question,
this is so deliciously
complicated
you may be asking yourself
what does a crimial mastermind want
with a simple gypsy fortune teller?
It's about her
brother, I tell you
when we find him and we must
after you find my luggage
go on
wait
where is it were going?
Paris, the most sensible
honeymoon destination of all..
So, why Paris?
Peaches
outside the city of montroy..
There's a gypsy camp famous
for it's dried fruit,
especially peaches
and there we shall find
our fortune teller..
And return her bag
(speaks French)
(Speaks French)
My ticket?
Unfortunately you won't
be needing yours
it's a shame Professor
I was looking forward
to don Giovanni
(speaks French) Thank
you/ thank you
follow meinhard!
(Speaks French)
Stop, thank you
wake up, we're here
brace yourself, were
about to be violated
don't be so cynical
(speaks French)
Good afternoon..
(Speaks French) Madam simza?
(Speaks French) Yes, yes, sir
perfect
they're taking my luggage..
Laugh them away Watson,
I have her bag
(speaks French)
This is her bag
you had her bag
now they have my coat
where is madam simza?
This is simza.
SIM is a goose
I am SIM
nice scarf.. I like
- you hungry?
- Famished.
Madam, this is a glorious
hedgehog goulash
I can't remember ever
having had better
do tell me, when was the last
time you had a hedgehog goulash?
I told you, Watson,
I can't remember
perhaps you've repressed it
that's where we differ,
unlike you, I repress nothing
perfectly normal
how dare you be rude to this woman
who has invited us into her tent
offered us her hedgehog?
Says the man who throws
women from trains
who are you two?
Concerned citizens
why did someone try to kill me?
Your brother has become involved
with a very dangerous man
who clearly believes that rene has
told you something you shouldn't know
I don't know anything
I've been looking for
him for over a year
that was why I was in London
- it's the last place anyone saw him.
- It's clear that your brother loves you
he'd never send you a message
that would put you in harm's way
any information, therefore, would
be, by default, unintentional
has he sent you anything else?
Just a few drawings
let's just see what
they have to tell us
unusual choice of paper, thicker
gauge, designed for a printing press
- and it's the same stock as the letter.
- Hmm..
They smell musty
must have been stored
somewhere cold and damp
what's that? Blood?
Wine.. So, a wine cellar located
near a printing press..
That should narrow it down
there's a wine cellar used by
the anarchist group lapin vert.
Rene was close to their leader
Claude ravache
- a bomb maker.
- I sampled some of his work last week
I was a part of the
movement, so was rene
until it became too
extreme for us.
Ravache knows me
if my brother's back
there, he will see us
go send him a message
whatever you do, don't let
these gypsies make you drink
of course
you dance?
For God's sake, don't dance!
It'll be the death of you
you know what happens
when you dance
oh, good morning, Mrs. Watson
- have you had breakfast?
- I...
Stanley here does a
wonderful deviled kidney.
- Carruthers?
- Morning, sir
telegram for Mrs. Watson
uh..
It just doesn't make any sense
allow me
oh, yes
my most loathed Mary, I do not love
you, I never wish to see you again
..every moment I count away
from you is a blessing
fret not, it's a double
encryption, my dear
that sherly and I have
used since we were boys
if the first letter of the
message is a consonant
then what follows is
the mirrored truth.
- I see.
- Hmm..
Stanley!
You know, although our time together
has been but a brief interlude
I'm beginning to understand how
a man of particular disposition
under certain circumstances,
extreme ones perhaps
might grow to enjoy
the company of
- a person of your gender..
- Hmm
thank you so much
most charming
may? Terribly sorry, thank you
where are you going, Stanley?
Still hiding in basements?
I'm not here to see you
yeah
with your English friends
1189, a seminal vintage
the year of our
glorious revolution
- is he here?
- When freedom triumphed over tyranny
is my brother here?
I haven't seen him
for a long time
you're lying
sit, please..
A letter was received from
rene using this same paper
of course, he took it
with him wherever he went
he's telling the truth..
Rene isn't here
- he was given another assignment...
- By an anonymous benefactor
another englishman
with money, power, who
supported our cause
and now
he dictates our every move
demanding I take responsibility
for his acts of terror
I made a deal with the devil
but after tonight
it will be over
my job is almost done
he's had you plant
another bomb, hasn't he?
Claude, please
these men can help you
I wish they could
you see, gentlemen
he has my wife and children
if you tell us
where the bomb is.
- I'll find a way to help your family.
- That's already taken care of
we have a deal
he and I
no loose ends
there's only one thing I can
do to keep my family safe
- you've less than 10 minutes.
- Don't!
He has no further need of that pistol, why
don't you take it and cover the stairs?
There's only one way
out of this place
right you are
ah, ingenious
that's the one..
Quickly as we can!
You know what to do with
that sandbag, Watson
quick now!
Doctor, could you
secure that leaver?
You could have told me.
Ravache was strong.. He lived for
liberty, he would never take his own life
calm yourself
my brother, he's weak.
SIM, I need you to
take a deep breath
and follow us
to the opera!
News paper: trade conference:
Meinhard at the hotel du triomphe
troller's label:
hotel du triomphe
I was mistaken
- what?
- I made a mistake
he took the shot from here
using a tripod and
a shooting stick
and realized there was
a better position
there's a faint scrape where he dragged
his tripod and set it up.. Here
- 600 yards..
- 650?
Not to mention.. A 7
or 8 mile an hour wind
he would've needed a wind gauge
which he placed here
and put a cigarette down here
can anyone shoot that far?
Not more than half a dozen
men in all of Europe
how many of those men
served in Afghanistan?
- Why?
- Hirschsprung with a touch of tekel
must have fallen out
when he was rolling up
wasn't that the blend
you all smoked?
- Didn't I read something about a colonel?
- Sebastian moran
best marksman in
the British army
dishonorable discharge
he's likely now a gun for hire, this is the
second victim of his, that I've encountered
what better way to
conceal a killing?
No one looks for a bullet
hole in a bomb blast
- he's 20 minutes late.
- He must come soon
I don't have any papers
and I am a foreigner
this climate is exactly
what moriarty wants
the omelette
finelle was divine
but they spared every
expense on the tea
now, shall we compare moods,
or consider what we know?
Last night's bombing
was clearly meant
to look like Germany's
retaliation for strasbourg
however, the bomb was also meant to
conceal the murder of just one man
the man killed by the gunshot was
none other than Alfred meinhard
he makes guns, big guns..
Only days ago, a large share of his company
was bought by an unknown investor.
Moriarty
the clues point in one direction, but
to avoid repeating last night's debacle
I was obliged to collect more
sufficient data, hence my tardiness
train departs in 40 minutes, sir
just the bags!
But..
We have enough time for me
to indulge my little habit
yes
his habit of feeding that urban
species, the feral pigeon
so there are seven mainline
railway stations in Paris
but taking 10 minutes to get
to the jardin des tuileries
where the largest concentration
of the winged vermin may be found
reduces there to one,
the gare du nord
where he will be just in time to
catch the 11:04 train to Berlin
it makes several stops along
the way, one of which is..
Heilbronn..
Exactly, where we must go..
Where meinhard's factory is
it's moriarty's factory now
unfortunately, due
to the bombing
the crossing between France
and Germany is to be closed
I'm afraid our pursuit is over,
unless we can happen upon a comrade
who knows their way
around borders
too English
however, you do make
a fantastic gypsy
certainly smell like
oh no no, I don't
mean be demeaning
it is a nice scarf
no, no, too English..
It'll suit you more
black one is yours,
gray one is mine
- and this is for you.
- Uhumm..
Right
- where are the wagons?
- The wagon is too slow
can't you ride?
It's not that he can't ride
how is it you put it, Holmes?
They're dangerous at both
ends and crafty in the middle
why would I want anything with a mind of
its own, bobbing about between my legs?
Then I shall require a
bicycle, thank you very much
it's 1891.. Could've
chartered a balloon
how can we make this
more manageable?
Here's the fire?
It's not as if Germany
is going somewhere
we know another way
slow and steady wins the race
come on!
We slip in through the loading
bay, find out what he's doing
and we get out
getting out might be tricky
we will get you out
if my brother's in
there, get him out alive
are you happy?
- What?
- At this moment
are you as happy as you would be
on your honeymoon in Brighton?
I'm not going to grace that
question with an answer
are you happy?
- Oh, we're here for another reason? I think we're
- okay.
- Shall we get on?
- Simple question.
- Are we gonna do something?
- Wait here for them to come back around?
- What time is it?
- 3.15
- over there
in the residential part of the
complex should be a telegraph office
send this to mycroft, be
back here on the hour
that's what you get, Mr. Holmes,
when industry marries arms
now put your gun down
it's a bit old-fashioned
what you need is one of these
go on
pick one
machine pistol, self-repeating
takes 1.63 caliber rounds
in one of these
a 10-shot box magazine
- easy enough to load.
- Hmm..
I'd imagine one would have to retract
the bolt to engage the first round
easier done than said
take him to the surgery
I'll find the doctor
come at once if convenient..
If inconvenient,
come all the same
it is schnapps
a telegram was sent from here
this isn't schnapps, it's aquavit,
distilled from potato mash
a common misconception..
Thank you, by the way
who was it sent to?
My horror at your
crimes is matched only
by my admiration at the skill
it took to achieve them
who was it sent to?
You used the anarchists and their
bombs to create a crisis in Europe
nation against nation
under various pseudonyms, you bought,
schemed, or murdered your way
to numerous industries, assuring that
none of it could be traced to you
cotton, opium, steel, now
arms and chemical weaponry
all to be shipped across
Europe in less than a week
everything from
bullets to bandages
now that you own the supply, you
intend to create the demand
a world war
you are familiar with
schubert's work?
The trout is perhaps my favorite
a fisherman grows weary of
trying to catch an elusive fish
out the way, out the way!
So he muddies the water
I'm warning ya
confuses the fish
you were warned
it doesn't realize until too late
that it has swum into a trap
let's try this again, shall we?
To whom did you
send the telegram?
To my..
To my brother mycroft
what are you playing at?
That's not fair..
I've just got one
more question for you
which one of us
is the fisherman?
And which the trout?
Holmes?
- Holmes?
- Uhh..
Take your time,
take your time..
Uh..
Always good to see you, Watson
- what were you thinking?
- Wait
wait..
Well, if you must know, I was thinking
I had him, right where I wanted him
right, crack on then..
Professor
I'm all right, I'm all right
don't waste time attending to me
I'll find them
I'll find them..
Turn in three, two, one
come on, hurry up!
Go!
- Did you see my brother?
- No, but I'm certain he's been here
- where are we going?
- Over that wall
- how do you know I would find you?
- You didn't find me
you collapsed a building on me!
- Where are the horses?
- They're behind!
- We need them.
- You wanna go back?
What's our way out?
That's our way out!
Go! Go!
Come on!
Marko! Marko!
He's not breathing
cradle his head!
Raise his legs!
Bloody, you're not
gonna die on me!
I'm not gonna make
this easy on you
come on, come on!
Come on!
I know you can hear me,
you selfish bastard!
Come on!
I know you can hear
me, you bastard!
His wedding gift..
Terrible dream!
You and Mary and gladstone
and I, were in a restaurant
that satanic pony was there as
well, a massive fork in his hoof!
And he turned on me!
What have you administered?
Your wedding present
who's been dancing on my chest?!
Me..
Why is my ankle so itchy?
Because you have a large piece
of wood sticking out of it
good lord! You, Thomas
I have an important job to discuss
with you, remind me of it later
sit down, drink this
I need to get that out
before it turns septic
- did you call me "selfish bastard"?
- Probably
just leave it in! Leave it!
You are a..
- Oh, you are some sort of..
- Be nice
I'm sorry you didn't
get to Brighton
me, too..
- I think we should go home.
- I concur
we're going home
via Switzerland
what better place to start
a war than a peace summit?
We'll drop in and see my brother,
I'm sure he's missed you
I still don't understand why you
simply don't cancel the summit
the fact is it's going to happen
whether we like it or not
everyone has already arrived
although these gentlemen
may be talking peace
believe me, they're readying
their armies at home
to cancel the summit now
would be tantamount to war
- the telegram, wasn't it clear?
- We have doubled the security, sir
oh, doubled security,
that's comforting
you don't understand the
delicacy of the situation
I passed the telegram
on to my superiors
but they're the one who brought moriarty into
advise on the peace process in the first place
he has positioned
himself brilliantly
he's one of our foremost intellectuals,
he's a personal friend..
Personal friend of the prime
ministery as we all know that
I believe you, but
where's your evidence?
He's too good to leave evidence
he doesn't leave loose ends
oh, he's alive.
Sherly, put that down
what is this contraption? May I have it?
The effect is most invigorating
that's my private and personal supply
of oxygen, and you're not to touch it
this argument is
getting us nowhere
I've arranged for documents to be prepared
which allow you into the ball, carruthers?
Stanley, Stanley
you haven't aged a day, is
that my favorite chutney?
The fact is, we don't
really know what he planned
- it would be another bomb.
- No, it wouldn't be another bomb
that doesn't make sense
why would he attack all the
nations, only to unite them?
It should be an assassination
by alone gunman at close range.
Rene
unfortunately, yes
- you knew.
- I had my suspicions
but having seen who would be
attending, I'm now certain
well, at least we know
who to look out for.
Rene will be the evidence
if we can find him and stop him, we
will perhaps not only save his life
but prevent the collapse
of Western civilization
no pressure
welcome, ambassador
Professor James moriarty
now we're all present
I can tell you that the targets are the
German chancellor and his ambassador
with French prime
minister and his man
and the other nations are really working out
which side to take should hostilities erupt
cause prince Michael, as cousin of
the tzar, and the Russian ambassador
and the archduke Karl Ludwig and
the austro-Hungarian ambassador
the Romanian prime minister
and his ambassador
and of course our prime minister
and the British ambassador
he'll choose a moment when the dignitaries
are assembled, preferably standing still
is there to be an
official photograph?
Indeed, yes in.. Uh..
38 minutes
in which case, we
might as well dance
I've never done this before
just follow my lead
- what do you see?
- Everything
that is my curse
but you don't see what
you're looking for
I thought you'd never ask
over my shoulder
young man, German
uniform, ceremonial sword
got him
professional opinion?
Trauma
major injury
but excellent repair work.
Doctor hoffmanstahl
you did say he was at the
forefront of a medical innovation
we've already seen an
example of his skills
those twins weren't twins
my suspicions were
aroused in heilbronn
when one failed to go
to the aid of the other
I also noticed the discreet but
unmistakable puckering behind the ear
where his skin had been drawn
back, I should've realized then
that they were a
surgical experiment
to see if it is possible to
make one man look like another
his face is no longer his own
what better way to guarantee his
world war, than to make the assassin
one of the ambassadors
that narrows down the
possibility to one of six
you and SIM shall
find her brother
- of this I have no doubt.
- Holmes
you know my methods
and I know where you'll be
no possible solution could be
more congenial to me than this
by the way, who taught
you how to dance?
You did
well, I've done a fine job
be careful
shall we go to work?
Ladies and gentlemen, please,
gather for the portrait
I'm sorry
is this a bad time?
Never better
- would you bring that clock?
- Hmmhh..
We get to play that
game after all
here we are
don't want you to catch a cold
a five-minute game?
If you think you can manage it
we both have two bishops
I may be absent from that
room, but my methods are not
you can't mean doctor
Watson, surely
that doesn't seem fair
right, the surgery
will have left scars
only four of them have the
hairline to hide them
the ambassador that you replaced
with rene, is he still alive?
Would you like me to
recommend your next move?
They're all my brother's
height, right build, but..
Their eyes
their eyes are wrong,
rene has blue eyes
he could be wearing glass
lenses to change the color
in which case, his
eyes will be hurting.
Rene is left-handed
perhaps the assassin
will take measures
to ensure he doesn't
give himself away
like a gambler concealing a tell
I think it might be him
you think?
Your clock is ticking
you have to be sure
may I remind you,
this is blitz chess
a single miscalculation
will cost you the game
if I tackle the wrong man to the
ground, I could start a war
maybe it's less obvious
a nervous tic, a
ﬂutter of anxiety
I expect everyone has a
reason to be nervous tonight
I don't know
so perhaps it's the opposite..
Failure to behave naturally
an actor so consumed
with his performance
that the one characteristic
he cannot accommodate
is spontaneous reaction.
Carruthers, protect
the prime minister!
Germany will pay!
Mark my words!
That doesn't bode well, does it?
Seems your bishop was of
some benefit, after all
the game is still young
actually, it's in
its adolescence
there are more of us!
Germany will pay!
No loose ends
what happened to him?
I'm a doctor, a doctor!
What happened?
- Curare (Muscle paralyzer)
- What's wrong with him?
It's poison
do something!
Doctor, do something!
No
I think you've just lost
your most valuable piece
but a winning strategy sometimes
necessitates sacrifice
a war has been averted
hmm.. Oh, I disagree
how so?
Didn't you find it strange,
that the telegram you sent
didn't inspire any
action to stop me?
You see, hidden within
the unconscious
is an insatiable
desire for conflict
so you're not fighting me, so much
as you are the human condition
all I want to do is own the
bullets and the bandages
war on an industrial
scale is inevitable
they'll do it themselves
within a few years
all I have to do is wait
I like Switzerland
they respect a
man's privacy here
particularly if he has a fortune
bishop takes knight, check!
The game is over
you should get that
shoulder looked at
about that fortune of yours
I believe it's just been
substantially reduced.
King to rook two
I attended several
of your lectures
the equations of motion, which
you will find in my book
the energy that is required to
release these explosions is
it was in oslo when I first caught
a glimpse of your little notebook
red leather-bound from
smythson of bond street
rook to king's
rook three, check!
Bishop to rook three
until I observed your
penchant for feeding pigeons
then it occurred that with
an empire so enormous
even you must keep a
record of it somewhere
bishop takes bishop
rook to bishop four
I then only required
the notebook itself
you didn't make it easy
just the bags
I would dare to endure a
considerable amount of pain.
Mycroft
care of her majesty's
secret service
but the notebook would undoubtedly be
encoded, so how then to break the code?
- Rook takes rook.
- Pawn takes rook
bishop to bishop seven
queen takes knight pawn
does the art of domestic
horticulture mean anything to you?
How could a man as meticulous
as you own such a book
yet completely neglect the flowers
in his own window box? Irony abounds
never mind, it's safe, in London
where my colleagues are
making good use of it
the most formidable criminal mind in
Europe has just had all his money stolen
by perhaps the most inept inspector
in the history of Scotland yard
any chance of a cup of tea?
Box 0403
- tick!
- Box 0801
- how much more is there?
- That's the end of page two
page three..
Be careful what you fish for!
He'll be making an anonymous donation
to the widows and orphans of war fund
bishop to bishop eight..
Discover check!
And, incidentally, mate!
I seem to have injured my
shoulder, would you mind?
Be my pleasure
once we've concluded
our business here
it's important you know
I shall endeavor to find the most
creative of endings for the doctor
and his wife
his advantage, my injury
my advantage, his rage
incoming assault,
feral, but experienced
use his momentum to counter
come now
you really think you're the
only one who can play this game
trap arm, target weakness
follow with haymaker
ah.. There we find the
boxing champion of Cambridge
competent, but predictable
now allow me to reply
arsenal running dry..
Adjust strategy
wound taking its toll
as I feared, injury
makes defense untenable
prognosis,
increasingly negative
let's not waste any more
of one another's time
we both know how this ends
conclusion, inevitable
unless..
A few words may suffice to
tell the little that remains..
Any attempt at finding the
bodies was absolutely hopeless..
And so there..
Deep down in that dreadful couldron
of swirling water and seething foam
will lie for all time..
The most dangerous criminal
and the foremost champion of
the law of their generation..
I shall ever regard
him as the best..
And the wisest man
whom I have ever known
John?
- John.
- Uhumm..
You should probably pack
it's half past two
- and the carriage is coming at four.
- Hmm
it's gonna be a beautiful
week in Brighton
yes, it'll be fun
I'm looking forward to it
you know I miss him too
in my own way
he would have wanted us to go
he would have wanted
to come with us
when's Mrs. Hudson
coming for gladstone?
Oh, soon
three o'clock
Mary?
Who delivered this parcel?
A postman
the usual chap or..
Did he look peculiar?
Encoded by m@husni