MAN 1: What, are you kidding me?
I love Sundays. I live for Sundays.
The whole family is together. Mom
makes braciole. Dad puts the jersey on.
We're all watching the game.
Yeah, it drives me crazy.
And, yes, I was negative.
You didn't even know I loved it, Nikki.
I just didn't appreciate it or you before.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
MAN 2: Come on. Time to go.
PAT: I lost all that. I blew it.
But you also blew it.
We can get it back.
We're gonna get it back.
It's gonna be better now.
I'm better now and I hope you are too.
I'm gonna appreciate...
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
- Be there in a minute.
MAN 2: Doctor's waiting. Let's go.
I'll be there in a minute.
(SIGHS) That's true love.
DANNY: That's when I had long hair.
People say I talk about hair too much.
It's the way I want it,
but he cut it back.
He cut this side to even up.
Didn't tell him that.
- I said, "Just cut the way you cut."
PAT: - Anything's possible.
I think if we get... We often get caught
in this state of negativity.
It's a poison like nothing else.
You can take him out
against our recommendation,
but you assume liability
in the eyes of the court.
And he's getting used
to the routine here.
I don't want him to get used
Eight months
is already long enough.
PAT: Hey, Mom.
Can we give Danny a ride
to North Philly?
What?
- I don't understand.
- Oh, no, it'll be fine. It'll be fine.
I guess everybody leaving today.
Hello, Mrs S.
An honour to finally meet you.
Pat told me how God made you
rich in character.
You're the mighty oak
that hold the household together.
And not to mention the lasagne you
make on game day when the Birds play.
(TRUCK HORN HONKS)
Danny was in for assault
because of crystal meth and alcohol.
- Bad combination.
- On top of an anxiety disorder.
That's when I was an x-ray technician
and I had my ADD and my anxiety.
I had a lot of access to medication
and I took advantage of it.
That's when my hair was long.
My hair only grew when I was older.
When I was younger,
my hair didn't grow...
Remember my brother had a Jheri curl
and I couldn't
- because my hair didn't grow long.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
I was jealous of my brother, but wait.
- Hello?
- It looks great now.
- You like it?
- It's good now.
You're going the wrong way.
- It's this way.
- What?
Are you sure about that?
I'll bring him back right away.
You lied to me, Pat.
Danny's not allowed to leave.
All right, Mom, let's talk about this.
- Mom, just listen.
- Do not touch the steering wheel!
(CAR HORN HONKING)
Pat, this whole thing was a mistake.
I'm sorry, Mom.
- You OK?
- I am out on a limb for you
- with the courts right now.
- It's my fault. Pat didn't know.
He's my friend
so he's rooting for me.
I'm having a disagreement with
the hospital. We're working it out.
Take me to the hospital,
but take Pat home, he's fine. Trust me.
You'll see, he's fine. It's my fault.
Can we stop at the library? I wanna read
Nikki's English high school syllabus.
Mom, it's a good thing.
I'm remaking myself.
RANDY: DeSean Jackson.
What happened to DeSean Jackson?
- Come on, tell me that one.
PAT SR.: - Insanity.
He spikes the ball at the 1-yard line,
the 1-fucking-yard line. I mean, I...
Get into the end zone, dummy. I mean,
he celebrates before he's even in.
You know something? Nothing new.
Your team does that all the time.
They get close and blow it.
They got an inferiority complex.
What are you talking about? What
makes the Cowboys America's team?
- Because we're America's team.
- We're in Philadelphia.
- What's the matter? You're a traitor.
- What's more American than a cowboy?
You know what's more American?
Benjamin Franklin.
- Benjamin Franklin?
- Franklin, the founder of our country.
RANDY: With the glasses,
long, scraggly hair?
PAT SR.: What about the lightning?
He stood in the storm with a kite.
RANDY: If he wasn't on a 100 dollar
bill, nobody would know who he is.
- Why do you got so many?
PAT SR.: - Don't touch.
RANDY: I didn't even touch them.
Don't blame me.
PAT SR.: Who did this?
Who took the remotes like this?
- Did you do this, Randy?
RANDY: - I don't touch them.
I don't know why you need so many.
Hey! Ah, there she is.
- Look how beautiful. Hey.
- What?
- What's this?
RANDY: - Hi.
- Everything good?
PAT: - Mm-hm.
Well...
- Where is it?
- It's right here.
PAT SR.: You got it. Ah.
Well, we don't want them
to steal that.
- You still got yours?
- Yeah, I got mine.
So you don't talk to me?
Didn't tell me you took him?
- Well, he's ready.
- Didn't tell Dad you're picking me up?
- Don't worry about that.
- I wanna make sure you're OK and I...
- She didn't say anything. Didn't tell me.
- The court said yes. Don't worry.
Yeah, but what did the doctor say?
Because the court listens to the doctor.
- The court listens to the doctor...
- Dad, Dad, Dad, relax.
The court said it's fine, OK?
Let it go.
WHISPERS: - Don't worry.
- I'm there because of the court.
That's the agreement we made.
It was a plea bargain with the courts.
The lawyer instructed,
he said we should plead that,
- I serve eight months and get out.
DOLORES: - It's all under control.
(SIGHS)
- Well, OK. OK, congratulations.
PAT: - Thank you.
- So, what are you doing?
- I'm gonna start a restaurant.
- A cheesesteak place.
PAT: - How you gonna pay for it?
PAT SR.: - I'm gonna pay, don't worry.
- From your bookmaking?
- Who told you that?
- Mom told me. Outside.
DOLORES: - No, I didn't.
- You just told me outside.
Five minutes ago, you said:
"Don't say anything, but Dad
lost his job and he's bookmaking."
Why, Dolores?
Why did you say that to him?
He has the wrong idea.
Everything's fine.
I'm more concerned about you
than anything else.
PAT: - Good, Dad, good.
OK, the question is:
What are you gonna do
with yourself?
PAT: I'm getting in shape.
I'm getting trimmed,
getting fit for Nikki.
I'm gonna read Nikki's teaching
syllabus and get my old job back.
You know, she...
Nikki sold the house. She left.
- Didn't your mother tell you she...?
- You don't know about my marriage.
Our marriage...
We're very, very much in love, OK?
Just like you two.
Listen, Patrick, she's gone.
She's not around anymore. Nikki left.
What are you doing, Dad?
You... Excelsior. Excelsior.
PAT SR.: - What does that mean?
- It means
I'm gonna take this negativity
and use it as fuel.
I'm gonna find a silver lining.
And that's no bullshit.
That's no bullshit.
That takes work and that's the truth.
(SIGHS)
What the fuck? Unh!
Stupid fucking book.
Can't believe Nikki's teaching that book.
The whole time. Let me break it down.
You're rooting for this Hemingway guy
to survive the war
and to be with Catherine Barkley.
It's 4.00 in the morning, Pat.
And he does. He does. He survives
the war after getting blown up.
Survives it and escapes to Switzerland
with Catherine.
But now Catherine's pregnant.
Isn't that wonderful?
They escape into the mountains.
They'll be happy,
and drinking wine and dance.
They both like to dance,
which was boring,
but I liked it
because they were happy.
You think he ends it there? No.
He writes another ending.
She dies, Dad.
I mean, the world's hard enough
as it is, guys.
Hard enough as it is. Can't somebody
say, "Hey, let's be positive?"
"Let's have a good ending
to the story?"
Pat, you owe us an apology.
Mom, I can't apologise.
I'm not gonna apologise for this.
You know what I will do? Apologise
on behalf of Ernest Hemingway
because that's who's to blame here.
Yeah, have Ernest Hemingway call us
and apologise to us too.
- Why didn't you run with me, huh?
- I was reading.
Do us a favour, don't read for a while.
Why are you wearing a garbage bag?
- Gonna go run now.
- Wait.
Where are you going?
Wait, you have to fix this window.
- I'll fix it when I get back.
- Now.
Get in the car.
You have to go to therapy.
- I don't wanna go to therapy.
- It's part of the deal.
You can't live with us and not go.
(STEVIE WONDER'S "MY CHERIE
AMOUR" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Is that song really playing?
RECEPTIONIST:
We have music sometimes.
That song is killing me.
- Could you please turn it off?
RECEPTIONIST: - I can't.
- What do you mean?
- Don't have the controls.
- Sorry...
- Did Dr Timbers put you up to this?
Is there a speaker here?
Is the speaker here?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, OK? I'm sorry.
I'll fix all this, OK?
(PANTS THEN SIGHS)
That was a messed-up thing you did,
Dr Patel. I'm sorry, but that's...
PATEL: - You can call me Cliff.
- Yeah, Cliff,
that's not the way
to meet people, OK?
Why don't you write that in...?
I don't know, a little book?
Sorry. I wanted to see
if it was still a trigger for you.
Bravo, it's a trigger.
- I'm not gonna take meds.
- You have to.
No, I'm not gonna.
It makes me foggy...
- You have to.
- I don't want to need meds.
I'm sorry. Look,
I am not the explosion guy, OK?
(SIGHS)
My father is the explosion guy.
I'm not that guy.
He got kicked out of that stadium.
He beat up people,
he's on the exclusion list.
- I had one incident.
- But one incident can change a lifetime.
But I'm ready. I'm ready to take
responsibility for my side of the street.
- She just needs to take responsibility.
- What's hers?
- Mm-hm.
Are you joking?
Well, let's go back to the incident.
I come home from work
after I left early, which I never do,
but I got in a fight with Nancy,
the principal.
I come home and what's playing?
The song.
The song that you so charmingly played
out here for us.
That's playing. I don't think
anything of it. I should have.
I come home, what do I see?
I walk in the door and I see underwear
and clothing,
a guy's pants with his belt.
And I walk up the stairs
and I see the DVD player.
On the player
is the CD playing the song.
And then I look down
and I see my wife's panties.
And then I look up
and see her in the shower.
I think, "That's sweet.
She's in the shower. Perfect."
"I'll go in. We never fuck in the shower
anymore. Maybe today we will."
I pull the curtain back and there's
the fucking history teacher with tenure.
(STEVIE WONDER'S
"MY CHERIE AMOUR" PLAYING)
And you know what he says to me?
"You should probably go."
That's what he says.
So, yeah, I snapped.
I almost beat him to death.
But I get chastised for it? And I'm
parallel to my father? I don't think so.
All right. Can you talk about something
that you did before or after?
Week before the incident,
I called the cops
and I told them my wife and the guy
were embezzling money
from the local high school, which...
...wasn't true. It was a delusion.
And we later found out from
the hospital that's because I'm, uh...
Undiagnosed bipolar.
Yeah.
With mood swings and weird thinking
brought on by severe stress,
which rarely happens, thank God.
And the shower incident happened,
everything snapped,
so I then realised that, "Oh, wow, I've
been dealing with this my whole life."
And without any supervision,
I've been doing it all on my own
with no help.
And basically, I've been like
white-knuckling it this whole time.
- That had to be hard.
- Yeah, it's a lot to deal with,
especially when you don't know what
is happening, which I do now. Sort of.
DOLORES: You have to take
your medication.
PAT: I can't.
DOLORES: I will call them.
- They'll come for you.
PAT: - You wouldn't do that.
- Why call them?
PAT SR.: - What's up?
PAT: I don't feel good when I...
I don't feel good. I'm clear without it.
Makes me bloated.
I don't like the way it makes me look.
Just take the medication.
I'm doing it with my physicality.
Working out, that's what I'm doing.
- Why is he wearing a garbage bag?
- Why are you?
- To sweat.
PAT SR.: - Sit down. Come on.
Seven minutes in, no score.
Help turn the juju around.
I don't believe in juju.
Come on, you wanna be positive?
Be positive.
Sit down. Come on.
PAT: I'll watch the beginning
of the game.
DOLORES: You're good luck.
PAT: What's in your hand?
It's a... It's...
- See? Yeah.
PAT: - Handkerchief?
TV ANNOUNCER: And they give it
to DeSean Jackson, takes it downfield.
That's OCD. That's crazy.
What OCD? I want my son
to watch with me, sue me.
No, just sit down. Come on.
I want you to watch the game with me.
I'm not superstitious.
A small thing that I do. If I make money
what's the difference if I do this?
It's a small thing.
Sit down. Come on.
I'm making crabby snacks
and homemades.
- Touchdown!
(ALL YELL)
- Oh, whoa!
PAT SR.: - You see? You see that?
You're meant to be here. This is special.
Everything happens for a reason.
(PHONE RINGING)
That's why you came home.
Embrace it. Embrace it.
PAT: I'm the reason?
I don't think so.
PAT SR.: Yeah, Tommy.
Tommy, yes, yes.
I got your whole sheet. Yup.
No, no. I'm just confirming. OK.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
- Wait, wait.
- Can I do an interview
- on mental illness?
- No. Don't pay any attention.
- Who was that? Rick D'Angelo?
DOLORES: - That's him.
- Guy who's having the problem?
- People are stupid.
Don't let them hurt your feelings.
Patrick.
DOLORES: Pat, don't look for Nikki.
PAT SR.: Get out of here
with that camera.
- Patrick, please.
- Pat.
- Patty. Patty.
- Don't look for Nikki!
(ALABAMA SHAKES'
"ALWAYS ALRIGHT" PLAYING)
PAT: Miss Metgers!
METGERS: Oh, God. Oh, God.
Nance. It's my lucky day.
Look at you working on a Sunday.
- How are you? Hey.
- What are you doing here?
I just came by to say hi,
I'm ready to work.
- You shouldn't be here.
- Full-time, half-time.
I'll work, I'll sub,
I'll work history, whatever.
Let me give you a hand. Sorry.
- I got it. I got it.
- Let me ask you something.
- Does Nikki still work here?
- Can't tell you.
- But Doug Culpepper is.
- Why would you tell me that?
He broke up my marriage.
Are you being a troublemaker?
You look good.
Did you lose a lot of weight?
- I did. Yeah, I did. Thank you.
- Aah! Get away from me. Get away.
OK, all right. I'm better.
I'm better now. OK, I'm better.
I feel so good. Look at my eyes.
Look how clear they are.
- Don't hug me.
- Not a complainer, I'm positive.
You have to give it time.
A lot went down.
- People will get over it. It'll work out.
- I'll take that as a silver development.
- That's a silver lining.
- Good luck.
Ronnie. Pat.
- There he is. He's back.
- Hey.
- Welcome home.
- Thank you.
- Welcome back, man.
- I'm out.
Yeah, you're "out" out? Cool.
You lost a lot of weight.
I didn't recognise you.
I'm sorry I didn't visit you.
Work's out of control.
You know, she had the baby.
I'm really glad you're back.
I miss you.
I really need someone to talk to.
Come see the baby. She's beautiful.
Veronica wants to make dinner for you.
Congratulations on the baby
but I'm not buying the invitation.
Because you think Veronica
still hates you?
- I know Veronica still hates me.
- That's not true.
Yes, it is. Nikki always said that
Ronnie's wife keeps his social calendar
- where she keeps his balls, her purse.
- That's not true.
VERONICA: - What are you doing?
- OK, it's a little true.
If you think she still hates you,
you're wrong
because why would she
invite you to dinner, hm?
- Did you invite him?
RONNIE: - Yes!
Well, can he make it?
I don't know yet!
- Can you make it next Sunday?
- Sure.
- I'll see you next Sunday.
- You are still in touch with Nikki, right?
- Does Veronica still talk to Nikki?
- Yeah.
- Get in here, please. I need you.
RONNIE: - OK.
As soon as you left, Redskins threw
a trick play, a pitchout to Randal El.
Andy Reid wastes a timeout challenging,
loses the challenge, the game.
You're in this house,
show some respect for what I do.
And we should spend time together.
I'm keeping you out of trouble.
PAT: I have very, very good news.
Very good news.
What's that? What's the good news?
PAT: - Things are looking up.
- Oh, are they?
I knew why they invited me over.
I know.
- She might be with that guy.
PAT: - Oh, no way.
- No, she might be with him.
PAT: - No way, Dad.
- She's afraid. She doesn't wanna talk.
- Doug Culpepper?
- Put the phone down. Please.
- What are you doing?
PAT SR.: - Stop.
- Look, look... Dad, Dad.
- This is my life.
- Give me the phone.
Give me the phone. Gotta
understand me. You wanna go back?
Stop this. Don't do this.
- Don't yell at me like that.
- Well, then don't behave this way.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
I got a call to check on this house.
Pat Solatano? Yeah?
Mrs Solatano, Mr Solatano,
I'm Officer Keogh.
I heard about the restraining order.
You went to your old house, school.
It's not OK.
I've been assigned to your case,
you'll see a lot of me.
Do yourself a favour. Respect the
restraining order. Five hundred feet.
You hear what he just said?
You have a restraining order.
- Yeah, I know.
- Thank you.
If you need anything, my card.
- Thank you. Sorry. We understand.
- Since when do cops have cards?
Tell me, would you like to be a guy
who goes back to jail
or to the hospital? Hm?
So take your medication.
- If you do fine, we'll reduce them.
- Nikki's waiting for me to get in shape,
get my life in order,
then she's gonna be with me.
And that's better
than any medication.
Pat, there's a possibility,
I want you to be prepared for it,
she may not return.
True love is about letting her go
and see if she returns.
Meantime, if you listen to that song,
I don't want you to fall apart.
So get a strategy, OK?
You need one.
- Let me say... Gonna say something.
- OK.
This is what I believe,
this is what I learned in the hospital.
You do everything you can,
work your hardest.
And if you do, if you stay positive,
you have a shot at a silver lining.
- Work on a strategy, OK?
- All right.
My friend Ronnie is having this party
on Sunday,
and it's like a real hoity-toity thing
and his wife Veronica's
a real stickler for...
Mom got this Gap outfit
she wants me to wear,
but I wanna wear a jersey
Jake got me from the Eagles.
- Which jersey?
- DeSean Jackson.
DeSean Jackson is the man.
Well, that settles that.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
RONNIE: Pat! What are you doing?
- I gotta go, man.
- Why?
I made a mistake.
I shouldn't have worn this.
I like that jersey.
I wish I was wearing that jersey.
- Are you comfortable?
- Veronica's not gonna like it.
Guest of honour.
Come however you wanna come.
- Really?
- Get over here.
DeSean Jackson's in the house.
- You mean rookie of the year?
RONNIE: - Yeah.
DeSean Jackson? DeSean Jackson?
Oh, you wore a jersey to dinner.
- Isn't it awesome?
- Not for dinner.
- Look, he got us flowers.
- Oh, aw, that's sweet. That's sweet, Pat.
- That's lovely. Hey.
- And wine.
Check this out.
We just redid the whole thing.
- Wow. Tremendous.
- Isn't it great?
- Yeah. I'm thinking of redoing it again.
- Why?
- You're making a lot.
- We're doing all right. I can't complain.
- Isn't the market down?
- It is.
But she wants more
so I'm giving her more, man.
My dad lost his pension.
- Sorry. A lot of people. My uncle too.
- Really?
No disrespect, it's not personal,
but this is the time to strike.
You start snapping up
commercial real estate, cheap.
You flip it over
and that's when you make the money.
But the pressure. Man, it's like...
- You OK?
(WHISPERS) I'm not OK.
Don't tell anybody.
Listen to me.
I feel like I'm getting crushed and...
(WHISPERS) - Crushed by what?
- Everything. Family, the baby, the job.
The fucking dicks at work,
and it's like, you know...
Like, I'm trying to do this, you know,
and then I'm, like, suffocating.
Holy shit.
You can't be happy all the time.
- Who told you you can't be happy?
- Do your best, you have no choice.
- Not true at all. Ronnie, Ronnie.
- You just can't.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
I hope you're OK with Veronica's sister
coming over. OK with that?
- Who?
- Veronica's sister.
- Tiffany and Tommy?
- Tiffany. Yeah. Just Tiffany.
- What happened to Tommy?
- He died.
- Tommy died?
- Cops die.
- How'd he die?
- Don't bring it up.
- No, how did he die?
- How did who die?
Hey, Tiffany. This is Pat.
Pat, my sister-in-law Tiffany.
You look nice.
- Thank you.
- I'm not flirting.
I didn't think you were.
I see you made an effort.
I'm gonna be better with my wife.
I wanna acknowledge her beauty.
I never used to do that.
Gonna do that.
We're gonna be better than ever, Nikki.
Just practicing. How'd Tommy die?
What about your job?
- I just got fired, actually.
- Oh, really? How?
I mean, I'm sorry.
How'd that happen?
Does it really matter?
Baby, how's it going?
RONNIE: Great, great. (LAUGHS)
VERONICA: Everyone having fun?
Oh, baby, can we
show them the house?
- Please, please, please.
RONNIE: - The whole house?
VERONICA: Yeah. It'll be fun. It'll be
fun. We're gonna go on a tour now.
- Let's go see the house.
RONNIE: - Let's go for the tour.
VERONICA: I've been planning
this forever. I love our house.
- I'm really excited about it.
- Come on.
VERONICA: Guess what it is.
PAT: Oh, it's a television.
- It's a computer screen.
RONNIE: - Nope.
- Keep going.
- A brick oven.
- It's a light.
- Oh, warmer.
It's a drawer where they pull out dead
bodies, shoot them with formaldehyde.
- Where would the body go though?
- It's a joke.
It's a fireplace.
In the middle of the wall?
We have a port in every room.
Who doesn't have an iPod?
I don't have an iPod.
I don't have a phone.
They won't let me.
They think I'm gonna call Nikki.
- Don't worry about it.
- I would call Nikki.
I'm gonna give you
one of my iPods.
Give me your iPod.
Give it to me. Thank you.
TIFFANY: Of all the rooms
there are iPod ports in,
I'm happy you brought us
into the bathroom.
I can play music in any room.
Can you play "Ride the Lightning"
by Metallica?
("BRAHMS' LULLABY"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
Pat was a history sub
at the high school, Tiffany.
Ask him about any president,
knows them all.
Here's a fun fact. You know
where the term OK comes from?
VERONICA: No. No, I don't.
- Where?
- Martin Van Buren,
eighth president of the United States,
is from Kinderhook.
He was part of a club,
a men's club called Old Kinderhook.
And if you were cool, you were in
the club, they'd say, "That guy's OK."
- In the Old Kinderhooks.
- Really?
PAT: Pretty cool, right?
RONNIE: Interesting.
Tiffany's been doing this dance thing
for years. She's real good at it.
She'll be competing
at the Ben Franklin Hotel.
- Really? Nikki loves dance.
- Why do you have to talk like that?
I'm bragging about you. Can I brag?
- Don't talk about me in the third person.
VERONICA: - Give me a break.
- I'm right here.
VERONICA: - Just be nice. Just be nice.
- Wow, wow, wow. Fascinating.
- Sorry. I don't wanna be mean.
I know. I know. I know.
- What meds are you on?
- Me? None.
I used to be on lithium,
and Seroquel and Abilify,
but I don't take them anymore, no.
They make me foggy
and they also make me bloated.
Yeah, I was on Xanax and Effexor, but
I agree, I wasn't as sharp so I stopped.
- You ever take Klonopin?
- Klonopin? Yeah.
- Right?
- Jesus.
- Like, "What? What day is it?"
- Yeah. (LAUGHS)
- How about trazodone?
- Trazodone?
It flattens you out.
I mean, you are done.
- It takes the life right out of your eyes.
- God, I bet it does.
- I'm tired. I wanna go.
VERONICA: - No, no, no. We haven't...
We haven't finished the salad yet
or the duck...
I made fire and ice cake.
I said I'm tired.
Are you gonna walk me home
or what?
- You mean me?
- Yeah, you. You gonna walk me home?
You have poor social skills.
You have a problem.
You say more inappropriate things than
appropriate things. You scare people.
- I tell the truth. You're mean.
- What, I'm not telling the truth?
Um, maybe I should drive them home?
No, you can drive them
both home. Now.
Stop talking about me in third person.
You love it when I have problems.
You love it because then
you can be the good one.
No, I don't. I don't.
- I just wanted to have a nice dinner.
TIFFANY: - God.
VERONICA: What is your problem?
Nothing's my problem.
I'm tired, I wanna go.
VERONICA: - You really wanna go?
- I really wanna go.
- It's been great.
- The baby is sleeping.
- Sorry, I don't wanna wake up the baby.
RONNIE: - Sorry, man.
TIFFANY: This is me.
I haven't dated
since before my marriage,
so I don't remember how this works.
How what works?
I saw the way
you were looking at me, Pat.
You felt it, I felt it.
Don't lie.
We're not liars like they are.
I live in the addition,
separate from my parents' house,
so there's no chance of them
walking in on us.
I hate that you wore a jersey
because I hate football,
but you can fuck me
if you turn the lights off, OK?
How old are you?
Old enough to have a marriage end
and not wind up in a mental hospital.
I had a good time tonight.
I think you're pretty,
but I'm married, OK?
(TIFFANY SCOFFS)
You're married?
So am I.
No, that's confusing. He's dead.
Wait, what? What's happening?
(TIFFANY SOBBING)
Oh, my God.
Hey.
(LED ZEPPELIN'S "WHAT IS AND
WHAT SHOULD NEVER BE" PLAYING)
Are you OK? Ronnie called.
- That makeup on your shirt?
- I don't know.
- Whoa. What happened?
- When am I gonna get a phone?
- In due time. What happened?
- Pat.
PAT: (WHISPERS) Mom, Mom. Mom,
I can't find my wedding video.
Mom, wake up.
- What is it?
- It's after 3.00, what are you doing?
PAT: I looked in here, but this is
all your shit. You put it up here?
DOLORES: What about
in your father's study?
Don't go in my study.
Dad, not now. Would you put it in here?
Makes no sense.
- What are you doing?
- He's got all his Eagles videos.
- Is it here?
PAT SR.: - Patty!
DOLORES: It's probably in the attic.
Are you going in my study?
It feels to me like you wanna hide
my wedding video.
- You think I can't handle it?
- Please stop yelling.
I'm not yelling, I'm just frustrated!
I should have my wedding video!
Pat, you're gonna
wake everybody up!
I already looked all over there.
(PAT SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
DOLORES: - Calm down.
- I'm not calming down!
I don't give a fuck! I'm not calming
down! Anybody can wake up!
I'm not ashamed of it!
Let the whole neighbourhood wake up!
- I don't care! No, Mom!
DOLORES: - Stop it! Stop it!
- What's going on?
DOLORES: - Lower it down!
What? Hey.
- It's my wedding! It's my wedding video!
DOLORES: - Pat, stop it, stop it, stop it!
(PHONE RINGING)
(DOGS BARKING)
I can't watch a video? No!
I can hear the fucking song
in my head!
(SOBBING AND
MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(DOLORES) Stop!
(DOLORES GRUNTS)
PAT: - Mom?
- What the fuck you doing?
- You throw your mother on...!
PAT: - No, no.
Stop it!
PAT: Get off me, Dad.
PAT: - I'm not doing...!
- Stop hitting him!
Patrizio, don't hit him!
- I'm not hitting him! He's hitting me!
PAT: - Stop it, Dad!
(DOORBELL RINGING)
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry.
(KEOGH)
Police. Open the door, please.
Open up.
Mr Solatano, I got a lot of calls.
People are scared. I gotta come in.
How are we doing in here, huh?
A lot of reports from your neighbours.
We got phone calls...
Nikki is being manipulated
and controlled.
Hey, sit down.
PAT SR.: Stop with these crazy theories.
He's a cop. What are you doing?
It's a medication problem,
but he's fine.
Wanna send him back to Baltimore?
We know about the explosion.
What explo...? No. Cliff is lying.
He's not allowed to talk about that.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Jesus Christ, who's that?
PAT SR.: - Keep an eye on him.
- Is this a bipolar episode?
- Get out of here, little fucking idiot.
- Someone help me!
- You can't tell Nikki about this.
- I had to make out a report.
- Hey, sit down.
- Listen, sir.
RICK: This guy's chasing me!
Help Me!
KEOGH: - Sit down.
- I could write a letter...
She has a court order against you,
500 feet... Listen to me!
I'll take that camera
and I'm gonna break it over your head.
I'm gonna interview you, what it's like to
get that camera broken over your head.
- What are you laughing about? Sorry.
ROSALIE: - I'm sorry.
MAN: Stop all that fucking noise.
Go back to sleep, the party's over.
Show's over.
Not a reflection of where I'm at.
You can't tell her.
- You can't tell Nikki.
- Pipe down.
Everything all right?
- Who was that, Dad?
PAT SR.: - That kid with the camera.
KEOGH:
Good luck. I gotta write this up.
PAT: Come on, don't write it up.
PAT SR.: It's OK, everything is OK.
We're fine.
Thank you, we appreciate it.
Thank you.
(ALT-J'S "BUFFALO" PLAYING)
- Hey!
- Whoa! Hey.
What the hell?
- What happened?
- Weight lifting accident.
TIFFANY: That sounds like bullshit.
WhY'd You run by my house?
- Did our conversation get you upset?
- This is my route. Just back oh'.
My neighbourhood.
You ran by my house.
- I like to run by myself, OK?
- Me too.
- I like to run alone. Stop.
- What?
- I'm running here.
- Me too.
Run somewhere else.
There's tons of roads to run in.
- I like this road, my neighbourhood.
- Come on, please!
Calm down, crazy.
Why are you...?
(PANTING)
Damn it.
TIFFANY: - Hey!
- What the fuck?
- I'm married!
- So am I!
What are you doing?
Your husband's dead!
- Where is your wife?
- You're crazy!
I'm not the one
that just got out of that hospital.
I'm not the big slut!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- I was a big slut, but I'm not anymore.
There's a part of me
that's sloppy and dirty, but I like that,
with all the other parts of myself.
Can you say the same about yourself,
fucker? Can you forgive?
Are you any good at that?
- Trouble last night.
- Let me just set the record straight.
Hurting my mother was a mistake.
I hate myself for it.
I hate my illness, I wanna control it.
My father had no trouble
slapping the shit out of me,
which I did not return
because I could've killed him.
He's 65.
Don't think I could've beat him?
He was scared for your mother
and you hurt him.
Yes, last night was a mess.
And I think he probably
just tried to do his best.
Pat, you have to have a strategy,
I told you earlier.
Recognise these feelings. Otherwise
you will be sent back to Baltimore.
So when you get these feelings,
you get to a quieter place
with peace with yourself,
however you can.
- Yeah, that's easier said than done.
- You have no choice.
- Excelsior.
- Yeah, excelsior.
Listen, I have a letter
I want you to give Nikki, OK?
- No.
- Why?
Because you have
a restraining order.
What good are you, man?
Why did you have this urgency
to see your wedding video?
Because I'm married,
I haven't seen my wife.
Maybe you think Nikki's not around
and Tiffany's an attractive girl.
Get drawn towards Tiffany, you'll spoil
your chances of getting Nikki back?
Not bad, Dr Jones.
I don't think I'm gonna blow it
with Nikki because Tiffany's a slut.
- Why is she a slut?
- After the dinner, she said, quote,
"We can go to the back house
and you can fuck me
"as long as we turn the lights out,"
unquote.
And she still wears
her wedding ring.
So she's a loyal,
married-to-a-dead-guy slut.
Maybe she needs a friend
and she thought if she offers you sex,
it will be easier for you
to become friends with her.
She said she's not a whore anymore,
but she likes that part of herself
along with all the other parts of herself,
and can I say the same?
Can you?
Is that...? You're ask...?
- You're really asking me that question?
- Yes.
With all my crazy sad shit?
Are you nuts?
Pat, the silver lining thing is yours.
I'm just giving back
your words to you.
This crazy sad shit, as you call it,
made you a happier, calmer person
with a beautiful, positive philosophy
of going outdoors, working out
- and reading books.
- No. No, not the books.
You said Nikki is friends
with Ronnie, Veronica, Tiffany.
If you become friends with Tiffany,
Nikki will think you're a kind, generous,
large-hearted person
who helps people in need,
who is basically thriving.
So if you help Tiffany,
it will be good for you.
GIRL 1: Trick or treat?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
BOY: Trick or treat?
GIRL 2: Trick or treat?
TIFFANY: Hey!
PAT: Whoa!
- How do you know when I run?
- I wanted to clarify something.
I just want us to be friends.
Did you hear what I said?
Why are you giving me
such a hard time?
No, I'm not giving you a hard time.
TIFFANY: I don't know how to act
with you when you do this shit.
You wanna have dinner at this diner?
Pick me up at 7.30.
(THE DAVE BRUBECK QUARTET'S
"UNSQUARE DANCE" PLAYING)
CHILDREN: Trick or treat?
BOY 1: Wait up!
BOY 2: Ooh, I got a king-size.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- Happy Halloween.
- Hi.
(LES PAUL & MARY FORD'S "THE
MOON OF MANAKOORA" PLAYING)
WAITRESS: Here you go.
TIFFANY: Thank you.
- Gonna get a bowl of your Raisin Bran.
WAITRESS: - Great.
Tea.
Be right back.
PAT: You look nice.
Thanks.
WAITRESS: Raisin Bran.
Here's some milk for you.
- Thank you.
WAITRESS: - Mm-hm.
(CRABCORPS' "MONSTER MASH"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
Do you wanna share this?
Why did you order Raisin Bran?
Why did you order tea?
Because you ordered Raisin Bran.
Because I didn't want there to be
any mistaking it for a date.
- It can still be if you order Raisin Bran.
- It's not a date.
So how's your thing going?
Dancing thing.
Good. How's your restraining order?
I wouldn't actually call
the restraining order my thing,
but getting back with Nikki is,
and I think I'm doing pretty well.
Except for a minor incident.
And the so-called incident
with the weights.
Yeah. That was a thing
with my parents.
I wish I could just explain it all in
a letter to Nikki because it was minor.
And I could just explain it and let her
know I'm actually not out of control.
And that I'm actually...
I'm doing really well.
I can get a letter to Nikki.
I see her sometimes with my sister.
(AMBRCDSIA PARSLEY & THE ELEGANT
TOO'S "GOODNIGHT MOON" PLAYING)
It would be so amazing
if you could get a letter to Nikki
from me.
I'd have to hide it from Veronica.
She's not into breaking the law,
which this letter
would definitely be doing.
(WHISPERS) But you would do it?
I'd have to be careful.
I'm already on thin ice with my family.
You should hear how I lost my job.
How'd you lose your job?
By...
...having sex with everybody
in the office.
Everybody?
I was very depressed after Tommy died.
It was a lot of people.
We don't have to talk about it.
- How many were there?
- Eleven.
- Wow.
- I know.
- I'm not gonna talk about it anymore.
- OK.
Can I ask you one more question?
Were there any women?
- Yes.
- Really?
Yes.
- What was that like?
- Hot.
Jesus Christ.
Was it like older women, a sexy teacher
who wants to seduce you...?
Made me sit on her lap
and do things? Yeah.
- What? You sat on her lap?
- Mm-hm.
- She told you what to do?
Oh, my God. Nikki hated when I talked
like this. Made me feel like such a perv.
- Maybe we should change the subject.
- I don't mind it.
- You don't, do you?
- No.
But then people were getting in fights
in the parking lot at work
and in the bathroom.
And the boss called me in to his office
and tried to pin it all on me.
So I accused him of harassment.
And then they fired me, sent me home
and put me on some meds.
I get it.
The song that was playing
when my wife
- was in the shower with the teacher.
- Heard about that.
My wedding song.
When I hear it, I go kind of crazy.
Sometimes I hear it
when it's not even playing.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
So they put me on medication,
which I feel ashamed of.
- Yeah.
- So I know.
TIFFANY: Mm-hm.
I just gotta get a strategy,
you know?
Me too.
- Better get back to the letter.
- Let's get back to the letter.
What if you told Nikki
when Veronica was in the bathroom?
Yes.
Yes, that could work. I love that.
I'm gonna go home
and write the letter right now.
Can I at least finish my tea?
- What?
- My tea. Can I finish it?
Wait a minute.
Did Veronica tell Nikki
about our dinner?
- Why would she do that? Was it a test?
- I kind of got that feeling, yeah.
Goddamn it. I knew it.
It was a test. How did I do?
I think I did pretty well.
She said you were cool, basically.
Basically?
Was I some percentage not cool?
No, she said you were cool,
but, you know...
No, I don't know.
- Sort of how you are. It's fine, relax.
- What do you mean? How am I?
- What does that mean?
- Sort of like me.
Sort of like you?
I hope to God
she didn't tell Nikki that.
- Why?
- Because it...
It's just not right.
Lumping you and I together, it's...
I mean, it's just wrong,
and Nikki wouldn't like that.
Especially after all the shit
you just told me.
You think that I'm crazier than you.
(CHUCKLES) Because...
We're different, I mean...
Oh, my God.
Ugh. You're killing me.
(TIFFANY SIGHS)
You know what?
Forget I offered to help you.
Forget the entire fucking idea.
Because that must have been
fucking crazy
because I am so much crazier
than you.
- Keep your voice down.
- I'm just the crazy slut
with a dead husband!
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
- Forget it! Fuck you!
PAT: - Shut the fuck up.
TIFFANY: You shut the fuck up.
PAT: Tiffany. Tiffany.
(PEOPLE CHEER AND WHISTLE)
MAN 1: Hey.
MAN 2: Go get her, man.
Slow down, Raisin Bran.
PAT: Hey. Hey, come on. Look,
I don't think you're crazy, all right?
Yes, you do. You told your therapist
you were in a superior mental
illness category, didn't you?
- Hey, calm down.
- Just leave me alone.
Can I just explain myself? I didn't want
Nikki to think that I was associated
with that behaviour
because I've never done that.
You may not have experienced
the shit that I did,
but you loved hearing about it,
didn't you?
You are afraid to be alive.
- That's...
- You are afraid to live.
You're a hypocrite. You're a conformist.
You're a liar.
I opened up to you and you judged me.
You are an asshole.
- You are an asshole. Get off of me.
- Calm down.
Get off! You're harassing me!
He's harassing me!
Shut up!
(CROWD CHATTERING)
- Get off.
- Man, take it easy.
- Dude, relax.
- He's harassing me.
PAT: - Get off me, dude.
- He's harassing me!
Stop it. Back off, all right?
- Calm down! Go home.
- Get off of me.
- Shut up, shut up. Stop it.
- Shut up.
(STEVIE WONDER'S
"MY CHERIE AMOUR" PLAYING)
(SIREN WAILS)
PAT: - Hey, hey, get off me.
- What are you doing?
Come on,
what are you doing to these kids?
You being a punk with these kids?
Wanna go back to Baltimore?
Is that what you wanna do?
What did these kids do to you?
You're begging to go back to Baltimore.
What's the matter?
- You're sick.
- It's the kids. It's the kids.
Honestly, he didn't do anything.
It was all the kids.
- They started it. He didn't do anything.
KEOGH: - Come on.
Come here. What are you
gonna do about that song? Huh?
Gonna go your whole life
scared of that song?
It's a song. Don't make it a monster.
Come on, breathe. There's no song.
There's no song.
There's no song playing.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(MUSIC FADES)
That's it.
That's it. Do it more. There you go.
KEOGH: - Move it out. Let's go. Let's go.
- I'm sorry.
KEOGH: Where are you going?
TIFFANY: I took it too far.
KEOGH:
Hey, was he messing with you?
No, this was just a joke.
This is a joke I started.
There's a restraining order on this guy.
That's not a good thing to do.
- I'm fucked up. What can I tell you?
- You're Tommy's widow?
I'm Tommy's crazy whore widow,
minus the whore thing for the most part.
You're a funny girl.
You wanna get a drink sometime?
- What'd I say?
- She doesn't do that anymore.
PAT: I'm sorry about what I said.
TIFFANY: I know.
- You didn't mean it.
- I didn't mean it.
TIFFANY: I know you say shit
you don't mean all the time.
I'll still give your letter to Nikki.
Don't worry.
Wow. Oh, I really appreciate that,
Tiffany.
TIFFANY: I know you do.
PAT: You do?
Yeah, sure.
I'll see you tomorrow?
With the letter?
RANDY: I'll bet I know what happened
if only one is missing.
Either Dolores or Pat needed
an envelope and one of them took it.
- That's the only answer.
- No, no, no.
Dolores. Somebody was in my study.
Who took one of my envelopes?
Somebody took an envelope.
- Maybe we should call the FBI.
- No, don't make fun. It's serious.
We'll take a look.
I'll show you what this is.
I'm gonna explain to you something.
You know what I'm doing, honey.
This is everything... I got this.
It all corresponds...
- Dad, I borrowed one of your envelopes.
- No, it's not OK.
"Do not go in my study
or I will eat you."
PAT SR.: It's not funny. What's
everybody making a joke out of this for?
Dolores, you are so beautiful.
Stop that.
Hey, hey, hey, stop, stop, stop.
A lot of envelopes go in and out
of my office every day after games,
a lot of cash in them
so show some respect for what I do.
I wanted to tell you the number.
Envelope was empty. Didn't wanna
wake you, needed an envelope.
You didn't wanna wake me?
He didn't wanna wake me.
Doesn't have a problem complaining
about Ernest Hemingway.
He doesn't have a problem
asking for his wedding video.
- Making crabby snacks, homemades.
- Come on, be nice.
Come on, she's making crabby snacks
and homemades. Come on, Dad.
What are you...?
What are you so up about?
DOLORES: - Very happy.
- I'm happy.
PAT SR.: You're so up.
PAT: Isn't that a good thing?
You're just up.
I don't know what that is.
Are you taking the proper dosage
of your medication?
Am I taking the right dose?
Of course I am.
- Taking a little too many or something?
- If I was taking that, I'd be on the floor.
Stay. Stay for the game.
Spend some family time.
Dad, I can't. Look, I'm ready to go.
What do you mean?
You mean OCD superstitious time?
RANDY: Come on,
your dad needs a winner.
- Come on.
- I can't.
It's the Seahawks.
Put on the jersey and stay, please.
Please. It's important, please.
DOLORES: - What are you up to?
- Nothing.
What's in the envelope?
Yeah, what...?
What's in that envelope?
I'm beating the song.
I'm on the scoreboard.
I'm playing downfield. I feel great.
(DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES)
Tiffany.
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hey, hey, how you doing?
Is Tiffany here?
- What do you want?
FATHER: - That another creep?
- What do you want, creep? Beat it.
- No, I'm married.
- Married creep.
- I'm her friend. We go running.
- Have you guys not seen?
MOTHER: - She's not here.
How's it going? Hey.
Is Tiffany home?
- Go away.
- I know her. I know her.
We've dated. We still date.
I've called her, texted her.
I haven't heard back.
Used to work together...
I just wanna give you my card
to give to her.
- What's he saying?
- He's saying you're being rude.
- How am I being rude?
- You know.
Sometimes it's OK with girls,
they wanna have fun.
Sometimes it's not, they got
a broken wing, they're an easy target.
In this particular case, I think that
that wing is being fixed, my friend.
Make sure it gets mended.
You're getting in the way of that.
She's sensitive, smart, artistic.
This is a great girl.
Be respectful to that.
Let me walk you down to your car.
You're a better guy than this.
She just texted me.
Hey! Hey! Hey, wait a second.
What are you doing? What happened?
- You weren't outside.
- I can't... I can't do it.
- What do you mean?
- I can't give the letter to Nikki.
Tiffany, what are you talking about?
What do you mean, can't give the letter?
Because what am I getting in return?
You said if I wrote a letter,
you'd get it to Nikki.
Because I do this. Time after time,
I do all this shit for other people.
And then I wake up and I'm empty,
I have nothing.
You seem like you're a tough girl
to me.
- You do things on your own.
- I always get myself in these situations.
I give everything to other people
and nobody ever...
I don't get what I want, OK?
I'm not my sister.
All right, well, ask for you.
What can I do for you?
I... I can't do it.
Tiffany, what do you want me to do?
- Think of something.
- There's this thing.
There's a thing.
OK, what kind of thing?
It's a thing. It's a thing.
- It's a dance thing.
- Dance thing, all right.
Competition at the Franklin Hotel.
Tommy would never do it.
Tommy's dead,
he's not gonna fucking do it.
I don't have a filter when I talk.
TIFFANY: Can we have one
conversation without you reminding me?
- OK, I'm sorry.
- Oh, my God.
But I can only do it if I have a partner.
I'm about to miss it for another year.
I'm not gonna dance.
What are you talking about?
Your schedule is busy? Grapes of Wrath
and watching football with your dad?
- I'm not gonna do a dance.
- I'm not giving your letter.
You promised you would do this.
Think about it.
I already did do something for you.
- What did you do for me?
- Took care of that jerkoff at your house.
- What? Jordie?
- Let me ask you,
you call him when you're lonely?
- That encourages him. Shouldn't do it.
- Say the same about Nikki?
Not at all like me and Nikki.
We're in love and married. It's different.
How are you in love?
Tell me about that.
The big Nikki love. Tell me about it.
I wanna understand it.
We have an unconventional chemistry.
Makes people feel awkward, but not me.
She's the most beautiful woman
I've ever been with.
- Wow.
- It's electric between us.
Yeah, we wanna change each other, but
that's normal. Couples wanna do that.
I want her to stop dressing like she
dresses, stop acting so superior to me.
She wanted me to lose weight,
stop my mood swings, which I've done.
People fight. Couples fight.
We would fight,
we wouldn't talk for a couple weeks.
She wanted the best. She wanted me
to be passionate and compassionate.
That's a good thing. I'm my best self
today and she's her best self today.
Our love's gonna be amazing.
You're gonna be amazing
and she's gonna be amazing.
You're not gonna take advantage
of a situation
without offering to do something back.
So think about the dance thing.
TV ANNOUNCER: ...went on a roll.
McNabb got not in the first half,
nine consecutive...
PAT: You're out of the hospital?
- And you're here on game day?
- I'm out. (LAUGHS)
It's official. They didn't convert me
to Mental Hygiene Law admission status
within two-thirds of the maximum length
of my felony sentence, so I'm out.
- They had to let me go.
- I never understand what he's saying.
OK, jailhouse lawyer, come back,
sit down the way you were before.
(CHUCKLES) - What a treat!
DANNY: - Let's do it.
PAT: - Dad's got you sitting here?
- He calls me "jailhouse lawyer."
Hold the remote the way you were.
PAT: - Now you're holding the remote?
- It's working. Your dad's a genius.
Now, sit up.
- And Danny's good luck?
- Danny's from you.
This is your house
so it comes down to you.
- You're the one, Pat.
PAT: - Superstition, Danny.
Come sit down. Don't disappear doing
God knows what with Tiffany Maxwell.
Dad, Dad. She's my friend.
Why would you say that?
Oh, she's a mess. Gotta be careful.
She does a lot of therapy.
I go to a lot of therapy, Ronnie.
- I'm saying...
PAT: - Am I messed up?
Stop judging. You're the one
who has a messed-up marriage.
- I'm just looking out for you.
- What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
At his house, it's like a circus there.
Not gonna hide this.
You need to deal with it.
Stop breaking my balls.
- I got you... I brought the iPod.
- Oh! Whoa.
- For me?
- Yeah. That's my old iPod, but...
Buddy, thank you.
That's so nice of you.
- Wow.
- Thirty-two gigabytes.
- How many songs is that?
- 7,000.
You got the Stranglers.
You love the Stranglers.
- Oh, the Sex Pistols. The Clash.
- Got some Clash.
Oh, West Side Story.
- It makes me peaceful.
- West Side Story?
♪ Just met a girl named Maria ♪
And then when I'm angry, which is a lot
these days, I go to the garage.
(WHISPERS) Metallica, Megadeth.
(GRUNTING)
I start fucking smashing shit.
- Get your marriage together.
- Breaking shit.
And I hurt my hand and I...
- Ronnie, that's fucked up.
- It makes me feel better.
It's like my therapy.
With Nikki,
I'm never gonna do stuff like that.
MAN: Whoa, Nikki?
What's all this about Nikki?
Restraining order's
nothing to fool with, bro.
Holy shit, look at you.
You are ripped.
You look absolutely amazing.
You feel good?
- How you doing, Jake?
- You look like Schwarzenegger. Shit.
Didn't I say
you wouldn't recognise him?
So, listen, I'm sorry that I didn't come
see you down at the hospital.
Those places creep me out
and the firm's been expanded.
Been helping Pop. He needs a legitimate
business. He needs a tax return.
The money he's making,
they're gonna come after him.
And it looks like I'm gonna
make partner at the firm.
I don't even know what to say
to you anymore.
You lost your wife,
I'm getting engaged.
I wanna be able to tell you
about those kind of things.
You lost your house,
I'm getting a new house.
You lost your job,
things are great for me at the firm.
Stop talking about stuff
that's good for you.
Leave it alone. Leave it alone.
We're watching the game.
You know what?
I'm just gonna stop talking.
I'm gonna shut my mouth.
As my friend Danny would say:
I got nothing but love for you,
brother.
DANNY: That's right. That's right.
RANDY: That's nice.
RONNIE: - That's nice.
- Thank God, finally.
PAT: - DeSean Jackson.
- Yeah. Did it fit?
- Yeah, wore it to Ronnie's.
- Beautiful jersey. I love that jersey.
- Veronica didn't like it.
- Veronica hates the jersey.
Whatever you do, watch out
for that restraining order, OK?
- Don't let Tiffany get you in trouble.
- You're up to something.
People like Tiffany, or Danny or me, we
know something you don't know, OK?
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Maybe we understand something
because we're more...
We have a sixth sense.
Everybody got it. Just not in touch.
- How you doing, Pat?
- Jesus.
Sixth sense forgot to tell him
cops were coming.
- I'm taking him back to the hospital.
- What? He passed, right?
First of all, check with
the latest legal development.
Got a call that they did convert you to
Mental Hygiene Law admission status
by the deadline.
Wait a minute.
Are you an Eagles fan or are you not?
KEOGH: - I'm an Eagles fan.
- What's the problem?
He's not going anywhere.
Let him finish the game.
Handkerchief is working.
We're killing the Seahawks, 27-10.
What's the matter with you?
Let him stay, please.
Don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm glad the Seahawks are losing,
we're winning,
but I gotta take Danny McDaniels
back to Baltimore, all right?
He can contest his case
from Baltimore.
DANNY: Not correct about the Mental
Hygiene Law. You're not correct.
You guys ought to be ashamed
of yourselves.
TIFFANY: Used insurance money
to build this. I designed it.
- Wow.
- All the floors are hard oak.
It has good bounce for dancers.
I'm not that great of a dancer,
but who cares? It's therapy and it's fun.
Walls are good, I can play music
really loud without anybody hearing.
- Where do you sleep?
- Upstairs.
It's a garage, I just renovated it.
Thinking about putting a ballet barre...
When are you gonna give it to her?
What?
The letter to Nikki.
- Probably tonight.
- Really?
Ronnie, Veronica and I,
we'll see her tonight.
I changed the first paragraph.
I did this thing about Shakespeare,
and maybe if she wanted to go dancing,
I can be able to do that.
- Good.
- I assume you're a good teacher.
- Yeah.
- You can teach us both.
And I also mentioned how you were...
How generous it is,
what I'm doing for you.
- Mm-hm. Really generous.
- Being of service.
- Yeah. Uh-huh.
- To your need.
All right, start simple.
Start at that corner, walk towards me.
Walk across the room.
- Can we do something besides dance?
- Are you kidding me?
- Want me to fix something?
- Deal is a deal.
I know, OK. I was just suggesting
that maybe there's a better scenario.
TIFFANY: Why don't you...
...walk towards me like I'm Nikki?
The only way to convey how much
you've missed me is by your walk.
By your slow walk. You can't talk.
- Not doing it.
- Only walk. Do it.
No. That's stupid.
No walk, no letter.
Walk to me like I'm Nikki, come on.
Do it. I'm Nikki. Come on.
(MUMBLES) You're not Nikki.
Don't look up
until you're halfway here.
That's right.
Not yet.
Yes.
Do you feel that? That's emotion.
I don't feel anything.
Has anybody ever told you
how Tommy died?
No.
We were married for three years
and five days, and I loved him.
But for the last couple months,
I just wasn't into sex at all.
It just felt like we were so different
and I was depressed.
Some of that is just me, some of it
was he wanted me to have kids.
I have a hard time
taking care of myself.
I don't think
that makes me a criminal.
Anyway, one night after dinner,
he drove to Victoria's Secret
at King of Prussia Mall
and got some lingerie
to get something going.
And on the way back,
he stopped on 76
to help a guy with a flat tyre
and he got hit by a car and killed.
And the Victoria's Secret box
was still in the front seat.
That's a feeling.
(BOB DYLAN & JOHNNY CASH'S "GIRL
FROM THE NORTH COUNTRY" PLAYS)
OK, this is the waltz.
I'm gonna teach you the waltz step.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
- Whoa, slow down.
- What?
Your father wanted you to have this.
Wants me to have
Eagles information.
DOLORES: It's his living.
Um, tell Dad thanks.
Your father expects
to spend time with you, Pat.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Football stays out of this place.
So does Lord of the Flies.
PAT: What are you doing?
I'm behind on my syllabus.
TIFFANY: I don't give a fuck.
PAT: What the hell are you doing?
Hey, hey!
- Did you throw that outside?
- You're not gonna read that on my time.
I can tell you about Lord of the Flies.
It's a bunch of boys on an island
and they have a conch, a shell,
and whoever has the conch
has power and can talk.
You don't have the conch,
don't have power.
Then there's a little chubby boy,
Piggy,
and they're mean,
and then there's a murder.
I mean, humanity is just nasty
and there's no silver lining.
Wow. That was a great synopsis.
I still need to read it, though.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Who's that?
Hello? What the...?
What are you doing here, man?
If one of your two supervising
physicians loses their license,
your whole adjudication
is thrown out.
PAT: How'd you know we were here?
DANNY: Your parents.
- Danny, Tiffany. Tiffany, Danny.
- Pat told me about you.
- Is this the girl you wrote about?
PAT: - Yeah.
You wrote about me? I'm "the girl"?
- He wrote about you.
- What did he say?
DANNY: You was helping
each other out
and you were nice.
And you had a mouth on you, but...
- Whoa, OK, OK.
DANNY: - A little mouthy.
- Tell me more about what he said.
- I'll just tell you.
- It was just a very general letter.
- Cool.
DANNY: - She's fine.
- She is my friend with an F.
- A capital F. She's fine.
- For "friend."
Mm. Can I see
what you guys are doing?
Yeah.
- One, two.
DANNY: - I like it, I like it.
- Do you?
DANNY: - It's good, yeah.
And then this goes
into something else.
- That's it?
- What is it? What is it? What is it?
- Can I say something?
TIFFANY: - No.
- You sure?
- Just say it.
I think, Pat,
you should be facing Tiffany.
Let me show you what I mean. You
gotta come with a little bit more soul.
You should move some more hips.
Pat, come in like this.
OK.
Yeah. Can you move
a little bit more hip?
That's it. Move a bit more.
You could turn around too.
Yeah. You're pretty good.
Yeah. Exactly.
(STEVIE WONDER'S "DON'T YOU
WORRY 'BOUT A THING" PLAYING)
- Yeah.
- OK, we got it, we got it.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, we got it.
- I'll switch with you.
Come on, Pat. Come on.
A little bit more soul, Pat.
- Black it up, Pat.
- What's that mean?
DANNY: - You know what it means.
- "Black it up"?
Oh, wait a minute, wait a minute,
wait a minute. Oh, man. I got an idea.
(JESSIE J'S "SILVER LINING"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
Jump up. Hold hands. Circle around
and around and around.
Don't look back.
(DAN NY VOCALIZES)
Come get some, Pat.
PAT: Is that it?
DANNY: That's it.
Bounce, bounce. Shuffle back,
shuffle, shuffle.
Shuffle back, shuffle back.
You gotta move your junk.
Pop. Pop your butt. Pop it.
I gotta get out of here.
Gotta see this girl, Tanya.
- Yeah, go see Tanya.
- OK, man, hey.
I'll be there. I want you to win.
- Excelsior, Pat.
PAT: - Excelsior.
That's my man. Let's go.
PAT SR.: Patty.
Patty.
Hey. Patty.
Pat.
Huh? Patty.
Where have you been? Huh?
We got a serious situation
on our hands, you know that.
We gotta beat the Giants if we wanna
have a chance of getting into division,
any chance of playing
in the playoffs.
Do you realise that?
Ahem. I didn't realise that.
Yeah, that's the bind we're in.
I mean, I think it would be wise
if we spent father-son time
reading about the Eagles,
talking about them,
just to strengthen the good-luck thing
that you're in.
- OK.
- Yeah?
- Right.
- Hm?
I just wanted to, uh...
Maybe I didn't
spend enough time
with you growing up.
I spent too much time
with your brother.
It might've made you feel worse
about your behaviour,
but I didn't know anything.
I didn't know how to handle it.
That's what all this Eagles stuff
is about.
It's about us spending time now.
I wanna do everything I can
to help you get back on your feet.
That's the whole point.
Yeah.
I wish you'd watch these games
with me
so we could talk,
we could get into things.
So, look, will you just come downstairs
and talk to me and Randy now, huh?
PAT SR.:
Randy, tell him what I'm doing.
He's betting everything
on the Giant game. Everything.
The money he needs
for the restaurant,
- he's betting on the Giant game.
PAT SR.: - Tell him why.
Because he believes in you.
- Is that true?
PAT SR.: - I believe in you, Patty.
I believe in you.
I want you to know that.
So I'm gonna bet heavy
on this game.
- You understand?
PAT: - Yeah.
Heavy. I want you to go
to the game with your brother.
- Want me to go to the game with Jake?
- I do.
- Does he want me to go?
- Of course.
- He told you that?
- He told me, yes.
- With his friends?
- With his friends. He trusts you.
- He's not embarrassed?
- No.
I'd love to go to the game too,
but I'm banned from the stadium.
I'd love to see us beat the Giants
and take a lot of money
from this asshole.
Listen, personally,
- I think it's a stupid bet.
- Randy.
I think it's ridiculous to bet all that
dough for the restaurant on a game.
PAT SR.: Randy. I just hope
you heard what I said.
It's like a family business,
it's our family endeavour.
We all stick together on this.
That's how it works.
That's a positive, positive vibe.
I made a commitment
about a project,
and we have an important part of it that
we have to go over on Sunday, so...
(SIGHS)
I... I'm...
It's... And it's good for me, Dad.
It's making me disciplined
and focused, and it's...
Never would've thought this,
but it's a good thing.
What is this thing you're doing?
Yeah, what is it?
What is this project, hon?
PAT: It's a dance thing, OK?
There's nothing more to it, Dad.
I swear.
Listen, I need to ask you something.
Tomorrow, can I spend
half the day with you?
- I'm gonna pretend that you didn't ask.
- Why?
These are the two days
that you have promised me
and we have prepared
to nail the big move.
It's not ready yet,
we don't have the move.
My dad opened up, and it was beautiful
and I wanna be of service to him.
He's worried the juju is being fucked up
because I'm spending time with you.
Oh, I messed up the Eagles' juju?
You're not messing it up,
the juju is messed up
because I'm not with him
during the games.
- Guess what.
- What?
Nikki replied to your letter.
But you can't read it
until after you nail the big move.
- Go.
(SIGHS)
(PAT GRUNTS)
(TIFFANY GRUNTS)
I can't do anything else
till I can read Nikki's letter.
It's in the back of my head.
We don't almost have it, all right?
TIFFANY: - I just hope you can handle it.
- Thank you.
What was her energy
when she gave it to you?
She was intrigued, excited,
and a little scared.
She was scared? About what?
Did she tell you?
Try to stay positive.
I'm just gonna read it out loud, OK?
Because if she says anything that's...
- Is that too much to ask?
- No.
- I thought you were gonna read it.
- OK. I'm sorry.
"Dear Pat." Ahem.
"It was very emotional for me
to get your letter, as you can imagine,
but I'm glad you took the risk
of getting it to me through Tiffany."
"This gives us a chance
to communicate
while I keep the restraining order
until I feel safe."
"I admit you sound terrific
and I'm happy you're feeling positive
and becoming a more loving and caring
man, which I always knew you were."
(SIGHS)
"I was moved to read about excelsior
and your belief in happy endings."
"I'm moved by your act of love
to read books I taught."
"I'm sorry you find them negative."
"They're great works that reflect
how hard life can be."
"They can help kids prepare
themselves for the hardness of life."
"In spite of these developments,
if it's me reading the signs,
I need to see something
to prove you are ready
to resume our marriage."
"Otherwise, I find myself thinking that
we might both be better off moving on
with our lives separately."
"Don't react quickly to this,
but take time to think about it."
"I'm glad you're doing so well.
Love, Nikki."
I think I'm done today, OK?
She said to show her something, Pat.
This dance can be that something.
You would've never done something
like this in a million years.
It shows all kinds of skills
on so many levels,
focus, collaboration, discipline.
It's romantic, like I said it would be.
It's for her.
Thanks for the letter.
I'll see you tomorrow, OK?
(DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES)
CROWD: E-A-G-L-E-S!
Eagles!
PAT: Can I use your phone?
- Is it an emergency?
- Yeah, kind of.
What kind of emergency?
I'm doing this project with Tiffany. I
wanna tell her I'm not gonna be on time.
Just don't make her an emergency,
that crazy girl.
I'm... She's...
I'll just borrow Jake's phone.
Too bad you can't come,
but I know you were kicked out,
beating everybody up.
Guess we're not that different,
huh, Dad?
That a bad thing?
No, I think it's a good thing.
Don't drink, don't hit anybody.
You'll be fine.
Yeah. I'm solid.
(THE WHITE STRIPES'
"HELLO OPERATOR" PLAYING)
- This is my brother Pat.
- How you doing? Pat.
Pat, what's this I hear
about you just getting out?
Yeah! From the loony bin!
Guys, what the fuck?
I talked to you about that.
- I told you.
- It's all right.
- He's a good dude. He's a good dude.
(ALL) Yeah!
(HORN HONKING)
Oh, shit. The Asian invasion.
Every week.
MAN 1: That's right, fool. We got this.
No.
JEFFREY: You better get your brother.
MAN 2: Cuckoo bird's taking off.
MAN 3: - Cuckoo bird!
- Dr Patel.
- Hey, Pat! Hey.
- Hey.
What are you doing here?
- We must beat the Giants.
- Not supposed to see you.
Outside the office.
- Is that illegal?
- I'm your brother in green,
not your therapist.
I'm happy to see you.
Wonderful that you are here.
This is Cliff. My doctor.
Two things. Watch that bubble screen
for Manning in the backfield
and make sure we knock
the receivers on their ass.
You can say that again.
Those cocksuckers!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(CHEERING)
(RARE EARTH'S "HEY BIG BROTHER"
PLAYING)
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL WOOFING)
I don't have her phone number.
If you really want, you can call
Veronica because she does,
- but I don't wanna.
PAT: - Why?
Because she brings me down!
She brings me down.
You're not gonna throw the marriage
away. There's some love there.
You guys have a thing that got broken.
You gotta fix it like a chiropractor.
Gotta give it
a chiropractic adjustment.
Enough with awkwardness!
I don't wanna not be able
to say what I wanna say.
You're right, you're right.
Whoo! Eagles, baby!
Yeah! Let's go! Whoo!
- What the fuck? What's that smell?
- What the hell?
MAN 1: Nasty Indian curry.
This is America, baby.
Go back to your country.
- Get out of here!
- What's wrong?
MAN 2: Hey. Hey.
What's going on?
JAKE: Stay back, Pat. Stay back.
Leave the fucking Indians alone.
- Tough guy.
MAN 1: - A traitor.
- Stay here. Stay here.
- I'm not gonna go in.
- They're cool!
MAN 1: - Let's go!
I'm not gonna fight,
I'm not gonna fight.
MAN 1: We're the real Eagle fans.
Not my brother! Hey, hey, hey!
MAN 1: Come on, get him!
PAT: Get off my brother!
GUARD: Break it up
or you'll be arrested!
MAN 3: Pat. Pat. Pat.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
What'd you do? What happened?
PAT: - Dad. Dad.
- What happened?
The Birds lose, I lose a fucking fortune.
A fortune to Randy.
What did you do? You fucking lost it.
You said you had it together,
you were solid.
I am solid. I was solid at the game.
I'm solid. I'm solid.
You fell apart!
What are you talking about?
It's all fucking ruined now.
It's all ruined.
- It's all ruined!
PAT: - No, Dad.
- It's ruined! It's ruined!
You little fucking shit!
PAT: - Come on, Dad!
- You fucking loser! You loser!
PAT: - I'm not a loser.
- You fucking loser! Spiked the ball...
PATEL: He defended his brother
and us.
- Spiked the ball at the one-yard line.
PAT: - No, Dad.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
PAT SR.: - Who is this?
- We need to talk now.
When you make a commitment,
it is not cool to not show up!
Wait. I tried to call.
- My God.
- Who is this?
PAT: I tried to call you, Tiffany.
TIFFANY: Oh, really?
PAT: I was gonna split my time
with my dad and you.
- Dad was pulling me in one direction.
- Sounds great.
That's great for all of them,
but all of them
didn't make a commitment to me
in return for my help.
I'm Tiffany, by the way.
What is this craziness
with Tiffany Maxwell?
PAT: No craziness.
I told you I was doing this thing.
PAT SR.: When you started
spending time with her, it fell apart.
- This is the reason right here.
- Think I fucked up the Eagles' juju?
Ever since.
Ever since he was with you. Since...
- Think I'm why today's happened?
PAT SR.: - You are why today happened.
- I'm why today happened?
PAT SR.: - I think so.
- Let's talk about that.
- Be my guest.
The first night that Pat and I met,
the Eagles beat the 49ers handily,
40 to 26.
The second time we got together,
the Phillies beat the Dodgers
7 to 5 in the NLCS.
JAKE: - She's right.
- Next time we went for a run,
the Eagles beat the Falcons, 27 to 14.
The third time we got together,
we had Raisin Bran in the diner.
Phillies dominated Tampa Bay, fourth
game of the World Series, 10 to 2.
PAT: - Oh, wow.
- Let me think about that. Wait a minute.
Why not think about when the Eagles
beat the Seahawks, 14 to 7?
- He was with you?
TIFFANY: - He was. We went for a run.
There have been no games since Pat
and I have been rehearsing every day.
And if Pat had been with me
like he was supposed to,
he wouldn't have gotten in a fight,
maybe the Eagles beat
the New York Giants.
She's making a lot of sense, Pop.
That's all right on all counts.
Does anybody here happen to know
what the official motto of New York is
on the official seal
of the state of New York?
- Anybody? Do you know?
- No.
- Excelsior. Look it up.
(ALL) - Oh!
PAT: What?
TIFFANY: Yeah.
- Excelsior.
DOLORES: - Oh, Pat.
Not that I give a fuck about football
or your superstitions,
but if it's me reading the signs,
I don't send the Eagles guy
whose personal motto is "excelsior"
to a fucking Giants game,
especially when he's already
in a legal situation.
RONNIE: - Unbelievable.
- Wow. How did you know all that stuff?
- I did my research.
(BOTTLE CAP POPS)
- Well, I gotta say, I'm impressed.
TIFFANY: - Thank you.
Yeah. I gotta rethink
this whole thing.
I didn't trust her before,
but I gotta say, now I do.
Oh, now you like her, Dad?
I have to say I do. Yup.
RANDY: Patrizio, I feel terrible,
you know?
You made the bet,
I won a lot of money,
and now your whole family
is in turmoil.
Oh, fuck off, Randy. You love it.
You live for this.
You've bet against my father for years.
You're twisting the knife now.
You get off on it!
That's not true. Don't say that.
- Fine, then prove it!
- Yeah, prove it.
RANDY: How do you want me
to prove it?
How do you prove it?
- How do I prove it?
- A chance to win back everything.
- Double or nothing.
- No, no, no.
Double or nothing on the Bengals
next week, is that what you're saying?
TIFFANY: Mm-mm.
- Against the Cowboys.
(ALL) - Oh!
RANDY: Oh, come on, are you kidding?
RONNIE: That's his team.
TIFFANY: That's your team,
isn't it, Randy?
- I know who his team is.
RANDY: - When is the game?
- December 28th, last of the season.
PAT: - Oh, my God.
Same day as the Benjamin Franklin Pairs
Open Freestyle Dance Competition.
DOLORES: - Oh, God.
- Randy.
Don't you believe
in America's team?
Yeah, don't you believe
I believe in America's team.
But if I win that bet, I win your book,
you're out of action,
you get no restaurant, no nothing.
- I like it.
DOLORES: - No. No, Patrizio.
I believe in the Eagles, my son.
I'll take the action. I'll take it.
PAT: - Dad.
- Patrizio, don't. It's toxic.
I have faith.
Excelsior belongs in this house.
- Dad.
- Not in New York. In this house.
Dad, I didn't know excelsior
was the motto of New York.
- But now I know.
- This is toxic.
Dad, this is toxic.
You shouldn't be doing this.
Quiet, you already did enough.
What do you say?
My Birds, Benjamin Franklin's team,
favoured one and a half points.
Give you 3 more.
Patrizio, stop it.
Randy, don't you take the bet!
- In fact, I'll give you 10 points.
- No, Dad!
- Dad! This is insanity!
- Dad!
- Take that bet on the Cowboys.
RANDY: - Dolores, will you stop him?
- Jesus!
PAT SR.: - Yeah.
How could you not take that bet?
Even with 10 points.
That's an insane spread to your
advantage. Cowboys are cowards.
I bet you're such a coward,
you won't take the 10.
Plus, whatever their score is
at the dance thing. What's that?
- What's that?
- No, no, no.
You're crazy to give away
that many points. I won't take that.
However, wait a second.
- I do like the idea of a parlay.
- What? No parlay! No.
- No, don't do it. Don't do it.
DOLORES: - Mother of God.
How do they run this dance
competition? How do they score it?
I don't know how they score.
We're participating, not a part of it.
There's people...
This is a high-end dance contest.
Do not put it as part of the parlay.
They go by Philadelphia rules.
Each dancer is scored 1 to 10,
10 the highest,
average the four judges' scores.
OK, scores from 1 to 10, right?
And you guys are how good?
- We suck.
- We don't suck.
Pat's a beginner, I'm OK.
We're happy just to be going.
RANDY:
The people you're competing against?
They're good.
Some of them are professionals.
RANDY: Better than you?
- A lot better.
RANDY: - A lot better.
If I was to say you only have to score 5,
I'd be really very generous, right?
No, no.
That'd be amazing if we got 5.
- Let's not get...
- We can get a 5. Give me a break.
- We can't get 5.
- Give me a break.
- You'll get a 5. You'll get a 5.
TIFFANY: - We can do a 5.
- What?
RANDY: - That's the parlay.
- Will somebody explain me the parlay?
- Win two bets or lose the whole thing.
For Pat Sr. to win,
Birds gotta beat the Cowboys,
plus Pat and Tiffany gotta get
at least a 5 at the dance.
PATEL: That's very, very manic indeed.
RONNIE: That's the parlay.
RANDY: We'll shake on it.
TIFFANY: Shake on it.
DOLORES: No! Oh, God.
RANDY: It's a bet.
I'm not gonna be a part of this.
Randy, you're a fucking sickness,
Randy. I'm out.
- Pat, you can't quit.
- I'm not doing the dance.
- Calm down. Think about...
PAT: - See you later.
- Pat, no. Pat.
- What are you doing?
- I'm out.
RONNIE: - What?
Here we are again
at the one-yard line.
DeSean, snatching defeat
from the jaws of victory.
- There you go.
- What does that mean?
That connection with DeSean Jackson,
it doesn't matter anymore.
Just because I have the jersey on.
I'm not gonna do it.
You are not a stand-up guy right now.
- If it's me reading the signs...
- You reading the signs? Oh, OK.
(DOOR SLAMS)
DOLORES: - Pat! Pat!
- You are not a stand-up guy!
Uh-oh.
DOLORES: I told you not to push it.
PAT SR.: He's gotta do this.
He can't be a quitter.
- He cannot be a quitter.
- You took that stupid parlay thing.
Now he won't do the dance. It was
very constructive for him. You ruined it.
Only one way to get him to show.
- What's that?
We have to tell him
Nikki's gonna be there.
DOLORES: - She won't come.
- We have to tell him she's coming.
- We have to tell him.
- That's a lie.
- White lie.
That's no big deal. So it's a little lie.
- No other way.
DOLORES: - No.
We gotta leave a trail
of breadcrumbs
so that he can live his life
without ruining it.
No. I don't approve.
- You can't do it.
- Well, you know, I didn't approve
when you told her where he was
running so she could ambush him.
I didn't approve of that,
but you did it anyway, so I'm doing this.
That's it.
We're gonna tell him
Nikki will be there.
(SIGHS)
- You gotta be part of it.
- We have to do it.
DOLORES: Aren't you nervous
to be lying?
No.
A little bit.
But it's for the best.
(MUTTERING)
PAT: "But if it was me
reading the signs..."
I...
That's it.
OK.
Hey.
PAT: Hey, what's up?
- Sorry I'm late.
- It's fine.
(FRANK SINATRA'S "HAVE YOURSELF A
MERRY LITTLE CHRISTMAS" PLAYING)
- Cheers.
This isn't working.
Stupid!
(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
PAT: Come on, it's gonna be great.
Nikki's gonna be there, you know?
Everything's gonna come together.
It's what's meant to be.
You OK?
- Well, don't get wobbly on me.
- I'm not.
We have a dance to do, a parlay.
Stay focused.
- I'm focused.
- Good, let's go.
- Look at the dancers. You see them?
- Shit.
(PIERO PICCIONI'S "AMORE A FORZA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
Hey, Randy, Jake. What do we got?
Dallas just tied it
with a field goal, 3-3.
JAKE: - I'm worried about the bet.
- Don't worry about the bet.
Holy shit.
Is this Dancing with the Stars?
Well, you knew that.
Maybe you should've scouted them.
RANDY: Look at those
fucking dancers.
(LAUGHING)
You can give me the money now,
you know.
Patty, all we have to do
is we have to make a 5.
- Watch the game with me.
- The Birds are better
- when Pat is with me, we settled that.
- Stay for...
PAT: Relax, we're gonna be fine.
I'll see you up there, OK?
Hey, Pat, Tiffany.
PAT: - Hey.
- Glorious, beautiful occasion.
Yeah, yeah. All right, I'll see you.
- All right, wish me luck.
PATEL: - Excelsior.
- What's this?
- I thought you were doing it.
I thought you were doing it. We're doing
a dance anyway, for God sakes.
You OK?
I want you to remember everything,
all of the good stuff that we have here.
PAT: - Of course I do.
- Just check in. I gotta go find Veronica.
- Good evening.
MAN: - Evening.
PAT: Check in.
MAN: Please.
PAT: How many dancers are there?
TIFFANY: What? Nikki?
Nikki.
Oh, Jesus.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
VERONICA: Let's get over here.
Come on.
What the fuck?
- Sweetie, sweetie. Honey, calm down.
(WHISPERS) - You're killing me.
She'll see how well he's doing,
maybe she'll lift the restraining order.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
RONNIE: - Pat told me.
He told me you should never
throw a marriage out the window.
- He did not say that.
RONNIE: - Yes.
Said it several times. It's his chance.
You gotta give him a chance.
(TOCO'S "GUARAPIRANGA"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING NEARBY)
Bartender.
Bartender, can I get
a vodka, please?
(APPLAUSE CONTINUES)
- So you want another one?
- Sure.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
So, what do you do?
MAN: I'm a lawyer.
- Litigator, actually.
- Oh.
EMCEE:
The scores for Santos-Aguilar...
- The arguing guy.
(MAN CHUCKLES)
EMCEE: Seven-point-six, 7.3,
7.4, and 6.9.
For an average score of 7.3.
TV ANNOUNCER: - Three, two, one!
- Holy shit!
Philadelphia beats Dallas!
They are on their way
- to the playoffs.
PAT SR.: - Randy, what is happening?
(TRIBUTE BEAT'S "SWAY"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(WHISPERS) - Where's Tiffany?
PAT: - I don't know, Mom.
- Seen her?
- Find her.
I know. Mom, I know.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Sorry. Hey. Hey, what are you doing?
MAN: - She's fine, buddy.
- She's fine?
Why don't you shut up, OK?
- How many drinks have you had?
- Two vodkas.
I don't know what choices you've made,
but deal with it. We're in this.
- We're in what?
EMCEE: - Next, Pat Solatano
and Tiffany Maxwell.
I used to think you were
the best thing that happened,
but now I think you might
maybe be the worst thing.
- I'm sorry that I ever met you.
PAT: - Good for you.
Come on, let's dance.
EMCEE: And the scores for Nakarov
and Tretiak are 6.7, 8.1,
7.5, and 6.5.
For an average score of 7.2.
They were great
and they only got a 7.2.
This is a tough room.
Got it.
EMCEE: Up next, ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Pat Solatano Jr.
and Tiffany Maxwell.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Come on, Pat!
Damn.
- Let's go, Patty!
- Come on, Pat.
(STEVIE WONDER'S "DON'T YOU
WORRY 'BOUT A THING" PLAYING)
(THE WHITE STRIPES' "FELL IN LOVE
WITH A GIRL" PLAYING)
(THE DAVE BRUBECK QUARTET'S
"MARIA" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SIGHS)
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
(AUDIENCE MURMURING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Yeah, Pat! Yeah!
JAKE: We love you, Pat!
EMCEE: All right, let's see the scores
for Solatano and Maxwell.
We have a 4.9...
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
...4.8, a 4.9.
That's too bad, guys.
That's a lot of 4's.
And a 5.4.
For an average score of 5.0.
WOMAN: Sorry.
MAN: Sorry about that, guys.
(CHEERING)
What? Come on!
PAT: Dad, did the Eagles win?
The Eagles won, 44-6.
They won, 44-6.
- Come on!
EMCEE: - We'll take a ten-minute break.
Why are they so excited about a 5?
Great. Good job.
(CHATTERING)
TIFFANY: Thank you.
You were amazing.
(JOHNNY MATHIS' "MISTY"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
PAT: Thank you for coming.
NIKKI: Of course.
PAT: - How are you? You OK?
- I'm good. How are you?
- I'm good. Thanks.
- You looked happy out there.
- Did I? Who'd have thought, dancing?
- Yeah.
- You look incredible.
- Thank you, yeah.
You lost a lot of weight.
Been reading your books,
I have a positive attitude.
I'm on medication and I'm in therapy.
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
(WHISPERING CONTINUES)
- Where's Tiffany?
- She left.
- What do you mean?
- What do you expect?
- Where is she?
I know you don't wanna listen
to your father.
You gotta pay attention to the signs.
Life reaches out a moment like this,
it's a sin if you don't reach back.
I'm telling you, it's a sin. It'll haunt you
the rest of your days like a curse.
You're facing a big challenge
in your life now, this very moment.
That girl loves you.
I don't know if Nikki ever did,
but she sure doesn't love you right now.
I'm telling you, don't fuck this up.
I love you, Dad.
(CAR HORN HONKS)
PAT: Hey!
- Would you just leave me alone?
- Wait a second!
- I have one more letter for you.
- Give it to her yourself!
You don't ever have to see me again
if you just read it, all right?
This is so fucked up.
Yeah, just read it.
"Dear Tiffany...
I know you wrote the letter."
- Only way you could meet my crazy.
- Was doing something crazy yourself.
Thank you.
I love you.
I knew it the minute I met you.
I'm sorry it took so long for me
to catch up.
I just got stuck.
Pat.
I wrote that a week ago.
- You wrote that a week ago?
- Yes, I did.
You let me lie to you for a week?
I was trying to be romantic.
You love me?
Yeah, I do.
OK.
PAT: The world will break your heart
ten ways to Sunday, that's guaranteed.
And I can't begin to explain that.
Or the craziness inside myself
and everybody else, but guess what.
Sunday is my favourite day again.
I think of everything everyone did
for me and I feel like a very lucky guy.
PAT SR.: We have to beat
the Vikings by 3. I'm giving you a 6,
which is very generous
after the beating you just took.
What are we talking about here?
Do another parlay
if you make it to the next round.
We are gonna make it
to the next round.
JAKE: Did you? I laid that down.
RONNIE: No.
- No, that was me.
JAKE: No, I played the jack.
Put the breadcrumbs, the garlic
in the steak,
- and you roll it up with the toothpicks?
- Yeah. For maybe three hours, plus.
PAT SR.: Everything's good,
everything's good.
I got you, you're all down.
Randy, he's complaining. He lost a lot
of money. He's moaning and groaning.
The restaurant's happening because
of Randy so everything's good.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(ALABAMA SHAKES'
"ALWAYS ALRIGHT" PLAYING)