* "L" is for the way *
* You look at me *
* "O" is for the only *
* One I see *
* "V" is very, very *
* Extraordinary *
* "E" is even more *
* Than anyone that you adore *
* And love is all that I can *
* Give to you *
* Love is more than *
* Just a game for two *
* Two in love can make it *
* Take my heart
and please don't break it *
* Love was made
for me and you *
* Love is all that I can *
* Give to you *
* Love is more than *
* Just a game for two *
* Two in love can make it *
* Take my heart
and please don't break it *
* Love was made
for me and you *
* "L" is for the way *
* You look at me *
* "O" is for the only *
* One I see *
* "V" is very, very *
* Extraordinary *
* "E" is even more than *
* Anyone that you adore *
* And love is all that *
* I can give to you *
* Love is more than
just a game for two *
- How 'bout a souvenir picture?
- * Two in love can make it *
- Turn towards each other.
- * Take my heart and please don't break it *
* Love was made *
* For me and you *
* For me and you **
My God! My phone just
does not work out here.
Oh, my God!
How are we ever gonna live?
Uh! Thanks.
There's a counsellor. Oh, excuse me.
Um, can you tell me where
the Navajo bunk is?
- It's right over there.
- Thanks.
Now, girls, let's find our duffles
as quickly as we can.
We have a big first day
ahead of us.
I'm going to turn the bullhorn
over now to my daughter,
and right-hand man,
Marva, Jr.
Marva, bunk assignments,
if you please.
All right, ladies,
here we go. Listen up.
Wait a minute.
I thought this was a boy's camp.
Okay, found my duffle.
Now the question is...
how do I get it out?
Okay, I can do it.
Okay... no, I can't.
- You must be new.
- How could you tell?
You didn't know how to grab your duffle...
before the aides tossed
it into the heap.
- I would say you need some serious help.
- Thanks.
It's the big, yellow one.
Whoa! Now,
that's my kinda woman.
- Yo, tie-dye girl!
- Hmm?
Could you give me an hand
with my duffle? It's the yellow one,
- buried way in there.
- Sure.
Oh, that?
No problem.
Hey, you're
from California?
Do you, like, live in Hollywood?
Do you, like, live next door to a movie star?
What are you two,
Lucy and Ethel?
I've never even been
to Hollywood.
I live in Napa. That's northern California.
And I live next door to a vineyard.
- A what-yard?
- A vineyard.
It's where you grow grapes
to make wine.
That's what we do.
Me and my dad, we own a vineyard.
- Parker, Hallie!
- Right here.
- Arapaho.
- Same as me. That's where I am.
Yes! Come on, you guys.
So, ah, either of you, by any chance,
know how to play poker?
- No.
- Never played it before.
No? Gee,
what a shame.
So, ah, how much cash did you guys
bring with you this summer?
- How much?
- A lot.
Whoa! Who is in there?
Come on. Let's go.
Well, here we are.
Camp Walden for Girls.
We travelled all the way
from London for this?
Well, it's rather picturesque.
Don't you think?
Eh, um--
Not exactly the term
I think I would have used.
- All right. Shall we review your mother's list?
- Mm-hmm.
- Now, let's see. Vitamins?
- Check.
- Minerals?
- List of daily fruits and vegetables.
- Check. Check.
Check for fruits,
check for vegetables. Go on.
Sun block, lip balm,
insect repellant,
stationery, stamps, photograph
of your mother, grandfather...
and, of course,
your trusty butler, me.
- Got it all, I think.
- Oh, and, um--
Here's a little something
from your grandfather.
A spanking-new deck
of cards.
Maybe you'll actually find somebody on this
continent who can whip your tush at poker.
Well, I doubt it.
But, thanks.
And thanks for
bringing me here, Martin.
Now, you remember,
if you change your mind...
and want me to come here and collect you at
the end of camp, I'm only a phone call away.
Thanks,
but I'll be fine.
Really. See you in eight weeks,
Marty ol' pal.
Missing you already,
queen of my heart.
- Have fun, old bean.
- I will.
- Toodle-oo.
Airport, please.
* Such a feeling
coming over me *
Okay, hurry up.
* There is wonder
in the things I see *
She brought a date.
She didn't.
Mom! Mom! Are you there?
Pick up! Mom!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Slow down. Thank you.
Have some too, okay?
- It's something.
- It smells good.
- I'll save ya a seat, Annie.
- Okay, thanks.
Excuse me, girls. I've just got to have
a scoop of these gorgeous strawberries.
- Would you care for some, dear?
- Oh, no thanks. Can't. I'm-- I'm allergic.
Oh, that's too bad.
How 'bout you, dear? Strawberries?
Oh, sorry, wish I could, but I can't.
I'm-I'm allergic.
Yes, allergic.
You just... told me that.
How did you get over there?
Oh, well. First day of camp.
You'll have to excuse the old girl.
At least I'm not putting
salt in the sugar shakers.
Ah, well, I mean, you know.
Sugar in the salt shak--
Now where did she go?
Touche.
Good job.
All right!
Excellent, kid.
The winner, and still undefeated
champ from Napa, California,
- Miss Hallie Parker.
- Yeah, Hallie.
Do we have
any challengers?
Oh, come on. Ladies,
let's not be damsels in distress here.
I'll take
a whack at it.
Okay. We've got ourselves
a chal-len-ger. Suit up.
Cool.
Ooh, thanks.
Here I go.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Go, Annie. Whoa!
Fencers ready?
Ready. - All set.
En garde! Fence!
- Oops.
- Ah!
Touche!
- Nice catch.
- Thanks.
Touche!
- Sorry, let me help you.
- No, let me help you!
- What'd ya do that for?
- Me? You pushed me in.
I did not.
Okay, that was
quite a show.
All right. I think we've got ourselves
a new camp champ from London, England,
Miss Annie James.
All right, girls.
Shake hands.
Come on, girls.
Oh, my!
Why's everyone
staring?
- Don't you see it?
- See what?
- The resemblance between us.
- Resemblance? Between you and me?
Let me see.
Turn sideways.
Now the other way.
Well, your eyes are
much closer together than mine.
Your ears, well, don't worry,
you'll grow into them.
Your teeth are a little crooked.
Ah! And that nose! Well, don't worry,
dear, those things can be fixed.
- Want me to deck her for ya?
- Hold on. I'm not quite finished yet.
You wanna know
the real difference between us?
Let me see.
I know how to fence and you don't?
Or, I have class and you don't.
Take your pick.
- Why, I oughta--
- Ladies, it's time to break up this little lovefest.
Annie, Hallie.
I mean, Hallie, Annie.
I-I-I mean-- Whoa!
Sorry, ladies. Two pair.
Read 'em and weep.
Aah! I'm out.
- So that's it? No more takers?
- I have nothing left.
I'll take
a whack at it.
Take a seat,
Parker.
Deal me in.
* Now, on the day
I was born *
* The nurses all
gathered 'round *
* And they gazed
in a wide wonder *
* At the joy
they had found *
* The head nurse spoke up *
* Said leave this one alone *
* She could tell right away
that I was bad to the bone *
* Bad to the bone **
Tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'll make you a little deal.
Loser jumps into the lake
after the game.
- Excellent.
- Butt naked.
Even more excellent.
Start unzipping, Parker.
Straight.
In diamonds.
You're good, James.
But, you're
just not good enough.
In your honour,
a royal flush.
- Love the birthday suit.
- Lookin' good.
Oww, baby!
Grab her clothes.
Oh, right. Fine.
If that's the way you want it,
then let the games begin.
I swear I heard your evil clone sneaking all
the way up toward the mess hall this morning.
I am so tired. I'm going back
into bed and sleeping till lunch.
That does not seem like
a possibility, babe.
- Why not?
- That's why not.
No... way.
Shh.
- Be quiet.
- Oh, I hope they're sleeping.
The coast is clear.
Okay, let's go in.
- Payback time.
- Don't wake her.
- Careful.
- Shh.
Got milk?
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
Oh, my God.
She didn't get me.
Ah! That girl
is without a doubt...
the lowest, most awful creature
that ever walked the planet!
Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Morning, girls.
- Morning, Marvas.
Marvas!
Surprise inspection.
Attention!
* Navajos **
No, no, Marva.
Do not go in there.
One of the girls got sick last night,
and it is a big, big mess.
Save yourself the aggravation.
It's really disgusting.
Oh, well, if someone's sick,
dear, then I must go in.
- Move aside, dear.
- No, no, really. I insist.
I can't let you go in there.
She's highly contagious.
Honest.
Actually, we're all
quite fine in here,
unless Hallie Parker knows
something we don't know.
Really. I insist. Open the door
and come see for yourself, ma'am.
Stand aside, Hallie.
Whoa!
Mommy!
No! No!
No!
- I told you it was a mess in here.
- She should know. She did it!
You!
And you!
Pack your bags!
Okay, girls.
The rest of you...
back to your activities.
You two...
the isolation cabin.
Oh!
Oh, gosh,
it's stuck.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Ah! Oh, man!
- Oh, here's your--
- Cuppy.
Any of your
pictures ruined?
- Only the beautiful Leo DiCaprio.
- Who?
You've never heard
of Leonardo DiCaprio?
How far away
is London anyway?
Well, from here
it's 3,000 miles,
but sometimes
it seems much further.
- How far away is your home?
- Oh, California is way at the other end of the country.
Actually, here's a picture of my house.
- Wow! It's beautiful.
- Yeah.
We built it when I was little.
We've got this incredible porch...
that looks over
the entire vineyard.
- And then--
- Who-- Who's that?
Oh, that's my dad. He didn't know
I was taking the picture then...
or else he would have
turned around.
He's kinda like my best friend.
We do everything together.
- What's the matter?
- Oh, it's chilly in here, that's all.
- Want one?
- Oh, sure, I love Oreos.
At home I eat them with--
I eat them with peanut butter.
You do?
That is so weird. So do l.
You're kidding. Most people
find that totally disgusting.
I know.
I don't get it.
Me either.
What's your
dad like?
I mean, is he the kind of father
you can talk to,
or is he one of those workaholic types who says,
"I'll talk to ya later, honey,"
but, you know,
never really does?
- I hate that.
- I don't have a father, actually.
I mean, I had one once,
I suppose.
But my parents
divorced years ago.
My mother never even
mentions him.
It's like he evaporated
into thin air or something.
It's scary the way nobody
stays together any more.
- Tell me about it.
- How old are you?
I'll be 12 on October 11.
- So will l.
- Your birthday's on October 11?
- Yeah.
- How weird is that?
Extremely.
Oh, hey.
It stopped raining.
You wanna go get
a Popsicle or something?
- What's the matter?
- Hallie, what's your mother like?
I never met her. She and my dad split
up when I was a baby, maybe even before.
I'm not sure.
He doesn't like to talk about her.
But I know she was
really, really beautiful.
How do you know that?
Well, because my dad had this old
picture of her hidden in his sock drawer,
and he caught me looking at it, like,
all the time, so he gave it to me to keep.
Look, I'm-I'm really thirsty. Sure you don't want
to go to the mess hall and get a lemonade?
Will you stop thinking about
your stomach at a time like this?
- At a time like what?
- Don't you realize what's happening?
I mean,
think about it.
I only
have a mother,
and you only have
a father.
You've never seen
your mom,
and I've never
seen my dad.
You have one old picture
of your mom,
and I have one old picture
of my dad.
But at least yours
is probably a whole picture.
Mine is a pathetic
little thing,
all crinkled and ripped
right down the middle and--
What are you rummaging
in your trunk for?
This.
It's a picture
of my mom,
and it's
ripped too.
Right down
the middle?
the middle.
This is so...
freaky.
Okay.
On the count of three,
we'll show them to each other, okay?
Okay.
One.
Two.
- Three.
- That's my dad.
- That's my mom.
That's the lunch bell.
I'm not so
hungry any more.
So if--
if your mom...
is my mom...
and my dad
is your dad...
and we're both born on October 11...
then you and I
are like--
Iike sisters.
Sisters?
Hallie, we're
like twins.
I just don't know what to say.
What's that
you're holding?
My locket.
I got it when I was born.
It has an "H"
on it.
I got mine when I was born, too,
except mine has
an "A" on it.
Ooh, now I've got goose bumps.
My God, so I'm
not an only child.
I'm a twin.
I'm a twin-- there's two of me.
I mean,
two of us.
- This is like--
- Mind boggling.
- Totally.
- Completely.
- Oh, my God.
Tell me, what's Mom like?
Well, she designs wedding gowns.
Really?
She's becoming
quite famous, actually.
A princess in Greece
just bought one of her gowns.
Wow.
Y-You know what's
interesting?
Neither one of our parents
ever got married again.
Has Dad ever been close
to getting remarried?
Never. He always says
I'm the only girl in his life.
Yeah, Mom's never
come close either.
I have a brilliant,
beyond brilliant idea.
I'm serious.
I am a total genius.
You want to know
what Dad is like, right?
Right.
And I'm dying
to know Mom.
So what I'm thinking is--
Don't freak out, okay?
I think we should switch places.
When camp's over
I'll go back to London as you,
and you go back
to California as me.
- What?
- Annie, we can pull it off. We're twins, aren't we?
Hallie, we're totally
and completely 100 %/% different.
So, what's the problem?
I'll teach you to be me...
and you teach me
to be you.
Look, I can
do you already.
Yes, you want to know
the difference between us?
I have class
and you don't.
Come on, Ann. I got to meet my ma.
The truth is, you know,
if we switch,
sooner or later
they'll have to unswitch us.
And when they do,
they'll have to meet again,
- face to face.
- After all these years.
Thank you. I told you I'm brilliant.
Okay. 'Tis grandfather.
- He's so cute. What do we call him?
- Grandfather.
Why didn't I think of that?
This is Martin,
he's our butler.
- We have a butler?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay. Living-room's first.
Then over here is the dining room.
But we never eat in there
except for Thanksgiving...
and Christmas and,
of course, October 11.
* Believe in the magic
that can set you free *
* Ahh-hh-hh *
* Talkin' 'bout the magic *
* Do you believe in magic *
* Do you believe, believe *
* Do you believe in magic **
Okay. I-I'm ready.
- Don't shut your eyes!
- Oh. Okay. Right.
Sorry. Just got
a little nervous.
You're nervous?
An 11-year-old is cutting my hair.
Hey, you sounded just like me.
Well, I'm supposed to, aren't I?
Go on, just do it.
Don't panic.
You look great.
Looking good.
This is so... scary.
Honey, you never
looked better.
Oh, my God!
What?
I have
pierced ears.
No. No, no and no.
Not happening.
Sorry, wrong number.
I won't.
I refuse.
Then cutting your hair
was a total waste,
'cause, I mean, there's no way
I can go to camp...
with pierced ears
and come home without 'em.
I mean, come on.
Get real.
Needle sterilized.
Y-You-- You sure you know
what you're doing?
Relax. I've gone with all my friends
to get their ears pierced.
It's nothing.
Just close your eyes,
and it will be over
before you know it.
- Earring ready?
- Yes.
Good.
Hand me the apple.
Thank you.
Just relax. I'm telling you,
this is not a big deal.
On the count of three,
remove the ice.
One... two...
three.
Girls, time to say
your last goodbyes.
- The busses are loading.
- Busses one and two leaving.
I'll see you guys next summer, I promise.
Okay, so call me every single day.
All right. And write me.
Don't forget.
I won't.
Okay. This is it.
So remember, you're going
to find out how Mom and Dad met.
- And you're going to find out why they broke up.
- Annie James,
- your car is here.
- That's you.
Here's your ticket and passport.
Martin will pick you up at the airport tomorrow morning.
- What time do you leave?
- Oh, not for a couple of hours. Give Mom a kiss for me.
- Give Dad one for me.
- Annie James, front and centre.
Bye.
- Bye.
- Last call, Annie James.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Good luck.
Okay. This is it.
God, I hope
she likes me.
Please like me.
Please.
- Annie!
- Martin.
- Missed you.
- What have you done to your hair?
- Cut it. Do you like it?
Love it. It's the new you.
And you've had
your ears pierced.
Give me five,
girlfriend.
* There she goes *
* There she goes again *
* Racing through my brain *
* And I just can't contain *
* This feeling
that she makes *
* There she goes *
* There she goes again *
* She calls my name **
- Home again.
- Thank you.
This is it.
7 Primbrook Lane.
Hello.
Grandfather?
- I'm home.
- Is that my little girl?
That tall, gangly thing?
Yes, it's me.
Oh, welcome home.
- Did you have a good time, sweet pea?
- Uh-huh, great.
What are you doing?
- Just smelling.
- Smelling?
- I'm making a memory.
- Oh.
Years from now,
when I'm all grown up,
I'll always remember
my grandfather...
and how he
always smelt of...
peppermint
and pipe tobacco.
Good to have you back.
Annie?
- Mother.
- You're back.
- I can't believe it's you.
- And I can't believe it's you.
And with short hair.
Who cut it for you?
A girl I met at camp.
Do you hate it?
No, I absolutely
love it.
You got your ears pierced?
Well, are there any other surprises?
Belly button rings,
tattoos?
Ah, darling,
what is it?
I'm sorry.
It's just--
I've missed you
so much.
Oh.
I know.
- It seems like it's been forever.
- You have no idea.
So, come on. Tell me,
did you like everyone? Was it fun?
- Ah, Martin.
- I found a stowaway in your suitcase.
Oh, my God. Cuppy!
- Cuppy?
- He-- He belongs to my friend,
the one I was, umm,
telling you about.
I can't imagine
how he got into my suitcase.
Well, since he's not our Cuppy, shall
we dispose of the little creature?
No! I mean, no.
I'll-- I'll mail him to her.
She loves this thing a lot--
a lot, a lot.
And she's, like,
slept with this thing her entire life,
And she could never be, like--
Stay in a foreign country without him.
No, no. I'll take care of it.
That will be all, Martin.
Thank you.
Hello.
Oh, hi.
How's the photo shoot going?
Hmm. Well, can't you
manage without me?
I mean, Annie just
got home from camp.
Hmm. Yeah.
* Here comes the sun
Do-dum-do-do *
* Here comes the sun *
* And I say
it's all right *
- * Little darlin', it's been a long, cold lonely winter *
- Okay. Hold on a moment.
Annie, would you hate very much
running down to the studio with me?
- * It seems like years *
- No, I'd love it.
* Since it's been here *
* Here comes the sun
Do-dum-do-do *
* Here comes the sun *
* And I say it's all right *
* Little darlin' *
* That smile's returning *
* To their faces *
* Little darlin'
It seems like years *
* Since it's been here *
* Here comes the sun
Do-dum-do-do *
- Wow. That's incredible. You designed that?
- * Here comes the sun and I say *
- * It's all right **
- Well, I had to do something while you were at camp.
- You don't think it's too--
- No, it's gorgeous. I love it.
You know who would look
really beautiful in that gown?
- I mean, like, really beautiful?
- Who?
- You.
- Me?
You know what? I think that time
change has made you a little loopy.
Come on. Let's see
what all the fuss is about.
Okay. I'm here.
Ah, we're saved.
- Hi, Angela.
- Hi. Sorry, we don't know what to do with the veil.
If she wears it, it covers the back
of the dress, and if she doesn't,
- the dress looks--
- lncomplete, you're right.
Can you try turning sideways
with your chin up?
Yeah, I see the problem.
Can I have the veil? Annie, darling,
pass me one of those hats
on display in the window.
- Me?
- Yes.
* Somebody like you *
- Which one do you like?
- The white one.
- Me too.
- * Do you know I'll never let you *
- * Go *
- Try this.
Now, throw the veil
straight back.
That's it. Now spin around.
I want to see the back of the dress.
That's beautiful. Did you get that?
Just how it falls. Just down there.
Don't worry about the bouquet.
You're married now. You've got to learn to juggle.
- Don't forget you look happy. It is your wedding day.
- My mom is too cool.
- * I'll never let you go *
- * Never, never gonna let you go *
* I'll never let you go *
* Never let you go *
* I'll never let you go **
So, doesn't designing all these
wedding gowns ever make you think about...
getting married again, or at least
make you think about the "F" word.
The "F" word?
- My father.
- Oh! Oh, that "F" word.
Well, no, actually,
because I didn't even wear a wedding
gown when I married the "F" word.
- You didn't? Why not?
- Why the sudden curiosity...
about your dad,
huh?
Well, maybe because
he's never mentioned.
And you can't blame
a kid for wondering.
Mother, you can't avoid
the subject forever.
At least tell me
what he was like.
Okay. He was quite lovely,
to tell you the truth.
When we met he was...
actually, entirely lovely.
- All right?
- All right.
So, did you meet
him here in London?
- We met on the Q.E. 2.
- Q.E. what?
The Queen Elizabeth 2.
It's an ocean liner that sails from London to New York,
'cause I wasn't keen on flying then
and neither was your father.
We met our first night on board ship.
We were seated next to each other at dinner.
- He's an American, you know.
- No kidding?
So, was it love at first sight?
I knew you were going to ask me
all these questions one day. Taxi!
Dear ol' Dad.
I wonder what he's doing
at this very moment.
Thanks.
- Got it?
- Oh, gosh.
It's him.
Hey, Hal!
Welcome home,
kiddo.
Get into these arms,
you little punk.
Dad. Finally.
Oh, I hope you had a lousy time at that
camp, because you are not going back.
I missed you too much.
What happened
to you, Hal?
Something's changed.
Are you
getting taller?
So, what's up,
Dad?
I mean, how's Chessy
and everybody?
Great. Everybody's great.
Can't wait to see you.
Eight weeks really
is too long, Hal.
- A lot's been happening around here.
- A lot's happened to me too, Dad.
I mean, I feel like
I'm practically a new woman.
What's the matter?
I cut myself shaving?
No, it's just-- just seeing you
for the first time.
I mean, you know,
in so long.
You look taller to me, too, Dad.
Come on, squirt.
Let's get home.
Oh, by the way,
thanks for all those newsy letters.
I'm really glad I bought you
that personalized stationery...
you just had
to have.
- Well, we meant to write, Dad, but we just got so--
- We?
Oh!
Oh, me and my friend.
I-I met this girl at camp
and we got really close.
- Great.
- Practically like sisters.
- She was a lovely girl.
- Lovely girl?
All of sudden
you're so proper?
You're still biting those nails, I see.
- Dad, you noticed.
- What do you mean noticed?
You've been biting
them since you could chew.
But I've decided to stop, Dad.
It's a horrid habit.
Lovely girl, horrid habit.
What did I do, send you
to summer camp or finishing school?
And why do you keep saying "Dad"
at the end of every sentence?
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
I was doing it, Dad.
Sorry, Dad.
Do you want to know
why I keep saying "dad"?
- The truth?
- Because you missed your old man so much, right?
Exactly. It's because
in my whole life,
I mean, you know,
for the past eight weeks,
I was never able to say the word "dad."
Never. Not once.
And if you ask me,
I mean,
a dad is an irreplaceable
person in a girl's life.
Think about it. There's a whole day
devoted to celebrating fathers.
Just imagine someone's life
without a father--
never buying a Father's Day card,
never sitting on their father's lap,
never being able to say, "Hi, Dad" or "What's up,
Dad" or "Catch you later, Dad."
I mean, a baby's first words
are always "dada," aren't they?
Let me see if I get this--
You miss being able to call me dad?
Yeah.
I really have, Dad.
Oh, my God.
Now you're starting to sound
like your old self.
Hello, gorgeous!
Oh, look at you!
Oh, you grew.
Oh, we missed you
so much.
Hey, don't you dare let your old man talk
you out of going back to camp. Okay?
You're a growing girl.
You need adventure.
- Okay.
- Oh, you hungry?
I made corn bread
and chili.
- Why are you so quiet? What's wrong?
- Nothing, it's just--
I'm so happy
to be home.
Hey, did I hear somethin' about
corn bread and chili?
Yeah, it's on
the stove. So...
something's changed
about you, Hal.
Umm, I can't
put my finger on it,
- but something about you is definitely changed.
- Really?
Well, it's just
the same old me. Honest.
Hi, Sammy.
What is wrong with you,
you goofball? It's Hallie.
Oh, I-I probably just smell
like camp, that's all.
What's the matter
with you?
It's like you didn't even recognize her.
Wow!
It's even better than the pictures.
Okay, kiddo.
What do ya wanna do first, huh?
You wanna eat and then unpack?
Or, uh, we could unpack and then eat.
- Or we could eat while we unpack.
- Do you mean I can eat in my room?
Yeah, I'd say it's
a definite possibility.
Hey, Hal, when you're done, come on down.
There's someone I want you to meet.
- Okay, Dad.
- Okay, Hal.
Look at you. Always eating.
- Did you tell her?
- No.
Nicky.
- I will. I will.
- Tell me what?
Hal, it is none of my business how your
father makes a fool out of himself. Okay?
He's a big boy.
He can do what he wants.
Okay. Okay.
So, who is she?
Her name's
Meredith Blake.
She's a publicist
from San Francisco.
Your father hired her
at the beginning of the summer...
to do some publicity
for the vineyard.
If you ask me, she's doin' a better job
of sellin' herself than the grapes.
What do you mean?
Oy.
Look, you and I both know
your father's...
not some kind of suave, debonair
bachelor-of-the-month type.
So, I gotta ask myself, "What does
a hot, young thing like that...
see in a guy who walks around
with his shirttail hangin' out...
and his cereal bowl
full of chili?"
Then, I realized there's about a million
reasons why that girl's gigglin'.
And all of them are sitting at
the Napa Valley Community Bank.
You mean, you don't think
she even really likes him?
Eh, what do I know?
But I'll tell you one thing.
This one's got your father
eating out of the palm of her hand.
They do everything together.
They ride together.
They swim together.
They go out to eat dinner every night.
But, you know what? Meet her. See for
yourself. Don't let me influence you.
There's my girl.
Honey, I want you to meet
a friend of mine. Hal,
this is Meredith Blake.
Hi.
Hi,
Meredith Blake.
Wow. I can't believe I'm finally
meeting the famous Hallie.
I have looked forward
to this all summer.
Really?
Well, here I am.
Oh, Nicky,
she's adorable!
You know, the way your father
talked about you,
I expected to meet a little girl,
but you are so grown up.
I'll be 12 soon. How old are you?
Twenty-six.
Only 15 years older than me.
How old are you, again, Dad?
Wow! Suddenly, you're
so interested in math.
Look, I'm gonna go inside.
I'm gonna get some more chili,
maybe a bottle of champagne
to celebrate.
- What are we celebrating?
- Your homecoming, of course.
Be right back.
Meredith Blake.
Hello, Reverend Mosby.
Mm-hmm. Of course. No, I understand
it's for a local charity?
Oh, yes.
I am writing it all down.
Okay, it sounds
very worthwhile, I agree.
But, unfortunately,
I see that Mr Parker...
is going to be
out of the country on those days.
Yes. Absolutely.
I will be sure to mention it to him.
Thank you.
So, how was camp, Hal?
Was it fabulous?
My dad's going
out of the country?
Oh, no. I just had to tell a little
white lie to get him out of something.
You know, I have never heard a man
talk about his daughter...
the way Nicky
talks about you.
You two are obviously
incredibly close.
Well, you know,
we're closer than close.
We're all
each other has.
Ohh!
Sorry. Did I
get you wet, Mer?
Just a little, Hal.
Mm.
Hey.
Guess what?
Your daddy took me riding the other day,
and he let me ride your horse.
I hope that's okay
with you.
Oh, sure. She's probably used
to strange women riding her.
Not that you're
strange or anything.
Actually, compared to the others,
you are relatively normal.
Others?
What others?
- Do you want the 411?
- What's the 411?
The information--
the lowdown on other women.
Can't say
I blame you.
I'd wanna know if I was number 28--
I mean, 29 in a man's life.
I'm number 29?
Yeah. It's always
the same routine--
horseback riding
through the vineyards,
romantic dinners with
his special reserved-label wine,
- moonlight swims--
- Here we go--
a bottle of my special
reserve-label.
So, did you girls find something
to talk about while I was gone?
- Does that mean yes?
- It sure does.
Will somebody grab that, please?
James residence.
Annie?
- Yes, Martin.
- Oh, dear. It sounds just like you on the phone.
I'm sorry.
To whom did you wish to speak?
Annie?
Of course.
One moment, please.
A Mildred Plotker
for you.
Sounds just like
your twin.
My twin?
Very funny.
Good one, Martin.
Hello.
Oh, Mildred, darling.
Hi. How are you?
- Hey, how's it going over there?
- Oh, everything's quite lovely here.
W-We're expecting
a bit of rain today.
But, Mildred, can you--
can you hold on for a moment?
Okay, but hurry, Hal.
I've got to talk to you.
Okay. Now I can talk. Oh, my God! Mom's incredible.
I cannot believe I lived
my entire life without knowing her.
Sh-She's beautiful
and fun...
- and smart, and I love the gowns she designs.
- But--
And I got her talking about how she
and Dad first met. And, if you ask me,
- there's like a whole possibility, like--
- Hallie, stop!
We've got a major problem. You're going to
have to bring Mother out here immediately.
Immediately? Are you nuts?
I've only had one day with her.
I'm just getting to know her.
I can't. I won't.
But this is an emergency!
Dad's in love.
Get out of here!
Dad doesn't fall in love.
I mean,
at least not seriously.
Trust me.
He's serious about this one.
He's always holding her hand
and kissing her neck...
and waiting on her
hand and foot.
- He is?
- It's disgusting.
Well, you'll just have to break 'em up.
Sabotage her. Do whatever you have to.
I'm trying, but, I mean,
I'm at a slight disadvantage.
I only met the man
12 hours ago.
Hal, you've got to get
back here to help me.
Annie, I can't.
I want more time with Mom.
What's going on?
Ann, are you still there?
I can barely hear you. Ann.
- I'm here. What do you--
- Operator. Operator.
- I think I lost you, Ann.
- Hello?
Thanks for all the help, Hal.
Hm.
Hi. I had a phone call
from a friend at camp.
Yeah. I-It's
an old camp tradition.
Talk to your friend from inside a closet.
Kinda stupid, I know, but--
So, breakfast anyone?
Okay. Here we go.
Most important meal of the day.
Eggs sunny-side up,
bacon, side of toast...
and, in case you're
really hungry,
a stack of humongous chocolate chip
pancakes, which smell incredible,
- if I do say so myself.
- Thanks, Chessy.
You're not hungry again?
You hardly touched your chili,
your favourite food in the world.
And now you don't want breakfast?
Are you sick, honey?
I'm fine.
I promise.
Where's Dad?
Oh. He and Miss "I'll Just Have
Half A Grapefruit, Thank You"...
Ieft about
an hour ago.
You overslept,
and he didn't want to wake you.
Of course, I'd probably oversleep, too,
if I were up until midnight...
making mysterious phone calls
from my bathroom.
Um. Oh. Oh. That.
I was calling a friend
from camp, Mildred.
She lives
in New York.
Oh, I see. So, you wanted
to wait and call Mildred...
at a time that was convenient for her
because of the time difference.
Exactly. Because--
Because of the time difference.
Uh-huh. So, you waited until it was
3:00 in the morning her time?
- That makes perfect sense.
- Actually--
It was 7:00 at night
her time.
You see, she lives in New York,
but she was on vacation...
with her family
in Bora Bora.
- Mm-hmm.
- Very smooth.
Okay, look, smarty pants,
your father wants you...
to meet him at his office as soon
as you're done with breakfast.
He does?
Thanks.
I'm done.
That dog
has gotten so weird.
Bye, Chessy. Thanks again
for breakfast. It was great.
Push, Hal.
Sorry. I... forgot.
Honey, I'm really glad
you're here,
'cause there's something really
important I want to talk to you about.
That's funny, because there's something really
important that I want to talk to you about.
- Yeah? Well, you go first.
- No, you.
Okay. I want to talk to you
about Meredith.
And I want to talk to you
about my mother.
- What about Meredith?
- Well, what about your mother?
Dad, I'm almost 12.
How long do you expect me...
to buy that story that the stork
dropped me on your doorstep?
Oh, come on, Hal.
We've talked about your mother.
No, we haven't.
Not really.
A girl needs more in life than
a half a crumpled old photograph.
Dad, I'm almost
a teenager.
Face it.
I need a mother.
You know what?
You're right.
You're absolutely right. You do need
a mother. Which brings me to--
- Meredith.
- Hi. Hello, Hal.
Hi.
Hallie, this is
my assistant, Richard.
Richard, this is Nick's daughter, the
one I've been telling you so much about.
- Oh, hello. How are you?
- Hi there.
- Did you tell her?
- Almost.
Hey, if you're free later,
why don't we all
have lunch on the terrace?
Well, actually, I promised Hal
we'd hang out together this afternoon.
Oh, no problem.
I've got plenty to do.
I'm working on a new label design,
Nicky, featuring Y-O-U.
You're gonna love it.
See you for dinner, darling.
- Bye, Hal.
- Bye.
The first change I make is to send
that two-faced little brat...
off to boarding-school
in Timbuktu.
Ooh. Ice Woman!
And proud of it, babe.
Come on, Dad.
Okay. Okay. You win.
Pull up.
Give that horse a rest.
Whoa, Sprout.
So, honey, are you excited about our camping trip?
- What camping trip?
The one
we take every summer...
before you go back
to school.
Oh. Oh. That camping trip.
Yeah. Sure. I can't wait.
So, uh, Hal.
What do you think
of Meredith?
As what, Dad?
Your-- Your publicist,
your friend, your--
No. Just what do you think
of her as a person?
Oh. She's cute.
She has nice hair,
good teeth.
She can spell
the word "you."
Honestly, Dad, the woman is
a complete stranger to me.
Why do you
want my opinion, anyway?
Well, I'll tell
you why, Hal.
- Because, believe it or not--
- Race you back to the ranch, Dad.
H-Hal.
Hal, I'm trying
to tell you something.
Hey!
Slow down.
I'm in so over my head, here.
I-I can't handle this.
I-I just can't.
I'm only one kid.
- You got something you want
to share with the class, there, Hal?
Chessy, you--
you gave me a fright.
I gave you
a fright?
You scared me. I didn't know
you were like-- Iike in here.
Are you sure there isn't anything
you want to talk to me about?
Like, why Sammy never comes
near you any more.
Or why your
appetite's changed.
Or why, all of a sudden,
you're neat as a pin...
and using expressions like,
"You gave me a fright."
Chessy, l... changed a lot
over the summer, that's all.
Okay.
Boy, if I didn't know any better,
I'd say it's almost like you were--
Forget it.
It's impossible.
Almost as if
I were who, Chessy?
Nobody. Nobody.
Forget I mentioned it.
Almost as if
I were... Annie?
You know
about Annie?
I am Annie.
- Oh.
- Hal.
Hal, why did you take off
on me like that?
I told you I wanted
to talk to you about something.
Chessy, why are you
looking at her like that?
Like what?
I'm not looking at her any special way.
I'm looking at her like
I've looked at her for 11 years.
Since the day she came home
from the hospital--
Six pounds, 11 ounces,
21 inches long--
This is how
I look at her.
Can I hug her?
Oh, she's so beautiful...
and so big.
I'm gonna make you
something special to eat.
What would you like?
Anything? You know what?
It doesn't matter. I'm just gonna
go whip up everything we've got.
Okay?
Okay.
Hal, come here.
Now, we have to talk.
- Okay. Shoot.
- Okay.
Honey,
I wanna know what you think
about making Meredith...
part of the family.
- Part of our family?
- Yeah.
- I think it's an awesome idea. Inspired.
- Yeah? You do?
- Brilliant. Really?
- Really? You do?
Totally. I mean, like it's a dream come
true. I've always wanted a big sister.
Oh.
Um. Honey, I think
you're kinda missin' the point.
No, I'm not.
You're going to adopt Meredith.
That is so sweet, Dad.
No, I'm not going
to adopt her.
I'm... going
to marry her.
Marry her!
That's insane!
How can you marry a woman
young enough to be my big sister?
Hal. Hal. Hal, calm down.
Hal.
Are you speaking French?
I-I learned it
at camp.
Okay.
I'm-I'm sorry.
Let-Let's discuss this calmly--
calmly and rationally.
- Yeah, and in English, if you don't mind. All right?
- Okay.
Sweetheart, what
has gotten into you?
Nothing. Nothing.
Just-- Just--
Dad, you can't
get married.
It'll totally ruin
completely everything.
Hal. Hal.
Hallie.
Don't look at me.
I don't know a thing.
She thought I was going to adopt her?
- Hi, doll.
- Hi.
Oh, you look
stressed, baby.
- How about a martini?
- How about a double?
Coming right up.
Chessy.
Don't you love it? It's just what
we need. It's such a big house.
Chessy!
You rang?
Two martinis, please.
And make Mr Parker's a double.
Chess, please.
I'm getting a migraine.
Mm-hmm.
I told Hallie.
You did?
And?
She went ballistic.
She started yelling in French.
I didn't even know
she spoke French.
I don't know what's
gotten into her.
Oh, Nicky. This reaction
is totally classic.
It's "Daddy's Getting
Remarried 101."
I'd be worried if
she didn't act this way.
Look. Why don't I
go talk to her?
You know,
woman to woman.
I-I think she's a little sensitive
about you right now.
That's why
I need to do it.
We've got to break
the ice sometime.
Wear your shirt
like this.
I like it when I can see
a little chest hair.
Hm.
Knock, knock.
Can I join you?
Sure.
Guess the news
of the engagement...
- came as a bit of a shock, huh?
- Basically.
You know, I remember
what it was like to be 11.
I had my first beau at 11.
It's a wonderful age.
You're just starting to feel
like a woman,
and, believe it or not,
soon, you'll understand...
what it's like
to be in love.
Me?
I don't think so.
I don't even have
my 12-year-old molars yet.
Oh, well.
Take it from someone...
who got their molars
very early in life,
being in love is
a fantastic mystery...
that takes a man
and a woman--
I don't mean to be jerky when you're
trying to be all mushy and everything,
but I know what mystery
my dad sees in you.
You do?
You're young and beautiful
and sexy.
And, hey.
The guy's only human.
But, if you ask me,
marriage is supposed to be...
based on something more
than just sex, right?
Boy.
Your father
underestimates you.
But you won't,
will you, Meredith?
Being young and beautiful
is not a crime, you know.
And for your 411,
I adore your father.
He's exactly the kind of man
I always planned on marrying.
This is
the real deal, honey,
and nothing you do is going
to come between us.
Hate to break
it to you, angel,
but you are no longer
the only girl in Nick Parker's life.
- Get over it.
- If this is the real deal,
then my dad's money...
has nothing to do with you
wanting to marry him, right?
Okay, puss. You listen,
and you listen good.
I am marrying your father in two weeks,
whether you like it or not.
So I suggest you do not tangle
with me any more.
You are in way over your head.
Is that clear?
Crystal.
Martin, a refill, please.
You must have grown
three inches, I swear,
in six weeks.
- Lovely choice of wine, by the way, Martin.
- Thank you, sir.
May I have a sip?
I don't think
you're gonna like it.
Well, if you ask me, the bouquet is
a little too robust for a Merlot,
but, then again, I'm partial to
the softer California grape.
She learned about wine
at this summer camp?
She must have.
Darling, are you all right?
I had one sip too many,
I guess.
You know, Mother, I feel like
I could use a bit of fresh air.
W-Would it be okay if
I stepped outside for a moment?
Are-Are you okay?
Would you like me to go with you?
Oh, no, no, no. I'll be fine.
Just got a touch woozy, that's all.
Woozy, huh?
Um, yes, I'd like to place
a collect call to America, please.
Hello.
- What's up?
- Hal, I'm desperate.
- Dad's getting married.
- What do you mean, getting married?
I mean black tie, white gown--
the whole enchilada.
- What?
- The wedding's in two weeks.
So, if there's any hope of getting
Mom and Dad back together,
we've got to do it fast,
and I mean really fast.
Okay. So, Mom and I are going out
to the theatre tonight.
I'll-I'll drop the bomb on her
first thing in the morning.
Okay. Thanks.
- And, Hallie, hurry!
- Okay, I will.
Oh, excuse me, sir.
- Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh. Yes.
Now, what say you and I
take a little stroll...
in the park,
eh, young lady?
- Okay.
- Um. Now--
- Come on. What's this all about?
- Well, it's a long story.
Well, it's a very big park, and we've
got plenty of time, you know.
Well, first of all--
Just do it, sweet pea.
Darling, come in.
I just have to finish this sketch...
and FedEx it
off to Paris.
And then, how about you and I
go out to lunch...
and spend the rest of the day
getting lost in Harrod's, huh?
I can't, Mother.
Sorry. I-I have to go
out of town today.
Oh, you have
to go out of town?
And where, may I ask,
are you going?
- Annie. Annie.
- That's where I have to go.
- I have to go see Annie.
- I see. And where might Annie be?
In Napa with her father,
Nick Parker.
You're not Annie?
That would be correct.
You're Hallie?
I am.
Annie and I
met at the camp,
and-and we decided
to switch places.
I'm sorry,
but I've never seen you,
and-and I dreamt of meeting you
my whole life.
And Annie felt the exact
same way about Dad, so--
so, we sorta
just switched lives.
I hope you're
not mad,
because I love you so much,
and I just hope that one day...
you could love me as me
and not as Annie.
Oh, darling.
I've loved you
your whole life.
I've never been so happy
in my entire life.
So, l-- I guess you have
to switch us back now, huh?
Well, technically,
you belong to your dad,
and Annie belongs to me.
His-and-hers kids.
No offence, Mom,
but this arrangement really sucks.
I agree,
it totally sucks.
Then, I say we fly to Napa,
see Annie and Dad...
and work this
whole thing out.
And I say
you're right.
Not to worry, darling.
I'll take care of everything.
You're not to worry.
Okay?
I'm sorry.
I can't handle this.
I mean, I haven't seen or heard
from Nick Parker in over 11 years,
and suddenly I'm flying
halfway across the world to--
I'm not mature enough for this.
If the man didn't make me so nuts,
I'd still be married to him.
I mean, we came up with this arrangement so
that we'd never have to see each other again.
I mean, look at me, Martin.
Have you ever seen me like this?
- We-- I--
- Don't answer that.
I mean, what if he doesn't
recognize me?
No, don't answer that,
either.
So, Hallie said
he was a-- a hunk?
He was rather dishy.
He had a smile that made me go weak
at the knees, if you can imagine that.
- Okay, I'm all set, Mom.
- Great. Me too. Almost.
Mom, your-your suitcase
is like totally empty.
Oh, right.
Sorry.
Um, did you speak
to your father, dear?
Um, yeah. Yeah.
I just hung up with him, actually.
He said he's really anxious
to see you.
Anxious-nervous, like he's totally,
completely dreading it?
- Or anxious-excited, like he's looking forward to it?
- Anxious-excited, definitely.
- Oh.
- He said he'll meet us tomorrow at noon...
at the Stafford Hotel
in San Francisco.
My, my, my.
That's incredibly soon. Isn't it?
Well, um, why don't you run downstairs
and-- and gather up our tickets...
- from your grandfather while I finish up here.
- Okay.
Liar, liar.
Pants on fire.
- Shh!
- Oh, Martin. I have a really ridiculous,
somewhat childish request
to make.
Martin, you know that
you're more than a butler to me.
You're more like a lovable brother who
just happens to wait on us, and, anyway,
- I was wondering if--
- I would accompany you on the trip?
- Make it a bit easier for you?
- Would you, Martin? Thank you so much.
I'd be so grateful and you don't
even have to come as our butler.
- Just as a friend.
- Madam, I'd be honoured.
And may I say as a friend,
if I was seeing my ex...
after 11 years
and I had your legs,
I'd wear
this little baby.
You'll kill in it!
- Bye, darling.
- Wish me luck.
Good luck.
- Bye, Pop.
- Bye, Hal.
So you're coming to Napa
for Thanksgiving. Right?
I wouldn't miss it
for the world.
Bye.
- Oh, and say hello to your father for me.
- I will.
Airport, please.
Okay. They'll be here
any minute.
Now, be nice, Daddy.
He's everything you ever wanted...
for your little girl,
plus millions more.
Then you know
I'll be nice.
Oh! Okay. There he is...
with the whole
motley crew.
- Hi, darling.
- Hi.
Hallie, Chessy
and Sammy!
What in the world
are you doing here?
Honey, a dog
at the Stafford?
- Hal begged me to bring him.
- Oh, you're such a softy.
- Oh!
- Good doggy.
So, Meredith.
These the folks?
Yes. Mom, Dad.
You finally meet.
This is my fianc and the love
of my life, Nicholas Parker.
Hello, Nicholas.
I'm so pleased to meet you.
- I'm Vicki.
- Hi.
And this is Nick's
adorable daughter, Hallie.
This entire prenuptial get together
was her idea, I'll have you know.
How are you, young lady?
We've heard nothing...
- but wonderful things about you.
- Hello, pet.
You may call me
Aunt Vicki.
- Other end, madam.
- Oops!
- Yopes!
- That was a great flight. Wasn't it?
- I mean, it was so quick.
- I've never seen you quite so thirsty before, madam.
Well, would you believe, Martin darling,
I've never tasted vodka before this trip.
You could have
fooled me, ma'am.
Come on. Let's rock and roll.
I am in such
major trouble here.
If the hotel can do it, I think
that room is perfect for the wedding.
Not too big. Not too cramped.
And not that...
I don't like the idea
of having the wedding at the house,
- it's just that this could be amazing.
- Sammy!
So, I've already checked us in.
Why don't we go upstairs,
- freshen up and then rendezvous for lunch?
- Great!
- Meet you in the bar in ten. Okay?
- Oh! Perf.
Sweetheart,
now that we're here,
why don't we go check out
the honeymoon suite?
I bet it is to die for.
Ooh. Oops!
I forgot my bag.
Hey, hang on. Sammy!
Sammy!
- Sammy.
- Excuse me. Did you find a beige-- Thank you.
- Oop!
- Mom!
Darling, you didn't have to wait for me.
I could have found the room by myself.
Besides, I need to get
a little fresh air.
Go on, sweetie.
I'll meet you up "thairs."
I like that jacket, by the way. Were you wearing
that the whole time we were on the plane?
- Mom, watch out!
- Sorry.
She's drunk. She's never had
more than one glass of wine...
in her entire life, and she chooses
today to show up totally zonked.
Yeah, well, just do
what the woman says...
and meet her up "thairs."
Maybe that's why they make
"do not disturb" signs.
Alone at last.
Hallie Parker.
Oh. Don't do this to me.
I'm already seeing double.
It's me, Mom,
Annie.
Oh, darling.
You look wonderful.
Oh, my girls.
I can't believe
you're together.
But how could you do this to me?
Excuse me.
I hate to interrupt but,
might I suggest that
we continue...
this little powwow inside?
Hi. You probably
don't remember me.
Chessy!
I knew I always
liked her.
One of you, I'm not sure
which one at the moment,
but one of you told me your father
knew I was arriving here today.
And I'm here to tell you
the man I just saw in the elevator...
had absolutely no idea he and I were on the
same planet, let alone in the same hotel.
- You saw Dad already?
- Yes, I did.
Oh! The man went
completely ashen like I was...
the bloody ghost
of Christmas past.
Can one of you get
something cold for my head?
I mean, don't you think I pondered
what it was going to be like to see...
your father after
all these years?
Well, let me tell you.
Me waving like a mindless idiot...
while Nick Parker's wrapped around
another woman's arms...
is not exactly the scenario
I had in mind.
No, sirree.
Martin! What are you doing?
Going for a dip, madam. Do you mind?
Uh? No, no. No, that's--
that's perfectly perfect. Have fun.
- Someone ought to.
- Hello.
Hello.
Hello to you.
- Chessy, this is our butler Martin.
- How do you do?
I'm her butler.
Gee! The pleasure
is all mine, monsieur.
Girls, you were going
to tell me why you lied...
- and brought me here without telling your father.
- Were they?
Okay, that's good. Uh, well,
then I'm just gonna go back to my room and check out...
- the old mini-bar situation.
- Allow me to assist you.
Wait! Does everyone here
know something I don't know?
Mom. Daddy's
getting married.
To Cruella de Vil.
She's awful, Mom.
- We can't let him go through with it.
- She's all wrong for him, Mom.
And the only way he won't marry her
is if-- You tell her.
She knows you better.
- Is if he sees you again.
- Wait a minute!
You're not trying to set me up
with your father?
Actually, we are.
You're perfect for each other.
Hold it.
You two knew about this?
What? Oh, no.
- No! Madam, no. Absolutely no idea.
- No, no, no, no. I had no idea.
- Yes. I did know something.
- Yes. Technically, yes. I had an inkling anyway.
- Hallie told me the story.
- It's their idea. It's so sweet.
- I'm an old romantic, you know. You know me.
- So am l.
Okay, okay.
Let me say this...
Ioud and clear.
Nick Parker and I have absolutely
nothing in common... any more.
Plus, in case
you haven't noticed,
he seems extremely content with his
leggy, tight-skirted, bare-backed fiance.
And I want the two of you to explain to your
father that I am here for one purpose only.
And that is to switch
the two of you back.
Now, let's do what we have to do
and be done with it. Understood?
- Hey, Dad. What's up?
- Hi. Just running down to the lobby. Hey, Hal!
- Huh?
- Do me a favour, will you, while I'm gone.
- Will you just look after Meredith for me?
- Mm-hmm.
- Huh? Thanks. Hallie, Hallie.
- Yeah?
How do I look?
Like presentable and everything?
- Not too old?
- You look fab, Dad. Young and fab.
- Dad.
- I thought you were going to keep Meredith company.
- I was?
- Yeah.
I mean, I am, yeah. I was
just looking for her, actually.
Great to see you,
Dad.
It's great to see
you too, squirt.
- Nice outfit.
- Oh. Thanks.
Well, go on.
Get up there. Come on.
* Let's get together
Yeah, yeah, yeah *
* Why don't you and I combine *
* Let's get together
What do you say **
- Have you seen your father?
- You talkin' to me?
What are you? Robert De Niro?
Yes, I am talking to you.
Oh, Meredith.
- Uh, yeah. I just saw him.
- Well, hello! Where was he?
Uh, he went that-a-way.
I think.
- What are you staring at?
- Oh, nothing, nothing.
You're just really very pretty.
That's all.
Oh. Don't tell me you're gonna
break your rotten streak...
and suddenly
be nice to me?
If you see your father,
tell him he's late and I'm waiting.
Whatever you say,
Cruella.
Here you go.
This will cure anything you've got.
- Just don't ask what's in it.
- Okay.
Here's to--
Here's to you.
May your life be
far less complicated than mine.
Thank you.
Ugh.
Martini, dry, please.
I beg your pardon.
I--
I think I just drank tar.
Here's your martini
and your bill, Ms James.
Thank you.
- You're Elizabeth James?
- Guilty.
Ah! I just saw a wedding dress you designed
in Vogue and fell completely in love with it.
I faxed your office just yesterday
and they said you were out of town...
and didn't know
if you could make another.
- I can't believe it. It's fate. I'm Meredith Blake.
- How do you do?
Sorry.
- Excuse me.
Where have you been?
We've been looking all over for you.
Nicholas, I think this hotel
is perfect for the wedding.
- The more I see of it, the more I like it.
- Me too.
Absolutely.
Now, tell me, dear. How many are we
expecting from your side of the family?
Just a guestimate.
Can I get back to you on that?
I'm-- I'm not sure at the moment.
Excuse me.
Pardon me. Sorry.
- Oh, boss, are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Uh, sir? Oh!
- Dad, watch out!
Oh! - Oh, careful!
- Hello, Liz.
- Hello, Nick.
Well, gosh. There you are.
What do you know?
Uh... is there something going on here
that I should know about,
because I'm stunned
to see you.
But, uh, you don't seem
as stunned to see me.
I mean, I haven't seen or heard
from you in what-- ten, eleven years?
- All of a sudden on the very day that--
- Dad...
- I can explain why she's here.
- Hallie. You know who this is?
Actually, yes.
And actually,
I'm not Hallie.
Actually,
I am.
Both of them?
Annie? Hallie?
I guess you and Mom kind of think
alike 'cause you both sent us...
to the same camp
and we met there.
And the whole thing
just sort of spilled out.
They switched
places on us, Nick.
You mean I've had Annie
with me all this time?
Well, I wanted to know what you were
like, and Hallie wanted to know Mom.
And...
are you angry?
Oh, honey.
Of course not.
I just can't believe
it's you.
Last time I saw you, you had diaper
rash. Oh, squirt, you're all wet.
- It's all right.
- Look at you.
Well, I'm grown up now
and quite without a father.
And I'm headed into my crazy,
mixed-up teenage years,
and I'll be the only girl I know
without a mother to fight with.
Hallie, you've been in London
all this time?
Come here,
squirt.
Mom's amazing, Dad. I don't know
how you ever let her go.
Girls, why-- why don't
you let your father and l...
talk alone for a couple
of minutes, okay?
- Sure. Fine.
- Take your time.
I don't
believe this.
Seeing them
together.
- And seeing you. Ow!
- Ooh! Let me help you with that.
- Oh, excuse me. Do you have a first aid kit?
- Yeah, of course.
Why don't you
lie down?
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
So, how are you,
Lizzy?
Or does everyone
call you Elizabeth now?
Oh, no, no. Lizzy's-Lizzy's fine.
My dad still calls
me Lizzy.
- Yeah. I've been, uh, been terrific.
- Yeah.
You know, you haven't
changed a bit.
Finally.
There you are.
Oh! Uh... oh, good. You've met.
Honey, Elizabeth designs...
wedding gowns
and she's going to make my--
Wait, um...
I-- I don't understand.
How did you two meet?
And Nicky, why are you all wet?
You're making my fiance's
wedding gown.
Well, I-I didn't know
she was your fiance.
Well, how did we meet?
How did you two meet?
- Am I missing something here?
- You know what?
- This is one small world.
- Um, how small?
- Hi, Meredith.
- Hello.
- How ya doin'?
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
Honey, did I ever mention to you
that Hallie was a twin?
No. I'm afraid you forgot
that little detail.
Don't feel bad, Mer.
He never mentioned it to me either.
By the way, I'm the real Hallie.
This is Annie.
She was pretending to be me
while I was pretending to be her.
And this is our mother,
Elizabeth James.
This is your mother?
- Yes. - Yes.
- You were married to him?
- Yeah.
- Guilty again.
Oh, well.
This is a small world.
- And getting smaller.
- And what a coincidence...
that we're all here
on the exact same weekend.
My, my, my.
How sweet.
Hal, I've had
enough surprises for one day.
Will you please just tell me
where we're going?
You're gonna love it, Dad.
Trust me.
Hello.
Hey.
So, uh... do you have
any idea where they're taking us?
- Not a clue.
- Right.
Where are we?
This is where
we're eating?
No. Actually,
that's where we're eating.
It's ours for the night.
Wow! So, how exactly
are we paying for this?
- Well, we pooled our allowances.
- Yeah. Right, Annie.
Okay.
Grandfather chipped in a bit.
- Annie.
- Okay. He chipped in a lot.
- Come on. You guys are gonna love it.
- Pretty snazzy.
Elizabeth and Nick,
your dinner awaits you.
Girls.
The table
is only set for two.
Oh, that's the other part
of the surprise.
- We're not joining you.
- You're not?
No, but I am.
Good evening. I'm Chessy,
and I'll be your server this evening.
- No wisecracks, please.
- And I'm Martin your sommelier.
May I offer you both
a taste of the bubbly...
in the hope that
you get a bit shnockered...
and not fire this lovely lady
and myself...
for following the orders
of these audacious 11-year-olds.
Annie, mood music,
please.
* I love you *
Just relax.
- * For sentimental reasons *
- Sail though time back to yesteryear.
* I hope you do believe me *
You do get all this,
don't you?
- Yes, I'm beginning to.
- * I'll give you my heart *
- They're recreating the night we met-- the boat,
the music-- - * I love you *
- The help.
- It's so sweet.
Martin, I think I'll take that drink.
Thank you, Martin.
Oh! Yeah.
- * And say we'll never part *
- To tell you the truth,
- I haven't been on a boat since the Q.E. 2.
- Neither have l.
Hmm? Well, then,
here's to, uh--
Our daughters.
* Darling, I'm never lonely *
- Now I know how a goldfish feels.
- Ugh!
You know, sometime
if we're ever really alone,
maybe we could...
talk about...
what happened
between us.
It all feels a bit hazy to me now.
It ended so fast.
It started so fast.
Well, that part
I remember perfectly.
- * I've given you my heart **
- It looks like things are heating up quite nicely.
I'd say it's safe
to serve the vichyssoise.
You ladle,
I'll serve.
I'm sorry.
Yes, I'll...
uh, ladle.
Right.
And then I'll--
- Serve?
- Right.
Right.
So... you've done
fantastically well. Um...
your dream of owning your own
vineyard actually came true.
Mm-hmm. What about you?
You were always drawing...
on napkins
and corners of newspapers.
- Now you're this major designer.
- Yeah, it's great.
We both actually got
where we wanted to go.
Yeah, we did.
Anyway, what are we going
to do about the girls?
Well, now that they met,
we can't very well keep them apart.
Well, I could keep them for half of
the year, and then you could keep them.
- Well-- - Guys.
They can't go to two different schools every year.
- That's nuts.
- I agree.
Well, then, I could keep them both for
a whole year, and you could keep them...
- Liz.
- Hmm. Mm-mm.
- That's why we came up with--
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, G-- Sorry. Ignore me. Enjoy your soup.
That's why we came up
with the solution that we have.
Really?
I thought it was because...
we decided never to see
each other again.
Not we, Liz.
Well, you know, that part's become
a bit hazy to me, too, over the years.
- You don't remember the day you packed?
- No, that day I remember perfectly.
Did I hurt you when
I threw that, um...
- What was it? Uh, uh--
- It was... a hair dryer.
Oh, right. Sorry.
You know, I may never
be alone with you again.
So, about that day that you packed--
Why'd you do it?
Oh, Nick.
We were so young...
and we both had tempers.
We said stupid things
and so I packed.
Got on
my very first 747,
and... you didn't
come after me.
I didn't know that
you wanted me to.
Well, it doesn't
really matter any more.
So, let's just
put a good face on...
for the girls and get the show
on the road, huh?
Yeah, sure.
Let's...
get the show
on the road.
Your passport, Ms James.
Have a safe trip home.
Thank you.
- All set then. Where's Annie?
- I just rang up. She's on her way down.
Right.
So, I'll send Hallie
back to you over Christmas.
- And Annie will spend Easter with you.
- Mm-hmm.
Honey, what are you doing in those
clothes? We've got a plane to catch.
Here's the deal, Mom. We thought it over,
and we decided we're being totally gypped.
Dad promised we'd go on our camping
trip. And we want to go... together.
What camping trip?
The one we go on every summer
before school starts.
Annie, this is ridiculous.
Go upstairs and put your clothes on.
- Are you sure I'm Annie?
- Well, of course, I'm sure.
But, it's kind of hard
to be 100 %/% positive, isn't it?
Girls, this is totally unfunny.
You're gonna make your mother miss her aeroplane.
- Annie!
- Yes!
This one's Hallie.
I'm positive.
You know, I hope
you're right, Dad.
Because you wouldn't want to send the
wrong kid all the way back to England.
Would you?
Here's our proposition.
We go back to Dad's house,
pack our stuff,
and the four of us leave
on the camping trip.
- The four of us?
- And when you bring us back,
- we'll tell you who's Annie and who's Hallie.
- Or you do as we say,
and I take one of you back with me
to London whether you like it or not.
And what am I supposed to do
for three days? Sit home and knit?
Honey, we have kind of
a sticky situation.
- Sticky situation? What do you mean,
"sticky situation"? What exactly-- - Hmm-hmm.
Excuse me.
What is she doing here?
You see, that's part of the deal.
The four of us--
We... go together.
- What are you suddenly, the Brady Bunch? This is ridic--
- Hello.
Everything all right?
Well, no.
Actually it isn't.
I didn't realize that
you were going on this little outing.
- And to tell you the truth,
I'm not so sure that I'm okay with it. - I agree.
I think the ex-wife in
the next sleeping bag is a little weird.
- Thank you.
- I absolutely insist that you come with us. Really.
Liz--
No, honestly, Nick.
I've messed up your entire weekend.
It's the least I can do.
Really, please.
Dad, what's Meredith
doing here?
- Your mother invited her.
- What?
Be nice.
- Okay. All set? Have fun, everyone.
- What?
Liz, what are
you doing?
Well, I really think that you and Meredith
need some time alone before the big day.
Mom, come on!
That's not the plan.
Ah, honestly, you'll have
much more fun without me.
Wait, wait. If you're not going,
I certainly don't have to go.
I mean, trust me,
I'm not a big nature girl.
But this is your chance
to really get to know the girls.
I mean after all,
starting next week, they're--
they're half yours.
Have fun all of you!
Bye-bye!
Oh, I would pay big money
to see that woman climb a mountain.
Whoa!
- Come on, you guys.
- Whoa! Oh!
Oh, I'm gonna
kill my trainer.
He says I'm in such great shape. I can't
believe people actually do this for fun.
Hold on.
We're stopping.
Again? Dad, at this rate,
it'll take us...
three days just
to get to the lake.
Meredith isn't used to the altitude.
Just chill, okay?
Ooh.
Ah, I'm in serious pain.
Somebody hand me my Evian.
I can't move.
Sure.
Brilliant.
Here you go, Mer.
Honey, you okay?
What happened?
This little guy was
on her Evian bottle.
Oh, he won't hurt you,
Meredith.
Oh, right, right, right.
Right. I know.
You, uh, go ahead.
I'll be fine.
Get that thing away from me.
I hate things that crawl.
Aagh! How can you touch that?
Just put it down.
Okay. Okay.
I'll put it down.
- Girls?
- What? - What?
I'm going to take the lead. The two
of you help Meredith. All right?
Sure, you'll help me.
Right over a cliff,
you'll help me.
- Not a bad idea.
- Yeah. See any cliffs?
- Aah, my backpack.
- Need a hand, Mer?
Not from you, thank you.
Don't think I can't see right past those angelic faces.
One more trick from you two,
and I promise...
I will make your lives miserable
from the day I say "I do."
Got it?
Got it, Cruella.
What did you call me?
Nothing, nothing.
Not a thing, Cruella.
Oh, by the way, Mer, I think there's
something on your head.
Are you all right?
- Aah!
- What... happened?
Ask... them.
What did we do, Dad?
We were right behind you.
Here we go, girls.
This will hold us for a while.
Sure you don't want
some trout, Mom?
Is that okay, by the way,
if we start calling you mom?
I think your mother would prefer
if you called me Meredith.
And no thank you. I do not eat...
trout... for the thousandth time.
I will wait
until breakfast.
- What are we having?
- Trout.
Come on. It's part of the experience.
Mmm. And what's the other part?
Being eaten to death by mosquitoes?
God, you'd think
they actually like this stuff.
Well, what's that you're using?
Let me see that.
Well, you're gonna attract every
mosquito in the state with this stuff.
It's sugar and water.
Where'd you get it?
That's it. I am taking
one large sleeping pill...
and going to bed.
Meredith,
what are you doing?
I don't want the mountain lions to--
There are no mountain lions
up here, are there?
No.
Good night.
Girls, I'm telling you.
Lay off.
This isn't her thing, okay? I'm not
marrying her because she's Annie Oakley.
Who's Annie Oakley?
Just cool it.
Come on. Come on.
Okay.
I hope that
one large sleeping pill worked.
- You take that side.
- All right.
- Gosh, she's heavy.
- She's also like... snoring.
Nicky?
Sweet dreams, Mommie Dearest.
Mmm.
That feels nice.
Nicky!
Oh, man.
Ooh!
Ugh!
Ugh! Ugh!
- What's goin' on?
- Here's what's going on, buddy!
The day we get married is the day
I ship those brats off to Switzerland.
Get the picture?
It's me or them. Take your pick.
Them.
- Excuse me?
- T-H-E-M, them.
Get the picture?
Hello.
You're back so soon.
- Did you have fun?
- Well, I wouldn't go right to fun.
- You wouldn't?
- We've been punished to the end of the century.
- Starting now. Go!
- Where's Meredith?
We played a couple of harmless tricks on
her and she kind of freaked out a little.
A little?
Hmm.
She threw this
at my head.
At least it's smaller
than a hair dryer.
Oh, Nick, it's all my fault.
If I hadn't suggested she go--
Or tricked!
Tricked would be more like it.
Like mother,
like daughters.
I-I really am sorry.
- We are too, Dad. Really.
- Yeah.
Up to your room...
now.
I gotta remember
to thank them one day.
So, where's Chessy?
I'm starving.
Well, she and Martin went off on
a picnic around noon... yesterday.
Really! Who would
have thought-- my nanny, your butler!
Hmm.
Well, what do you say,
I whip us up something to eat?
- You can cook now?
- Oh, yeah. I can, uh, make pasta and pasta and, uh--
- Mmm, pasta sounds good.
- Well, pasta it is.
Okay, I'll take two.
- Hey, Dad!
- Wow! You look so nice!
- Where are you going?
- Good night, ladies.
- Oh, wow!
- This is where I keep my private stash.
Did you know
I also collect wine?
- Really?
- I'm a man of limited interest. Come here.
This...
is a 1921 Burgundy.
- They say the rain that year made this
the best Burgundy ever harvested. - Oh.
Now, you will appreciate this.
Come here.
Look.
"VJ day, 1945."
- That's incredible.
- I love that.
Now, this is the same wine that
was served at my parents' wedding.
- A Bordeaux-- '52.
- Aww.
I think my sister
was conceived on this baby.
What's this one?
"Where dreams have no end--
- 1983."
- That one actually took me years to track down.
Why?
Where's it from?
It's the wine that we drank
at our wedding.
I know. I have
every bottle ever made.
You do?
I do.
- Can we open one?
- You're the only one I'd drink it with.
- You okay?
- Oh, yeah. I just got a little dust in my eye.
Hmm?
I can offer you a clean sleeve.
No, no.
I'm fine really. All better.
You don't always have
to be so brave, you know.
Oh, but I do actually.
That will be Chessy.
She has a key.
Hello. Anybody home?
We'll be right up.
* Oh *
* Every time *
* We say goodbye *
* I die a little *
* Every time *
* We say goodbye *
* I wonder why *
* A little *
* Why the gods *
* Above me *
* Who must be in the know *
* Think so little of me *
- Take care of yourself.
- Yeah, I will. You too.
* They allow you to go *
* And when you're near *
* There sits an air *
- I love you.
- I love you too.
* Of spring about it *
* I can hear *
* A lark somewhere *
* Begin to sing *
* About it *
* There's no love *
* So finer *
* But how strange
the change *
* You made *
* Your mind up *
* Every time *
* We say goodbye **
Hello.
We're home.
- Grandfather?
- I'll check the study.
Hey, stranger.
Hey, Mom, did you know the Concorde
gets you here in half the time?
Yes, I-I've heard that.
Huh!
What are you doing here?
It took us around 30 seconds
after you guys left...
for us to realize we didn't
want to lose you two again.
We?
We.
I made the mistake of not coming
after you once, Lizzy.
I'm not going to do that again
no matter how brave you are.
And I suppose you just expect
me to go weak at the knees...
and fall into your arms
and cry hysterically...
and say we'll just figure this whole
thing out-- a bicontinental relationship...
with our daughters being raised
here an-and there and...
and you and I just... picking up
where we left off, and--
and growing old
together and--
and--
Come on, Nick.
What do you expect?
- To live happily ever after?
- Yes...
to all the above.
Except you don't have
to cry hysterically.
Oh, yes, I do.
We actually did it.
* This will be
an everlasting love *
the one I've waited for *
* This will be
the first time *
* Anyone has loved me *
* I'm so glad
you found me in time *
* And I'm so glad that
you rectified my mind *
* This will be
an everlasting love *
* For me
Yeah, whoa-oa *
* Loving you
is some kind of wonderful *
* Because you've shown me
just how much you care *
* You've given me
the thrill of a lifetime *
* And made me believe you've got
more thrills to spare, oh *
* This will be
an everlasting love *
* Oh, yes, it will now *
* You've brought a lot
of sunshine into my life *
* You've filled me
with happiness I never knew *
* You gave me more joy
than I ever dreamed of *
* And no one, no one
can take the place of you *
* This will be you and me *
* Yes, sirree, eternally *
* Hugging and squeezing
and kissing and pleasing *
* Together forever
Through rain and whatever *
* Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
You and me *
* So long as I'm living
true love I'll be giving *
* To you I'll be serving
'cause you're so deserving *
* Hey, you're so deserving *
* From now on
From now on, yeah *
From now on *
* From now on **