THE LAST LEGION
The legend began
beneath these dark hills
and under this same sky.
It tells of a sword of great power
forged for the conqueror, Julius Caesar.
This weapon was passed down
until it reached the
last of Caesars noble line,
the Emperor Tiberius.
On his death, it was hidden away
to keep from the hands of evil men.
For generations, it lay in a secret
place marked by the sign of a pentangle
and, as it was written,
under the very gaze of Caesar.
I, Ambrosinus, born in Britannia...
...was one of many men
who sought it.
In a time of injustice, I made it
my life's task to find the sword
and the one righteous
enough to wield it.
I journeyed far across the continent,
to the heart of an empire that
ruled half the known world.
Now a threatened Rome
was calling back her bravest
and best to defend her boundaries.
ROME 460 A.D.
Greetings, Aurelius.
Make way!
Good to be home, commander?
Is this what I'm supposed to wear?
I can't even remember how to put it on.
Why us, Vatrenus, huh? Why me?
Because they trust you.
You are a true Roman.
Besides, it's a glorious thing,
they say, to guard the new Caesar.
We held Africa for them
for ten years.
Grew old on their battlefields.
Lost good men.
- What was it all for?
- We're soldiers, Aurelius.
Politicians make the decisions.
Two breeds of men
to be avoided like the pox...
...politicians and philosophers.
You know, in Alexandria,
they cut off the hand that steals.
No, please.
Once the hand is off, it's for God
to decide whether you live or die.
Most die.
Batiatus!
Do it outside, it'll make a mess.
Blood everywhere.
- He's lame in the forefoot.
- Who's this?
- A thief caught in the act.
- I'm not a thief.
- No, he's yours, big man.
- One hand or two, commander?
- Oh, just the one.
No, let me go, please!
I wasn't gonna steal it, I swear to you.
- I give you my word.
- Your word?
You? A street boy.
A thief.
How can you be a man of your word?
I just wanted to look at it.
I'm Aurlianus Caius Antonius,
citizen of Rome,
commander of the Imperial Guard,
and I'm asking you, would you lie to me?
I would not lie to you.
You come back in ten years, boy.
I'll give you your own sword.
Now get out of here.
Another worthy foe vanguished,
then, commander?
- Are you thirsty ?
- It's heartening to see
- Soldiers of Rome dispiay such valour.
- Who are you?
One who knows humiliation
to be a poor teacher...
- ...for both men and boys.
- I smell a philosopher.
Are you all right?
- Take the boy and go.
- In our own good time.
He said go, old man.
More than a philosopher, then.
How did he do that?
Every time we have goose for dinner,
you do that same old trick.
Oh, dear. Have I done that one before?
- And I didn't need your help.
By the way, you missed
your Greek lesson.
How come you never told me
you knew how to fight?
Get out of here.
Both of you. Go, go.
Let them pass.
- Odoacer.
- Orestes.
For ten years I have supported Rome.
Ten years! My warriors fought
beside your legions.
- Who is that?
- The Commander of the Goths.
So now here I am,
to claim my dues.
And what are your dues, general?
- One third of all Italy.
- You think I'm joking?
- Is this true, Orestes?
- Did you make such a pact?
- No.
How could I promise
what isn't mine to give?
One third of Italy!
That way, the allianct continues.
And your new caesar will not topple from
his throne like the others before him.
I promised you nothing beyond
the rewards you already given.
You have grown so tall, Orestes.
You forget whose shoulders you stand on.
Romulus, where have you been?
We've been looking everuwhere.
Ambrosinus, you took him outside,
without a guard?
You know the danger.
It's a fine morning. We went for a walk.
No harm done.
A walk? You know what
tomorrow holds for him?
- For all of us?
- I know perfectIy weII, Orestes.
I've as much care for your son as you.
What did you say?
You go too far, schoolmaster.
Leave us.
Orestes, sometimes i think you
forget he's just a boy.
He has your blood in his veins.
Bloodline ofthe Caesars.
- He was neverjust a boy.
Mother...
...in five years, there
have been five emperors...
...and they were all murdered.
What will happen to me?
You will be guarded by the best.
You will live long and rule wisely.
Romulus!
My son, this day you join the immortals.
Hail Caesar, Caesar, Caesar!
Mother, am I now
the most powerful man in the world?
You are.
Then why can't I stay out
on the day I'm crowned?
What am I to be, a god or a boy?
You are caesar.
And my Caesar must be protected.
- But who would harm me?
- The one you saw.
- Odoacer the Goth.
- He is our ally.
You, teacher of words and numbers,
what is the business
of the state to you?
My only concern is
the welfare of your son.
You may concern yourself no longer.
He is Caesar now.
He's still a boy.
Perhaps he still needs me.
Well...
Your task is over. Leave us.
Don't come back.
Romulus.
Hail Caesar.
This is Aurelius of the Nova Invicta.
He will command your personal guard.
May I see your sword, commander?
He must do everything to protect me
from harm, must he not, father?
- Indeed. He must.
- To the last breath.
- And do I have your word on that?
- You have his word.
He is sworn to serve you.
Is it so, commander?
Thank you.
I only wanted to look at it.
Open the gate.
And this is also
Caesar's will?
Now you've been weil
rewarded. Go back where you came from.
My crime is putting new ideas
into a young head.
- Teaching a lad to think for himself.
- This lad is our emperor.
Which do you serve?
Caesar or your own ideas?
A wise man never asks
what another man serves...
For only his actions
will speak the true answer.
You've read your Seneca.
I find poets as dangerous
as philosophers.
And you...
Where did you get this?
A long time ago.
In another land.
From a man who loved only power.
So you're an adventurer as well?
if I see you again in Rome,
it'll be on the point of my sword.
Take care in the mist, commander.
it may hide what the gods themselves
dare not look upon.
And who will guard
the guardians themselves?
Nestor?
Leave us.
The senator.
Well, these sit better on me
than armour ever did.
- How is it with you, Aurelius?
- Oh, a little older.
- No wiser.
- After all these years?
- Did you ever marry, have children?
- No.
- So, what do you make of Rome?
- Different. Uneasy.
If you are to guard our new Caesar,
keep your wits keep about you.
And come and see me.
- Friends are a rare commodity.
- I will.
The Goths! They've betrayed us!
You, to the wall.
- Commander!
- Prepare to fire!
- Release!
- Down!
Defend the emperor!
Back! Behind! Go, go!
They're going
to target the main gate.
Form wall!
On my command!
Hold the line!
- Get back, boy.
- To the walls!
Yahh!
Ahh!
Father!
Odoacer wants the boy alive!
I'll do my best.
Save yourself.
Yahh!
King, the emissary from Constantinople.
Welcome, Excellency.
The city is ours.
I ask that your empire recognise me
as the sole ruler of Rome
- and all her dominions.
- My emperor is in Constantinople.
I am his eyes and his ears,
but I cannot speak on his behalf.
Then go and seek his word.
Master.
Aurelius. Fetch water.
The boy, Caesar.
- Is he alive?
- I couldn't find him.
His mother and father were killed,
as were my men.
How did this happen?
Some of your men survived,
that I do know.
Vatrenus was taken prisoner.
There may be others with him, but...
...they're to be executed,
as an example to those
who would stand against Odoacer.
Come to me.
is it for you that
so many people have died?
Such an innocent fact.
The blood of the caesars
flows in his veins.
Lord Wulfila here thinks
that I should fear you.
Is this true?
He is the last of the blood line.
End it now.
- Old Rome will die, and we will rule.
- We?
We rule?
Take car, Wulfila. Sometimes
your tongue runs ahead of your brain.
What do you say, boy?
Should I be afraid of you?
Why is Caesar treated so?
"Why is Caesar treated so?"
Perhaps Wulfila's right.
Perhaps I should end this here,
right now.
Can you see yourself?
Can you see your fact?
What do you see?
Do you see a boy?
Or do you see a caesar?
- I see...
- Tell me.
I see a Caesar.
I am Caesar.
Wrong answer.
Take him away, cut his throat.
That would be
a grave error, Lord Odoacer.
Who are you?
Kill the boy,
you make a martyr of him.
And Caesar's ghost
will haunt you ever after.
- Is that so?
- Read the signs.
- What signs?
- An omen.
- Do not mistake it, Odoacer.
If you hear one thing,
then hear this.
What now happens in this room
will echo across an empire.
A city may be won by blood.
It takes a man of vision to rule.
- All empires are built on blood.
- People will judge you.
The people will thank the Gods
that they survived
and serve their new master.
Now I asked, who are you?
Will they respect a leader
who so feared a Roman child
he had to butcher him?
Perhaps the boy is
more use to us aIive than dead.
Do you want to look a fool?
Kill them both!
Fool?!
Your best hope for the future,
Lord Wulfila, lies in silence!
Give me your hand.
Now I ask, who are you?
- I'm known by many names.
- Like a thief.
Here I'm called Ambrosinus.
The boy will be taken to
the island fortress at Capri.
You... You will be his prison guard.
That's your reward.
No harm comes to him unless I say so.
Not a hair on his head.
You understand me?
And take this one too.
I don't trust him.
- Someone's here.
- Where?
Please.
Wait, Aurelius.
I know this man.
He speaks for the Eastern Empire.
- Is the boy alive?
- I saw him, in chains.
They're taking him to capri.
I'll find him, bring him back.
From capri? That's impossible.
It's an island, a natural fortress.
- I'll need my men.
- We've long been allies, senator.
Free your Caesar.
My emperor will give him sanctuary until
it is safe for him to return to Rome.
We meet at Fanum in six days,
on the beach.
If you bring back the boy,
there'll be a boat to take us east.
Six days then. To the last breath.
To the last breath.
What's this?
The ambassador's guard.
You'll need help to free your men.
These people are our allies, use them.
Follow me.
Act as my prisoner.
When I give the signal, try to escape.
You understand what I've told you, yes?
Then do as I've said and nothing more.
- Him first.
- Stop!
Another prisoner.
I'm to take
this one's head back to Rome.
An assassin sent to kill Lord Odoacer.
Go.
Get him!
Ambrosinus...
...I want to be with them.
I want to be with
my mother and father.
You are with them.
They live on in your heart.
You cannot see them, but it's as if you
are in one room and they're in the next.
- I should have died too.
- Not your destiny.
I have no destiny.
Every living creature has a destiny,
be sure of it.
But when the pathway gets dark,
and it's difficult to see the way...
Well...
...that's why you have me.
For all that I'm worth.
Damn bird.
Forgot to feed it.
- Fuge! Fuge!
I knew it.
- I knew it was a trick.
- Shh!
Is this our destiny?
To be prisoners
here for the rest of our lives?
Have faith.
There is a purpose behind all things.
Where is he now?
No sign of the Goths.
But we should stay close to the river.
- The river, yes.
- They'll have scouts all the way.
- Agreed. So we...
- Mira.
Yes.
- What?
- My name, Mira.
There's your boat.
How do you wanna do this?
If we all go down,
we'll scare him off.
He'll be gone before we get there.
Wait here.
He's a woman.
This fortress
was built as a palace by
the great Emperor Tiberius,
who, it is written,
was a man of great dignity and bearing.
- Both of which you've inherited.
- So my ancestors built my prison.
A prison it is.
You thirsty, boy, hm?
Go on, drink.
Hmm? Drink.
You dare insult me, boy?! Huh?
This is a long way down.
How many fingers
will it take you to learn?
Your fate lies in the palm
of this child's hand.
As sure as Odoacer is your master,
throw this boy to the rocks,
you wiII follow.
When the time comes, boy,
I will send you to join
your mother and your father.
Mmm?
You. Odoacer said nothing of you.
String him up!
Hold.
What is this?
Are you some kind of priest,
a sorcerer?
Just a seeker after the truth.
You would never understand.
- Put him up.
How long is it to climb to the top?
An hour.
Faster coming down.
Take up all the wood we can spare.
And rope.
You stay on the boat.
- You may need me.
- No.
The pentangle.
Of course, of course, of course.
This is the place.
The sword.
Tiberius must have brought it here.
And the boy will find it!
- Romulus!
- Ambrosinus?
Go to the temple.
Look for your ancestor, Julius Caesar.
There is something he guards for you.
Look under the gaze of Caesar.
Of course, of course, of course.
Under the gaze of Caesar.
I told you to stay in the boat.
You will need my help.
Do you know what happens to a soldier
of mine who disobeys an order?
Your men are too slow.
Stay out of sight.
I don't see why you take the risk.
I serve my emperor.
He's your country's ally,
so I am with you.
Where did you learn to fight?
I come from Kerala,
in the south of India.
We were taught to fight
like our forefathers.
It is called Kalaripayattu.
When I was 14,
I was at the seventh level.
- Out of how many?
- Seven
Shall we talk all day or climb?
Julius Caesar.
"One edge to defend,
one to defeat.
In Britannia was I forged to fit
the hand of he who is destined to rule."
I have work for you.
Give me that sword.
Give it to me!
- You?
- Only two to rescue an emperor?
More are coming.
- Caesar!
- The temple!
You can't hide forever!
Yours.
Romulus?
You found the sword, boy.
- Save the emperor.
Caesar's sword.
- It's this way.
Get them away.
Get them away!
I got it.
Batiatus.
Yours.
Go! This way.
Get the boy away.
Roman!
- Where's the boy?
- Safe below with the others.
You were right, Batiatus.
it is guicker on the way down.
"One edge to defend, one to defeat.
In Britannia was I forged, to fit
the hand of he who is destined to rule."
Caesar's sword.
That is why it had such power.
Britannia.
Gather the men.
Made for a congueror.
Julius Caesar.
Caius Julius Caesar Ensis Caliburnus.
Feel the weight.
The sword carries a prophecy.
Did you see anything?
Anything written?
Then you know all you need to know.
Take it.
It's yours.
Welcome, Caesar.
Aurelius, all of you.
There is food and drink inside the tent.
We need to talk. Alone.
You're safe now.
From here you'll be taken to
the Eastern Empire to Constantinople.
You'll have sanctuary.
Uh...
Mmm.
The ambassador has heard
from Constantinopole.
The emperor will not give
sanctuary to the boy.
He will not oppose Odoacer,
nor offend him.
Everything has changed.
The day after you left, the garrison
of Rome swore allegianct to Odoacer.
Now, the rst of the commanders
have declared.
They all stand with the Goth.
There must be others still in the field.
What about the Ninth?
Ninth Legion?
They're to the north in Britannia.
For all we know,
Britannia has crumbled into the sea.
Well, then let's move fast.
Can you get me men?
Yes, you can keep your rank,
command a new army.
Good. Do it. We'll drive out
the invaders, if I can have 5,000.
Not for that, Aurlius.
I can't do that.
Why not? What is it with you, Nestor?
- Odoacer isn't just a barbarian.
- Is he not?
No, he's become a politician.
And a very astute one.
- Now he has the senate on his side.
- How many ofthe senate?
We have to see things as they are.
You're with them.
In time, perhaps,
we can challenge Odoacer. Not now.
So let's say you give me
this army, senator.
- What will you ask for in return?
- The boy.
You mean Caesar?
"Caesar" is a word from the past.
There is no Caesar.
Prepare the horses.
Where is the boat?
I said, prepare the horses.
Where is the boat to take
the emperor to Constantinopole?
I gave you an order.
What was it?
- Prepare the horses.
- Do it.
You are a soidier, Aurelius.
Leave the politics to me.
This is an order.
Give up the boy.
Without the emperor, there is no Rome.
Then you will run like a dog
until they hunt you down.
Commander!
- There he is! There's the boy!
- The boy! Get the boy!
Stop, comrades! We're all Romans!
Ah!
Vatrenus.
You don't understand,
Aurelius. I had to do it.
Aurelius, my friend,
if you ever loved me...
- For friendship.
Now that the Eastern Empire
has gone over to the Goths,
we have no refuge in Constantinople.
Or here. Or in Germania.
Where do we go, then?
The Ninth Legion is in Britannia.
it's the only way left to us.
North, to find them.
This is not your fight.
You're free to go.
Go? Where should I go?
I have broken my sacred oath,
killed my commander. I'm like you.
I have no country now.
My road is your road.
Commander, where we go
is not your decision to make.
Caesar?
We go north... to Britannia.
Beyond that peak is Gaul.
By the next full moon,
we'll be in sight of Britannia.
My beloved Britannia.
Nobody alive, commander.
There are horses here.
After all these years,
it's still happening.
Who could have done this?
Only one man.
His name is Vortgyn.
- What is this?
- Hadrian's Wall.
Last fortress of the empire.
A monument to Roman law and order.
The Ninth legion.
We've found them.
Look, the dragon.
They were here once.
So where are the Ninth, old man?
This is your country.
What has happened here?
This is where
the empire ends, Demetrius.
There's nothing left but this wall.
We came all this way
for a legion of ghosts.
We should have made our stand in Rome.
It would have been hopeless.
He must know.
Ah, he's fought
hopeIess battles before.
And you'd have stood by him?
Anytime, anywhere.
- They look like farmers.
- Who are you?
I'm Aurelianus Antonius
of the Nova Invicta.
These are my men.
I'm Kustennin.
These are mine.
I'm looking for the Ninth Legion
of the Roman Army.
Why do you come so far for them?
Rome has fallen.
What happened here?
The Dragon Legion is no more.
They were more than a thousand strong.
Who could have defeated them?
Kustennin, where are my countrymen?
Commander,
I am Flavius Konstantinus Marcellus...
...general of the Ninth Legion.
Rome abandoned us.
Some men left to fight in Gaul.
Those with families stayed here.
Now, you see, we live like celts.
We have a whole new generation.
We saw villages destroyed.
People slaughtered.
Vortgyn, King of Anglia.
He's taken the southern kingdoms,
and now he wants to ruIe all Britannia.
He's left us in peace so far.
We are no threat to him.
And he knows
we are no ordinary farmers. Come.
We bring greetings to Lord Vortgyn,
congueror of the Anglian people.
Righftul ruler of Britannia.
There is a boy.
- A boy?
- He carries a sword.
The sword carries a prophecy.
"One edge to defend, one to defeat.
In Britannia was I forged,
to fit the hand of..."
"He who is destined to rule."
You know of this?
You say a boy has it?
Where is this boy?
Here, in Britannia.
I've waited all my life for this.
Lord Vortgyn, the sword belongs...
"To the hand of he
who is destined to rule."
This is the hand.
Then I take the boy.
And the man who travels with him.
This man.
Tell me about the man.
He is the boy's teacher.
Acts like a priest.
He is not Roman.
Maybe from Gaul, or here in Britannia.
He has a scar here
in the shape of a sword.
- Like this?
- The same.
When I have the sword...
...I will make you a gift of the boy.
And the man?
The man is mine.
This blade was forged
from a flaming stone
that fell to earth from the stars.
Who has ever seen such a thing
in the dark ofthe sky at night?
Then you will know, and you will know,
and you will know, and you will know,
that what I tell you is true.
This stone offire that fell to earth,
cooled in the ice of a mountain
and turned to iron.
There, it was found
by a master blacksmith, a Calibian.
He hammerd the metal in his furnace
for three days and three nights,
hammering in the white heat, with no
stop, not so much as to eat or drink.
The cutting edge,
he tempered in the blood of a lion.
And see here,
he carved the pentangle,
our symbol of faith and truth.
So...
...whoever held this sword
would have faith
and know that it would serve
one cause and one cause onIy.
The truth.
Would you take up arms again?
For the emperor?
We swore a sacred oath to defend
our emperor to the death.
But to go against the Goth...
...it would take a miracle.
It's so simple for them.
They like each other,
and they're not afraid to show it.
How do you see me, Aurelius?
You're a fine warrior.
You let your guard drop occasionally.
Careless sometimes.
Show me.
Is that all you see me as?
A warrior?
You're a handsome woman,
in your way.
- Such passion, commander.
You must have broken many hearts.
You're getting slow.
Must be age!
You know, your attacks
are a little too predictable.
So where am I open?
There.
Not bad.
- Do you know this place?
- Once, yes, I knew it well.
This was a sanctuary
for those whose lives
were dedicated to the secret
ofthe sword.
Did you live here, Ambrosinus?
Here I was given this.
By Vortgyn.
Where is it?
He wanted the power
of the sword for himself.
But the secret could only be given
to a righteous man.
That moment, so long ago...
...marked the path of both our lives
forever after.
The pentangle.
The same as on sword.
Remember the prophecy?
"In Britannia was I forged to fit the
hand of he who is destined to rule."
I left Britannia in search
ofthe sword. I found you.
I knew then that what was written
must come to pass.
But I am Caesar without an empire.
How can I fulfil the prophecy?
Have I taught you nothing?
Prophecy is an act of faith.
And we are the keepers ofthe faith.
What do you think, Aurelius?
Would you bury your sword for this?
To have a home. Keep cattle.
Grow fat.
When it's over...
...maybe then.
I'm coid.
Well, little one...
...I want you to go back to your people.
carry a message for me.
You have a friend who comes
from a distant land.
They must give him up.
Look.
- Ygraine?
The blacksmith's family.
This is Vortgyn at work.
- Oh, please, not me, don't kill me!
- No, no, no.
- They won't kill you.
Oh, yes, they will. They'll kill us all!
Unless we give them...
...him.
Romulus?
Lovely Romulus.
The boy.
He is the one.
He is Romulus Augustus Caesar.
Why us, Aurelius?
Why did you come to us?
I lost my wife...
...and two sons today.
And I want revenge.
But the bitter truth is...
...if we stand against Vortgyn,
many more will die.
Perhaps all of us and our families.
That's not revenge, that's suicide.
The boy should go.
- And those who came with him.
- It's not our fight.
- Let us hear Aurelius.
- i will speak for him.
Everything you have been told is true.
I am Caesar.
We came asking for your loyalty
but Rome has not been loyal to you.
Now, if it is the right path,
and if it will save more lives,
then I will surrender to Vortgyn.
Whatever is decided here
will be my destiny.
What are we doing?
This is our emperor.
One day will decide this.
One final battle.
At dawn, I leave for the fort with
my men to fight and defend from there.
Those ofyou who will stand with us,
we welcome you as brothers.
Those who will not,
we leave you aIso as brothers.
I salute you all.
- Hail Caesar!
You kept your armour
after all these years?
Ten years a farmer gives you
something worth fighting for.
Twenty years a legionary
teaches you to be ready for the day.
Good man.
- It was made for my brother.
- Doesn't he need it?
He's grown since then.
If we all die tomorrow, Ambrosinus,
what happens to the prophecy?
Now is the test of our faith,
and we are the keepers of the faith.
We keep the flame alive.
What happens after is not ours to know.
If we don't live to see tomorrow...
Nothing will ever part us.
Commander!
A boy once took your sword.
What if he now offered you his
in exchange?
I would use it well...
...and salute the Caesar
to whom it belongs.
You are Caesar.
Wherever you are...
...always remember.
My friends...
...we've all seen many mornings
Iike this one.
Together, we've watched the sunrise and
not known if that day would be our last.
Some comrades I've seen
scarctly out of boyhood,
- trembling before their first battle.
- It was a cold morning, commander.
That it was, Demetrius.
And you men ofthe Ninth Legion,
all of us,
together we have fought
all our lives for the empire
that our ancestors created,
and together we have watched
that empire crumble to dust.
And with its fall,
we have lost true friends.
And I can tell you that
in the darkest moments,
I came to believe that there was
nothing left to fight for.
But I've been shown,
through the wisdom of others,
that there is one more battle
to be waged.
Against tyranny and the slaughter
of innoctnts.
Let us defend to the last breath
this island of Britannia
against those who would tear out
its heart and soul.
And then those who come after us will
remember that there was such a thing...
...as a Roman soldier with a Roman sword
and a Roman heart!
- Hail Caesar!
- Demetrius!
- Commander!
- Secure the gate!
- How many?
- A thousand. Maybe more.
Not as many as I thought.
You two man the walls.
Tertius, command the archers.
Watch to the south, sentries!
To the ramparts!
One man every five paces!
Archers!
- Attack!
Aim! Loose!
Vortgyn, I give you...
...fire!
Aim! Loose!
Sorcerer!
They have a sorcerer!
Fire!
That is no sorcerer.
That is the keeper of the sword.
Stay close to me.
Repel those ladders!
The gate won't hold!
Watch out!
- Demetrius!
Ahh!
Bring me Caesar's sword!
No!
- I thought... I thought I had them.
- Too many, old friend.
We don't have a chance.
They're coming.
The Ninth. Now we have a fight.
- To the last breath.
Form testudo!
Archers!
Prepare! Loose!
Romulus.
Romulus?
For all you've done
to my country...
...my Britannia.
- Burn in hell!
Behold!
The tyrant Vortgyn, he's dead!
Retreat! Retreat! Fall back!
Vortgyn is dead!
Romulus?
Romulus!
That's for my mother.
And my father.
Aurelius.
Aurelius, stay.
Stay with us.
You fought like a dragon.
And you fought like the son of a dragon.
You once swore to defend me.
To the last breath.
Have I discharged you from that oath?
Then live, Aurelius Antonius.
And all ofyou,
the last of my legions...
...you won a great victory today.
And now I say...
...no more blood.
No more war!
And that was how
the last of the Romans
found a home here in Britannia
and how, after years of turmoil,
they brought peace to the land.
What happened to the commander,
Aurelius?
Oh, he lived.
He took the warrior maiden,
Mira, for his wife.
- And Romulus, the boy?
- They raised him as their own son.
He grew to be a wise ruler.
He took a celtic name,
"Son of a Dragon."
- Pendragon.
- Pendragon. That's my father.
And you remember the little girl,
Ygraine?
- He married her.
- My mother?
And Ambrosinus took back
his real name.
- Merlin.
- You?
Merlin, it's just a story.
You made it up. It's a legend.
Arthur, Arthur, Arthur,
have I ever lied to you?
Every day.
That's it. That's where
the last legion made their stand.
Great legends were made here.
With you as the hero.
Of course.
We need heroes, don't we?