- Fluffy, why are you there?
- Put your cat away.
The alarm is off.
Heat the sauna, dear.
Right away.
I'm incredibly thirsty.
Mom, look!
What's that?
The stereo is gone.
My porcelain soldiers!
Mom, your soldiers!
Don't touch anything!
- Call the police.
- At once.
Laura, don't touch!
There is a letter.
The stereo is in the fridge.
Readme!
Your Days of Plenty are Numbered.
They work 14-hours days for peanuts!
7 days a week!
We buy the shoes for 100 Euros.
But they only cost 5 Euros to make!
Do you know who really makes those shoes?
No
Children in Indonesia, the Philippines...
Please leave the store.
In Indonesia, Philippines...
This isn't allowed.
That's enough. Get out!
I'm just handing out flyers.
Don't touch me!
They’re made by children
between the ages of 12 and 16!
Capitalist pigs!
Pigs!
The state supports capitalism!
Let go of him!
The demonstration is legal!
,
There's Miss Lindner!
Eviction papers for you.
Two weeks to vacate.
Leave it in tip-top shape
or loose deposit.
But I paid the rent back.
Yes, but 6 months too late.
Have a nice day!
Ticket control!
Tickets please.
Young man, did you hear me?
You, there. Ticket please!
What a stench!
He stinks up the entire car
Let's see you ticket.
- Stop drinking.
- ¡Leave me alone!
Take it easy or else!
Show me your ticket.
Ticket, please.
Do you have a ticket?
Take your hands off!
No drinking in here!
That's enough!
What's going on?
Mind your own business.
He is a total wreck.
Leave him alone.
What's it to you?
End of the line for you.
Here, you dropped this.
Hold on.
Jule, what's wrong?
Everything, nothing...
Move in with us for now.
A cosy little commune.
Sure.
Taste this. It's raspberry.
Choose the bright colors,
not always the depressing ones.
Shit!
Jan!
What a pain!
Bastard!
Do you think it was a good
idea to move in with Jan?
Jan is totally alright.
You just have to know him better.
I dunno.
Sometimes he gives me
this really aggressive look.
Really scary.
Jule, I've known Jan for 15 years.
He's a little unpredictable.
But he's a loyal soul.
And he's got a backbone.
Not many people do.
I dunno. He's kind of weird.
What's that?
Oxygen concentrator...
He bought it "used" the other day.
Really?
Are you excited
about going to Barcelona?
Sure!
Are you excited?
It's just that my debts
are out of control.
Baby, it's my treat. Completely.
We'll have a great time.
You just don't get it.
I have to straighten this out.
Beating yourself up
wont make things better.
Try to relax!
Just forget it.
Hello.
Man, we have to find
a new approach.
Take it to another level.
Everything is fine.
Bullshit!
We need to see things...
in a larger context.
What are you talking about?
Forget it!
- Got a light?
- Check in my bag.
No.
Look in the small one.
Open your eyes!
What is this?
Looks like a watch to me.
Won it at poker?
I think so, yeah.
- Peter, are you nuts?
- No, I won it.
Put it back where you found it.
- Yeah, I'll do that.
- OK. Thanks.
- Man, are you crazy?
- What?
You just threw 5000 Euros
out of the window!
So what?
Yeah, so what?
It's a principle!
You and your damn morals!
What morals?
What's it worth if we
are seen as common burglars?
If we can't agree,
then let's just drop it.
OK, man. I got it.
But in Kreuzberg,
I know this Turk...
He would have given me 2500 for it.
We could have split 50/50.
You don't get it
and you don't want to!
But it was just sitting there...
So shiny, calling out to me.
It's green.
Change the station.
So far, so far away from home...
Shit it won't get any louder.
No hellos, no hearts, no kisses
No sorrow.
Everything so far, so far away.
The best of times
You asshole!
...where flowers bloom,
where my sweetheart lives...
One more time!
Fucking awesome!
Miss!
We ordered Williams pear brandy.
That's William pear brandy.
But never in these glasses!
These are liqueur glasses.
So?
Can't beverages be served
in their proper glasses?
I simply cannot drink
from this glass.
Thank you.
- Just a moment, please.
- By the way...
Don't use the same brandy.
It's lost its flavor, understand?
Yes, by all means.
Table 47 prefers brandy glasses.
You have more customers.
At table 22.
Dream on your own time!
Be careful getting home!
- Sweet dreams.
- You too.
Can't you do something else?
Putting up those posters
doesn't pay much.
Plus, you're out all night.
Yeah, I'm sick of it too.
But there's nothing else
Good night.
What?
You can't go?
I have to turn over the apartment.
That asshole! I can't believe it.
It's only 3 days.
I don't get it.
Shit!
Then I'm staying too.
No, this is your big break.
You have to go alone.
I'll find someone to help you, OK?
Sorry, I overslept.
You can use this one.
- Here?
- Maybe over there.
How about some music?
Is that Jeff Cole?
I saw him in concert.
At the Columbia?
I was there.
Funny, I didn't see you!
This is a great place.
Why move?
I can't afford it.
Your debts?
Peter told you?
He mentioned it.
That idiot.
It's not a big deal.
We all have debts.
But not like me.
I probably can't compeed but...
How much?
1000 Euros? 10000 Euros?
More? 20000?
- 30000?
- Jan, please...
Don't ruin my day.
94500.
Euros?
What did you do? Burn down a factory?
If only.
A year ago, on the highway...
I was in my old Golf.
Ahead of me, this executive
driving his Mercedes S-Class.
He brakes. I don't.
His car is totaled.
My registration had expired.
I hadn't paid my insurance.
That fucking Mercedes
cost 100000 Euros.
But I'm now down to 94500.
You work your butt off
so that some big shot
can drive a Mercedes?
For executives like him...
That car is petty cash.
But it was my fault.
He was in the right
In the right? Is that justice?
You are paying for
some jerk's lifestyle.
A 100000-Euro car?
Why not gold-plated pipes?
It makes me sick too!
I should never have reached
for the glove compartment.
I screwed up.
Now I pay the price.
Who says that?
The cops?
The prosecutors, the news rags?
Fucking petty bourgeois ethic!
Decency, honesty, family values...
Get to work on time,
pay your taxes...
All hammered into us.
First in school, then on TV.
For what?
So guys like that can
buy expensive cars?
To hell with those morals!
Ruining a young woman's
life is immoral.
Think that guy ever thought
he was wrong?
You are right.
But I missed a payment once...
They were knocking on my door.
Step 1: Recognizing injustice.
Step 2: Action.
But how?
Take the first step alone.
Find allies for the second.
From where?
Take the first step, then call me.
I calculated how much of my life...
I'm giving to that asshole...
Just for fun.
And?
About 8 years.
But only once I'm a teacher.
That's what you want to do?
Better than waitressing.
Concretely...
I guess I wanted...
This might sound stupid.
I guess I just wanted
to live wild an free.
That's not stupid.
It's OK.
That's what half of us want.
Then come the compromises.
That's how it goes.
Not necessarily.
Sometimes not.
Some people make it.
Anyhow...
If you keep working
for that asshole,
you'll loose faith
in everything.
I go this way.
I go that way.
Thanks again.
If you still need help,
I can come again.
Great!
Sure.
- So where are you headed?
- Sleeping at a girlfriend's.
How about you?
I think I'll cook something.
Want to join me?
Gladly.
DAYS OF PLENTY.
All washed up?
Shall we cook?
Jan, it was great.
Guys who can cook
must get all the girls.
Not really.
Other things count more.
You join me for a smoke?
I don't know.
It's dessert.
Dope chokes young people's
revolutionary energy.
Grass too?
No, grass is OK.
The drugs the body produces
aren't bad either.
Actually, they're greats.
Like adrenalin?
For example.
There are thousands. Endorphins...
Happiness hormones
when you are in love...
Now you're talking hard drugs.
Watch out for those.
Don't fall into a life of crime!
Fear is an awesome drug.
Don't let fear take control.
Use it as a motor.
It takes practice.
Put yourself into a situation
where you're scared stiff.
First there's panic.
But after a while,
the body's self-protection
system kicks in.
You do things you never dared.
You overcome you limitations.
You believe you can do anything.
Really!
Do you know it or think it?
I know it.
Done it a thousand times.
¨A thousand times gone bad...¨
Run a check on-that plate.
It's OK.
It works if you smear it.
It's not good wallpaper.
- How come?
- The glue isn't right.
But i followed the instructions.
Shit!
You know what?
Fuck the deposit!
We should have done this before.
It works.
Hope they'll like it.
Look.
Every heart is a revolutionary cell.
Smile!
Excuse me...
Your hair!
Yes, I'll fix it.
Roast beef with potatoes
and summer vegetables.
We should smoke downstairs
in the storeroom.
Why not tell him too?
That way he can say
all we do is smoke.
You're right.
There you are!
The place is packed.
Just fixing my hair.
I can tell.
Are you crazy?
In the kitchen?
- I'm truly sorry, .
- What were you thinking?
Know what?
I've had it with you.
That's enough. You're fired.
No, boss. I need this job.
It's my fault. I smoked first.
I said it was OK.
Then you are fired too.
- What?
- Pack it up!
Wait, Jule. Let me.
Boss, wait!
Why can't I shut up?
What for?
It's great that you defended him.
Yeah sure.
But I need that job, you see.
No, I don't see.
You go to all those protests...
against exploitation and oppression...
but you're still
some bastard's slave.
Those protests are totally useless.
The rebellion is difficult now.
Before, all it took was
dope and long hair.
And the establishment
was automatically against you.
What was considered subversive then
you can buy in shops today.
Che Guevara t-shirts
or anarchy stickers.
That's why there aren't any more
youth movements.
Everyone has the feeling
it's all be done before.
Others tried and failed.
Why should it work for us?
For all revolutions,
one thing is clear...
Even if some didn’t work,
the most important thing is...
that the best ideas survived.
The same goes for personal revolts.
What turns out good...
what survives in you...
that makes you stronger.
What do you think?
How many people down there
are thinking about revolution?
In this moment, not many.
At 10:45, they are watching TV.
Probably.
Europeans spend 4 hours a day
in front of the boob tube.
4 hours!
Terrible!
Doesn't leave much time
for revolutionary thoughts.
You know...
Not being part of all that...
that's not the problem.
The problem is...
I can't find anything
I really want to believe in.
Got any ideas for me?
Follow me.
Now what?
Who lives here?
You never wondered why
Peter and I stay out all night?
To put up posters. What else?
Then...
What do you do?
We are driving around looking for villas.
When we find one we like...
we take a closer look.
Then what? You take pretty photos
and put them in an album?
Is this a joke?
We break into them.
Just one catch.
We don't steal anything.
We re-arrange the furniture.
And we leave a message.
"Your Days of Plenty are Numbered"
or "You Have Too Much Money"...
signed "The Edukators"
You and Peter are the Edukators?
Why?
So they feel less safe...
in their high security neighborhoods.
It's a creepy feeling...
Someone has been in your home.
They have been watching you.
And they will keep watching you.
Why not empty the villas
and give everything to the poor?
They expect burglars.
We want to really scare them.
Standing in the bank,
they'll hear faint whispers:
"You have too much money..."
They'll feel completely alone.
Nothing can help them.
Not money, not a spouse,
not any damn cop.
Are you serious?
I'll show you.
Guess where the camera is?
Behind the grill.
Skeleton key...
Look at this.
Peter found this list.
The x's mark our hits.
This is real.
No way... This is insane.
How did it start?
Not a clue.
Peter installed alarm systems.
I once asked him...
if he knew how
to disable an alarm system.
He said no problem.
So we did it
You two...
Isn't this Zehelendorf?
Which street?
Finkenbachstrasse.
No way! Wait...
Shit!
Jan, shit!
Take a left down there, OK?
Now I'll show you!
That must be it, there!
Stop, pull over there.
I think that asshole...
I owe money to lives there.
What are you doing?
He really lives here.
The mailbox is full.
They must be away.
Let's take a look.
Down at the lake we can get in.
Don't be a drag!
Let's just take a peek.
Wait up!
See?
Check out this place!
With boat and private dock...
The blinds are down.
They must be on vacation.
Don't be so sure.
How would you break in?
Maybe through a cellar window.
Let's go closer!
Doesn't that look like
the ideal point of entry?
Totally hidden.
It could work.
Let's break.
You're insane. No way!
I have to see how
that asshole lives. Please!
This is too spontaneous.
It's too risky
But you're a pro.
I just want a peek!
Jule, I'm not a pro.
We have to monitor the house first.
You can see no one's home.
Please!
We can come back a few times.
Then do it with Peter.
They'll be back then.
But only if the house
is on file, which I really doubt.
Agreed.
Shit!
What?
- Bingo!
- What?
- We've got his alarm system.
- We are going in?
I'll only have 30 seconds
to find the main console.
- We do it Edukators style.
- Agreed.
Once I open the window,
I'll have only 30 seconds.
When the alarm is off,
I'll come for you.
- So I wait here?
- Yes.
Jan, check out the pool.
Come on!
Let's make sure no one's home.
It's OK.
I told you...
petty cash.
- What are you doing?
- Don't panic.
Less conspicuous than a flashlight.
You can take off you mask.
No one's home.
This is him.
He needs cooling off.
And vertically?
Got it?
Awesome!
Looks much better now!
You have too much money.
The Edukators.
OK, let's go.
Come on, Jan.
Let's do something extreme.
I need to work off some aggression.
Please!
You're crazy.
We have been here to long.
Let's throw the couch in the pool.
It's a great idea. Come on!
Let's do it!
Then we'll go.
- Will it pass?
- It's hot here.
First things first!
One...
two...
Three!
Come on
Help me.
¡Idiot!
¿What's that?
It's me!
Where from?
Jule, give it back.
Come and get it..
Wait here. I'll be right back.
Don't do this, man.
Jan, let's go now!
Pack our things.
I'll be right back.
Got everything?
- Shit!
- What's wrong?
Cops!
That was so awesome!
I'd love to see Hardenberg's face!
when he comes home
and finds his couch in the pool.
It was the best, I tell you.
38 degrees...
the whole city is one big party.
But what was really the best...
I found this in Barcelona.
Look.
"Strange Edukators...
Nasty surprise for Berlin family,
upon return from vacation,
Perpetrators
had broken into their villa.
But nothing was stolen.
Only furniture
and valuables were moved.
Responsibility claimed
in a note signed: The Edukators.
Police still have no solid leads
to their identities".
Which paper?
The Tagesanzeiger.
Super.
I got this for Jule.
Think she'll like it?
It's perfect for her.
Wake up, man.
You seem out of it.
That must be Jule.
How are you?
And you? Everything OK?
I have to tell you something.
Wait... I brought you something.
We have to talk.
I left my phone at the villa.
What? Really?
I'm pretty sure.
I know I had it in the car before.
- It's not in my bag anymore.
- Don't tell Peter.
Why not?
Just don't tell him anything.
Look.
Isn't it nice?
Try it on.
He really needs a chick.
I'm sure that would help.
Really.
Jan, see her?
She's been checking you out.
Isn't she sweet?
Is she sweet or what?
So ask her to dance.
Leave him alone.
Want me to ask for you?
I'll ask her.
Sleep well.
- You, too.
- Bye.
I'm going for a walk.
I need some air.
Come in, man. Let's have a drink.
Put your oxygen on.
Not today.
I'll stay out for a while.
I'm off to bed.
Let's get out here.
I have a bad feeling.
We need to find your phone.
But maybe they already saw
the hole in the window.
What would you tell the cops?
Hardenberg know you.
Jan, please.
No. We have to go back in.
Want to go to jail?
It’s not here.
Where was the jacket?
- And?
- No.
Let's try calling it.
It's on voice mail.
I should've known.
I'll go upstairs.
I have to get rid of fingerprints.
- Hurry!
- I'll be right back.
I just arrived.
Where? Home, of course!
Rita, I didn't drive 700 km
at night to...
I already told you.
Gerling says he needs me.
What could I do?
Like I told you,
in 3 days if all goes well.
Shit!
Theresa left the bathroom light
on again.
Me too.
Say hi to the kids.
Take care, bye.
Found it!
What are you doing here?
I know you...
Hold on!
Fucking shit!
Is he alive?
Should we call the medics?
- No.
- Let's just go.
Did he see you?
Yes.
Did he recognize you?
Of course.
Then we can't go.
- Come on.
- We can't just go!
Think hard!
- What are we going to do?
- Fucking shit!
Not a clue!
Not a clue, man!
I don't know what to do!
I don't either!
Call Peter.
No.
Why not?
Because, no.
But why not?
You call him. I can't.
- What?
- Just call him!
It can't be...
This is Jule.
Jan and I are in big shit.
We need your help.
Please come right away.
Is this necessary?
Just run away.
The police don't have to know.
I won't say anything.
Maybe he won't talk.
Let's just go.
Are you crazy?
That guy lies all day long!
Shit! He dialed the cops.
Did the call go through?
We have to go.
- But we...
- We're out of time, OK?
He is coming with us.
Can't we come to a solution?
Shut up!
I won't be a kidnapper!
You can't pull out now!
The cops are coming.
We'll take him and decide later.
End of discussion.
This is crazy!
Open the door.
Come here!
Man, what were you thinking?
This was our thing.
You dragged Jule into it.
Why didn’t you tell me sooner?
I don't know.
I just wanted to help.
We won't hurt you, OK?
You can trust me.
OK, drive.
Got the flashlight?
- Go on!
- Be careful.
It's a 100-meter drop.
Two people were killed last year.
Put the groceries there.
We can sleep in here.
Good.
- A fire?
- Yeah, super.
The matches are up here.
Your uncle comes here often?
Hardly ever.
Does he rent it out?
No.
We say we are on vacation.
In case the forest ranger comes by.
Don't let Hardenberg out.
Good morning.
We'll make it.
I don't know how,
but we'll get out of this.
How about a 70s style
political kidnapping?
We hang a sign around his neck:
"Prisoner of the Edukators"
We tape it for the TV stations.
This is our chance, guys.
Finally a living example
to test our methods.
We need bread, milk and toilet paper.
And a newspaper.
A radio wouldn't be bad.
I'll go down
and check the village.
I'll shop. You guys cook.
- Someone have money?
- Not really.
Hardenberg's buying first round.
How's the People's Prison?
Careful!
What are you expecting?
By reaching so few?
Never heard of:
"Reach one, Educate 100"?
Words get around.
We might get some copycats.
We are just the fuse.
You think you're so much better?
You're not better than terrorists.
You use the same methods...
Spreading fear and panic.
Our goal isn't to be better
at any price.
We think it's more original
to have a cause...
To make a difference
Isn't that crazy?
We struggle like crazy
to minimize your damage.
How ungrateful!
Our little break-ins are nothing.
Compared to the violence
used by people like you.
The state legitimizes you.
Us...
We get it from ourselves.
So you're Germany's savior?
The new millennium's RAF?
We're not hanging out in pubs
talking about the great revolution.
But it's true...
Serious action makes you vulnerable.
How truly terrible!
Peter, we never discussed it...
How do you endure it all?
Maybe because I'm not
particularly cultivated.
Or maybe because...
I'm just a really cool guy.
What will you do with me?
You'll see soon.
We have 3 possibilities.
Plan A, we make this a kidnapping
and demand ransom money.
At least this shit
will give us money for a new life.
We surely can't go back
to the old one.
All in the past, Jule.
Plan B...
We put him in the morgue.
Are you crazy?
You've really lost it!
Jule, I'm joking. Calm down.
I've had it with your dumb jokes.
- This is about a human being!
- OK!
Bad joke.
I'll be serious.
Plan B, we leave him here
with food for a week.
Then we inform the rangers.
But not before we're far away.
Tea?
What do you earn per year?
More or less 200 000.
3.4 million.
That's what I read in Tagesspiegel.
Sounds like more, not less.
Don't you feel guilty?
Ruining a girl's life for a car
worth petty cash to you.
Why?
Alright.
I should have paid more attention
to  who was involved.
I was stressed out.
I'm sorry.
How many hours a day
do you work?
13, 14 hours, easily.
What do you do with all that money?
You amass things.
Big, expensive things.
Fat cars, enormous villa, a yacht...
A lot of stuff to indicate:
"I'm an Alpha Male".
I can't see any other reason.
You don't even have time
to cruise on your yacht.
So why do you always want more?
We live in a democracy.
I don't have to justify why
I own certain things.
I paid for them.
Wrong!
We live in a capitalist dictatorship.
You stole everything you possess.
I can afford more
because I work more.
I had the right ideas
at the right time.
Besides...
I'm not the only one.
Everyone get the same chances.
A real contender, aren't you?
In Southeast Asia, many people work
13, 14 hours per day.
But they don't have villas.
They earn 30 Euros per month.
They might have good ideas, too.
But they can't even pay
for a bus ticket to the next town.
Sorry I wasn't born
in Southeast Asia.
But you can still help
make life bearable there.
The First World could cancel
the Third World's debts.
That's only 0.01% of the GNP!
That would collapse
the world's financial system.
You want them poor!
It's the way to control them.
Make them sell their raw goods.
at dirt cheap prices...
What do you know?
Like you didn't cancel Jule's debt.
- That's absurd!
- No.
It's the basic rule of the system.
Suck others dry...
It stops them from reacting.
That's not true.
Sure, things need improvement...
Environmental protection,
raising producer prices...
But the system won't change.
Why not?
Yes, why not?
The nature of man is
to want to be better than others.
In every group,
a leader emerges quickly.
Plus, most people are happy
only when buying something new.
Happy?
Think they are happy, Hardenberg?
Look around.
Get out of that company car...
Walk on the street!
Anyone look happy?
Or more like scared animals?
Look into their living rooms.
All glued to the TV...
Listening to chick zombies...
speaking of a happiness long gone.
Drive around town.
You'll see all the filth,
the overcrowding...
The masses in department stores...
Up and down,
like robots on escalators.
Nobody knows anybody.
They think
Happiness is an inch away.
But it's unreachable,
because you stole it.
That's how it is.
You know perfectly well.
But I have news for you,
executive...
The system is overheated.
We're just forerunners.
Your time is almost over.
Swim in you shit technology,
but others are full of rage.
The rage of children living in slums,
watching American action films.
That's one part. Let's see...
Mental illness is rising.
Serial killers, shattered souls,
senseless violence...
You can't sedate them
with game shows and shopping.
The antidepressants
won't work forever either.
The people have had enough
of you shit system.
I admit some of what you say is true.
But I'm the wrong scapegoat.
I play the game,
but I didn’t make up the rules.
It’s not who invented the gun,
but who pulls the trigger.
I'll be in the kitchen...
Washing dishes.
You know, it's not that simple.
You don't get off that easily.
It's an island in the Mediterranean.
Practically no guards.
It's the control center
for Europe’s 13 main satellites.
If the transmitter is sabotaged,
every TV screen in Europe
will go black.
There's a fairly simple way.
I came up with it myself.
It's easier than you think.
Can I have a toke?
I thought people like you
hated dope heads.
People like me?
Yeah, people like you.
You think I was born this way?
You probably weren't loved enough
as a child.
I don't agree with you what you’re doing,
but your arguments...
They remind me of another time.
Give us a history lesson!
Well, we did make history.
68 was a wild time.
I looked different then.
Long curly hair...
old leather jacket,
bell bottom pants...
Always a cap...
A true rebel.
Must have been long ago!
Turbulent times...
I was one of the leaders of the SDS.
Rudi Dutschke
was a good friend of mine.
Who was chairman?
K.D. Wolf, Karl Dietrich Wolf.
Number 2?
His brother, Frank Wolf.
This morning
was a far cry for revolt.
Yeah...It's been a while...
30 years ago.
We would have liked to get hold
of a big shot like me.
And today, here I am!
Pretty funny.
I don't want to kiss up to you.
And I don't think it's right
what you're doing to me.
But your idealism...
I can respect that.
Morning.
Everything OK?
Yes, fine.
Pass me the jam, please.
This one.
Can I have some bread?
It's in my interest
that things go problem-free.
So i have a suggestion.
I must make a call before 16:00
Our cleaning woman
mustn't go in the house.
Or she'll see the window.
There's no network.
And cell phones can be traced.
I'll drive him down to the village.
There's a phone booth.
He'll run away.
If he tries,
I'll shoot him in the leg.
That won't be necessary.
I won't run away.
I won't scream for help.
I don't have a secret code
with the maid, in case of kidnapping.
And I have to call my wife.
If not, she'll make a fuss.
Peter, can we talk?
What's that about?
Just a gas pistol I bought.
It's not loaded and it's broken.
It looks like real to a cop.
Jule called
in the middle of the night.
So I brought it with me.
It sounded like an emergency.
We could forget all that business
about the accident.
I could draw up a document
to end it.
I don't think this phone thing
is going to work.
- Us three with a 50-year-old...
- Forget it.
The streets are dead at noon.
OK?
And if he screams?
He won't.
not with my gun in his side.
We have no choice...
The maid can't go inside.
There's not just the whole in the window.
Come on.
But give me the gun.
I'll do it.
I didn't bother with it
because I'm always on the move.
I gave it to my lawyer.
It was business as usual for him.
Nobody knew to what extent
it would affect someone.
You think I'm the weakest link here?
Think I'll buy all your bullshit?
But this is about
more than the damn accident!
Where are the keys?
Check in my jacket.
Don't do anything stupid.
It's Mr. Hardenberg...
Hello Mrs. Rose.
Yes, thank you.
No need to come today.
I came home earlier
to work in peace.
I have some business to finish.
Please come next Wednesday.
I'll call you on Tuesday.
Good, same to you. Thank you.
Bye.
- Now my wife?
- Yes.
It's me.
I had...
Hold on...
A water pipe burst last night.
It was a big mess.
I had to call a plumber.
No... everything is fine now.
But I couldn't call before.
Yes, on Monday.
At least, I hope on Monday...
I'll call you.
Kisses from me.
Bye.
Good...
You're a good liar.
It's a sauna in there.
Bad cell phone reception.
Yeah, my son is in withdrawal.
Alright, let's go.
You heard... Drive.
I guess it’s been a while...
Since you did your own wash.
How can someone with your past
live the way you do?
You must have had ideals.
My father told me:
"Under 30 and not liberal, no heart.
"Over 30 and still liberal,
no brain.
Yeah, right.
But I don't believe that crap.
It's the standard excuse
of guys like you.
It happened slowly, gradually.
you hardly notice it.
One day, you abandon your old car.
You want a dependable car,
with air conditioning, a warranty.
You get married,
raise a family, buy a house...
The kids need a good education.
That costs money... Security!
You create endless debts,
so you need a career to pay them.
So you do like they do.
Then one day,
to your surprise at the polls...
You vote conservative.
Who made this great pasta?
Me..
Respect.
Thanks.
Who cooks at your house?
Your wife?
Mrs. Schwarz.
Our cook.
Before, I used to love to cook.
For my wife and I,
the others in the commune.
Like big parties.
How many where you?
We were 6.
Rolf, Bernard, I,
Lizzy, Gabi, my wife.
First, Rolf and Gabi were together.
Then, Bernd and Gabi,
then Lizzy and me.
Then Bernd and Lizzy...
Then Lizzy and my wife
for a while...
It wasn't just a political movement.
We had fun.
Free love...
But I don't have to tell you three.
You skip.
Skip again.
I'll draw 2.
Funny.
I pass.
I don't care.
- You make the rules.
- Yes, I do.
When I was little...
with my friends...
we played house with dolls...
It was so real for them.
They were so into it.
I was never able to forget
they were only dolls.
I always felt like...
More of a watcher than a player.
You know?
I still feel like that.
In real life.
It's the Matrix.
If you see it,
you can't be living in it.
Neither can I.
Good morning.
Someone has to grocery shop.
We're out of coffee, wine...
No more food,
no more toilet paper...
I can't anymore.
It's your turn.
I'll go.
I'll go with you.
There's no more dope!
Ask in the store!
Hardi, how about a game of cards?
Awesome.
Let's go in.
It's cold.
I thought...
money would bring freedom.
On the contrary.
You're burdened with responsibility.
Sometimes I feel like I'm in jail.
Stop moaning.
Isn't 3 million a year
enough compensation?
I don't know what to do
with the money.
Give it to those who need it.
With your annual salary
you could save 1000 persons
from starvation.
Sounds corny, but it's true.
I could do that.
But only once.
So do it!
To be honest, Peter...
I've thought of giving it all up.
Just sell everything,
move to the countryside...
Live modestly with my wife,
both of us work as teachers..
Like when we were students.
Poor but happy.
We were in love.
When you talked about free love,
why mention the three of us?
Don't know it?
You bought them anyway!
They are disgusting.
They are for Hardenberg.
You two got something going?
Have you lost it?
Kiss my ass! This is your shit.
I'm out of here.
¡Peter, I’m sorry!
Sorry for what?
It just happened.
I fell in love.
Good, then I can go.
You don't love me anymore.
You bastard!
What were you thinking, man?
We hit it off, sorry.
Hit it off? Just like that?
Not "just like that".
We got to know each other.
I thought we were friends.
- We are friends.
- I trusted you!
You told me to help her!
Help her, not fuck her.
Asshole!
Coffee?
No, thanks.
Can I help you?
No, forget it.
I'm going to lie down.
I'm a little tired.
The keys!
We screwed up.
Kidnapping Hardenberg was wrong.
We did it to save our own asses,
not the world.
I guess this is it.
Thanks for driving me home.
Don't worry about the cops.
Wait!
Your sweater.
Here.
This is for you.
Waiver of Debt.
I won't ruin your life.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
After what I did,
I can't make demands.
It’s over.
Talk like that,
and you're one of them.
It's not the Jule thing that hurt.
It’s that you take me for an idiot.
If I pocket a Rolex,
that's not an insult to our case.
I believe in it, man.
Us three... That's more important
than stuffy bourgeois ethics.
The best ideas survive.
Come on.
Some People Never Change.