- Good morning, Bastian.
- Morning, Dad.
I had another dream, Dad.
About Mom.
I understand, son.
But we have to get on with things.
We each have responsibilities.
We can't let Mom's death...
...be an excuse for not
getting the job done, right?
Yeah.
I think it's time we had a talk.
I got a call from
your math teacher yesterday.
She says that you were drawing
horses in your math book.
- Unicorns. They were unicorns.
- What?
Nothing.
She also says you haven't been
doing your homework on time.
I'm disappointed you didn't
try out for the swim team.
As to those riding lessons
you wanted...
...you say you love horses but
you're afraid to get on a real one.
You're old enough to get your head
down out of the clouds...
...and keep both feet
on the ground, right?
Okay.
Stop daydreaming.
Start facing your problems. Okay?
- Okay.
There, I think we've had a nice talk.
We should have more.
Have a good day.
Don't be late for school again.
But yesterday I wasn't.
Hey, it's the weirdo.
Weirdo, you got any cash for us today?
Let's get him!
You're dead, weirdo!
- You can't get away, jerk.
- You're dead, chicken!
We're gonna get you!
- Where's your money?
- I don't have any!
No money? Mama's boy is holding out.
If you ain't got money,
you go in the garbage.
Yeah, all right!
Way to go!
Maybe the chicken can lay
an egg in there.
Who said you could get
out of the garbage?
- Get back in there.
- No, not again.
- Not again!
- Where are you going, wimp?
He went that way.
Which way?
Get out of here! I don't like kids.
Are you still here?
Didn't you hear me?
- You're hiding, aren't you?
- No...
The arcade is down the street.
Here, we just sell small
rectangular objects called books.
They require effort and make no beeps.
On your way, please.
I know books.
I have 186 of them at home.
- Comic books.
- I have Treasure Island...
...The Last of the Mohicans,
Lord of the Rings...
...20,000 Leagues Under the Sea,
Tarzan...
Who are you running away from?
- Just some kids from school.
- Why?
- They threw me in the garbage.
- Why not punch them in the nose?
I don't know.
What's that book about?
Oh, this is something special.
Well, what is it?
Look...
...your books are safe.
While you're reading...
...you get to become Tarzan
or Robinson Crusoe.
That's what I like about them.
But afterwards you get to be
a little boy again.
- Well, what do you mean?
- Listen.
Have you ever been...
...Captain Nemo trapped
inside your submarine...
...while the giant squid
is attacking you?
Weren't you afraid
you couldn't escape?
- But it's only a story.
- That's what I'm talking about.
The ones you read are safe.
And that one isn't?
- Don't worry about it.
- But you just said it was...
Forget about it.
This book is not for you.
Koreander's.
What can I do for you?
I don't have it but I could find it.
Well, they run maybe 300, 375...
It'd take me a few weeks.
Goodbye.
Math test. Oh, no!
"It was midnight
in the Howling Forest.
The wind whistled through
the tops of the ancient trees.
Suddenly, something enormous...
...crashed and rumbled
through the eerie woods."
What's that?
Excuse me.
Would it be all right
if I joined you this evening?
You see, I've been traveling all day.
Aha!
Now I see why you picked this camp.
A delicious-Iooking limestone rock!
Nice bouquet.
Must be a real vintage year.
Yes, you're right.
Those delicious rocks
are why we've camped here.
- Is he a nut case?
- He's a Rockbiter.
A Rock... A Rockbiter!
Sorry.
- Poor baby.
Pardon me.
That was limestone,
with a dash of quartz.
Very tasty.
Where I come from in the North...
...we used to have
exquisite gourmet rocks.
Only now...
Now...
They're all gone.
I know how it happened.
I swear it wasn't me.
No, I think I know what it was.
Tell us more.
Near my home,
there used to be a beautiful lake...
...but then...
Then it was gone.
- Did the lake dry up?
- No. It just wasn't there anymore.
Nothing was there anymore.
Not even a dried-up lake.
- A hole?
- A hole would be something.
No, it was Nothing.
And it got bigger and bigger.
First, there was no lake anymore.
And then, finally, no rocks.
If he keeps stuffing his face,
there won't be any rocks left here.
Night Hob, this could be serious!
What you said is also happening
where I live in the West.
A strange Nothing
is destroying everything.
Yes. We Night Hobs live in the South
and it's there too.
So it's...
It's not just in our part of Fantasia?
Maybe it's already everywhere.
Maybe our whole land is in danger.
What can we do?
My people sent me to the Ivory Tower,
to the Empress, for help.
We are on the same...
We are on the same mission.
If the Empress can't save us...
...who could?
Why are we all just sitting here...
...instead of taking off
for the Ivory Tower?
- What are we waiting for?
- Yes. Let's go now.
Wake up!
- Come on, old girl.
- We can't just hang around here.
Wake up! Ready for takeoff.
Oh, stupid bat!
We can't wait for a snail.
Can I carry you?
Don't worry. It's a racing snail.
But we can't even wait
for a racing snail...
Tallyho!
It really is a racing snail.
Nobody cares about me
and my stupid bat.
Maybe I'll take a few
of these yummy gourmet rocks...
...for the road.
Oh, no!
The Nothing!
Look!
There it is!
The heart of Fantasia!
I never knew it was that beautiful.
Stay awake!
I told you to stay awake.
The home of the Empress.
She's our only hope.
Friends, I know why you are all here.
The Nothing...
...is destroying our world.
I also know that you...
...have come to beseech...
...the Empress for help.
But l...
I have terrible news.
The Empress herself
has become deathly ill.
There seems to be a mysterious link
between her illness and the Nothing.
She's dying.
So she cannot save...
...us.
But there just might be one chance.
The plains people
who hunt the purple buffalo...
...have a great warrior.
He alone has a chance
to fight the Nothing and save us.
He is our only hope.
His name is Atreyu.
Atreyu.
"The Empress had already
sent for the great warrior.
When he finally appeared
on the terrace of the Ivory Tower...
...he carried with him
the hopes of all Fantasia."
A little boy!
I'm sorry, but this is not
the time nor place for children.
- You must leave.
- lf you don't want me...
...you shouldn't have sent for me.
Is he a nut case?
- It wasn't you we sent for but Atreyu.
- I am Atreyu.
Not Atreyu the child.
Atreyu the warrior.
I am the only Atreyu.
I'm happy to return
to hunting buffalo.
No, wait!
Come back, please.
If you really are
the Atreyu we sent for...
...you would be willing
to go on a quest?
Yes, of course.
What kind of a quest?
To find a cure for the Empress...
...and to save our world.
No one can give you
any advice except this:
You must go alone.
You must leave
all your weapons behind.
It will be very dangerous.
- Is there any chance of success?
- I do not know.
But if you fail...
...the Empress will surely die...
...and our whole world
will be destroyed.
When do I begin?
Now. And you must hurry.
The Nothing grows stronger every day.
Take this.
The Auryn!
He who wears the Auryn
speaks for the Empress.
It will guide and protect you.
- Wake up.
- Farewell, Atreyu!
Take care.
"At the same time,
elsewhere in Fantasia...
...a creature of darkness
also began his quest.
They had been traveling aimlessly
for almost a week...
...but they could not find a cure.
Neither Atreyu nor his horse,
Artax, had the vaguest suspicion...
...that the Creature of Darkness,
the G'mork...
...was already tracking them down."
What is it, Artax?
Is it time to go already?
I know what you want.
It's time to eat.
Good idea.
No, it's a great idea!
Not too much.
We still have a long way to go.
"Atreyu and Artax had searched
the Silver Mountains...
...the Desert of Shattered Hopes
and the Crystal Towers...
...without success.
And so there was
only one chance left.
To find Morla, the Ancient One...
...the wisest being in Fantasia...
...whose home was
the Shell Mountain...
...somewhere in the deadly
Swamps of Sadness."
Come on, boy. Come on.
That's it, boy.
It's okay.
"Everyone knew that whoever
let the sadness overtake him...
...would sink into the swamp."
You're doing fine, Artax.
That's right.
Come on.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
Come on, boy.
What's the matter?
I understand.
It's too difficult for you.
You're sinking! Come on!
Turn around! You have to! Now!
Come on! Artax!
Fight against the sadness!
Artax, please. Don't let the sadness
of the swamps get to you.
You have to try. You have to care.
For me.
You're my friend. I love you.
Stupid horse!
You gotta move or you'll die!
Move. Please!
I won't give up! Don't quit!
The Shell Mountain.
Morla, the Ancient One.
Morla!
Huh?
But that's impossible.
They couldn't have heard me.
Are you Morla, the Ancient One?
Not that it matters...
...but yes.
Please help me. Do you recognize this?
Well...
...we haven't seen...
...the Auryn in a long time.
We?
Is someone else here too?
We haven't spoken to anyone else...
...for thousands of years.
So we started talking...
...to ourselves.
I bring terrible news.
Did you know the Empress is ill?
Not that it matters, but yes.
- Actually, we don't care.
- lf I don't save her, she'll die.
The Nothing is sweeping over the land.
- Don't you care about that?
- We don't even care...
...whether or not we care.
- Do you have a cold?
- No.
We're allergic to youth.
- Do you know how to help the Empress?
- Not that it matters...
...but yes.
Tell me! If the Nothing comes,
you'll die too!
- Both of you!
- Die?
That, at least, would be something.
Please help.
You said you knew the answ...
We're tired of sneezing.
Go away! Nothing matters.
That's not true. If it didn't
matter to you, you could tell me.
- Clever boy.
- Tell me, please!
We don't know.
But you can ask...
...the Southern Oracle.
- How can I get there?
You can't.
It's 10,000...
...miles away.
- But that's so far.
- That's right.
Forget it.
Give up.
No.
Atreyu wouldn't quit now.
Oh, boy!
"After days and nights
of unconsciousness...
...Atreyu slowly opened his eyes...
...and found himself
in strange surroundings.
He was clean and
his wounds were dressed."
Leaving so soon?
I was just going to... I have to...
- I was trying to...
- Sneak away?
Yeah. I mean, no!
- I like children.
- For breakfast?
Never. I'm a luck dragon.
My name is Falkor.
- And my name is...
- Atreyu. And you're on a quest.
- How did you know that?
- You were unconscious.
And you talked in your sleep.
Could you get around...
...and scratch behind my right ear?
I can never quite reach it.
Here?
That's so good.
Thank you.
So, little fellow, you're on your way
to the Southern Oracle?
Yes. But it's hopeless.
- It's too far away.
- I wouldn't necessarily say that.
- You know how to get there?
- Sure. It's right around the corner.
How did all this happen?
With luck.
You brought me
the entire 10,000 miles?
Only 9891...
...as the dragon flies.
- You're amazing!
Having a luck dragon with you
is the only way to go on a quest.
Things will work out fine, Atreyu.
Never give up
and good luck will find you.
It's good to have a friend again.
You have more than one.
Look.
Get out of my light.
You're disturbing my scientific work.
You and your scientific work.
What the boy needs now
is one of my potions.
The boy will need
my scientific advice much more.
But not until he's well.
Get back to your own corner, Engy.
I'm always finding you in my place.
He's well!
- Now it's my turn with him.
- Oh, no, you don't!
I decide when he's well.
I say when it's your turn.
- Little man, still in pain?
- It's all right.
I like that! The patient telling
the doctor it's all right?
It has to hurt if it's to heal.
Here.
Drink that.
Good?
That's my batwing broth...
...with eye of newt,
tree mold, old lizard brains...
...scales from a rancid sea serpent.
Just where did you
and your dragon come from?
What are you on to? Anything of
interest to the scientific community?
I'm Atreyu. I came to find
the Southern Oracle.
- Here we go again.
- You've come to the right place.
I am an expert on the Southern Oracle.
It is my scientific specialty.
"It's my scientific specialty."
Why don't you sit down
and be quiet for once?
You keep quiet, wench. It's my turn.
My name is Engywook.
She's Urgl. Ever heard of me?
I don't think so.
You don't move in scientific circles.
I am the expert
on the Southern Oracle.
You've come to the right place.
- There's no fool like an old fool.
- Wait! Stay here.
The observatory. To the winch, wench.
Come on, lazybones!
Can't you go any faster?
I've studied the Southern Oracle
for years.
One day I'll publish my book:
A Century of Studying
the Southern Oracle.
Volume l: The Early Years.
Have you been to the Southern Oracle?
What do you think?
I work scientifically.
Look.
Is that the Southern Oracle?
It's the first of the two gates
you must pass through...
...before you reach
the Southern Oracle...
...and get me the final
information for my book.
Of course, most people...
...never get that far.
Why?
The Sphinxes' eyes
stay closed until someone...
...who does not feel his own worth
tries to pass by.
Here comes one that looks fancy.
Let's see what he really
thinks of himself.
Look, look.
Go on, scaredy-cat!
Oh, go on!
It's my turn. Let me see.
I'm the scientist.
He's going on.
I think he'll make it.
The Sphinxes' eyes,
are they open or shut? Let me see.
They're shut.
No, wait!
The eyes are opening!
Did he make it? Did he?
Fancy armor doesn't help.
The Sphinxes can see
straight into your heart.
Listen, next time
let me see what happens.
It's my telescope.
- I'm gonna try.
- No!
Don't go yet.
I haven't told you...
...about the next gate.
It's even worse than this one.
Atreyu!
He'll never make it.
He'll never make it!
Don't start to doubt yourself.
Be confident!
Be confident. Be confident!
Run, Atreyu, run!
Run, Atreyu!
Run! Now!
He made it! He made it!
He made it!
You could use a dose of vitamins too.
He made it! Atreyu made it
through the Sphinx gate.
- I always said he could do it.
- Oh, good!
But that's no reason
to fall out of the basket again.
I knew he would be safe.
Nonsense!
You don't understand anything.
The worst one is coming up.
Next is the Magic Mirror Gate.
- Atreyu has to face his true self.
- So what?
- That won't be too hard for him.
- That's what everyone thinks.
But kind people find
that they are cruel.
Brave men discover
that they are really cowards.
Confronted with their true selves...
...most men run away screaming.
Now this is going too far.
What if they...
...really do know about me
in Fantasia?
The Southern Oracle?
Do not be afraid.
We will not harm you.
We have been waiting for you...
...a long time, Atreyu.
Are you the Southern Oracle?
Yes, we are.
Then you must know
what can save Fantasia.
Yes, we do.
Well, what is it? I have to know!
The Empress...
...needs...
...a new name.
A new name?
That's all? But that's easy.
I can give her any name she wants.
No one from Fantasia...
...can do it.
Only a human child...
...can give her this new name.
A human child? Where can I find one?
You can only find one...
...beyond the boundaries of Fantasia.
If you want to save our world...
...you must hurry!
We don't know...
...how much longer
we can withstand the Nothing.
Falkor!
The Nothing's everywhere.
- Don't worry.
We'll reach
the boundaries of Fantasia.
- Do you know where they are?
- I have no idea.
- Then how do we find a human child?
- With luck.
Faster, Falkor! We have to hurry.
All right, hang on tight!
Wow!
What a shame they don't ask me.
My mother...
...she had such a wonderful name.
"On and on they flew until they
reached the Sea of Possibilities...
...where they could go no further."
Look, Atreyu. The Nothing!
- Falkor!
- Atreyu!
Atreyu.
Falkor!
Falkor! Where are you?
Atreyu! Where are you?
Atreyu!
Falkor!
They look like big...
...good, strong hands, don't they?
I always thought
that's what they were.
My little friends.
The little man
with his racing snail...
...the Night Hob...
...even the stupid bat.
I couldn't hold on to them.
The Nothing...
...pulled them right out of my hands.
I failed.
No, you didn't fail.
I'm the one who failed.
I was the one chosen
to stop the Nothing.
But I lost the Auryn.
I can't find my luck dragon.
I won't be able to get beyond
the boundaries of Fantasia.
Listen.
The Nothing will be here any minute.
I will just sit here...
...and let it take me away too.
They look...
...like good...
...strong...
...hands. Don't they?
Morla?
Artax!
Artax.
If you come any closer...
...I will rip you to shreds.
Who are you?
I am G'mork.
And you, whoever you are...
...can have the honor
of being my last victim.
I will not die easily. I am a warrior.
Brave warrior.
- Then fight the Nothing.
- But I can't!
I can't get beyond
the boundaries of Fantasia.
- What's so funny about that?
- Fantasia...
...has no boundaries.
That's not true. You're lying.
Foolish boy.
Don't you know anything
about Fantasia?
It's the world of human fantasy.
Every part...
...every creature of it...
...is a piece of the dreams
and hopes of mankind.
Therefore...
...it has no boundaries.
Why is Fantasia dying then?
Because people have begun
to lose their hopes...
...and forget their dreams.
So the Nothing grows stronger.
- What is the Nothing?
- It's the emptiness that's left.
It is like a despair
destroying this world.
And I have been trying to help it.
- But why?
- Because people who have no hopes...
...are easy to control.
And whoever has the control...
...has the power.
Who are you, really?
I am the servant...
...of the power behind the Nothing.
I was sent to kill the only one...
...who could have stopped the Nothing.
I lost him in the Swamps of Sadness.
His name...
...was Atreyu.
If we're about to die anyway,
I'd rather die fighting!
Come for me, G'mork. I am Atreyu!
Falkor!
"That was the end of Fantasia.
Only a few fragments
of this once rich...
...and beautiful world
had been left by the Nothing."
Good old Falkor.
Can you see anything?
Anything at all?
No.
All the land is gone.
I know. And all because I failed.
You tried.
Could the Ivory Tower
still be standing?
Let's hope so, Atreyu.
Let's hope so.
Let the Auryn guide you.
If the Ivory Tower still stands,
take us there.
Falkor!
The Ivory Tower!
The Empress.
Go on.
Atreyu.
Why do you look so sad?
I have failed you, Empress.
No. You haven't.
You brought him with you.
Who?
The earthling child.
The one who can save us all.
You knew about the earthling child?
Of course. I knew everything.
My horse died, I nearly drowned...
...I barely escaped from the Nothing
to find out what you already knew?
It was the only way to get
in touch with an earthling.
But I didn't get in touch
with an earthling!
Yes, you did.
He has suffered with you.
He went through everything
you went through.
And now, he has come here...
...with you.
He is very close, listening...
...to every word...
...we say.
What?
Where is he? If he's so close,
why doesn't he arrive?
He doesn't realize he's already
part of The Neverending Story.
The Neverending Story? What's that?
Just as he is sharing all your
adventures, others are sharing his.
They were with him when he hid
from the boys in the bookstore.
But that's impossible!
They were with him
when he took the book...
...with the Auryn symbol
on the cover...
...in which he's reading
his own story...
...right now.
I can't believe it.
They can't be talking about me.
- What if he doesn't appear?
- Then our world will disappear.
And so will I.
- How can he let that happen?
- He doesn't see...
...he's the one
with the power to stop it.
He simply can't imagine that one
little boy could be that important.
Is it really me?
- Maybe he doesn't know what to do!
- What do I have to do?
He has to give me a new name.
He's already chosen it.
He just has to call it out.
But it's only a story. It's not real.
Atreyu, no!
Atreyu!
Bastian!
Why don't you do
what you dream, Bastian?
But I can't!
I must keep my feet on the ground!
Call my name.
Bastian, please!
Save us!
All right! I'll do it!
I'll save you! I will do what I dream!
Moon Child!
Why is it so dark?
In the beginning, it is always dark.
What is that?
One grain of sand.
It is all that remains
of my vast empire.
Fantasia has totally disappeared?
Yes.
Then everything's been in vain.
No, it hasn't.
Fantasia can arise in you...
...from your dreams and wishes.
- How?
- Open your hand.
What are you going to wish for?
I don't know.
Then there will be
no Fantasia anymore.
How many wishes do I get?
As many as you want.
And the more wishes you make...
...the more magnificent
Fantasia will become.
Really?
Try it.
Then my first wish is...
Falkor, it's even more beautiful
than I thought!
- Like it?
- Falkor, it's wonderful!
It's like the Nothing never was!
Atreyu! Artax!
What would you like to wish for next?
Look, there they are!
It's a monster!
Get them! Let's see
how you like it, chickens!
Down here!
We're gonna get you!
Bastian made many other wishes...
...and had many other
amazing adventures...
...before he finally returned
to the ordinary world.
But that's another story.