Ladies and gentlemen, we are about
to descend into Los Angeles.
The sound you just heard
was the landing gear.
The weather in Los Angeles is clear,
temperature 7 2 degrees.
We expect to make our flight today
in four hours and eighteen minutes.
We enjoyed having you on board
and hope to see you again soon.
[Skipped item nr. 6]
What's wrong?
The guests are all downstairs.
They're waiting to see you, Ben.
Dad, can you tell them
that I need to be alone for a while?
These are our good friends.
Most of them have known you
practically since you were born.
What is it, Ben?
I'm just . . .
Worried?
Well . . .
About what?
I guess about my future.
What about it?
I don't know.
I want it to be . . .
To be what?
Different.
Is anything wrong?
- No, we were just coming down.
The Carlsons are here!
- They are? Well, c'mon!
They came all the way from Tarzana!
C'mon, let's go! - It's wonderful
to have so many devoted friends.
There's the scholar!
- We're very proud of you.
Thanks, Mrs. Carlson.
- Is that the new car outside?
Ben's graduation gift. - Pickin' up
the teenyboppers won't be hard now!
I think Ben is past the teenybopper
stage, aren't you, Ben? - Yes, ma'am.
Excuse me,
I have to check the car for a minute.
Bob bought him an Alfa Romeo.
Here's the track star. How are you?
- Just fine, Mr. Loomis.
I wanna drink, then I want to hear
about that Hopperman award you won.
Helpingham.
- Right. Wait right here!
Ben, we're all so proud of you!
- Proud! Proud! Proud!
What are you going to do now?
- Go upstairs. - With your future?
Your life?
- That's a little hard to say.
Ben!
- Excuse me! Mr. McGuire.
Come with me, I want to talk to you.
Excuse us, Joanne. - Of course.
I just want to say one word to you.
Yes, sir?
- Are you listening? - Yes, I am.
Plastics!
Exactly how do you mean? - There's a
great future there. Think about it.
Think about it, OK?
- I will.
Enough said. That's a deal.
There he is! There's Ben!
Excuse me just a minute.
Listen everybody,
I want you all to be quiet!
I have Ben's yearbook. Let me read you
some wonderful things about him.
Quiet, please!
"Captain of the Cross-Country Team,
Head of the Debating Club, Associate
Newspaper Editor his junior year . . ."
I guess this isn't the bathroom.
- It's down the hall.
How are you, Benjamin?
- Fine, thanks, Mrs. Robinson.
The bathroom's at the end of the hall.
Such a pleasant room.
- Look, Mrs. Robinson,
I don't mean to be rude, but I'm . . .
- Is there an ashtray in here?
No. - I forgot.
The track star doesn't smoke.
Is it a girl?
Is what a girl?
Whatever is upsetting you.
No, I'm just disturbed about things.
- In general? - That's right.
Well . . .
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
I want to ask you something.
Will you take me home?
My husband took the car.
Will you drive me home?
Here . . . you take it.
You know how to work a foreign shift?
You don't?
- No.
Let's go.
Thank you.
- Right.
Will you come in, please?
- What?
Until I get the lights on. - Why?
- I don't feel safe until they're on.
Please go ahead of me to the porch.
I feel funny about a dark house.
But it's light in there.
- Please.
What do you drink? Bourbon?
Look, Mrs. Robinson, I drove you home.
I was glad to do it. But I have some
things on my mind. Do you understand?
What do you drink?
I don't want to be left alone
in the house. - Why not?
Wait till my husband comes.
When is he coming back?
- I don't know.
Drink?
- No.
Are you always this much afraid
of being alone? - Yes.
Can't you just lock the doors?
I'm very neurotic.
May I ask you a question?
What do you think of me?
What do you mean? - You've known me
all your life. You have some opinion.
I always thought
you were a very nice person.
Did you know I was an alcoholic?
What?
Did you know?
I think I should be going.
Sit down. - Mrs. Robinson,
this conversation has become strange.
Mr. Robinson will be here any minute.
- No, my husband will be home late.
He should be gone for several hours.
Oh, my God!
Pardon?
- Oh, no, Mrs. Robinson! No!
What's wrong?
- You didn't expect . . .?
What?
You didn't think I'd do something like
that? - What? - What do you think?
I don't know. - For God's sake,
Mrs. Robinson, here we are.
You got me in your house.
You give me a drink, put music on,
open up your private life and tell me
your husband's coming late. - So?
Mrs. Robinson,
you're trying to seduce me!
Aren't you?
I hadn't thought of it.
I feel very flattered.
Mrs. Robinson, please forgive me.
It's all right. - It's not all right.
It's horrible. - Sit down.
Please forgive me, I'm just mixed up.
- It's all right. Finish your drink.
It makes me sick that I said that.
- Forget it now.
What is wrong with me?
- Have you seen Elaine's portrait?
Her portrait?
- Yes. - No.
We did it last Christmas.
Want to see it? - Very much.
It's here, in Elaine's room.
Elaine really is an attractive girl.
I don't remember her as having
brown eyes. - Come over here.
Over there?
Sure.
Will you unzip my dress?
I'll go to bed. - Well, good night!
Won't you unzip my dress?
- I'd rather not.
You still think I'm seducing you?
- No, I don't, I just feel funny.
You've known me for so long.
Come on, it's hard for me to reach.
Thank you.
What are you scared of? - I'm not
scared. - Why do you keep walking out?
Because you're going to bed.
I shouldn't be up here.
Haven't you ever seen anybody
in a slip before? - Yes, but . . .
What if Mr. Robinson came back?
- What if? - It would look strange.
Don't you think he trusts us?
- But he might get the wrong idea!
How could anyone think you and I . . .
- But they would! Don't you see?
I am not trying to seduce you!
- I know, but please, Mrs. Robinson!
Would you like me to seduce you?
- What?
Is that what you're trying to tell me?
- I'm going now.
I hope you can forget what I said.
But I'm going home right now.
Can you bring up my purse?
- I must go.
I don't want to put this back on.
- Where is it?
On the table in the hall.
I'm in the bathroom. - Here's
the purse. - Could you bring it up?
I'll hand it to you.
Come to the railing.
I'm tired of this suspicion! If you
won't do this simple favor, well . . .
I'm putting it on the top step.
- For God's sake, bring me the purse!
I'm putting it by the door. - Will
you bring it to me? - I'd rather not.
All right, put it in Elaine's room,
where we were. - Right.
Oh, God!
Let me out!
- Don't be nervous.
Get away from that door. - First, I
want you to know that you can have me.
If you won't sleep with me now,
you can call me up any other time.
Understand?
- Let me out!
Did you understand? I find you
very attractive, and any time you . . .
That's him!
Is that Ben's car in front?
- Yes, sir!
I drove Mrs. Robinson home.
She asked me to, so I drove her home.
I appreciate it.
She's upstairs. She wanted me
to wait down here until you got home.
Standing guard over the old castle?
- Yes, sir.
Congratulations!
- Thank you.
Looks like you need a refill.
- Oh, no, I have to go.
Is anything wrong?
You look a little shaken up.
No. I'm just a little worried
about my future. Just a little upset.
Let's have a nightcap together.
Scotch? - Bourbon.
How old are you now?
20, I'll be 21 next week.
That's a helluva good age to be.
- Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
I wish I was that age again.
Because, Ben . . . - Sir?
You'll never be young again.
- I know.
Can I say something to you?
- What?
How long have we known each other?
How long have you and I
known each other?
How long have your Dad and I
been partners? - Quite a while.
I watched you grow up, Ben.
- Yes, sir.
In many ways I feel as though
you were my own son. - Thank you.
So I hope you won't mind
a friendly piece of advice.
I'd like to hear it.
I think
you ought to be taking it a little
easier right now than you seem to be.
Sow a few wild oats.
Take things as they come.
Have a good time with the girls.
- Don't get up.
I was just telling . . .
- Ben. - . . . Ben
to sow a few wild oats. Have a good
time. You think that's sound advice?
Yes, I do.
- I've got to go.
You have yourself
a few flings this summer.
I'll bet you're quite a ladies' man?
- Oh, no.
What? You look like the kind of guy
who has to fight them off.
Doesn't he look to you like he has
to fight them off? - Yes, he does.
Oh, say, Elaine gets down
from Berkeley on Saturday. - Oh, yes.
Why don't you give her a call?
- I will.
Thanks for taking me home.
I'll see you soon, I hope.
Your attention, please. For this
afternoon's feature attraction
Hey, over there, yes, I mean you!
Your attention please.
Are you ready, feature attraction?
- Can I speak to you for a second?
Listen, I need some applause
to bring this boy out here, OK? No!
Let me amend that.
To bring this young man out here,
because today he is 21 .
Let's go!
Hold on, I've got a few words to say.
- You always do!
Look who's talking!
Dad, can we talk for a second?
- I can't hold them much longer.
I'd like to discuss this.
- This boy, I'm sorry . . .
this young man, will continue learning
as a Helpingham Award scholar.
but before he does, before he does . . .
You're disappointing them, Ben.
You really are! - Dad, listen . . .
I'll give you ten seconds!
He is going to give us a demonstration
of what I feel safe in saying is a
pretty exciting birthday present.
It'd better work, or I'm out
over two hundred bucks.
Okay, let's hear it now for Benjamin
Braddock!
Come on, Benjie!
Let's hear it. Thatta boy!
Now folks, this remarkable young man
will perform some spectacular
and amazing feats of daring
in water that is over 6 feet deep.
Hello?
I don't know how to put this . . .
- Benjamin?
I was thinking about that time
after the party . . . - Where are you?
I was wondering if I could
buy you a drink. - Where are you?
The Taft Hotel.
- Did you get a room? - No.
I know it's pretty late, and . . .
- Give me an hour. - What?
I'll be there in an hour.
Can I help you, sir?
What? No, I'm just . . .
Are you here for an affair, sir?
What?
The Singleman party?
Yes, the Singleman party.
- It's in the Main Ballroom. - Thanks.
You must be one of the Porters?
- No, I . . .
This is my sister, Miss DeWitte.
- How do you do? - How do you do?
That's my husband, Mr. Singleman.
And Jeffrey, of course.
I didn't get your name, sir.
- Benjamin Braddock, sir.
Yes, but I'm afraid . . .
- I'll find your table!
Not Braniff? We have a Braniff.
I'm looking for a friend.
- I don't understand.
I'm not with your party, I'm sorry.
- I don't get it.
I've enjoyed meeting you, Mr. Braniff.
Hello, Benjamin.
- Oh, hello.
May I sit down?
- Of course. - Thank you.
How are you?
- Very well, thank you.
May I have a drink?
- A drink? Of course.
He didn't see me.
- Waiter!
I will have a Martini.
- Yes, madam.
You don't have to be so nervous.
- Nervous?
I am a bit nervous.
It's hard to be suave when you're . . .
Did you get us a room? - What?
- Did you get a room yet? - No.
Do you want to? - Well, I don't . . .
I could . . . Or we could just talk.
Do you want me to get it?
- No, I'll get it.
Now?
- Now? - Yes.
I don't know.
Why don't you get it?
- Well, I will then, excuse me.
Excuse me.
Yes, sir?
A room. I'd like a room, please.
- Single or double?
A single. Just for myself.
- Sign the register, please.
Is anything wrong, sir?
- What? No, nothing.
Do you have luggage, Mr. Gladstone?
- Luggage?
Yes, I do.
- Where is it?
What?
- Where is your luggage?
It's out in the car.
- I'll have a porter get it.- Oh no!
I don't want to cause any trouble.
I just have a toothbrush.
I can get it myself. - Of course.
I'll have a porter show you the room.
Oh, actually,
I'd just as soon find it myself.
I just have a toothbrush to carry
and I think I can handle it myself.
Whatever you say, sir.
- Thank you.
Mrs. Robinson?
For you.
- Thank you.
Hello?
- Mrs. Robinson?
It's Benjamin.
- Yes?
Benjamin Braddock.
- Where are you?
Can you look through the glass?
Can you see me now?
- Yes, I can.
I got a single room.
- That's fine.
But there's one thing. The desk clerk
seemed a little suspicious.
I don't know their policy . . .
- Do you want to go up first? - Yes.
I'll be up in five minutes.
- Goodbye then. - Benjamin!
Isn't there something
you want to tell me?
I want you to know how much
I appreciate this. - The number.
You ought to tell me the number.
You're absolutely right.
It's 568.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Well,
I'll see you later, Mrs. Robinson.
Check, please.
I've got it.
I say I've got it.
The toothbrush! - Very good, sir.
Well, good night.
- Good night, sir.
Hello, Benjamin.
Hello, Mrs. Robinson.
Well . . .
Benjamin . . .
Yes?
I'll get undressed now, alright?
- Sure, shall I . . .?
Shall I just stand here?
I don't know what you want me to do?
Why don't you watch? - OK, thank you.
- Will you bring me a hanger? - What?
A hanger.
- Oh, yes.
Wood?
What?
- Wood or wire? They have both.
Either one.
- Okay.
Thank you.
Would you help me, please?
- Certainly.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Would this be easier in the dark?
- I can't do this.
You what?
- This all is wrong.
Do you find me undesirable?
- No!
You are the most attractive of all my
parent's friends. You're desirable
But for God's sake, what would my
parents say if they were here now?
What? - I have no idea.
But they made a good life for me.
They deserve a little better than
going to bed with the partner's wife.
Are you afraid of me?
- No, you're missing the point.
Maybe we could do something else.
Would you like to go to a movie?
Can I ask you a personal question?
- Anything. - Is this your first time?
Is this what?
- It is, isn't it? Your first time?
That's a laugh, Mrs. Robinson.
- You can admit that, can't you?
Are you kidding?
- It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Who said it was my first time?
- You're afraid of being inadequate.
Inadequate?
I guess I'd better . . .
- Don't move!
Ben, what are you doing?
I would say I am just drifting
here in the pool. - Why?
It's very comfortable
just to drift here.
Have you thought about
Graduate school? - No.
How about telling me what those
four years of college were for?
You got me.
- Now listen, Ben . . .
Look,
I think it's good for a young man,
after he's done some very good work,
to enjoy himself,
lie around and drink beer.
But after a few weeks
I believe that person would want
to take some stock in himself
and think about getting off his ass.
The Robinsons are here.
Hi, Ben,
what are you doing these days?
Oh, not too much. Taking it easy.
That's what I would do if I could.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Elaine's coming from Berkeley.
I want you to call her. - I will.
I think
you two would really hit it off.
Say hello to Mrs. Robinson.
Hello, Mrs. Robinson.
Hello, Benjamin.
Oh, my!
Can I talk to you for a minute.
- Sure.
Benjie, darling,
I'm going to ask you something,
but you don't have to tell me
if you don't want to. - What?
I'm going to ask you what you do
when you go off at night.
When I go off?
You don't have to tell me. - No,
I want to tell you. I drive around.
What else?
- Nothing else.
You don't drive from midnight
to noon the next day. - No.
Then what do you do?
Do you meet someone?
Why do you ask?
- Well, it's your business.
I don't want to play games.
- Wait!
I don't meet anyone, but why?
- I don't want to pry into your life,
but I would rather you didn't say
anything then be dishonest. - Wait!
Wait a minute!
Wait a minute, please.
Mrs. Robinson, do you think we could
talk a little first this time?
I don't think
we have much to say to each other.
For months, all we've done is
come up here and leap into bed.
Are you tired of it?
- I'm not, no.
But do you think we could liven it up
with some talk? - About what?
Anything at all.
Do you want to tell me about your
college experiences? - Oh, my God!
Think of another topic.
How about art?
- That's good. You start it off.
You start it off.
I know nothing about it.
Are you interested more
in Modern or in Classical Art?
Neither. - Neither? Why do you want
to talk about it? - I don't.
We're going to have a conversation!
Tell me what you did today.
I got up.
I fixed breakfast for my husband.
- That's something we can talk about.
Your husband!
- Oh, him.
I mean everything. I don't know
anything about how you work this.
What do you say when you leave?
- Nothing, he's asleep. - Always?
Doesn't he wake up when you come
home? - We have separate bedrooms.
Oh, I see. So you don't . . .
I don't want to pry,
but you don't sleep with him? - No.
How long has this been going on?
Why did you marry him?
See if you can guess.
- I can't. - Think real hard.
I can't see why you did, unless . . .
Were you forced to marry him?
Don't tell Elaine. - You had
to marry him because you got pregnant.
Are you shocked?
I never thought of you two as . . .
- Alright, let's get to bed.
Wait a minute!
So how did it happen?
- What?
You and Mr. Robinson. Do you feel like
telling me the circumstances?
Not really.
Was he a law student at the time?
And you were a student also?
At college?
- Yes.
What was your major?
Why are you asking all the questions?
- Because I'm interested.
What was your major at college?
Art.
- Art?
But I thought . . .
I guess you lost interest
in it over the years then.
Kind of.
How did it happen?
What?
- You and Mr. Robinson.
How do you think? - In his room,
or did he take you to a hotel?
What does it possibly matter?
- I'm curious.
We'd go to his car.
- In a car you did it?
I don't think we were the first.
- What kind of car was it?
What?
- Do you remember the make of the car?
Oh, my God!
- I want to know! - A Ford.
A Ford!
God damn it, that's great!
That's enough.
So old Elaine Robinson
got started in a Ford.
Don't talk about Elaine.
- Don't talk about Elaine?
No.
Why not?
Because I don't want you to.
- Why don't you tell me then?
There's nothing to tell.
- Why is she a big taboo subject?
I guess I'll have to ask her out
and find out what the big deal is.
Don't you ever take that girl out!
Do you understand that?
I have no intention of taking her out.
Good.
I was just kidding around.
But why shouldn't I?
I have my reasons. - Let's hear 'em.
- No. - I think I know the reason.
I'm not good enough for her, am I?
I can't even talk about her, can I?
Let's drop it. - No! I'm good enough
for you, but not for your daughter!
That's it, isn't it?
Yes.
You go
straight to hell, Mrs. Robinson!
Do you think I'm proud of all this?
- I wouldn't know. - I'm not.
I'm not proud that I spend my time
with a broken-down alcoholic.
I see. - I come here for no reason
other than sheer boredom.
This is the sickest, most perverted
thing that ever happened to me.
Do what you want, I'm done with this!
- Are you? - Goddamn right!
That's how you feel? That I'm sick
and disgusting? - Don't start this.
What? - Don't start acting hurt.
- Don't you expect me to be hurt?
You told me I'm not
good enough for Elaine. - Did I?
In so many words.
I want to apologize to you
if that's the impression you got.
Two minutes ago you told me I wasn't
good enough, now you say you're sorry!
I didn't mean it. I don't think
you'd be right for each other.
I would never say you weren't
as good a person as she is.
You wouldn't?
Of course I wouldn't.
What are you doing? - It's pretty
obvious you don't want me around.
I was kind of upset there.
I'm sorry I said those things.
- It's alright.
I can understand why
I'm disgusting to you. - I dunno.
I like you or I wouldn't keep
coming here if I didn't like you.
Wasn't it sickening?
- It's not . . .
I enjoy it. I look forward to it.
It's the one thing I look forward to.
You don't have to say that.
- I wouldn't, not if it wasn't true.
May I stay then?
Yes, please, I want you to.
Thank you. - Don't thank me.
Because I want you to.
But you won't ever take Elaine out,
will you? I want you to promise.
Why did you bring this up? It never
occurred to me. - Then give your word.
This is absurd.
Promise me, Benjamin.
Alright. For Christ's sake,
I promise I'll never take Elaine out.
Thank you.
Let's not talk about it.
Let's not talk at all.
Elaine's back from school.
It might be a nice gesture
if you asked her out.
I guess she's not good enough for you?
- Elaine and I do not get along.
You haven't seen her since
high school! I guess your evenings
are just too valuable.
- That has nothing to do with it.
I'll just have to tell Mr. Robinson
that you're too busy every evening.
Don't go on like this. If Ben
absolutely refuses to take her out . . .
I do. - . . . then I will just have to
invite the Robinsons over Thursday.
Well, Braddock, it's about time
you got around to doing this.
Your wife thinks you would say . . .
"Katy Duvalle . . ."
No points, right.
Here's the next question.
What's your wife's most unusual habit?
Come on in! I'm afraid
the young lady isn't quite ready yet.
What would you say to a short one?
Scotch still your drink? - Bourbon.
Not shaving her legs.
I'll see if she's ready yet.
This was my father's idea!
- I thought I was clear about this.
We'll go to dinner and have a drink
and I'll bring her right back.
It was that or a dinner party for both
families, and I couldn't handle that.
I have no intention of ever taking
her out again, so don't get upset!
But I am. I'm extremely
upset about it, Benjamin.
Hello.
I want you to keep your wits tonight.
You never know what tricks
Ben picked up back there in the East.
You're living at home now, right?
- Yes.
Do you know what you're going to do?
- No.
Are you going to Graduate School?
Do you always drive like this?
- Yes.
Sit down!
Why don't you watch the show?
Do you dislike me for some reason?
- No, why should I?
I don't know.
You're missing a great effect here.
How do you like that?
Could you do it?
Elaine, I'm sorry.
Will you take me home now?
- I'm sorry I took you in there.
Where's the car?
- I want to tell you something.
I just want to go home.
- But can I just tell you one thing?
What? - This date was my parents'
idea. They forced me into it.
That's very nice of you to tell me.
- No, I mean I'm not really like this.
I hate myself like this.
Could you just stop crying?
- No, I couldn't.
But could you try?
- No.
Since I graduated, I feel like I have
to always be rude. Do you understand?
Yes, I do.
It's like I've been playing a game,
but the rules don't make any sense.
They're being made up
by all the wrong people. No,
I mean no one makes them up,
they seem to make themselves up.
I wonder if I could request you
to turn that down a little?
Would you like to come in?
I could make you some coffee. - No.
I wouldn't want to wake anyone up.
- We won't.
Let's go inside.
Wait a minute.
- Is anything wrong?
I was thinking. It's still early.
Maybe we could do something,
go somewhere else.
Alright.
Where are we going?
- Where is a place to have a drink?
Isn't there one in the Taft Hotel?
What is the matter?
Nothing! I'm just wondering
if they have a bar? Let's go see.
Let's go see if they do or not.
It seems to me there isn't a bar here.
- Yes, there is. Look, the Palm Room!
Good evening.
- How are you, sir?
Good evening, Mr. Gladstone.
- Hello again.
Hi, Mr. Gladstone.
How are you this evening?
Let's go somewhere else.
- Do they know you? - Of course not!
Good evening, sir.
- Come on, we're leaving.
Mr. Gladstone, how are you?
What's happening?
- They must think that I'm Gladstone.
Hello, Mr. Braniff.
Elaine, I like you.
I like you so much.
Do you believe that?
Do you?
- Yes.
You're the first . . .
You're the first thing
for so long that I've liked.
The first person
I could stand to be with.
My whole life is such a waste.
It's just nothing.
I'm sorry. I'll take you home now.
Are you having an affair with someone?
I'm sorry. That's not my business.
It just happened.
It was just this thing that happened
along with everything else.
Can you understand that?
Was she married or something?
Yes.
With a family?
- Yes. She had a husband and a son.
Did they ever find out?
- No.
And it's all over now?
Yes.
I'm glad.
Can we do something tomorrow?
- Alright.
During the day?
Go for a drive or something. - Okay.
You sure you really want to?
- Yes.
I only want to if you want to.
- I do. - You do?
Benjamin, I really do.
Drive!
Elaine and I have a date.
We're going for a drive.
Do exactly as I say!
It seems to me . . .
- Listen to me very carefully.
You are not to see Elaine again.
Those are my orders. Is that clear?
I can make things quite unpleasant.
- How?
To keep Elaine away from you,
I'm prepared to tell her everything.
I don't believe you.
You'd better do.
You wouldn't do that.
Try me.
Benjamin? - I'm coming up!
- I'm not dressed yet. Benjamin!
Go over the back fence. I'll meet you
around the corner. Put your shoes on.
What are you doing?
- I have to tell you something.
That woman,
that older woman I told you about.
That one? - Yes. That wasn't just
some woman. - What are you telling me?
Just tell me what this is all about?
Oh, no.
Oh, my God!
Get out of here.
- Don't cry. - Get out!
Goodbye, Benjamin.
Say that again.
I'm going to marry Elaine Robinson.
What's happening?
Ben says that
he and Elaine are getting married.
I don't believe it! - That's what he
says. - I'm going to Berkeley today.
This is so exciting.
Call the Robinsons. We have to
celebrate. - I think you should wait.
They don't know? - No.
- When did you decide this?
An hour ago. - Wait a minute.
You talked to Elaine this morning?
No. She doesn't know about it.
- That you're coming up to Berkeley?
No, that we're getting married.
- When did you two talk this over?
We haven't.
- You haven't?
This whole idea
sounds pretty half-baked.
No, it's not. It's completely baked.
It's a decision I've made.
How do you know she'll marry you?
- I don't. She doesn't even like me.
Student? - Not exactly.
- What's that? - Not exactly.
What are you then?
- I'm just sort of traveling through.
I like to know who's living here
and what my boys are up to.
I'm not up to much, actually.
I'm just visiting.
I've always wanted to see Berkeley.
You're not one of those
outside agitators? I hate that.
I won't stand for that.
What a coincidence!
I was wondering where you were
headed. - I'm meeting someone.
Where?
Where are you meeting this person?
- At the zoo. - The zoo?
They have a good one here?
I don't know. I've never seen it.
- I haven't either.
I might ride out there with you.
Is that him over there?
- No.
Where did he say he would meet you?
- I thought by the monkey house.
What are you doing here?
In Berkeley? I have this nice room,
and I've been getting to classes . . .
But you're not enrolled!
- No, I just sit in.
You're . . . I don't know what to say.
- Maybe we can talk about it.
Really incredible!
Here he comes. - What?
- I really think this is the fella.
He certainly is a good walker.
Am I late? I'm sorry.
- We thought by the monkey house.
Benjamin Braddock. Carl Smith.
Benjamin rode here with me on the bus.
Glad to meet you, Ben.
- Great meeting you, Carl!
Who is it? - I ask you one question,
then I'm going. - Come in. - No.
Why are you here? - Because I am.
- Is it because I am here?
What do you think? - I think it is.
I said, I think it is.
Alright then, yes!
- I want you to leave. - I love you!
Do you just hate everything? How could
you possibly rape my mother? - What?
How could anyone do a thing like that?
- Tell me what she said. - Why?
Because it isn't true. Tell me.
She said she was having a drink, that
you waited for her in the parking lot,
that she was too drunk to drive home
and that you'd get her a room.
Then what?
- You went upstairs and raped her.
That's not true. There was this party
at my parents. I drove her home . . .
I don't want to hear it!
- We went up to see your portrait.
She got undressed!
- She's my mother!
Suddenly she was naked!
- Shut . . .!
Hello, Mr. McCleery.
- Who screamed?
It's alright.
- Screaming is not alright here.
It was just a visitor.
But it's alright now.
What'd you do to her? - She's upset
and she screamed, but it's OK now.
Shall I get the cops?
Wait a minute.
Look, here she is, having some water.
There's no need for the cops.
Alright boys, you can all go
back to your rooms now. Go ahead.
We won't have
any more of this agitation.
Will we, Braddock?
- No, sir.
I want you out of here.
- What do you mean? - Out of here!
What for?
- Because I don't like you.
I'm sorry I screamed.
When you came up here, what did you
think was going to happen between us?
I don't feel like talking. I'm sorry,
but I think I'll just do this now.
Can I sit here while you're packing?
- If you want.
What're you going to do now?
I don't know.
Are you going home?
- No.
Where are you going?
Stop asking me that.
I don't want you to leave.
I don't understand.
I don't want you to go anywhere
until you have a definite plan.
Goodbye.
What's happening?
- Benjamin. - What?
Will you kiss me?
Will you marry me?
You won't?
- I don't know.
But you might?
I might.
Is that so? You might marry me?
Yes.
When?
I don't know.
How about tomorrow? I don't mean to
be pushy, but . . . - I don't know.
I don't know what's happening.
You're confused?
Don't be confused.
We're getting married.
I don't see how we can.
We just can.
I have to go now.
Are you serious about this?
I'll think about it.
- You really will? - Yes.
Good God!
We get our blood tests tomorrow.
Or today's a good day.
I haven't said I'll marry you.
I happen to have my birth certificate
with me. Where's yours?
I just don't think it would work.
- Why wouldn't it?
Why wouldn't it?
- I just don't think it would.
Can we get our blood tests tomorrow?
Why don't you just drag me off
if you want to marry me so much?
Alright, I will. Right after we get
the tests. - I have to see Carl first.
Carl who?
Carl Smith! We've known him for years.
- That guy at the zoo?
Why do you have to see him?
- I said I might marry him.
You what?
How'd he do it? Did he get down
on his knees? I hope he didn't.
No.
- What did he say? I'm curious.
He said he thought we'd make a pretty
good team. - Oh no! He said that?
Where did he do it?
I'd like to know where it happened.
It wasn't in his car, was it?
Good night.
Are we getting married tomorrow?
No.
The day after tomorrow?
I don't know.
Maybe we are and maybe we're not.
Do you want to try
and tell me why you did it?
Mr. Robinson?
Do you have a grudge against me? Do
you feel a strong resentment? - No.
Did I say something wrong, or do you
just despise the things I stand for?
It has nothing to do with you, sir
- It was quite a bit to do with me!
We're civilized. Is it necessary to
threaten each other? - I didn't.
Could you unclench your fists?
Thank you. I can see in the dark.
I've been here quite a while.
I'm trying to say I have no personal
feelings here. I do not resent you.
You don't respect me either, do you?
No, sir.
- What? - No, sir.
Don't shout at me. I may not be as
young as you, but I still hear well.
Wait till I finish!
I think you should know that my wife
and I are getting divorced soon.
But why?
- Why?
What happened between
Mrs. Robinson and me was nothing!
It didn't mean anything. We might
as well have been shaking hands.
That's not saying much for my wife.
- You miss the point. - I guess I do.
The point is, I don't love your wife.
I love your daughter, sir.
Listen to this: I don't know
if I can prosecute, but I think I can.
I think I can get you behind bars
if you ever look at my daughter again.
I've made sure you can't get to her.
Stay away from me, Ben!
I don't want to mince words with you.
As far as Elaine is concerned, you're
to get her out of your filthy mind!
Is that clear to you?
That's all. You'll pardon me
if I don't shake hands with you!
I think you are filth!
I think you are scum!
You are a degenerate!
Do you have some change for a
phone call? - I want you out of here!
I'll give you ten dollars for a dime.
I'll give you twenty.
Will you let me use that phone?
- I'm gonna call the police.
Could I make one phone call first?
- Get outta here!
Elaine Robinson has left school.
Her roommate
is coming down with a note for you.
Dear Benjamin, please forgive me,
for what I'm doing is best for you.
My father is so upset. I love you
but it would never work out.
Hello, Benjamin.
Where is she?
- Get me the police, please.
One minute, Benjamin. Do you have a
patrol car near 1 200 Glenview Road?
Good. We have a burglar here.
I'll ask him. Are you armed?
I don't believe he is.
Where is she? - Everything is under
control. A quick drink before you go?
You can't stop me from seeing her.
I'll find her.
You can't come to the wedding.
It's already been planned.
What the hell have you done to her?
I don't think you'll
have time for that drink, after all.
I'll find her.
- I don't think so.
Say, fellas . . .
Anyone know where Carl Smith is? - He
took off last night, to get married.
Probably
one step ahead of the shotgun!
Where is he getting married?
I'm supposed to be there.
Ask Carter.
Where can I find him?
Hey, Carter?
Where's the Make Out King getting
married? - Santa Barbara.
Do you know exactly where in Santa
Barbara. I'm supposed to be there.
Where in Santa Barbara? - I don't
know. Maybe at his old man's home.
Or in the maternity ward!
Are you going to the wedding?
Tell him to save a piece for me . . .
. . . of the wedding cake!
Can I use your phone?
- Yeah.
657-2036. - Hello, who is this?
- Dr. Smith's answering service.
Is the doctor anywhere?
- Sorry, the doctor can't . . .
Where is he? - He's at his son's
wedding. But I'm sure it's over now.
I'm the Dr.'s brother, Reverend Smith.
I'm supposed to perform the ceremony.
I just got in from Portland
and I've forgotten what church.
I'm not sure, but maybe the First
Presbyterian, Allan Street. - Thanks.
Allan Street, where is it?
It's six blocks up and three over.
You need any gas, Father?
Oh, Jesus God, no!
Who is that guy? What's he doing?
I'll take care of him.
- He's too late.
We've got to stop him.
You crazy punk!
It's too late!
- Not for me!