Unh!
[ Loud Revelry ]
[ Revelry Continues ]
[ Squeals, Grunts ]
We have killed Babylonians!
[ Cheering ]
We have killed
Mesopotamians!
- [ Cheering Continues ]
- We have killed Assyrians,
Mycenaeans, Sumerians,
but...
we have never
had the pleasure...
of killing...
an Akkadian.
[ Cheering ]
[ Grunting ]
Which limb do I take first?
[ Shouting All At Once ]
May the gods
have pity on you...
because my brother
will not.
[ Growls ]
Boo.
[ Screaming ]
[ Yelling ]
You missed.
[ Screaming ]
You're lucky
we have the same mother.
[ Man Narrating ]
Before the time of the pyramids,
a fearsome horde
came from the East...
and swept across
the barren lands
of the ancient world.
[ Whinnying ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Narrator ]
By the law of the horde,
their greatest warrior
was proclaimed their king.
His name was Memnon.
[ Narrator ]
He was the greatest swordsman
the world had ever seen.
[ Whinnies ]
[ Narrator ]
With the predictions
of a sorcerer...
who could foretell
the outcome of every battle,
Memnon slaughtered
all who resisted him,
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Arrows Continue Flying ]
[ Narrator ]
until only a brave few remained.
[ Loud Argumentation ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
- Silence!
- My father has
called for silence!
Hold your tongues!
[ Shouting Stops Abruptly ]
We are gathered
in this place...
to put our differences
aside.
There is still time for us,
the last
of the free tribes,
to stand together
against this tyrant.
With his sorcerer at his side,
no mortal can defeat Memnon.
And if the sorcerer
were to die, what then?
It's too late
for your schemes, Pheron.
I have raided
Memnon's caravans,
broken the supply lines
to his troops,
but he still
swept across the land
like a plague.
I will not send my people
to their deaths in a battle
that can't be won.
And what people
would that be,
Balthazar?
You are
the ruler of nothing...
but a pile of rocks
and sand.
If I'm no king,
[ Whimpers ]
why are you
on your knees before me?
Balthazar! Guards!
Akkadians.
I thought they were
wiped out long ago.
They are the last
of their kind.
By their hand,
the sorcerer will die.
You put your faith
in a clan of cutthroats
who kill for money?
They are more than that.
They are skilled assassins...
trained for generations
in the deadly arts.
And what price do these
mercenaries ask from us,
Father?
[ Sack Rattles ]
Twenty blood rubies.
- That's the last
of our treasury.
- Be quiet.
If these men
kill the sorcerer,
will you fight?
[ Commotion ]
[ Shouting Affirmations ]
So be it.
As long as
one of us still breathes,
the sorcerer will die.
Assassin!
Him...
we'll kill for free.
We can reach
Memnon's encampment
by nightfall.
When are you gonna get rid
of that filthy beast?
[ Bellows ]
He doesn't
mean anything by it.
- Horses are faster.
- But camels are smarter.
Hyah!
[ Whinnies ]
Hyah! Hyah!
[ Whistles Birdcall ]
That one's mine.
Live free.
Die well.
Stop. Stop. Listen to me.
I am a high priest of Set.
Spare me, and I shall bless thee
in five different languages.
- [ Whimpers ]
- You'll scream in five
different languages.
Horse thief.
Wait! Wait!
[ Whistles Birdcall ]
[ Groans ]
Hey! I'm not that heavy.
[ Grunting ]
[ Yelling ]
Look out for the first one!
He's behind you!
Help me! Help me!
Whoever you are, help me!
- Oh, thank you.
Thank you, good sir.
- Quiet.
Surely you've heard
of the enormous reward
for my safe return.
[ Men Talking In Distance ]
[ Whistles Birdcall ]
The sorcerer's tent.
[ Neighs ]
Back!
[ Commotion ]
- Make way!
- Find the other one!
You've been betrayed,
Mathayus.
- You know my name?
- And why you're here.
[ Grunts ]
[ Man ]
He's in the tent!
You! Move around back!
[ Yells ]
[ Grunts ]
A living, breathing Akkadian.
This is a rare pleasure.
I hear you train yourselves
to bear great pain.
You must teach me this,
if you live long enough.
[ Spits ]
Not looking
so full of yourself,
are you now, assassin?
You... betrayed
your own father?
Yes. He was very shocked.
You could tell
by the look on his face.
By my father's head,
I pledge my allegiance.
[ Memnon ]
You have proven
your loyalty, Takmet.
This one still lives.
[ Groaning ]
Beautiful.
Bring him to me.
[ Grunts ]
- [ Grunting ]
- Mathayus.
Mathayus.
Live free.
Die well, my brother.
[ Grunts ]
So,
how shall this one die?
- He shall not die tonight.
- Really?
We shall see.
Nor shall he die
by your hand...
or any hand you command.
You have seen this
in a vision?
To ignore this would
bring great misfortune.
The gods show him favor
on this night.
Just the gods?
[ Growls ]
A puzzle then.
How to kill you
without using my hand
or any hand I command?
[ Groans ]
Fascinating,
isn't it?
The smoke, it causes
the fire ants to abandon
their homes, you see?
All the sooner to feast
on our naked heads.
[ Laughs ]
You think this is funny?
It's a little bit funny.
Yes. You see,
I am about to escape,
while you are about to die
a horrible death for leaving me
to die last night.
So what are you waiting for?
You see that one
up there?
He's been drinking that Yak piss
for about an hour now
and sometime very soon--
Ahh. You see?
[ Groaning ]
[ Soldier Urinating ]
Hey! Where's the horse thief?
- Ooh!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Soldier Sputters, Gasps ]
[ Grunting ]
All right. Come on.
Get me outta here.
Do you, uh,
promise not to kill me?
Yes, I promise.
Remember,
you are an Akkadian.
You make an oath, you always
have to keep it, right?
That's right.
Promise to take me with you
and share in the spoils
of your adventures.
What? All right. Fine.
Yes, I promise.
All right. Now hold still.
Oh, here's one.
Ah. That's a big one!
[ Grunts ]
My! Here comes
the mother.
[ Grunts ]
So, where are we going?
To Memnon's kingdom
to avenge my brother's death.
[ Gulps ]
Never touch the bow.
Not a problem.
[ Whistles Birdcall ]
Who are you calling?
My ride.
[ Bellows ]
It's a nice camel.
Not much room
back here.
Scoot up, please.
Aah. Hey!
We had a deal!
That's right.
And I haven't killed you... yet.
What news
from my sorceress today?
[ Screaming ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
What news?
Your armies will
conquer in the West.
Queen Isis's forces
will scatter to the four winds.
Give the generals the news.
Have them
make their armies ready
for the final campaign.
[ Both ]
Yes, my Lord.
[ Doors Open, Close ]
[ Snarling ]
You think I'm cruel,
don't you?
Perhaps you've forgotten
what it's like outside
these walls.
Heartless, ignorant
and savage.
[ Snarling Subsides ]
But I can change that.
I will bring order
after centuries of chaos.
An order which will last
for a thousand years.
Rivers of blood
can never bring peace.
But they can bring obedience.
That will suffice for now.
And when I have
become the king of legend,
then you shall
take your place beside me...
on a throne...
and in my bed.
But, my lord,
in your bed I would
lose my gift of sight...
and you would lose
your advantage in battle.
The day I speak of...
is the day I no longer
need your vision.
Gomorrah.
[ Bleats ]
Let me tell you,
after a hard day of looting
and pillaging, there is
no greater city than Gomorrah.
Except maybe Sodom.
[ Nervous Chuckle ]
I wish
I could join you.
You're not going?
Believe me, I'd like to
even the score with a few
of those Red Guards myself.
But with the price I've got
on my head, I'd never make it
through those gates.
I have faith in you,
my friend.
You'll get us in.
[ Grunts ]
[ Bellows]
You see? They've got
the city sealed up tighter
than a crab's buttocks.
I wish there was something
I could do to help, but I-I--
Oh, but there is.
What business
do you have here?
I've come
to collect a bounty.
Horse thief.
Oh. I know this dog.
They'll behead him for sure
this time.
He'll be
all the prettier
without it.
[ Sputtering ]
[ Spitting Water]
[ Chuckles ]
What happened?
You got us in.
I knew you could do it.
Ajug of your finest wine
for my road-weary friend here.
Wait a minute.
The last thing that--
that I remember
was this huge...
Akkadian fist
coming straight into--
Here's your wine, sir.
Please, let me know
if there's anything else
you'd like.
Ah. It's good to be back
in the big city.
Watch my camel for me?
Gladly.
[ Chuckles ]
Been working here
long time?
How's the kabob?
[ Grunts ]
Merchandise
of the highest quality.
Virgin steel forged by
the monks of Pompeii.
Here! Here they are!
The world's finest swords.
Huh? You can't
get respect in Gomorrah
without a quality blade--
Birds of paradise,
birds of prey.
The most beautiful birds
in the world.
Hey, soldier.
Those big muscles
look cramped.
Perhaps one of us
can help you relax.
Maybe all of us.
[ Donkey Braying ]
Mister, mister.
Guide, mister.
You need a guide
to find your way
in Gomorrah.
A good guide might be
able to show me a way
into Memnon's palace.
But a smart guide wouldn't,
or he'd be shown
into Memnon's dungeon.
[ Boys Laughing ]
I don't have it.
[ Sack Rattling ]
[ Hollow Thud ]
[ High-Pitched Thud ]
Do you wanna
earn this one?
[ Voices, Indistinct ]
[ Gasps ]
Shh!
Get ready.
I'll kill half,
you kill half.
All right.
I'll kill 'em all.
How about
we go around them
and not kill anybody?
- Good Lord.
Are you going to kill me?
- Maybe later.
Memnon's
always threatening
to have my head.
Don't touch that.
- What is it?
- That's my special
magic powder.
[ Boy ]
Magic powder?
[ Bird Squawks ]
Yeah, magic powder.
It's a Chinese formula
that I procured
at great expense.
If I get the recipe right,
it'll move mountains,
clear roadways
in an instant--
do great things,
wonderful things.
Or terrible things.
Like all my inventions,
Memnon will try to use it
for war.
- Where is Memnon?
- Oh, you mean to kill him,
do you?
Yes.
Well, in that case,
I'd say he was
in the training courtyard.
[ Yells ]
Aah!
[ Cheering ]
Shukrin.
[ Applause, Cheering ]
No! Let me go!
[ Grunting ]
I didn't do anything!
You know the penalty
for thievery.
No!
[ Whimpers ]
Oh, no.
No!
Intruder!
Follow me!
- You again.
- How do I get outta here?
Through that door.
What's that?
That's one of
my latest inventions.
It was meant to be a means
of quick transportation,
but there was
a little problem
with the landings.
- [ Pounding On Door ]
- [ Man ] Open!
- Open!
- Don't touch that.
You'll set it off.
Right.
Aah!
[ Commotion ]
Oh.
[ Giggles ]
Oh, my!
A man.
What is this place?
Lord Memnon's harem.
- But he visits so rarely.
- And it gets so lonely.
- Can't you leave me alone,
Thorak?
- Watch your tongue, Philos.
Careful with those!
They're delicate
instruments.
You're lucky Lord Memnon
has a taste for your ''science,''
you old fool.
If I find out
you had anything to do
with this intruder,
I will send
the executioner.
We know
how to please.
[ Nervous Chuckle ]
Oh, I'm sure you do,
ladies, but I--
Stay with us.
That's nice,
but now's not a good time.
We will make
your every fantasy
come true.
[ Loud Gonging ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Women Screaming ]
Kill him!
After him!
Oh!
Go get him!
Aah!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Groaning ]
Well, are you
gonna try to kill me
or just stare at me?
Hyah!
Ow.
Humph.
[ Gasps ]
Take a breath.
Oh! Whoa-oh-oh!
Aah!
[ Gasps ]
Gods be praised!
[ Grunts ]
How dare you touch me!
Oh!
Sorceress,
I am an Akkadian
hired to kill you.
Now, I find myself
in a position where you are
of more use to me alive.
Don't make me
change my mind.
And he said, it's not
the size of the hump,
it is the motion
of the camel.
[ Laughter]
[ Horns Sounding ]
[ Women Screaming ]
Alas, I must leave you now.
[ Horns Continue Sounding ]
- There's the traitor!
- Oh, great gods!
[ Camel Bellowing ]
He is dead!
Just admit it,
you smelly camel!
- [ Bellowing ]
- I am your master now!
You belong to me!
He's dead!
Dead!
You are alive.
I knew it!
Right.
I was just saying to the camel,
''Camel, no one could kill
our good friend Mathayus.''
Get on.
Why should I
make it easy for you?
You're sworn to kill me.
- Others will die first.
- [ Camel Grunts ]
That's comforting.
- So who is your friend?
- Memnon's sorcerer.
Memnon's sorcerer?
Are you insane? She's
going to get us all killed!
Memnon will have to leave
the safety of his palace
to get her.
So you're going to
use me first
and then kill me?
I feel
so much better.
I could always do it
the other way around
and kill you first.
So where
are we going?
The Valley of the Dead.
The Valley
of the Dead?
Nobody goes to
the Valley of the Dead!
That's why they call it
Wait for me, please!
Take a dozen
of your best men,
track him down,
kill him...
and bring her back to me.
Send me news
when he's dead.
Yes, my lord.
My lord.
There are rumors
spreading to the armies
that she's gone.
- Is this true?
- It is, my lord.
Then silence them!
They must believe she is here,
if only for a short time.
And when you
find the Akkadian,
give him this from me.
[ Wind Whistling ]
Are we where
I think we are?
Yes.
Home.
[ Grunts ]
Where are you going,
Sorceress?
[ Grunting ]
[ Growls ]
In a hurry
to get back to Memnon?
No, I'm in a hurry to
get away from you. I'll
never go back to Memnon.
He's kept me prisoner
since I was a child.
Why did you help me
that night in the tent?
I knew you were the one man
who could help me escape.
Run if you like.
There are worse dangers
out there than me.
[ Bellows ]
- What do you mean
you can't find it?
- [ Bellows ]
- I know it's around here
somewhere.
- What are you looking for?
-Just a little place
to get out of the storm.
- What storm?
You'll see.
Thorak.
Memnon didn't come,
did he?
Sent his maggots
to do his work.
He's smarter than you think.
Or more cowardly.
Can I go home now?
Stay here. Cover up.
You'll be safe.
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Bleats ]
Hyah!
Look, sir.
He's attacking!
Alone?
The sun has
fried his brain.
A thousand duranas
for the one that
brings me his head.
Hyah!
[ Whinnying ]
Akkadian bastard!
Where is he?
[ Blow Lands, Man Screams ]
[ Bleats ]
This way!
You two first.
Come on. Go.
[ Clatter]
Aah!
[ Foot Tapping Ground ]
Stay on the stones.
[ Clatter ]
[ Whimpers ]
Aah!
Come with me.
[ Choking ]
- Aah!
- [ Blow Landing ]
- Don't touch that.
- [ Screaming ]
[ Man Screams ]
Aah!
[ Whimpers ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Coward!
Show your face!
[ Groans ]
Aah!
Ah.
[ Coughing ]
Oh. Ohh.
The Akkadian.
[ Whinnies ]
Mathayus!
[ Bellows ]
[ Grunting ]
Ahh!
You are alive!
You swatted them like flies!
You are invincible!
[ Groaning ]
[ Grunts ]
Tell me.
Do you think
you can save him?
His fever's high.
The poison was made
with scorpion venom.
If he does live,
the blood of the scorpion...
will always
flow through his veins.
[ Grunts ]
[ Shivering ]
Sorceress.
[ Gasps ]
It-It's a miracle.
She cured you.
I knew it!
I felt her magic!
It almost killed her,
but the gods,
they were on our side.
Why? Why would you
risk your life to save mine?
Because I believe
you can save the people.
The people are not my problem.
Memnon is.
You and the people
have the same problem.
[ Bird Chirping ]
[ Door Closes ]
Pardon, my lord.
A message from Thorak.
Finally
the Akkadian is dead.
Is there something wrong,
my lord?
Not at all.
Everything is in order.
In fact,
things are going so well...
that I'm moving up our plans.
Tomorrow night,
we feast to celebrate
our impending victory.
And then we'll drive
the last of the rebels
into the sea.
Now, go.
My lord,
it is customary
for the sorceress to be
present at these meetings.
Why is she
not here today?
- She's indisposed.
- It is nothing serious,
I hope.
If it were serious,
then you would know about it.
Now, go!
She is alive.
She is with him
and he's coming here.
Get ready.
It works! It works!
[ Laughing ]
My lady. How lovely
to see you out here
in this desolate place!
Let me show you.
It works!
[ Laughing ]
Come, come, come!
My lady sorceress.
[ Chuckles ]
You see?
I worked it out.
My Chinese formula.
My magic powder works!
All I needed was salt.
Petered salt.
It was here all the time.
This place is just full of it.
By the way, do any of you
happen to have any water?
What do you think?
Is it safe to drink?
Whoo-hoo!
Not anymore.
Delicious.
The sandstone must act
as a natural filter.
Quiet.
I'm alive! I'm alive!
For the moment.
Mathayus.
Move!
Assassin.
The gods are good to me.
When we last met,
you offered to kill me.
Now I have a chance
to return the favor.
You're trespassers here.
Our survival depends on this
place being kept a secret.
So we have a problem...
as long as you're alive.
[ Thief ]
No problem. I can keep
a secret like no other.
In fact, I cannot
remember how we got here.
We took a left turn--
- It's too late for that.
- Balthazar!
This place is sanctuary
for all of Memnon's enemies.
You know that.
This man is dangerous.
- Your judgment is clouded.
- My judgment keeps
all of you alive.
This man cannot be trusted,
and I'll prove it.
Bring the woman to me.
The first man to touch her
will have to come through me.
I had hoped for nothing less.
[ All Shouting, Cheering ]
[ Yells ]
[ Yelling ]
Aah.
[ Clangs ]
- That's not fair.
- [ Yells ]
[ Clucking ]
Get him.
No!
Yeah!
Do you yield?
Then you're a fool.
Never.
We're brothers
in the same cause.
Brothers?
You brought death
to my people.
Memnon will follow you.
He will come
for his sorceress.
Yes, I know who she is.
And Memnon will stop at nothing
till she's returned.
He'll come swifter
and deadlier once he has her.
Memnon will stop at nothing.
Hide here as long as you can,
but believe me when I say
he'll find you.
And if he isn't stopped,
he'll sweep across this land
and kill all of you.
[ Chuckling ]
And who's gonna
stop him, Akkadian?
You? Will you stand alone
before the fury of his armies?
Yes.
[ Cheering ]
A gentleman always
lets a lady win.
You didn't.
Best two
out of three?
Dates?
Oh, thank you.
[ Distant Screams ]
- Cassandra!
- [ Horse Whinnies ]
[ Gasps ]
I've had a vision.
Memnon will follow me here
and destroy these people.
You know this?
The things I see...
are like shimmers in a pond.
Some are certain,
and some remain shadows.
But I do know this--
Memnon will release his armies
and ride straight
through this place.
Memnon will die by my hand.
It seems the gods favor me
tonight, Akkadian.
[ Groans ]
If you face Memnon,
you'll die.
That is your destiny.
I make my own destiny.
I need your help.
[ Sighs ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Thief ]
You can't leave us here.
[ Philos ]
Mathayus, don't be so stubborn.
Listen to reason.
You can't go alone.
You're going to
get yourself killed.
Where do you think
you're going with my horse?
To Gomorrah.
Nothing we can say
will stop him.
Without your sorceress?
She returned to save
the lives of your people.
I won't let her face
Memnon's wrath alone.
Step aside.
Akkadian,
you're riding
to your death.
If I let you ride alone,
what glory will there be
left for me?
[ Percussion, Distant ]
[ Continues ]
[ Stops ]
[ Crowd Cheers ]
So tonight we celebrate.
Eat and drink your fill...
for tomorrow
we ride into battle.
[ Applause, Cheers ]
I would've captured him myself,
but he ran like a coward.
He left his bow behind.
My lord.
There is something
that is troubling our soldiers.
How distressing.
Pray tell.
It's been said the sorceress
is no longer by your side.
Soldiers
will fall prey to...
idle palace gossip.
You have my word,
she's perfectly safe.
If the men
are to fight, to die,
they may need more than that.
Do you doubt my word?
It is not that, sire.
It's just she is a symbol
from which the men
derive courage.
Symbols are most
effective when seen.
My lord.
[ Murmuring ]
I am here at your request.
Pardon my absence.
I was not well.
But our impending victory
has lifted my spirit.
Is this sufficient
to placate your men?
Tell them
what you see, Sorceress.
I see a great victory.
[ Murmuring ]
Your enemies will
reveal themselves to you.
Halt.
- What is in the cart?
- ''What is in the cart''?
Actually, it is
a bit of a surprise.
- A gift
for tonight's festivities.
- [ Giggling ]
Prince Takmet's request.
[ Chuckles ]
Very nice.
Well, now. Let's see
that pretty little face.
[ Clangs ]
Aah!
- [ Whistles Birdcall ]
- [ Grunts ]
Now go
to my chambers.
We have things
to discuss.
My sincerest apologies,
my lord.
I understand.
You are fearful, weak.
[ All Gasp ]
The feast is over.
To bed, men,
for tomorrow we conquer.
Fortify the palace guard.
Whoa.
All right.
That was the easy part.
- Everybody know what to do?
- Cripple the guards.
- Ignite the powder.
- And try not to get killed.
- What are you doing here?
You could get hurt.
- So could you.
- Stay in the wagon.
- [ Sighs ]
You watch yourself, Akkadian.
- No need for concern, miss.
- Oh, he's gonna pay for that.
Hey, hey.
Seal the gates.
Seal all the gates.
Though I'm relieved
to see you unharmed,
I am somewhat surprised
the Akkadian didn't kill you.
He was after you.
I was merely a pawn.
But you escaped his grasp?
I'm not
without my wiles.
Yes, I'm well aware of that.
Bring them.
Tomorrow
my victory is complete.
That is your vision?
As I said,
I have seen it.
Have you?
I sense a change in you.
You seem somehow...
diminished.
I assure you.
I am myself.
Good. A small demonstration
shouldn't trouble you then.
A simple test.
[ Hissing ]
Now go.
Everyone leave.
Where am I going?
Stop.
It's over there.
Should be just there.
Good man.
[ Creaking ]
Well, well.
What do we have here?
[ Grunts ]
One at a time.
Six urns, four cobras.
Now.
Let's see what you can see.
Excellent.
One empty pot left now.
[ Shattering ]
Who dies first?
[ All Yelling ]
We're almost there.
You know what I see?
Fear.
You have lost your power,
thrown it all away.
[ Hissing ]
What magic is this?
My magic.
I see your fate,
hollow king.
And its time has come.
You wish to test
magic against steel?
I've come for the woman
and your head.
The assassin
and the sorceress,
how romantic.
I'll bury you both together.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
And here it is,
the foundation stone.
- Hurry,
we're running out of time.
- I'm hurrying, I'm hurrying.
[ Hissing ]
[ Pounding On Door ]
Fire in front,
palace guard at your back.
Looks like I'll
be keeping my head
after all, Akkadian.
- Kill the witch!
- [ Yelling ]
[ Gasps ]
Mathayus!
For your father.
[ Screams ]
[ Clangs ]
Die well, assassin.
[ Groaning ]
It seems the gods
favor me tonight, Akkadian.
Mathayus!
[ Screams ]
Hurry up and light it.
You hurry up and light it.
This is your invention.
Follow me.
[ Groaning ]
Ready!
Weapons!
[ Yells ]
Aah!
[ All Yelling ]
So much for
not getting killed.
[ Yells ]
[ Grunting ]
Catch this.
[ Memnon Screaming ]
Oh.
- Hail to the king!
- Hail, hail!
I knew it from the start.
- Hail!
- Yeah!
- Mathayus!
[ Cheering Continues ]
Stay here with us, Balthazar.
There's much work to be done.
I have to look after
my own people.
You're a king now, Akkadian,
and a good one, I think.
Don't forget how you got here
or the people you came from.
My people will
live on through me.
Remember, there'll always
be a place for you here.
Live free.
Rule well.
Remember, Nubian eyes
will be watching you,
Scorpion King.
I see a time of great
peace and prosperity ahead.
How is it you see this?
Don't the legends say you'll
lose your powers if you--
Can you think of
a better way to keep a king
from taking advantage?
Well, neither could
my ancestors.
And how long will this
time of peace last?
Nothing lasts forever,
my king.
That is the destiny
of all kingdoms.
Then we'll make
our own destiny.
[ Applause, Cheering ]
[ Hard Rock ]
I've told you this
once before
You can't control me
If you try to take me down
you're gonna break
And I feel your every nothing
that you're doing for me
I'm picking you out of me
You run away
I stand alone
inside
You're always hiding behind
your so-called goddess
So what you don't think
that we can see your face
Resurrected back before
the final fallen
I'll never rest
until I can make my own way
I'm not afraid of fading
I stand alone
Feeling your sting
down inside me
I'm not dying for it
I stand alone
Everything
that I believe is fading
I stand alone
inside
And now it's my time
Now it's my time
It's my time to dream
Dream of the sky
Make me believe
that this place is invaded
By the poison in me
Help me decide
if my fire will burn out
Before you can breathe
Breathe into me
I stand alone
inside
Feeling your sting
down inside me
I'm not dying for it
I stand alone
Everything that I believe
is fading
I stand alone
inside
[ Hard Rock ]
I'm dizzy and weary
from the heat
As the sands
erase the hands of time
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
Do a job with you involved
This is a betrayal
I walk through the valley
and stab him to death
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
I see a face
I can't seem to forget
The war you wage
Whatever that happens
you pay
Something wrong in you
Comes alive in your hate
Lose yourself
in some kind of hell
Left you burnin'up
where you are now
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
You'll never ever get out
No
Somewhere along the way
Time changes everything
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
This race cannot be won
Some days it crawls
while other days it flies
It feeds on our flaws
It knows no compromise
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Ends ]