Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
this subtittle corrected by
http://rock_wtf@yahoo.com
Go get him, Petey!
Petey, what's up, pup?
Get it, Stormy, get it!
Don't worry about it!
All right, good catch!
I'll be back later, mom ...
Got anything, Porky?
- Not a bite, Buckwheet ...
I got something! I got something!
- Me too! A big fat one!
Yo Petey, come here!
Thanks Petey!
Hey Porky, look! a note.
What's it say?
We gotta learn to read ...
You ok...you ok...allright...goin' in...you ok...goin' in
What's the hi sign? Goin' in...
You okay ..
Wrong sign, Porky... Ok, goin' in...
You're ok, Elmer.
You little freak ...
Club "Men who hate female"
Gentlemen and gentlemen, I give you our president, Spanky!
How are ya? Good to see ya ...
You zip open ...
Welcome
All raise your right hand!
No, your
other right hand...
I ...
- "I ..."
Stymie ...
- "Stymie ..."
Member in good standing of the
He-man Woman Haters Club
- (all repeat)…"
do solemnly swear to be a heman
& hate women & not play with them or talk to them unless I have to.
and especially never fall in love, and if I do,
may I die slowly &
painfully & suffer for hours or until I scream bloody murder.
You thinkin' what I'm thinkin' Woim?
Ya, Butch ...
"What are we thinkin'?
How much fun it's gonna be funny to stomp those guys in the race!
Ready to take down the minutes, Uh-huh?
- Uh-huh ...
As you know, today I called an emergency meeting
for a very important reason.
But first, any good stories?
Buckwheat!
- Yes, this morning my sister left the toilet seat down..
Woman make man miserable!
- Froggy!
- Yeah, there's this girl moved in across the street
and she came over because she wanted to play ..
But don't worry, I solved it!
What did you do? (all repeat)
I whipped out my lizard!
...(Everyone cheers)
Good job, Frog-man!
Are you getting this, Uh-huh?
-Uh-huh!
All right men, let's talk about the pride of our club: "The Blur"!
"The Blur" is never been beaten,
since the beginning of time; five years!
This Sunday we defend our honor, our undefeated streak and our trophy!..(Everyone cheers)
First of all, this year's trophy will be presented
by none other than the famous Indy Race-car driver AJ Ferguson!
Wow! He's the best driver in the whole world!
Man! Can I have an Azuga! ..(all repeat)
...Heeei nice "azugas"!
And now, the reason for the emergency meeting. The choosing of the driver!
Our driver should be a man who's all He-man!
A He-man so manly, that if he fell off a building, it hit directly over a girl!
Gentlemen, this year our driver's name is ...
none other than my life-long chump, my best buddy in the whole wide world, the one & only ...
Alfalfa! ..(Everyone cheers)
- O-Tay!!!
Say, Where the heck is Alfalfa? ..(Everyone shrugs)
There he is, you guys, come on!
Quiet Petey!
Oh no! This is awful!
Buckwheat, hand me your fishing-pole ...
Oh, Darla, we are two hearts but with one beat!
.. two souls but wi...shoe..
And then how can you belong to that silly Woman-Haters Club?
You know, I am a woman ... sort of ...
Let me tell you something, Darla!!! I am not like those guys.
I am a sensitive male ...
I'm in the sharing, chering, feeling & healing. I'm in touch with my feminine side ..
How nice!
It's worse than I thought!
You know Alfalfa, the big talent show at the fair is coming up...
... and I was sort of wondering if may be you'd like to sing with me ..
You mean it? I would be honored!
I've got an idea! Let me take you on a picnic tomorrow...
Excuse me?
The way you feed my soul I can ..
.. feed your face!
Cool! And to prove you're proud of me...
...why don't we have our picnic in your club-house?
No!
Tomorrow ... tomorrow? Swimming Day! Sure!
Oh Alfalfa, you're a sweety-poo!
All-right, Woim! Ready for the test-run?
Ready, Butch!
Look! There goes our bumper!
All this work for nothing ...
Everything's working out perfectly! The guys are at the swimming pool...
and I'm at home with a toothache.
Nothing can possibly go wrong!
Hi, Butch!
-Shut up!
When is the last time we beat you up?
Let's see. Today is the 10th. 30 days has September...
April, June and November ...
It's not a leap year ... yesterday...
You're due!
-Look!
-I don't see nothing ...
-Come on, you doink!
Let's go, he can't run very fast.
Come back here, you ugly little squid!
These are for you!
Fify!... Good dog!
I hope Fify didn't sturdle you. He's so playful!
Excuse my frankness, but you're a lady rose slowly
weeds in a garden ...
You sophistication of a woman of 12 years!
My name is Waldo Alowischiss Dromston III!
I am Alfalfa!
Yeah, I'm sure you ...
And I'm Darla!
-We just moved into town.
My father bought the oil refinery.
That explains why you're so refined!
Yes, and so oily!
Take care, buddy!
I hope ravad you soon!
-You can arrange!
You appear to contest the talent that will be soon!
Yes, November 2 we will sing a duet ... together!
How reduntant!
-Thanks ...
I gotta go.
What stallion!
-It is smoother than a baby's bottom!
And it smells much better!
You're so nice that you brought me here.
A candlelit dinner! I am amazed!
Sorry ...
I seem to have some Vantu-banturi ..
-No problem!
grape juice?
-Yes, please!
For us!
It tastes like someone poured l'had a old boot!
In fact, from Tennessee!
It must have been a bad year ..
Maybe I should look in the bag!
What sandwich I brought you?
-That!
What would you do instead? What's yours and mine
and what's mine is ours!
You know exactly what to say to a girl your breath!
That's her breathtaking!
Porky certainly know how to make a sand (sand), Vishal!
But it was not sand ... it was the cat litter.
Do not worry, it's pretty fresh!
You did a sendvis delicious!
And you too!Very crunchy!
Maybe you should move on .. sweet!
It's a surprise!
s beautiful!
-He had to eat
six bags of snacks with surprise to find him!
It's the symbol of my undying affection for you!
I love diamonds!
I misjudged, Alfalfa!You not ashamed of the woman you love!
Darla, do you mind if you ask one big and wet?
What?
A kiss ..
Well ..
Oh God ...Disgusting ...
Alfalfa Thanks!
Alfalfa open this door!
In my haste to eat, I forgot you are a club tour!
This is a wall, here another, and here's closet!
You've lost your mind?
I do not want to go there?
Just as I thought, I'm ashamed of myself!
No, I'm proud of you, just do not want anyone to see you.
Up here! I left!
Well .. you guys back early ..
What is maseaua, buddy?
I think I maseaua out of mind ..
That explains why it behave foolishly!
We enter the club ..
"But it is a day so beautiful!
What was that noise?
Darla!
Fire foooooooooc!
You two go and call the fire!
-Yes sir!
Quick, who is number 911?
"I know where?
-Let 's go!
Look hose, open it when I say!
Oh ..
Spanky, here!
Run, run, faster!
Wow, that really was fast!
Piss off, mate!
Stymie, go ahead!
May I speak with 00:21:55:08 00:21:52:03 you as live!
tell him when he returns, guys!
Goodbye! Sorry!
Well, Darla, I thought it was you!
What do you walk with my father's Bentley?
And then eat one Belgian croissant.
We talk about talent contest ..Can compete together!
That sounds great!I had a hard ...
e Club Roast
-Our lives have ended!
And it's your fault!
standing Spanky comes the judge!
How do you plead?
-So: please, I beg you, have mercy!
grandmother pledare Mmm ..!
You want to make a statement?
I just never knew that .. if you like a girl
can get to it!
I disappointed friends, club, and the best friend!
Swietzer Alfalfa, I condemn the execution at dawn!
Your Honor, may I suggest that the defendant was punished
and that the punishment will be keeping the car racing day and night!
Court approves!
I mean I want to spend the night here?
Alone? Outside? But if they are wolves?
You're doing too!
Another term of the bail the accused will be
Or ...
And I will take care not to happen!
You are so beautiful
-I love you, Alfalfa!
I want to die in your arms?
-Want?
Well, not right now!I gotta go with Sir Spankus!
What is maseaua, boy?
But you're my toy boy!I will not let go!
You must choose between us!
Yes, you must choose.
Maybe this will help you decide!
Tell me you leave me no never!
-I'll never leave!
So here, traitor! Must finish with love
until it breaks our preietenia!
Choose or die!Choose or die!Choose or die!
Calm down buddy, we are!
I came to keep your ugly!
What are wet?
No worry, Alfalfa, and I had the same problem!
It's just a hole in the tent!
I think about Darla, right?
and I wonder if she thinks of me!
Why are guys such assholes?
I think of Alfalfa, right?
Oh no no no, no way!
You sure?
girls are like a bad song!Once you enter head
You can not remove them!
What must be so ... different?
girls understand each other!
Boys defend their honor!
care guys!
guys take what they deserve!
Boys Do not listen!
All they want is to talk!
They like to do the bosses!
No, not so!
giggling and gossip!
The winds beat and shoot!
Barbie dolls and bracelets!
snot and bugs!
skating!
Bungee-jumping!
synchronized swimming!
And just try to make place to stay!
Guys!
Girls!
And worst of all:
smell funny!
Afternoon Sir!
I and my friends we must build a new house.
You have to buy some planks.
In what way?
-Lemme!
I did Cheta.
wood Give us all money, please.
wrapped up in paper or plastic?
$ 450 for boards?
How to pull money?
I do not know.
You know what they say: wood does not grow on trees!
Guys, come here!
"loans on the spot!"
All in favor say "IOI io io io!"
Io io io io ioooi!
Thanks, good man!
six children, hardworking, honest and trustworthy .. loan refused?
Hello 00:29:39:17 00:29:43:25-good man
-Gentlemen, sit down!
Can we sit down?
-Are you kidding?
We can not stand the game, my good man!
What can I do for you?
Baban We want a loan!
-Of course!
You account with us?
-And yet, how!
.. What is your account number?
-A .. 7 ..
-7?7?
-Try 8!
-8?
I've heard enough!
If you were I would punish my children!
If we had your children, we punish yourself!
Clear the premises immediately!
You can not treat people like this, sir!
You are not people, are children.
Thanks! Cheers!
loves me, loves me not!Loves me, loves me not!
I love!
I do not know what you speak!
You must see it!
"But that's a violation of your security!
I know, I write a note and I'll take it!
Wait November hated women!We can not go love letters!
Love Letter?No!That will be one of hatred!
That sounds good!
"Dear Darla, I hate you to death! You make me puke
you trash between my fingers! "
("Can not live without you .. seriously .. not kidding, yours Romeo!")
What is it, guys?
, Buckwheat, where's my ticket?
ticket, ticket .. I know it's on here ..
I look ...
I know you I gave you!
What happens?
-Sorry ..
It's okay, I remember!
"Dear Darla hate you to death! You make me vomit,
you trash between my fingers! "Love, Alfalfa!
Yeah .. but was upset?
You have to go to her, and tell him what happened!
No way, buddy! 1. any home that is not the ballet recital
and 2 .. it was 2?
Spanky said you can not talk to her!
What?Can I talk to Darla when I want!Spanky's not my boss!
Hi buddy!
-Oh, no ...
Believe me .. it is for your own good!After a leave,
you feel like a new man!
But I like I like the old "I"!
Hello! I hope you enjoy the show!
You who are you?
I am with him, and we need to talk with Darla!
I'm afraid you can not .. is about to get on stage.
Get out the door ..
What sucks ..Eh .. go!
partner Wait ... wait here until leaving Darla!
Oh God ...
It will be like stealing candy from a baby!
Come!
There, a dollar!
Duckling, duck!
There's nothing better than a dollar and a miss.
Wait, stupid rate!
What's this?
Oh, no, no pickles!
We have a dollar, we have a dollar, hey hey hey!
I was bored!
Oh, thank you!
Oh, no, Butch and Woim! Put that in your pocket and let's go!
There they are!
Come!
"Costume Room"
Well, boys!
Bunaciunilor not you ever see two fools on here?
I mean, besides you?
I think they got there!
Thanks, doll!
Bye-bye ...
One, two, three!
What do you think?
You may not be here!
I will accompany to the door!
No, it hurts me hard!
Jupa it kills me ..
-And me ..
Hi!
-Good ...
You are fairies?
-No ..
You know, fairy ballerinas!
-Yes, of course!
What happened?
-A, I think is a frog in the throat!
I'm so excited!Sweating like a pig ..
I think it's because recital ..
Come ..Look, my handkerchief!
Oh, thank you!
That's fine .. you can keep it.
And I'm excited ..Waldo will be here ..
Darla's boyfriend's Waldo!
I love you?
No .. no .. not sure ..
But it is a boy who just would not want to know him better ..
And his name is Alfalfa? What physical!
You crazy?
And I saw a Alfalfa.He kidnapped the best years of life.
Same here.I like you tricked me and then left me like a hot potato.
Plus, you know what?
No, what?
I heard the girls clothes!
I do not miss it at all, but his voice ..!
When singing makes me melt like a lollipop for July 4th!
It's very romantic!
It was very nice, but we gotta go!
guys, it's time to put yourself in position!
It's time for the show!
Spanky, what?
Now, scenes from the Nutcracker!
Two, three ...
rid of it ...
Come here, hold my hand!
-Are you crazy?
To get out of here!
Well I finally caught that frog!
Yes, I should only worry about the warts!
You've destroyed the recital!Where e. ..?
Get out of there, lady!
I would not do this for you!
This is a professional ballet school!Come out and will not return!
"I'll distract them and you run ..
-Thanks, Spanky, you're a good friend!
I do thank ...
Well again filled donuts!Go with me?
We would expect Pavement .. but two dwarves, and to CAFTA!
Your loss, baby!
You have a hamburger to go after shake that?
It's him!
Come back, freak!
And do not go!
The situation may not worsen more!
And the clouds opened up and God said: "I hate you, Alfalfa!"
Nice tan! Some last words?
Yeah ... see you!
I'll drive yourself towards the exit!Thanks!
You better!
We were locked out!
Alfalfa, this is a part of you that I have ever seen!
Darla, there is an explanation for all this,
to invent that later!
You like pickled cucumbers?
Well, I guess!
"I love pickled cucumbers!
-My mother obliged to eat.
I am crazy about her.
I sell my cucumber with five money!
How about two?
-Welcome ..
I 2 cucumbers, 2 cucumbers have today, hey hey hey!
hard day?
-Do not ask me!
Hebrew Am I ready?
"We guys terminator
Crocodile girls throw! "
"club fucked us, we have no money,
But I came here to do! "
It looks good .. it will be easy!
Spanky, me and Porky, we have an idea!
keep it, you may need it when you grow up!
Well ...
"Entry - $ 3"
Hey, maybe this works!Go!
Ladies and gentlemen! Boys and girls!
Come if you dare to see the quirks of nature!
No science can not explain!
Come see this mutant, amazing and incredible!
It's 1 meter 20 and eating chicken!
Let people have to make some money!
May Give us money, a lion, anything!
We must build a new house!
Hurry up!
People, we need your money!
Want to join?
-At least give people in cars!
Please enter my mind!
I will not think Darla, I will not think Darla!
It Spanky is right!Maybe they should take my mind off love!
Oh, I do not have paper!
No, not that kind of paper!
Thanks Petey!
"stuff to do: air cushion, sendvisuri sand ..."
Betrayed by Spanky!
It's come as Darla hates me!
Come and you, Petey! Wait!
Well Spanky, so things had not really emerged as ..
Yes, even we have less money than when I arrived!
Hey, I thought the show had to be free!
Look how much money!
What happens?
I put that one ad-
and people began to pay us.
Buckwheat, Porky, some are geniuses!
-Thanks!
What would you take me, and I take a break?
Well!
McFarley Spanky!
-Ms. Crabtree!
I would expect that from a child of four years, but not from you!
Spanky, it is wrong to deceive people!
It's like when you copy the theme!
But me ..
What do we do with all that money?
We can not back to all these people!
Ms. Crabtree, I have a suggestion!
Interesting ..Intriguing ..
I like it!
Ms. Crabtree, you still have room for another number?
I think you can sneak.
-Thank you, Miss Crabtree!
You're welcome!
Guys, I persuaded Miss Crabtree to use money as a prize to the rally!
Imagine! In three days, the money will be ours!
It all went wrong, but not in any way we can lose the race!
- "The Blur" now belongs to Butch!
-And his Woim ..
Oh, it's even Falafel!
-Alfalfa!
Anyway .. I hope you have not lost my duet with Darla.
You call that duo?
-It was great!
And she did not sing bad either ..
What do Forgive me?
I warm voice.I'm about to win it back on Darla by song.
You do not understand?Darla you can not stand it!
Alfalfa, you follow!
I love Darla after her to sing!
can not resist my voice, she even told me!
Oh, dear ..
It's a love song about a loser ..
Long ago, I fell in love with a girl and because the best friends
that betrayed me, she came to believe that hate women!
But I love them!So I dedicate this cup to the girl I love most ...
Please do not call me names, please do not tell me the name ..
Darla!
I'll break this miserable pain!
I hate you, Alfalfa!
Hello, Mr. Balloon!
It was the most painful act of love that I've seen!
Do not talk to me, traitor! Judas!It's your fault!
My fault?
You burn the club!
And my fault?Really, you should guard car racing pampalaule!
Relax, mancatorule mud, I parked it right there!
was here ...
-So where is he?
Boy, you just mistakes!
So far, fearful parrot!I want to have a club that you give out!
You know, dirty and slippery ball?If would be a club, I would resign!
Why do not you go reconcile with him, Alfalfa?
You friends when you were a year.
-He started it!
And you should finish it.You are a team, as Bert and Ernie,
Superman and Clark Kent, Millie and vanilla.
At least go and talk to him, what cost?
I mean apart from my dignity and pride?
All I know is that you're not a friend of life, a life!
Spanky's home?
-Sorry, Alfalfa, not e.
I'm sorry, Spanky, Alfalfa is not here.
Naspa!
-Naspa!
I thought that you find here!
I'm sorry I made eating mud.And dirty and slippery ball.
I'm sorry I made fearful and pampalau parrot!
I'm sorry I said that spew crusty asshole!
But you told me so!
A. I think just a thought ..
fire Sorry!
-I'm sorry I ruined your picnic with Darla!
Maybe I am a little responsible for the fire ..
You know Spanky?I like girls .. and I think it will be worse when you stop growing.
I know you like girls, fly! The problem is that rules are rules.
But hatred for women is the most important thing?
I mean, can not be a club we like something?
Yes, but without a box, we can not have a club.
Hey, you have burned a box, not the club.
A club is made up of friends who are together in any situation.
I wish only that we can participate in the rally.But it's impossible!
Who said that?We can if we work together.
Go after materials, guys!
He, Petey!
screwdriver!
-Screwdriver!
Key!
-Key!
Yo, Oh, you there?
-Oh!
gauge!
Make us proud, buddy!
-Definitely!
Competitors, remember: Rally starts at 3:30.See you there.
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls!
Welcome to the 73 th rally!
guys got into the car and get ready!
careful not to break necks!
How to overcome that?
It looks like The Blur, with another layer of paint.
We go to the rally!A place to win one!
And you're a bad!
Well Dad, am I!I'll be so proud when I won the race!
Waldo, you be the best that money can buy it!
Thanks Dad!
Not bad.You are!
-Yes, you!
Yes, you!
-Your mom is ugly!
The streets are marked with arrows, and the race ends here.
All right!This is a place prize.About $ 500.
You say it's from an anonymous donor.
It was done!
Waldo, hurry .. I'm late!
-Be serious .. we make entry.
Relax, relax and leave everything to me!
I wonder where is AJFerguson.
I do not know, but I can not wait to meet him.
Well guys, put your seat belts!
Oh, oh, Mr. Johnson.We are glad you came.
last car is in position.
Oh, it's even Waldo.Not to get all the money in the world
replace work and ingenuity.
You have a rich fantasy.
-Thanks.
dickhead!
What do you do with that?
-Darla's handkerchief.
All Knights go to battle wearing the colors of their beloved.
I hear ...
Look, my mother is here!
-Upiii ...
He who would cross the finish line first will receive a gold trophy.
And also $ 500.
Gentlemen, start your engines!
1, 2, 3, Go!
I Burns, Woim!
You bastards have stolen our car!
Who found it, it's either.
Waldo, I think we need to return here!
girls have a sense of orientation.
-You 'gives me the pip.
Look out!
Excuse us!
little bastards!
10 points for old!
It's time to leave behind the losers and guys!
Start 01:07:08:14 01:07:13:11 atomic batteries!Speed turbines!
us escape!
-Hold on!
Spins
Active rockets!
You idiot!You put them backwards!
And two guys?Although I hate to do this.
spikes!
You could kill them!
-Forget that one dork who eat soap!
So you're responsible for balloon talent contest.
Stop!I do not want to finish the race like you!
Yes, baby! Now get out!
Forgive me Where are we?
Look, we're back in the race!
Hey, good shortcut!
Well, how they got here?
I do not worry .. this one to "help".
What is that?
I can see!
Where are we?Ajutoooor!
What happens?
I do not see!
My eyes, I see!
See your nice, bogatanule!
Thanks buddy!
Take the wheel!
-Are you crazy?
You must finish line!
Not without it!
You're crazy!
careful, you fall!
Remember me feet!
endure!Almost there!
The mustache!
You did Alfalfa!You won!
We did it!Everyone!
Gentlemen, say for Alfalfa a "Smoly-Oly!
Smoly-Oly!Smoly-Oly!Smoly-Oly!
It's not normal!We struggled to steal your car and still win!
Get ready, because now even gets hurt!
They are usually a pacifist, but if your are ready to make an exception!
Mud Pig ..
Let me!
You look good!
Hey, there he is the guy who risked his neck for us!
I must admit, has proven to work.Damn!
Yes hand, buddy.You're an honorable guy!
You know, we have a club of "men who hate women"
Alfalfa, trying to bring a member in May.What?
Not Waldo!
-You will hear from my lawyers!
So who's the guy who saved us butts?
Hi guys, how are you?
-A girl!
It outran them all.
It is my pleasure to hand over the trophy and money
Swietzer Alfalfa and Spanky's McFarley.
You're licking cow happy to see me?
Genre: silent and strong, right?
do not take it personally, lady, but my friend is very disappointed.
What happened pie?
Well, hopefully AJFerguson we handed over the trophy ...
Guys, today is your lucky day, for exactly what I am!
You're the best driver in the world!
-Thanks a lot!Nothing you have not been below!
What do you say it all?Give me one here!
Here!
I saw what you did with my Batistuta, Alfalfa!
my heart melted.
-And very romantic!
Thanks .. but I thought you hate me.
I hate you .. just sometimes do bad things.
As if, at the picnic.
-Can I explain it.
I've ruined your Picnic with alfalfa.You see, I thought trying to
steal my best friend.I thought trying to sabotage our club.
But I think I was wrong.Sorry!
My Alfalfanatorul!
My Darlooney Delicious!
Club Men Who Hate Women - Women are welcome!
You live around here?
Yeah ...
Do you like dolls?
-No ..
Wed yeah!
Nice!
Does ancestors have betrayed us?
I stopped generations of men who hate women?
Hey, Oh learned a new word!
In fact, I always had an extensive vocabulary, and do not forget
excellent grammar and syntax developed a superlative.
I just chose not to use them.
Well, I suppose that things must change at last.
What's my reply?
Let's start again!
I do not want.
Thanx for Watching!!!!!!!!
http://harry_axl@yahoo.com
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org