Subtitles by demonseye
I knew Harvey Dent.
I was his friend.
And it will be a very long time
before someone inspires us the way he did.
I believed in Harvey Dent.
Dr. Pavel... I'm CIA.
He wasn't alone.
- Uh... You don't get to bring friends.
- They are not my friends.
Don't worry, no charge for them.
- And why would I want them?
- They were trying to grab your prize.
They work for the mercenary.
The masked man.
- Bane?
- Aye.
Get 'em on board. I'll call it in.
The flight plan I just filed
with the agency...
lists me, my men, Dr. Pavel here...
but only one... of you!
First one to talk
gets to stay on my aircraft!
Who paid you to grab Dr. Pavel?
He didn't fly so good!
Who wants to try next?
Tell me about Bane!
Why does he wear the mask?
A lot o' loyalty for a hired gun!
Well, perhaps he's wonderin'
why someone would shoot a man...
before throwing him out of a plane.
At least you can talk.
- Who are you?
- It doesn't matter who we are.
What matters is our plan.
No one cared who I was
till I put on the mask.
If I pull that off, will you die?
- It would be extremely painful.
- You're a big guy.
For you.
- Was getting caught part of your plan?
- Of course.
Dr. Pavel refused our offer
in favor of yours.
- We had to find out what he told you...
- Nothing. I said nothing.
Well, congratulations!
You got yourself caught.
- Sir?
- Now what's the next step of your masterplan?
Crashing this plane...
with no survivors!
Mayday, Mayday!
Mayday...
What you doin' to me?
Let me out!
No!
No, no, no! No!
No! They expect one of us
in the wreckage, brother.
Have we started the fire?
Yes. Fhe fire rises.
Calm down, doctor.
Now is not the time for fear.
That comes later.
Harvey Dent Day
may not be our oldest public holiday,
but we're here tonight
because it's one of the most important.
Harvey Dent's uncompromising stand
against organized crime
had made Gotham a safer place than it was
at the time of his death, eight years ago.
This city has seen a historic turnaround.
No city is without crime, but this city is
without organized crime because the Dent Act
gave law enforcement
teeth in its fight against the mob.
Now,  people are talking about
repealing the Dent Act
and to them I say
"Not on my watch".
I wanna thank the Wayne Foundation
for hosting this event.
I'm told Mr. Wayne couldn't be here tonight.
I'm sure he's with us in spirit.
And now I'm gonna... give way
to an important voice....
You ever lay eyes on Wayne
at one of these things?
No one has. Not in years.
... people put their faith
in a murderous thug in a mask and a cape.
A thug who showed his true nature...
when he betrayed the trust
of this great man...
and murdered 'im in cold blood.
Sweetheart!
Not so fast with the chow.
- Shrimp balls?
- Jim Gordon...
Thank you.
... can tell you the truth about Harvey Dent.
He could... But I-I'll let 'im tell you himself.
Commissioner Gordon!
The truth?
I have...
written a speech...
telling the truth about Harvey Dent.
Maybe the time isn't right.
Maybe right now...
all you need to know is
that there are...
1,000 inmates in Blackgate Prison
as a direct result of the Dent Act.
These are violent criminals, essential... cogs
in the organized-crime machine.
Maybe, for now, all I should say
about the death of Harvey Dent is this...
it has not been for nothing.
- Did you see the guy who owns the house?
- No. You know, I heard
- he never leaves the east wing.
- You know, I heard he had an accident.
- Yeah, that he's disfigured. He has to wear a...
- Mr. Till!
Why are your people
using the main staircase?
And where's Mrs. Bolton?
Uh, she's at the bar, sir.
Can I help?
The east drawing room.
Unlock the door, put the tray on the table,
lock the door again. Nothing more.
I'm sorry, Miss Tate.
I tried, but he won't see you.
And you know,
you mustn't take it personally.
Everyone knows that Wayne's holed up
in there with 8-inch nails,
peeing into Mason jars...
It's very good of you
to let me on the ground.
Why are you wasting your time
trying to talk to a man
who threw away your investment
on some save-the-world vanity project?
He can't get your money back.
I can.
I could try explaining that
a save-the-world project, vain or not,
is worth investing in, Mr. Daggett.
But you understand only money
and the power you think it buys,
so, why waste my time... indeed?
Second shift reports in?
You should spend some more time
with the mayor.
Well, that's your department.
Anyone shown him the crime stats?
He goes by his gut and it continues to bother 'im,
no matter what the numbers.
Must be popular with his wife.
Not really.
She took the kids and left for Cleveland.
He'll have plenty o' time for visits.
The mayor's gonna dump 'im in the spring.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
- But he's a hero.
- A war hero. This is peacetime.
Oh! Sorry, sorry.
I'm so terribly sorry, Mr. Wayne.
It is Mr. Wayne, isn't it?
Although you don't have the long nails
or... the facial scars, sir.
That what they say about me?
It's just that no... no one ever sees you.
That's a beautiful necklace. Reminds me
of one that belonged to my mother.
It can't be the same one...
cause her pearls are in this safe...
the manufacturer clearly explained...
is uncrackable.
Oops.
Nobody told me it was uncrackable.
I'm afraid
I can't let you take those.
Look, you wouldn't beat up a woman
any more than I would beat up a cripple.
Of course... sometimes
exceptions have to be made.
Good night, Mr. Wayne.
Can I have a ride?
You read my mind.
Let's go.
- Miss Tate was asking to see you again.
- She's very persistent.
And quite lovely,
in case you were wondering.
- I wasn't.
- What are you doing?
Examining print dust.
We've been robbed.
And this is your idea
of, uh, sounding the alarm, is it?
She took the pearls,
tracking device and all.
- "She"?
- One o' the maids.
Perhaps you should stop lettin' em
in this side of the house.
Perhaps you should start learning
to make your own bed.
- Why were you dusting for prints?
- I wasn't.
She was.
Sir. Congressman Gilly's wife
has been calling in.
Apparently, the Congressman never made it home
after the Wayne Foundation event.
That's a job for the police?
When you and Dent cleaned up the streets,
you cleaned them good.
And pretty soon we'll be chasing down, uh,
overdue library books.
And yet, here you are,
like we're still at war.
- What's your name, son?
- Blake, sir.
You have something
you wanna ask me, officer Blake?
It's about that night. This night,
eight years ago. The night Dent died.
The last confirmed sighting of the Batman.
He murders those people,
takes down two SWAT teams,
breaks Dent's neck
and then just... vanishes?
I'm not hearing a question, son.
Don't you wanna know who he was?
I know exactly who he was.
He was the Batman.
Let's go see
about the Congressman's wife.
Master Wayne?
You haven't been down here
in a long time.
Trying to find out more about
our jewel thief. I ran her... prints.
Unless she's lost a lot o' weight...
she was wearing
someone else's fingerprints.
She's... good.
She may be, but we have a trace
on the necklace.
We do. So, I cross-referenced
the address she went back to...
with police data
on high-end B and E's, and, um....
Selina Kyle.
Databases are full of close-calls...
tips from fences...
She's good, but the ground
is shrinking beneath her feet.
We should send the police
before she fences the pearls.
She won't.
She likes them too much.
And they weren't
what she was after.
- What was she after?
- My fingerprints.
It was printer toner
mixed with graphite on the safe.
It gives a good pull
and it's untraceable.
Fascinating. You two should exchange
notes over coffee.
So, now you're tryin'
to set me up with a jewel thief...
At this point, I'd set you up with a chimpanzee,
if it brought you back to the world.
- There's nothing out there for me.
- And that's the problem.
You hung up your cape and your cowl,
but you didn't move on.
You never went to find a life.
- To find someone.
- Alfred...
- I did find someone.
- I know, and you lost them.
But that's all part of living, sir.
But you're not living, you're just waiting,
hoping for things to go bad again.
Remember when you left Gotham?
Before all this, before Batman?
You were gone seven years.
Seven years I waited,
hoping that you wouldn't come back.
Every year, I took a holiday.
I-I went to Florence.
There's this cafe
on the banks of the Arno.
Every fine evening I'd sit there
and order a Fernet Branca.
I had this fantasy...
that I would look across the tables...
and I'd see you there, with a... wife.
Maybe, uh, a couple o' kids.
You wouldn't say anything to me,
nor me to you.
But we'd both know...
that you'd made it.
That you were happy.
I never wanted you...
to come back to Gotham.
I always knew there was nothing here
for you, except pain... and tragedy.
And I wanted something
more for you than that.
I still do.
They wash up here
a couple o' times a month.
And more when it gets colder.
Homeless,
sheltering in the tunnels.
Uh, we pulled 'im from the basin,
but other than that we didn't touch 'im.
- What?
- Name's Jimmy. He's from St. Swithin's.
It's the boys' home
where I... coach some ball.
Jimmy hadn't been around for months.
- No? Why?
- Blake, you know why.
He aged out. We don't have the resources
to keep boys on after 16.
Yeah, look, I thought the Wayne Foundation
gave money for that.
Not for the past couple o' years.
- He has a brother here, doesn't he?
- Mark. I'll tell 'im.
I'd like to... if that's all right.
You know what he was doing
down there in the tunnels?
Lot of guys been goin' down the tunnels
when they age out.
Say you can live down there.
- Say there's work down there.
- Work?
What kinda work
are you gonna find in the sewers?
More than you can find up here,
I guess.
- So, you know about him?
- Course.
Do you think he's comin' back?
I don't know.
You brought a date?
I like having someone around
to open doors for me.
Right hand. No partials.
- Very nice.
- Mm-hm.
Not so fast, handsome.
You got somethin' for me?
Ah, yes.
I don't know what you're planning
to do with Mr. Wayne's prints,
but... I'm guessing
you'll need his thumb.
- You don't count so good, huh?
- I count fine.
In fact,
I'm counting to 10... right now.
Okay.
My friend's outside.
Just... hit "Send".
- This place is a little dead.
- It'll liven up in a minute. Trust me.
- Is everything okay?
- Great. Catch you later.
Hm.
It would have been a lot easier...
to just give me what we agreed.
We can't have loose ends.
And even in that dress,
no one's gonna miss you.
No.
But my friend over there?
Every cop in the city's missing him.
That's cute.
But... they're not gonna
be looking in a place like this.
I don't know.
You did just use his cell phone.
- Go!
Police! Get down now!
Help me! Help me!
Help me, please! Please, help me!
Keep some pressure on that,
sweetheart.
Call me?
- You okay, miss?
- He's bleeding. You gotta help 'im.
I got the Congressman.
Clear!
Manhole! Get this up!
Get the DWP down here!
You three, down with me.
You two, you go down,
cover the next exit!
What, they went down there?
- We're gonna go down there, right?
- That was a gas explosion, kid.
- Wasn't gas. It's a sewer.
- No one goes in there till we know what's down there.
We know what's down there, sir.
The police commissioner.
Someone get this hothead outta here?
And where's that DWP guy?
Why are you here?
Answer him.
I was asking you.
It's the police commissioner.
And you brought him down here?
- We didn't know what to do. We just thought...
- You panicked.
And your weakness has cost the lives
of three others.
No, he-he's alone.
Search him.
Then I will kill you.
- He's dead.
- So, show me his body.
The water runs to any one of the outflows.
We'll never find 'im.
- Follow him!
- Follow him?
You okay? You okay?
Hey! Hey! You awake?
I need to see Bruce Wayne.
I'm sorry, Mr. Wayne doesn't take
unscheduled calls.
Even from a police officer.
And if I go get a warrant for
the investigation of Harvey Dent's murder?
That still count as unscheduled?
What can I do for you, officer?
Commissioner Gordon's been shot.
He chased a gunman
down into the sewers.
When I pulled 'im out, he was babblin'
about an underground army.
A masked man called Bane.
Well, shouldn't you be telling
your superior officers about this?
They asked me if he saw
any giant alligators.
He needs you.
He needs the Batman.
- If Commissioner Gordon thinks...
- Oh, he doesn't know or care who you are.
But we've met before.
It was a long time ago.
I was a kid. Uh... St. Swithin's?
It used to be funded by
the Wayne Foundation. It's an orphanage.
My mom died when I was small. It was
a car accident, I don't really remember it.
But... my dad got shot a couple years later
over a gambling debt...
and I remember that one... just fine.
Not a lot o' people know
what it feels like, do they?
To be angry...
in your bones...
I mean, they understand.
Foster parents.
Everybody understands...
for a while.
And then they want the angry little kid
to do something he knows he can't do.
Move on.
So, after a while,
they stop understanding.
They send the angry kid
to a boys' home.
I figured it out too late.
You gotta learn to hide the anger.
Practice smiling in a mirror.
It's like puttin' on a mask.
So, you showed up this one day,
in a cool car.
Pretty girl on your arm.
We were so excited.
Bruce Wayne, billionaire orphan?
I mean, we used to make up stories
about you, man. Legends.
And, you know, with the other kids,
that's all it was, just stories, but....
Right when I saw you,
I knew who you really were.
I'd seen that look on your face before.
It's the same one I taught myself.
I don't know why you took the fall
for Dent's murder...
but I'm still a believer in the Batman...
even if you're not.
Why did you say that your boys' home
used to be funded by the Wayne Foundation?
Because the money stopped.
Might be time to get some fresh air.
Start payin' attention to the details.
Some o' those details
might need your help.
You check that name? Bane?
He's a mercenary.
No other known names.
Him and his men were behind
a coup in West Africa...
that secured mining operations
for our friend John Daggett.
- Now Daggett's brought 'em here.
- Or so it seems.
- I'll keep digging.
- Yeah.
Alfred! Why did the Wayne Foundation
stop funding boys' homes in the city?
The foundation is funded by
the profits of Wayne Enterprises.
There have to be some.
- Time to talk to Mr. Fox, I think.
- I'll get 'im on the phone.
No, no, no, no, no. Do we still have
any cars... around the place?
Yes. One or two.
I need an appointment
at the hospital for my leg.
- Which hospital?
- Whichever one Jim Gordon's in.
-  I have seen worse cartilage in knees.
- That's good.
No. That's because
there is no cartilage in your knee,
and not much of any use
in your elbows or your shoulders.
Between that and the scar tissue
on your kidneys,
the residual concussive damage
to your brain tissue
and the general scarred-over quality
of your body,
I cannot recommend
that you go heli-skiing, Mr. Wayne.
Right.
We were in this together...
then you were gone.
The Batman wasn't needed anymore.
- We won.
- Based on a lie.
And now there's evil
rising from where we tried to bury it.
- The Batman... has to come back.
- What if he doesn't exist anymore?
He must.
You took my goddamn wallet,
didn't you?
- You f... You took my wallet!
- No, I...
- Get out.
-  She took my... Ah!
- Now.
- Creep!
I don't know what he's so upset about.
There's only 60 bucks in here.
Probably the watch.
Who's that?
Another stiff can barely
climb out of his sports car.
- No, that's Bruce Wayne!
- Mr. Wayne, over here!
- I'm not sure if my assistant...
- Right through here, Mr. Wayne.
Thank you so much.
Bruce Wayne... at a charity ball.
Miss Tate, isn't it?
Even before you became a recluse,
you never came to these things.
The proceeds go to the big fat spread.
It's not about charity.
It's about feeding the ego
of... whichever society hag laid this on.
Actually,
this is my party, Mr. Wayne.
Oh.
And the proceeds will go where they should,
because I paid for the big fat spread myself.
That's very generous o' you.
You have to invest if you want
to restore balance to the world.
Take our clean-energy project.
Sometimes
the investment doesn't pay off.
- I'm sorry.
- You have a practised apathy, Mr. Wayne.
But a man who doesn't care about the world
doesn't spend half his fortune on a plan to save it.
And isn't so wounded when it fails...
that he goes into hiding.
Have a good evening, Mr. Wayne.
You mind if I cut in?
Thank you.
- You don't seem happy to see me.
- You were supposed to be a shut-in.
I felt like some fresh air.
Why didn't you call the police?
I have a powerful friend
who deals with things like this.
That's a brazen costume for a...
cat burglar.
Yeah?
Who are you pretending to be?
Bruce Wayne. Eccentric billionaire.
- Who's your date?
- His wife's in Ibiza.
She left her diamonds behind, though.
Worried they might get stolen.
It's pronounced "Ibiza".
You wouldn't want any o' these folks
realizing you're a crook, not a social climber.
You think I care what anyone
in this room thinks of me?
I doubt you care what anyone
in any room thinks of you.
Don't condescend, Mr. Wayne.
You don't know a thing about me.
Well, Selina Kyle... I know that you came here
from your walk-up in Old Town.
A modest place for a master jewel thief.
Which means that either
you're saving for retirement
or... you're in deep
with the wrong people.
You don't get to judge me
just because you were born
in the master bedroom of Wayne Manor.
- Actually, I was born in the Regency Room.
- I started out doing what I had to.
Once you've done what you had to,
they never let you do what you want to.
Start fresh.
Ugh. There's no fresh start
in today's world.
Any 12-year-old with a cell phone
could find out what you did.
Everything we do is collated
and quantified. Everything sticks.
Is that how you justify stealing?
I take what I need from those
who have more than enough.
I don't stand on the shoulders
of people with less.
Robin Hood?
I think I'd do more to help someone
than most of the people in this room. Than you.
You think maybe you're assuming
a little too much?
Maybe you're being unrealistic about
what's really in your pants other than your wallet.
Ouch.
You think all this can last?
There's a storm coming, Mr. Wayne.
You and your friends better batten down
the hatches, cause when it hits...
you're all gonna wonder how
you ever thought you could live so large
and leave so little for the rest of us.
You sound like
you're looking forward to it.
I'm adaptable.
Those pearls do look better on you
than they did in my safe.
But I still can't let you keep 'em.
You... You...
You scared her off!
Not likely.
Must have lost my ticket.
- Your wife said you were taking a cab home.
- My wife?!
Just you, sir?
Don't worry, Master Wayne.
Takes a little time to get back
in the swing of things.
Bruce Wayne... as I live and breathe.
What brings you out of cryo-sleep,
Mr. Wayne?
I see
you haven't lost your sense of humor.
Even if you have lost...
most o' my money.
Actually, you did that.
If you funnel
your entire R & D budget
into a fusion project
that you then mothball,
- your company is unlikely to thrive.
- What are my options?
Well, if you're unwilling
to turn on the machine...
- I can't. I can't, Lucius.
- Well, then sit tight.
Your majority keeps Daggett at bay,
while we figure out a future for
the energy program with Miranda Tate.
She has supported the project
all the way.
She's smart. And... quite lovely.
We all just want
what's best for you, Bruce.
Show her the machine.
- I'll think it over.
- Anything else?
Nope. Why?
These conversations used to end
with an unusual request.
I retired.
Mm-hm. Well, let me show you
some stuff anyway.
Just for old times' sake.
I figured you'd have
shut this place down.
Oh, it was always shut down...
officially.
All this new stuff.
After your father died, Wayne Enterprises
set up 14 different defense subsidiaries.
For years, I've been shuttering
and consolidating
all the different prototypes
under one roof.
- My roof.
- Why?
Keep them from falling
into the wrong hands.
Oh, now you're just showin' off.
Defense Department projects
for tight geometry urban pacification.
Rotors are configured to maneuver
between buildings without recirculation.
What's it called?
Oh, it has a long, uninteresting
Wayne Enterprises designation.
I just took to calling it...
the Bat.
And, yes, Mr. Wayne,
it does come in black.
Works fine...
except for the autopilot.
- Takes a better mind than mine to fix it.
- Better mind?
Well... I was trying to be modest.
A less busy mind.
Yours.
- Is it really painful?
- You're very welcome to try it, Alfred.
Happy watching. Thank you, sir.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
If you're seriously considering
going back out there,
you should hear the rumors
surrounding Bane.
I'm all ears.
There is a prison
in a more ancient part of the world.
A pit... where men are thrown
to suffer and die.
But sometimes
a man rises from the darkness.
Sometimes
the pit sends something back.
- Bane.
Born and raised in hell on earth.
- Born in a prison?
- No one knows why, or how he escaped.
But they do know that once he did...
he was trained by Ra's Al Ghul,
your mentor.
Bane was a member
of the League of Shadows...
And then...
he was excommunicated.
And any man who is too extreme
for Ra's Al Ghul is not to be trifled with.
I didn't realize I was known
for trifling with criminals.
That was then.
And you can strap up your leg
and put your mask back on,
but that doesn't make you
what you were.
If this man is everything that you say he is,
then the city needs me.
The city needs Bruce Wayne.
Your resources, your knowledge.
It doesn't need your body,
or your life.
That time's past.
You're afraid that, if I go back out there,
I'll fail.
No.
I'm afraid that you want to.
You can't short the stock because
Bruce Wayne goes to a party.
Wayne coming back is change.
Change is either good or bad. I vote bad.
- On what basis?
- I flipped a coin.
Rye. It says rye.
I said no rye, man.
Hey, rookie! Lose the helmet.
We need faces for camera.
Come on. Let's go scalping.
C'mon.
Everybody down, now!
Right now!
This is a stock exchange.
There's no money you can steal.
Really?
Then why are you people here?
Please, everybody, stay back!
Go down to the end of the block!
We have an emergency situation!
You gotta get in there!
This is a hostage situation.
No, no, no. This is a robbery. They have
direct access to the online trading desk.
I'm not riskin' my men
for your money.
Sir, we're gonna have to ask you
to move. We have a situation here.
It's not our money,
it's everybody's.
Really?
Mine's in my mattress.
You don't put these guys down,
that stuffing in your mattress
might be worth a whole helluva lot less.
Cut the fiber cable
and take out that cell tower.
- Thank you.
- That'll slow 'em down.
They cut the fiber.
Cell's working.
For now.
Get all these barriers up.
I want all of them up.
No one gets in or out
o' any of these streets.
- Where am I supposed to move it?
- Back it up.
All right,
just stay in your vehicle, okay?
How much longer
does the program need?
Eight minutes.
- Time to go mobile.
- Everybody, up!
You two, move!
Thank you.
Steady...
Steady!
I've got something.
Hold your fire,
they've got hostages.
Hold your fire!
Go, go!
Please! Just let me go!
Hey! Please! Hey!
Shoot the tires.
There's no shot.
Now, back off.
Back off, they've got hostages.
... P.D. are pursuing
the four suspects through downtown,
in response to a hostage situation.
Gotham P.D...
What's goin' on with the lights?
It can't be.
What the hell was that?
Oh, boy, you are in
for a show tonight, son.
Please! Help, help, help!
Sorry.
Put that thing away
before you hurt yourself. Get in!
Let's go. You, get in the car!
They've spotted the Batman.
Call everyone in. Every car patrol,
beat cop, off-duty too.
Pull 'em in now! I'm gonna do
what Jim Gordon never could.
- What's that?
- I'm gonna take down the Batman.
... are confirming four suspects
are carrying two hostages
that were kidnapped
from the Gotham Stock Exchange.
- Reports from the eyewitnesses...
- Scott, look at that spot dead center o' your screen.
- What do you see?
- I see that Bat... Batman.
Hard to believe, but the four suspects
are now being pursued
by what appears to be...
the Batman.
Well, what do you know?
Sir, what about the armed robbers?
Please! Just let me go! Please!
One bike's pulled off.
No hostage. Should we pursue?
Negative. Stay on the Batman.
- He's gettin' away.
- Who do you wanna catch, huh?
Some robber, or the son of a bitch
who killed Harvey Dent?
... the entire upper west hill,
Central Heights
and East Park Side areas.
Eight years... he has to pick tonight.
He's drawing the cops off Bane.
Please! Just let me go!
Please!
We lost 'im.
How could you lose 'im?
He's got a lot of firepower.
What, and you don't?!
He's headin' back downtown.
Then he's as dumb as he dresses.
Close it off, gentlemen.
Like a rat in a trap, gentlemen.
You might have
the wrong animal there, sir.
You sure it was 'im?
Bane says the Batman interfered,
but the task was accomplished.
What about the men they arrested?
He said, and I quote,
"They would die before talking".
Where does he find these guys?
Open the champagne.
- And can we get some girls in here?
- Careful what you wish for.
- Cat got your tongue?
- You dumb bitch.
Nobody ever accused me
of being dumb.
You're dumb...
for comin' here tonight.
I want what you owe me.
Want... doesn't get.
Nice outfit.
Those heels make it tough to walk?
I don't know.
Do they?
- So, where is it?
- Where is what?
The program. The "clean slate".
The ultimate tool for a master thief
with a record.
Hold it right there!
- Where is it?
- The clean slate?
Where you type in someone's name,
date of birth,
in a few minutes they're gone
from every database on earth?
- Sound a little too good to be true?
- You're lying!
- Rykin Data took it to prototype stage.
- That's why I bought 'em.
But they had nothing.
It was a gangland myth.
Stay back!
I'm not bluffing!
They know.
They just don't care.
You gotta be kidding me.
- No guns. No killing.
- Where's the fun in that?
My mother warned me about
getting into cars with strange men.
This isn't a car.
See you around.
You're welcome.
- I had it under control.
- Those weren't street thugs.
They were trained killers.
I saved your life.
In return, I need to know
what you did with Bruce Wayne's fingerprints.
Wayne wasn't kidding about
a powerful friend.
I sold his prints to Daggett...
for something
that doesn't even exist.
- I doubt many people get the better of you.
- Hey, when a girl's desperate....
- What's he gonna do with them?
- I don't know,
but Daggett seemed pretty interested
in that mess at the stock market.
Miss Kyle?
So, that's what that feels like.
I see from the television coverage
that you got your taste
for wanton destruction back.
I retrieved this.
Aren't the police supposed
to be investigating, then?
- They don't have the tools to analyze it.
- They would if you gave them to them.
One man's tool...
is another man's weapon.
In your mind, perhaps. But there aren't
many things you can't turn into a weapon.
Alfred, enough!
The police weren't gettin' it done.
Perhaps they might have...
if you hadn't made a sideshow of yourself.
- You thought I didn't have it in me.
- Now, you led a bloated police force on a merry chase
with a load of fancy new toys from Fox.
What about when
you come up against him? What then?
- I'll fight harder. I always have.
- Take a look. His speed... his ferocity, his training....
I see the power of belief.
I see... the League of Shadows resurgent.
- You said he was excommunicated.
- By Ra's Al Ghul.
Who leads them now?
Ra's Al Ghul was
the League of Shadows and I beat 'im.
Bane is just a mercenary.
We need to find out what he's up to.
Trades... of some kind. Coded.
And my fingerprint,
courtesy of Selina Kyle.
Get this to Fox.
He can crack the code and tell us...
what trades they were executing.
I'll get this to Mr. Fox,
but no more.
I've sewn you up, I've set your bones,
but I won't bury you.
I've buried enough members...
of the Wayne family.
- You'll leave me?
- You see only one end to your journey.
Leaving is all I have...
to make you understand.
You used to talk about finishing,
about a life beyond that awful cave.
Alfred, Rachel died... knowing
that we had decided to be together.
That was my life beyond the cave.
I can't just... move on.
She... She didn't. She couldn't.
What if she had?
She... I mean,
I can't change that.
What if before she died
she wrote a letter,
saying she chose
Harvey Dent over you?
And what if...
to spare you pain...
I burnt that letter?
How dare you use Rachel...
to try to stop me?
I am using the truth,
Master Wayne.
Maybe it's time we all stopped
trying to outsmart the truth
and let it have its day.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
You expect to destroy my world...
and then think that
we're gonna shake hands?
No, no.
- I know what this means.
- What does it mean?
It means your hatred.
And it also means losing someone
that I have cared for
since I first heard his cries... echo
through this house.
But it might also mean
saving your life.
And that... is more important.
Goodbye, Alfred.
Alfred?
- Answering your own door?
- Yeah.
Page three.
Seems you made a series of large
put options on the futures exchange...
verified by thumbprint.
Those options expired
at midnight last night.
Long-term, we may be able to prove fraud.
But for now, you're completely broke
and Wayne Enterprises is about
to fall into the hands of John Daggett.
The weapons. We can't let Daggett
get his hands on Applied Sciences.
No. Applied Sciences is all locked up
and off the books.
The energy project, however,
is a different story.
Miranda Tate.
We need to convince the board
to get behind her.
Let's show 'er the reactor.
We're meeting her there in... 35 minutes,
so you better get dressed.
You brought me out here
to show me this, Mr. Fox?
Bear with me, Miss Tate.
Please, keep hands and feet
inside the car at all times.
This is it, isn't it?
The reactor is beneath the river...
so it can be instantly flooded
in the event of a security breach.
Is Bruce Wayne really that paranoid?
I'm gonna plead the Fifth
on that one.
I thought you might like to see
what your investment built.
No fossil fuels.
Free clean energy for an entire city.
Three years ago,
a Russian scientist published a paper
on weaponized fusion reactions.
One week later, your reactor
started developing problems.
I think this machine works.
Miranda... If it were operational...
the danger to Gotham would be too great.
Would it make you feel better
to know that the Russian scientist
died in a plane crash
six months ago?
Someone will work out
what Dr. Pavel did.
Someone will figure out a way to...
make this power source... into a nuclear weapon.
I need you to take control
of Wayne Enterprises...
and this reactor.
- To do what with it?
- Nothing.
Until we can guarantee its safety.
- And if we can't?
- Decommission it. Flood it.
Destroy the world's best chance
for a sustainable future?
If the world's not ready, yes.
Bruce, if you want to save the world,
you have to start trusting it.
I'm trusting you.
Doesn't count.
You have no choice.
I could have flooded this chamber
at any time in the last three years.
I'm choosing to trust you.
Please.
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
This meeting will now come to order.
I'd like to point out that we have
a non-board member here,
which is highly irregular,
even if his family name is above the door.
Bruce Wayne's family
built this company.
And he himself has run it.
Into the ground, sir! Does anybody disagree?
And check the share price this morning.
Crazy gamblin' on futures
has not only cost Mr. Wayne his seat,
it's cost us all a lot of money.
And he has to go.
I'm afraid he has a point, Mr. Wayne.
Now, back to business.
- Hey, Mr. Wayne, over here!
- How's it feel to be one o' the people, Mr. Wayne?
Mr. Wayne,
they're towing your car!
I didn't know what to do,
they had paperwork, I didnt notice it.
Looks like you need a ride, huh?
Wayne, we'll give you a ride!
How the hell did Miranda Tate get
the inside track on the Wayne board?
I mean, she been meeting with 'im?
She been sleeping with 'im?
- Not that we know of.
- Ah, clearly, you don't know much of anything, do you?
- Where is Bane?
- Oh, we told him it was urgent.
- Oh, where is that masked...?
- Speak of the devil...
and he shall appear.
What... the hell is going on?
- The plan is proceeding as expected.
- Oh, really?
Do I look like I'm running
Wayne Enterprises right now?
Your hit on the stock exchange,
it didn't work, my friend.
And now you have my construction crews
going around the city at 24 hours a day.
How exactly is that supposed to help
my company absorb Wayne's?
- Leave us.
- No. You stay here.
I'm in charge.
Do you feel in charge?
- I've paid you a small fortune.
- And this gives you power over me?
What is this?
Your money and infrastructure
have been important...
till now.
- What are you?
- I'm Gotham's reckoning.
Here to end the borrowed time
you've all been living on.
You're... pure evil.
I'm necessary evil.
No. No, no, no!
When you started, why the mask?
- To protect the people closest to me.
- Yet you were a loner, right?
- You didn't have any family?
- There are always people you care about.
You just... don't realize how much
until they're gone.
The idea was to be a symbol.
Batman... could be anybody.
That was the point.
- Well, it's damn good to see 'im back.
- Not everybody agrees.
- They'll figure that out in the end.
- You got anything on Bane's whereabouts?
Yeah. I got 500 pages of tunnel records
and a flashlight.
I could use some help, actually.
You know what?
Drop me in Old Town.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I don't think so!
- That's the way this works!
- I don't think so! Hey!
- That is the way...
- He's not a mark.
And he doesn't have a cent
to his name, anyway.
Yeah, it's not much. But...
it's more than you've got right now.
Actually,
they're... letting me keep the house.
The rich don't even go broke
the same as the rest of us, huh?
My powerful... friend might hope
to change your mind about leaving.
- And how would he do that?
- By giving you what you want.
- It doesn't exist.
- He says it does.
- He wants to meet tonight.
- Why?
He needs to find Bane.
Says you'd know how.
- Tell him I'll think about it.
- Okay.
I like your place.
Mr. Wayne?
I'm sorry they took all your money.
No, you're not.
- Can we help you, officer?
- Uh, yeah.
John Daggett's body was just found
in a dumpster about an hour ago.
- Thought you might wanna know.
- Why?
Well,
his name's all over these permits
I just pulled to, uh,
map the tunnels under Gotham.
That's MTA maintenance, uh,
sewer construction, couple of other things.
Where did you get to
with the tunnel searches?
Remind me to tell detail
to keep hotheads out.
We've had teams down there.
It's a huge network.
Well, get more men. Work a grid.
I want 'im found.
Yeah, the, uh, masked man.
We're on it.
Lose the uniform.
You're working for me now.
And we could use some hotter heads
around here.
- Sir, that could also be a coincidence.
- You're a detective now, son.
You're not allowed to believe
in coincidence anymore.
Nobody's answering.
No.
I'm... on my own now.
Do you have keys?
Never needed them.
Hope you didn't like me
for my money.
Suffering builds character.
I'll take care of
your parents' legacy, Bruce.
Who's this?
Where's Alfred?
He left...
taking everything.
What's that?
My power's been shut off.
You're good at that.
When I was a child,
we had almost nothing.
But on the nights when we had a fire,
we felt very rich indeed.
I assumed your family was... wealthy.
Not always.
Not when I was young.
An old mistake.
I've made a few myself.
More than a few.
We could leave.
Tonight.
Take my plane...
go anywhere we wanted.
Someday, perhaps.
Not tonight.
Don't be shy.
Wayne says you can get me
the clean slate.
- That depends.
- On what?
On what you want it for.
I acquired it to keep it
out of the wrong hands.
Still don't trust me, huh?
- How can we change that?
- Start by taking me to Bane.
You asked.
From here,
Bane's men patrol the tunnels.
And they're not
your average brawlers.
Neither am I.
- He's behind you.
- Who?
Me.
What do you think you're...?
Just a little further.
I had to find a way to stop them
trying to kill me.
- You made a serious mistake.
- Not as serious as yours... I fear.
Bane.
Let's not stand on ceremony here...
Mr. Wayne.
Peace has cost you your strength.
Victory has defeated you.
Theatricality and deception,
powerful agents to the uninitiated.
But we are initiated,
aren't we, Bruce?
Members of the League of Shadows.
And you betrayed us.
"Us"? You were excommunicated...
by a gang of psychopaths.
I am the League of Shadows.
And I'm here to fulfill
Ra's Al Ghul's destiny.
You fight like a younger man.
Nothing held back.
Admirable... but mistaken.
Oh, you think darkness is your ally...
But you merely adopted the dark.
I was born in it.
Molded by it.
I didn't see the light
until I was already a man.
By then, it was nothing to me
but blinding!
The shadows betray you
because they belong to me!
I will show you where
I have made my home,
whilst preparing to bring justice.
Then, I will break you.
Your precious armory.
Gratefully accepted.
We will need it.
Ah, yes! I was wondering
what would break first.
Your spirit...
or your body.
Get me commissioner Gordon. I got a line
on the Congressman's kidnapping.
- Excuse me, miss.
- Uh, yes?
I'm gonna need to see your ticket
and identification, please.
Oh. Do you mind?
I showed your picture
to the Congressman. Guess what.
Don't tell me. Still in love?
Oh, head over heels.
Pressing charges, though.
You've made some mistakes... Miss Kyle.
- Girl's gotta eat.
- And you have an appetite.
Why would you run?
You can't hide from us with a record like this.
Maybe it's not you
I'm running from.
Who then? Bane?
What do you know about him?
That you should be
as afraid of him as I am.
We can offer you protection.
Okay.
When I spotted you, I was looking
for a friend of mine. Bruce Wayne.
Did they kill 'im?
I'm not sure.
Why didn't you just...
kill me?
You don't fear death,
you welcome it.
Your punishment must be more severe.
- Torture?
- Yes.
But not of your body.
Of your soul.
- Where am I?
- Home.
Where I learned
the truth about despair.
As will you.
There is a reason why
this prison is the worst hell on earth.
Hope.
Every man who has rotted here
over the centuries
has... looked up to the light
and imagined climbing to freedom.
So easy. So simple.
And like shipwrecked men turning
to seawater from uncontrollable thirst...
many have died trying.
I learned here that there can be
no true despair without hope.
So... as I terrorize Gotham,
I will feed its people hope
to poison their souls.
I will let them believe
that they can survive,
so that you can watch them
clambering over each other to stay in the sun.
You can watch me
torture an entire city.
And then, when you have truly understood
the depth of your failure...
we will fulfill Ra's Al Ghul's destiny.
We will destroy Gotham.
And then, when it is done...
and Gotham is...
ashes...
then you have my permission to die.
You're locking her up in here?
The Dent Act allows non-segregation
based on extraordinary need.
First time she broke out
of women's correctional, she was 16.
- Little closer, baby.
- Why, honey? You wanna hold my hand?
She's gonna be fine.
I still don't see the need of
a board meeting for the energy project.
Bruce got a lot of things right.
Keeping the board in the dark
was not one of them.
How good of you to join us.
Chair. President.
All I need now is
one more ordinary board member.
Mr. Fox,
would you like to nominate?
No.
I will volunteer.
Where you taking us?
You were right, commissioner.
Will you excuse us, please?
What happened?
Your masked man kidnapped
the Wayne Enterprises board.
He let most of 'em go,
but he took three of them into the sewers.
No more patrols.
No more hide and seek.
Get every available cop down there
and smoke 'im out!
- The mayor won't want panic.
- So, it's a training exercise?
I'm sorry
I didn't take you seriously.
Not you.
You're telling me the Batman's gone...
so you chase up the Daggett leads...
any way you can.
Yes, sir.
He asks how much
you would pay us to let you die.
I told 'im.
I told 'im you have nothing.
Do it for the pleasure.
They pay me more than that
to keep you alive.
He will try the climb.
Has anyone... ever made it?
Of course not.
He says there is one who did.
A child.
- A child born in this hell.
- Bane.
An old legend. Nothing more.
Don't.
Whatever it is they want you to see,
it's happening soon.
Fire in the hole!
Turn it on.
I only need one other board member.
There are eight others waiting.
I won't do it.
All right, stop.
Lucius, you'll kill this man,
and yourself...
and you'll barely slow them down.
Go on, then. Do your work.
Take them up to the surface.
People of their status
deserve to experience
the next era of western civilization.
I've been to half of Daggett's
cement plants and log locations
they poured for underground construction.
Anything strange about the pourings?
Honestly, commissioner...
I don't know anything about civil engineering.
But you know about patterns.
Keep lookin'.
It's done.
This is now...
a 4-megaton nuclear bomb.
Pull the core out of the reactor.
No, you cannot.
This is the only power source
capable of sustaining it.
If you move it,
the core will decay in a matter of months.
- Five, by my calculations.
- And then it will go off!
And for the sake of your children,
Dr. Pavel...
indeed I hope it does.
Hey. Hey!
That was you in front
of the stock exchange, wasn't it?
- When?
When half the city's cops were tryin'
to pull onto Castle Street
and your truck was shuttin' them out.
- Oh, yeah. You're the cop.
- Detective now.
And, uh, as a detective,
we're not allowed to believe in coincidence.
What were you doin' here?
What are you workin' on?
Commissioner, it's Blake.
I got two dead witnesses
and a lot of questions. Call me whenev...
Wait a minute. I'm looking at
four barrels of poly-isobutylene.
That looks like motor oil
right next to it.
Jesus! They're not makin' cement.
They're makin' explosives.
- Patch me in to Foley.
- Foley's overseeing the operation.
They're heading into a trap!
We're seeing literally thousands of police
heading into the sewers.
- Mr. Mayor? Lit-literally thousands of police.
- It's a training exercise, that's all.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I've got tickets
to watch our boys thrash Rapid City.
- Foley.
- It's a trap! Pull everyone out!
Bane has been pouring concrete
laced with explosives!
Where?
There's a ring around the tunnels!
They're gonna blow it and
trap the cops underground!
Pull 'em out. Pull 'em out! Now!
That's a lovely, lovely voice.
Let the games begin.
Everybody okay?
- Let's move! Move, move!
- Go, go!
Gotham...
take control.
Take control of your city.
- Foley.
- Jesus, Blake.
Every cop in the city's
down in those tunnels.
Not every cop.
Sir, are you okay? I'm a police officer.
I need your car right now.
Clear the corners, rookie.
Get my coat, son.
This....
This is the instrument
of your liberation.
Satellite shows a radiation spike.
Whatever it is... it's nuclear.
Identify yourself to the world.
Dr. Leonid Pavel... nuclear physicist.
Pavel was confirmed dead.
Plane crash on an agency
pull out of Uzbekistan, but....
It looks like it's him.
And what...? What is this?
It's a... fully primed neutron bomb...
with a blast radius of... six miles.
And who is capable of disarming
such a device?
Only me.
Only you.
Thank you, good doctor.
Now... this bomb is armed!
And this bomb is mobile!
And the identity of the triggerman
is a mystery.
For one of you... holds the detonator!
Now,
we come here not as conquerors...
but as liberators, to return control
of this city to the people.
And at the first sign of interference
from the outside world...
or from those people
attempting to flee...
this anonymous Gothamite...
this unsung hero... will trigger the bomb.
For now, martial law is in effect.
Return to your homes...
hold your families close...
and wait.
Tomorrow, you claim
what is rightfully yours.
Pull back the fighters.
Start
high-level reconnaissance flights.
Get the President on the line.
Tanks and planes cannot stop us
from detonating our device.
Send an emissary
to discuss terms of access
for supplies and communication.
How many of you are there, son?
You don't have enough men to stop
12 million people from leaving this island.
No. No, we don't.
But you do.
Now, why the hell would I try
to help you keep your hostages?
If one person crosses this bridge...
Gotham gets blown to hell.
The people of our greatest
city are resilient.
They have proven this before...
and they will prove it again.
We do not negotiate with terrorists...
but we do recognize realities.
As this situation develops...
one thing must be understood
above all others.
People of Gotham,
we have not abandoned you.
What does that mean?
It means we're on our own.
I have to get in front of a camera.
Oh, sir, they will kill you
the second you show your face.
Bane says he's giving Gotham back
to the people. They need to know I could lead.
- Bane's not gonna let that happen.
- Then he'll show his true colors.
And you'll be dead.
Behind you...
stands a symbol of oppression.
Blackgate Prison,
where a thousand men have languished
under the name of this man:
Harvey Dent.
Who has been held up to you
as the shining example of justice!
We're just gonna keep moving you
till we can get you in front of a camera.
You have been supplied
with a false idol to stop you
tearing down this corrupt city!
Yes! Yes!
Let me tell you the truth
about Harvey Dent.
From the words of Gotham's
police commissioner...
James Gordon...
"The Batman didn't murder Harvey Dent."
"He saved my boy,"
"then took the blame
for Harvey's appalling crimes"
"so that I could, to my shame,"
"build a lie around this fallen idol."
"I praised the madman
who tried to murder my own child."
"Well, I can no longer live with my lie."
"It is time to trust the people of Gotham
with the truth..."
"and it is time for me to resign."
And do you accept
this man's resignation?
the resignation of all of these liars?
Of all the corrupt?
Those men locked up
for eight years in Blackgate
and denied parole under the Dent Act,
it was based on a lie.
Gotham needed a hero.
Well, it needs it now more than ever.
You betrayed everything you stood for.
There's a point... far out there
when the structures fail you,
and when the rules
aren't weapons anymore,
they're... shackles,
letting the bad guy get ahead.
One day... you may face
such a moment of crisis.
And in that moment,
I hope you have a friend like I did...
to plunge their hands into the filth,
so that you can keep yours clean!
Your hands look plenty filthy to me,
commissioner.
We take Gotham from the corrupt!
The rich!
The oppressors of generations
who have kept you down
with myths of opportunity.
And we give it back to you...
the people.
Gotham is yours!
None shall interfere.
Do as you please.
But start by storming Blackgate
and freeing the oppressed!
Open it!
Step forward,
those who would serve...
for an army will be raised.
The powerful will be ripped
from their decadent nests...
and cast out into the cold world
that we know and endure.
Courts will be convened.
Spoils will be enjoyed!
Blood will be shed!
The police will survive...
as they learn to serve... true justice!
This great city...
it will endure.
Gotham will survive!
He says
you must first fix your back.
- How does he know?
- Ah, he was the prison doctor.
He's a morphine addict
who incurred the displeasure
of powerful people...
including your masked friend.
How?
Many years ago...
it was a time of plague.
Some of the other prisoners
attacked Bane.
The doctor's fumbling attempts
to repair the damage...
left him in perpetual agony.
- The mask holds the pain at bay.
- Bane... was the child you spoke of?
He was born here?
The legend is that there was a mercenary
who worked for a local warlord.
He fell in love with
the warlord's daughter.
They were married in secret.
When the warlord found out...
the mercenary was...
condemned to this pit.
But then he exiled him instead.
The mercenary understood that
it was the daughter who had secured his release.
But what he could not know...
was the true price of his freedom.
She took his place in the pit.
And she was with child,
I mean, the-the mercenary's child.
Innocence cannot flower underground.
It has to be stamped out.
One day... the doctor forgot
to lock the cell.
But the child had a friend...
a protector... who showed the others
that this innocence was their redemption.
It was to be prized.
The mother was not so lucky.
This is Bane's prison now.
He wouldn't want this story told.
There's a vertebra...
protruding from your back.
It has to be put back.
Stay like this until you stand.
Did you not think
I would return, Bruce? Hm?
I told you I was immortal.
I watched... I watched you die.
Oh, there are
many forms of immortality.
Once, I had a wife...
my great love.
- She was taken from me.
- You were the mercenary.
Bane is your child.
Your heir.
An heir to ensure
the League of Shadows fulfills its duty
to restore balance to civilization.
No.
You yourself fought the decadence
of Gotham for years...
with all your strength...
all your resources,
all your moral authority.
And the only victory
you could achieve was a lie.
Now you understand.
Gotham is beyond saving.
No.
- And must be allowed to die.
- No!
Yeah. Just lift your head.
Oh, that's good.
No. No!
- What's that?
- This was someone's home.
And now it's everyone's home.
There's a storm coming, remember?
This is what you wanted.
It's for the bus.
In case there's a chance to evacuate.
Any news?
Is the commissioner...?
The less you know, father.
How are the boys doin'?
Well, we've had more power on,
so they've got some TV.
It's good to see you.
Blake, you be careful out there.
They're huntin' down cops like dogs.
Why build yourself?
- I'm not meant to die in here.
- Here, there. What's the difference?
- I told you it could not be done.
- You told me a child did it.
But no ordinary child.
A child... born in hell.
Forged from suffering.
Hardened by pain.
Not a man from privilege.
We got boots on the ground, sir.
Just waiting on intel.
- You have ID?
- Course not.
- Well, how can we trust you?
- We don't have any choice.
Commissioner Gordon.
Captain Jones, Special Forces.
Captain.
Glad to have you here.
It's our job, sir.
Now, uh, how many of you are there?
Well, there's dozens.
I-I'd rather not say exactly.
But the men trapped underground
number almost 3,000.
- What kinda condition are they in?
- They're getting food an' water.
- Can we break 'em out?
- Yes, sir.
Take out the mercenaries
guarding the outflow south of Ackerman Park....
blow the rubble, we can make a hole
big enough for 10 at a time.
I-I'm in contact with my partner
who's down there.
They're just waitin' for the day.
Men who haven't seen daylight
in 3 months?
Police officers who haven't seen daylight
in 3 months.
What about the bomb?
Satellite can't pick up any... radiation hot spots.
They keep it on a truck.
It must have a lead-lined roof.
- They-they move it constantly.
-  Good. So you know the truck?
Well, it's one of three.
We've been tracking it.
Decoy.
You don't really think
he's comin' back, do you?
Doesn't matter what I think.
Actually, it does. You should put your faith
in something a little more real.
- The-the routes don't vary much.
- Okay. What about the triggerman?
No leads. It's-it's a bluff. Bane wouldn't
give control of that bomb to someone else.
We can't take that chance. Until we have
the triggerman, we just track the device.
And meanwhile, Gotham lives
under a warlord, like some failed state?
Dial it back, officer.
This situation is unprecedented.
We can't do anything to risk millions of lives.
You gonna tell 'im?
You gonna tell 'im what's really goin' on?
Captain, the... situation is
more complicated than you think.
There's... someone you need to meet.
Came upstairs
lookin' for a vantage point.
Found the people
who run the corporation livin' out there.
- What corporation?
- Wayne Enterprises. You good?
Mr. Fox, would you like to brief
the captain?
Uh, Miss Tate's
fully aware of the situation.
And as CEO of Wayne Enterprises,
I have to take responsibility for it.
- Why?
- We built it.
You built the bomb?
It was built as a fusion reactor.
First of its kind.
Bane turned the core into a bomb
and removed it from the reactor.
- Here's the important part.
- As the device's fuel cells deteriorate,
it becomes increasingly unstable,
to the point of detonation.
This bomb is a time bomb.
And it will go off in 23 days,
regardless of Bane's revolution
or what we, or the outside world,
choose to do.
So, your appease men plan
might not be as practical as you thought.
- Could you disarm it?
- I could reconnect it to the reactor. Stabilize it.
- Let's move away from this location and call it in.
- Right. Let's go.
No, no, we'll take it from here.
You stay and look after these folks.
Someone sold us out.
Go, go, go!
- I'll die before I talk.
- I'm on your schedule, captain.
There were people living upstairs.
Round them up for judgment...
and hang them...
where the world could see.
Police have cordoned off the entire
Central Heights and East Park Side areas...
as well as Merchant and South Shoreline
Boulevards in an attempt...
He says the leap to freedom
is not about strength.
My body makes the jump.
Survival is the spirit. The soul.
My soul is as ready to escape
as my body.
- Fear... is why you fail.
- No, I'm not afraid.
I'm angry.
Bruce.
Why do we fall?
You do not fear death.
You think this makes you strong.
It makes you weak.
Why?
How can you move
faster than possible...
fight longer than possible...
without the most powerful impulse
of the spirit?
The fear of death.
I do fear death.
I fear dying in here...
while my city burns.
There's no one there to save it.
Then make the climb.
How?
As the child did...
Without the rope.
Then fear will find you again.
Ah, supplies for your journey?
Oh, that's... that's wonderful. That's....
- What does that mean?
- Rise.
No.
No, there's been a mistake!
Take... take me to Bane!
I wanna see Bane!
Order!
This is a mistake!
Where is Bane?
There's been no mistake,
Mr. Stryver.
You are... Philip Stryver,
executive vice-president
of... Daggett Industries...
who, for years, has been living
off the blood and sweat
- of people less powerful than him.
- Call Bane. I'm... I am one of you.
Bane has no authority here.
This is merely a sentencing hearing.
Now, the choice is yours.
Exile... or death!
Order!
Exi... exile.
Sold.
To the man in the cold sweat.
You follow the thick ice.
You try to swim...
you're dead in minutes.
Has anyone made it?
Where the hell are they?
It's not like we have a lot o' time here.
- How long?
- Bomb goes off tomorrow.
- We have about 18 hours to do something.
- To do what?
To mark the truck.
Get a GPS on it
so we can start to figure out
how to bring it down.
That's it?
Foley.
- Where's Foley, damn it?
- You shouldn't be out on the streets.
- Jim, he's not here.
- You let your wife come to the door?
- When the city's under occupation?
- Wait in the kitchen, honey.
What did you do?
Bury your uniform in the backyard?
You saw what they did
to those Special Forces.
Have you forgotten all the years
we were out on patrol?
When every gangbanger wanted to plant one
as soon as our backs were turned?
That was different and you know it.
These guys run the city.
The government's done a deal with 'em.
Bane's got their balls in a vice.
That's not a deal.
You move on Bane...
the triggerman is gonna hit the button.
You think he's given control of that bomb
to one of the people?
You think
this is part of some revolution?
There's one man with his finger
on the button. That's Bane.
Look... We've all gotta keep
our heads down till they can fix this.
- If you still had a family here...
- This only gets fixed from inside the city!
Look, Peter.
I'm not asking you to... walk down Grand in
your dress blues, but something has to be done.
- Sorry, Jim. I gotta...
- ... Keep your head down?
What good's that gonna do tomorrow
when that thing blows?
You don't know
that's gonna happen.
I hear you're looking for men,
commissioner.
How about me instead?
Miss Tate, I, uh,
I can't ask you to do that.
Please.
You little punk!
What'd you take?
I... nothing!
I didn't take anything!
You steal from us...
you little bastard?
Now... You boys know
you can't come into my neighborhood
without asking politely.
Never steal anything from someone
you can't outrun, kid.
You're pretty generous...
for a thief.
- I thought they killed you.
- Not yet.
- If you're expecting an apology...
- It wouldn't suit you.
I need your help.
- And why would I help you?
- For this. Clean slate.
You'd trust me with that?
After what I did to you?
I'll admit,
I was a little let down.
But I still think there's more to you.
In fact, I think that for you...
this isn't just a tool.
It's an escape route.
You wanna disappear. Start fresh.
- I can't even get off this island.
- I can give you a way off...
once you get me to Lucius Fox.
I need you to find out where
they're holding him and take me in.
Why do you need Fox?
- To save the city.
- Who says it needs saving?
Maybe I like it this way.
Maybe you do...
but tomorrow that bomb's going off.
Got your powerful friend
on the case?
I'm trying...
but I need Fox.
As it approaches...
flip the switch.
The needle hits 200, you give me the signal,
I'll mark the truck. Okay?
Heads up, heads up.
- I got it.
- Mercenaries on your 6.
Stand still! Keep your hands
where we can see them!
Commissioner Gordon,
you are under arrest.
- On whose authority?
- The people of Gotham.
No lawyer? No witnesses?
What sort o' due process is this?
Your guilt has been determined,
this is merely a sentencing hearing.
Now, what will it be?
Death... or... exile?
Crane, if you think we're going out
onto that ice willingly...
you have another thing coming.
Death, then.
- Looks that way.
- Very well.
Death...
by exile.
Bring her to me.
Hey! Hey, hey, we're goin' now.
Blake says they're ready!
Get your gear on! Hey!
Find this one a spot,
got a big day tomorrow.
We all do.
It's not every day you bag Bruce Wayne.
- Bruce.
- You okay?
Picked a hell of a time
to go on vacation, Mr. Wayne.
How long until that core ignites?
- That bomb goes off in 12 hours.
- Unless we can reconnect it to the reactor.
- Can you get Miranda out of here?
- Not tonight. I'm sorry.
- Do what's necessary.
- Tonight I need you.
- What for?
- To get me back in the game.
Sorry to spoil things, boys,
but... Bane wants these guys to 'imself.
- I won't forget about you, Miranda.
- I know.
- I like your girlfriend, Mr. Wayne.
- He should be so lucky.
Any move I make on Bane or the bomb...
triggerman sets it off.
Well, they won't use radio or cell.
Too much interference.
Infrared doesn't have the range.
It'll have to be a microburst.
Longwave.
- Could you block it?
- Yes.
But I'll need
the EMP cannon guidance mount from the Bat.
Remember where you parked?
She fly okay?
Yeah. Even without the autopilot,
thanks.
Autopilot?
That's what you're there for.
Okay. It's clear. Come on, quick.
One at a time.
Wait, wait!
Ross!
Ross?
- Lock it up.
- No, keep down.
Get down!
Who are you?
Light it up.
- Dad, check it out.
- Honey! Come take a look.
Impossible.
Keep 'er close.
He'll come for her.
Where's Miranda Tate?
Bane took her.
He's holed up at city hall,
surrounded by his army.
This blocks the remote detonator signal
to the bomb.
Get it onto it before sunrise.
They might hit the button when it starts.
- When what starts?
- War.
You missed a spot.
If you working alone...
wear a mask.
I'm not afraid to be seen
standing up to these guys.
Count to five, then throw.
Hey, no offense, but you got
somethin' bigger in that belt?
- What now?
- All-out assault on Bane.
But you need to get people
across the bridge.
- Why?
- In case we fail.
Lead an exodus.
Save as many lives as you can.
- You don't need me here?
- You've given me an army.
Now go.
- Hey, thanks.
- Don't thank me yet.
Well, I might not get a chance later.
You shouldn't have.
The midtown tunnel's
blocked by debris...
but the cannons have enough firepower
to make a path for people.
Wait until the fighting begins.
You're gonna wage a war
to save your stuck-up girlfriend?
To start it, throttle...
- I got it.
- We have 45 minutes to save this city.
No, I've got 45 minutes
to get clear of the blast radius
cause you don't stand a chance
against these guys.
- With your help, I might.
- I'll open that tunnel, then I'm gone.
There's more to you than that.
Sorry to keep letting you down.
Come with me.
Save yourself.
You don't owe these people any more.
You've given them everything.
Not everything.
Not yet.
Disperse!
Disperse or be fired upon!
There's only one police
in this town.
Open fire.
- Here it comes!
- Get ready!
So, you came back
to die with your city.
No. I came back to stop you.
Now!
That's impossible.
Cut over to Fifth!
Off you go.
Get on the bus. Go ahead.
You, come with me. You too.
Hey, you, you, and you,
come 'ere, come 'ere.
Everyone else
get on the bus, okay?
You guys... you go knock on doors
and spread the word, okay?
The bomb is gonna go off. You get out by
the South Street tunnel or over the bridge.
You go, you do two blocks,
you get back to the bus. All right?
Go, go! Go!
Is he back?
Keep your eyes open.
Go, go.
Cover the doors!
Where's your trigger?!
Where is it?!
You'd never give it
to an ordinary citizen!
Where is it?
Where's your trigger?!
Where is it?! Where is it?!
Tell me where the trigger is.
Then... you have my permission to die.
I broke you.
How have you come back?
You think you're the only one...
who could learn the strength to escape?
Where's the trigger?
But I never escaped.
But the child...
The child of Ra's Al Ghul
made the climb.
But he's not the child of Ra's Al Ghul.
I am.
And though I'm not ordinary...
I'm a citizen.
Miranda?
Why?
Talia.
My mother named me Talia,
before she was killed...
the way I would have been killed,
if not for my protector...
Bane.
Goodbye.
I climbed out of the pit.
I found my father...
and brought him back
to exact terrible vengeance.
But by that time...
the prisoners and doctor had done
their work to my friend.
My protector.
The League took us in.
Trained us.
But my father could not accept Bane.
He saw only a monster.
His very existence was a reminder
of the hell he'd left his wife to die in.
He excommunicated Bane
from the League of Shadows.
His only crime...
was that he loved me.
I could not forgive my father.
Until you murdered him.
He was trying... to kill...
millions of innocent people.
Innocent is a strong word
to throw around Gotham, Bruce.
I honor my father
by finishing his work.
Vengeance against the man who killed him
is simply a reward for my patience.
You see...
it's the slow knife,
the knife that takes its time.
The knife...
that waits...
years without forgetting...
then slips quietly between the bones.
That's the knife...
that cuts deepest.
Please.
Maybe... your knife...
- was too slow.
- The truck is under attack.
Gordon. You gave him
a way to block my signal.
No matter.
He's bought Gotham 11 minutes.
Come on!
This way!
Stay there!
What are you doin'?
Blake, MCU!
I'm gettin' these boys to safety!
You're gettin' us all killed!
If anyone crosses this bridge,
they'll blow the city!
It's gonna blow anyway!
We need to open this bridge, now!
Detective, if you take one step forward,
we will shoot you!
If you take two steps forward,
we will blow the bridge!
Okay, go back by the bus and wait for me,
all right? Just go back and wait.
Prepare a convoy. We must secure
the bomb until it detonates.
Don't kill him.
I want him to feel the heat.
Feel the fire of
12 million souls you failed.
Goodbye, my friend.
Goodbye.
Keep movin' forward!
Flank them at the stairs!
Shoot them.
Shoot them all.
We both know
that I have to kill you now.
You'll just have
to imagine the fire.
About the whole no-guns thing...
I'm not sure I feel
as strongly about it as you do.
Pull up.
Stay level.
We have to force that convoy east
to the entrance to the reactor.
I need you on the ground.
I'll be in the air. Go!
The situation has changed.
Your orders are out o' date.
I'm a cop, like you,
and I'm walkin' out there.
Please, do not shoot me!
Shoot at his feet.
Nothing like a little air superiority.
Detective! Please, stop!
Please, detective! Stop!
Stop walking!
Blow it! Do it!
You have to get that bomb here.
And you've got 10 minutes.
They're pushing us
to the entrance of the reactor.
They're gonna
try to reconnect the core.
You idiots! You sons of bitches!
You're killin' us!
Yeah, follow your orders!
All right, boys. Get in a circle.
Bow your heads.
It's on my side.
Hey, father, let's get everyone
back on the bus, okay? Go, go, go, go!
- Back on the bus!
- There's nowhere to go.
On the bus!
You've got to turn the truck east!
Stay straight!
Gimme a hand!
We can get a cable on it!
Fox showed me
how to override the reactor.
Oh, dear.
Including... the emergency flood.
There's... no way...
this bomb...
will be stopped.
What are you doing?
Protection from the blast.
We're gonna be all right!
- Tunnel time. Go!
- It's an atom bomb!
You think they need
to hear that right now?
You wanna let 'em die
without hope? C'mon!
Prepare yourselves.
My father's... work...
is done.
- What are you doing?
- I can get it out over the bay!
Set it to fly out over the water,
then eject?
No autopilot.
You could've gone anywhere,
been anything. But you came back here.
So did you.
I guess we're both suckers.
- I never cared who you were.
- And you were right.
Shouldn't the people know
the hero who saved them?
A hero can be anyone.
Even a man doing simple things,
as simple... and reassuring
as putting a coat around
a young boy's shoulders...
to let 'im know
the world hadn't ended.
Bruce Wayne?
C'mon! There you go!
Okay, you too. Come on, father.
Hey, heads down!
This is it!
- No.
- No! That's Batman!
That's detonation!
It's out over the bay!
It's clear of the city!
"I see a beautiful city..."
"and a brilliant people..."
"rising from this abyss."
"I see the lives... for which
I lay down my life..."
"peaceful..."
"useful, prosperous and happy."
"I see that I hold
a sanctuary in their hearts..."
"and in the hearts
of their descendants..."
"generations hence."
"It is a far, far better thing
that I do..."
"than I have ever done."
"It is a far, far better rest
that I go to..."
"than I have ever known."
I'm so sorry.
I failed you.
You trusted me...
and I failed you.
Can I change your mind...
about quitting the force?
You know what you said about...
structures becomin' shackles?
You were right,
and I can't take it. The... injustice.
I mean... no one's ever gonna know
who saved an entire city.
They know.
It was the Batman.
Mr. Wayne's will was not amended
to reflect his more modest estate.
Nonetheless, there are considerable
assets to... dispose of.
The contents of the house are to be sold
to settle the estate's accounts
and the remainder is left in its entirety
to Alfred J. Pennyworth.
The house and grounds are left
to the city of Gotham on condition
that they never be demolished,
altered or otherwise interfered with...
and that they shall be used for
one purpose, and one purpose only:
the housing and care of the city's
at-risk and orphaned children.
My clerk can help anyone with
the smaller correspondences and instructions.
Blake, John.
- Nothing here.
- Uh, um, try my legal name.
You should use your full name.
I like that name....
-  ... Robin.
- Thanks.
Why do we even worry about
the stabilization software?
This entire autopilot system's
completely obsolete.
Please... I just need to know
what I could've done to fix it.
But... Mr. Fox, i-it's already been fixed.
Software patch. Six months ago.
Check the ID on the patch.
Bruce Wayne.
- Any news on the missing item?
- Not yet.
They better leave
no stone unturned.
We can't leave a string of pearls
on the manifest as lost.