Now, children,
are you sitting comfortably?
Then I'll begin.
This story started many
thousands of years ago,
but it was all over
in just seven days.
All that long, long time ago,
none of the things we can see now...
the sun, the moon, the stars,
the earth, the animals and plants...
not a single one existed.
Only God existed, and so
only He could have created them.
And He did.
Mr. Simpson. What a character!
I wonder whatever became of him?
Oh, I imagine he's dead,
like all the rest.
Ah, those were the days.
Mr. Tuttle, your hair!
Yes?
Good morning, ma'am.
We've come about the...
Oh yes, of course.
Come in.
I wasn't expecting you so soon.
You are?
I'm Bertha Mills, ma'am.
And this is Edmund Tuttle.
Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
You must be the gardener.
Ay, that's right, the gardener.
And this young lady's called Lydia.
Have you had
much experience in service?
Oh, don't let that angel face fool
you. She's older than she looks.
Can you iron?
What's the matter?
Has the cat got your tongue?
Ah, she can't talk, ma'am.
The poor little mite's a mute.
Oh, but she's a good little
worker, I can promise you that.
All right. All right.
The other girl I had spoke
too much anyway. Follow me.
You and the girl will sleep in the
attic room at the top of the stairs.
- And you, Mr...
- Tuttle, ma'am.
Ah, Tuttle. Ah, you can sleep
in the shed, around the back.
As you can see,
the housework has been rather
neglected since the servants
disappeared, almost a week ago.
You mean they just vanished?
Into thin air.
No notice, nothing.
They didn't even collect their
wages. They... they just left us.
What a strange thing to do!
There are times when this house
is not exactly an ideal home.
Hence my advertisement in the paper
for honest, hardworking people.
There's nobody more honest or
hardworking that us, eh, Mr. Tuttle?
Oh, ay, we're very honest.
And uhm... very hardworking.
The kitchen.
I have breakfast at eight,
the children at nine,
lunch will be served at one
and dinner at half past seven.
And the master, ma'am?
The master went off to war
a year and a half ago.
I've had no news
since the war ended.
Which of you does the cooking?
I'm so sorry, ma'am.
You all notice what I'm doing?
In this house,
no door must be opened without
the previous one being closed first.
It is vital
that you remember this.
It is not as easy as it may seem.
There are fifteen different keys
for all of the fifty doors,
depending on the area of the house.
Mrs. Mills, from tomorrow I'll
be leaving a set in your charge.
Yes, ma'am.
The music room.
That old piano was already here
when we moved in. Please do not
let the children
thump away on it.
It sets off my migraine.
Silence is something that
we prize very highly in this house.
That is why
you will not find a telephone,
a radio or anything else
that makes a racket.
Ah... we don't have
electricity either.
The Germans kept cutting it off, so
we just learned to live without it.
- Let's continue.
- Ma'am,
there's really no need to show us
around the whole house, we...
Yes!
Yes, there is.
Because here, most of the time,
you can hardly see your way.
It's often difficult
to make out if there is a table,
a chair, a door, a sideboard...
or one of my children
playing hide-and-seek.
What do you mean, ma'am?
Perhaps I should introduce
you to the children.
Mr. Tuttle, see to the garden now.
You'll find tools in the shed.
Yes, ma'am.
You two can start
closing the curtains.
All of them.
Come.
I'll wake them.
You wait here.
Whatever you do,
don't open the curtains.
Wakey-wakey.
Now, come on,
eyes closed, hands together.
Blessed be, at light of day,
Jesus, to whom now I pray.
Blessed be the Virgin pure
whom I greet with faith so sure.
Jesus, Mary, Spotless Rose,
keep us till this day doth close.
- They're still half-asleep.
- What sweet little
children!
Well? What do you say?
How do you do?
How do you, children?
My name's Mrs. Mills,
but you can call me Bertha
if you like.
What are your names?
Anne.
Nicholas.
Anne and Nicholas.
What pretty names!
Are you going
to be our new nanny?
Yes, my dears,
I'm your new nanny.
It's time for their breakfast.
Lydia, go
to the kitchen
and close every shutter.
The doctors were never
able to find a cure.
For what?
Their condition.
The children have
a very serious allergy to light.
They are photosensitive and they
must never be exposed to any light
much stronger than this.
Otherwise in minutes they would
break out in sores and blisters
and begin to suffocate.
It would eventually be fatal.
Good heavens!
- I don't like this toast.
- Oh, why not?
It tastes funny.
I liked it better before.
Well, that's because,
before, somebody else made it.
When are they coming back?
They're not coming back, child.
Just like daddy.
Daddy is coming back, though.
Mrs. Mills, our father is fighting
in a war in France, you know.
It's the World War.
I know, but he's in France.
That's enough, chatterboxes.
Finish up your breakfasts.
Are you going to leave us too?
Of course not.
Why should I leave you?
The others said they wouldn't
but they did. And then it happened.
Be quiet!
What do you mean, Anne?
What happened?
Mummy went...
mad.
- Nothing happened.
- Yes, it did.
No, it didn't!
Yes, it did!
Be quiet!
What's going on?
I want to see those plates
empty in less than a minute.
Is that clear?
Mrs. Mills, would you
come outside a moment?
I'd like a word with you.
Yes, ma'am.
The postman usually
comes every Wednesday,
but I've just checked the letter box
and this week he hasn't.
I'm afraid I don't follow, ma'am.
This letter should have been
collected and delivered
to the newspaper five days ago.
It's an advertisement for servants.
Since it was never
published, would you mind
explaining to me what you're
doing here?
Now I understand.
Well, ma'am, that's exactly what
I was going to say to you when you
opened the door to us.
The truth is that
we just come by
on the off-chance.
A big house like this is always in
need of someone who knows the ropes.
You mean you've served
in a house like this one before?
This may come as a surprise
to you, ma'am, but...
We, in fact,
used to work here.
Here?
Oh, now, it was a few years ago.
And if you don't mind
my saying so, ma'am,
they were the best years
of my life.
That's why we come by,
because this house
means a lot to us.
Perhaps I'd best show you
our references, ma'am.
No, no, no.
Don't bother, there's no need.
Ah, so you say
you know the house well?
Like the back of my hand.
Well, that is always assuming that
the walls haven't sprouted legs
and moved in the meantime.
The only thing that
moves here is the light.
But it changes everything.
It's rather difficult,
to say the least.
One might almost say...
unbearable.
The only way of enduring it
is by keeping a cool head.
Oh, yes, ma'am.
I don't like fantasies.
Strange ideas,
do you know what I mean?
I think so, ma'am.
My children sometimes
have strange ideas.
But you mustn't pay
any attention to them.
Children will be children.
Yes, of course, ma'am.
All right,
you can stay.
Thank you very much, ma'am.
It did happen.
"The Roman governor tried to make
them change their minds afterwards."
"To make them change
their minds," full stop.
- "Afterwards...
- "Afterwards."
"...he ordered them to be beaten.
But Justus and Pastor,
far from being afraid,
rejoiced and showed
themselves willing
to die for Christ.
When he
saw this, the Roman governor
was filled with rage
and ordered their heads
to be cut off."
What do you find so amusing?
Well...
- Well, what?
- Those children
were really stupid.
- Why?
- Because
they said they only believed in
Jesus and then got killed for it.
And what would you
- have done, deny Christ?
- Well, yes.
Inside, I would have
believed in him.
But I wouldn't have told
the Romans that.
Is that what
you think too, Nicholas?
I see.
So you both would have lied
to the point of denying Christ.
Oh, you'd have saved your heads
being chopped off by the Romans...
- But what would have happened after?
- When?
In the next life,
the one that's waiting
for us after
we die?
Where would you have gone?
Where, Nicholas?
- To the children's Limbo.
- What is
- the children's Limbo, Anne?
- One of the four Hells.
Which are?
Me, me, me, me,
me, me!
No, no, no,
let him answer. Which are?
There's the hell
where the damned go,
then there's Purgatory...
- Yes?
- And the Bosom of Abraham,
where the Just go,
and Limbo, where children go.
At the centre of the Earth.
Where it's very, very hot.
That's where children go who tell
lies, but not just for a few days.
Oh, no.
No, they're damned.
Forever.
Think about it.
Try to imagine
the end of eternity.
Close your eyes.
Close your eyes
and try to imagine it.
Forever.
Pain.
I'm getting dizzy.
Now do you understand
why Justus and Pastor
told the truth?
Right.
Ah, open your readers
at Lesson 6.
- Can we go and play?
- You most certainly cannot.
First, you're going to read the
lesson and then learn it by heart.
All of it?
Anne, any more protests and there'll
be no playing for you at all today.
In fact...
I think you can study
in separate rooms.
- No, no, no!
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
- We get scared if we're separated.
- You get scared?
As if you weren't used
to this house by now.
What if we see a ghost?
Has your sister been
telling you one of her stories?
I haven't told him anything.
Well, if you see a ghost,
you say hello and you continue
on studying. Anne, come
with me to the music room.
Why me?
Because I say so!
Now come on,
take your book.
Nicholas, I want to see that lesson
learned in less than an hour.
- Mummy...
- What?
Give me a kiss.
"Give me a kiss,
give me a kiss..."
Anne, wait for me outside.
You know I can't.
Over there.
Mrs. Mills,
close all the curtains. My daughter
is going to cross the living room.
Yes, ma'am.
All right, Anne.
Darling...
mummy can't be
with you all the time.
You must learn
to be on your own.
Where's your rosary?
Whenever you feel afraid,
I want you to squeeze it with all
your might and say an Our Father,
and then your fear will go away.
- It won't.
- Yes, yes, it will. Honestly.
Don't you see that when
you do this, the Lord is with you?
There's no reason to be afraid.
"The house and the family.
We all live in
a house with our family.
The family is usually
made up of parents,
children and their grandparents.
We must be obedient..."
"...and kind towards
the other members of our family
and we must never argue or fight
with our brothers and sisters..."
Do you have any children?
No.
Mr. Tuttle
and the girl, Lydia,
are all I've got.
- And I'm all they've got.
- Was she born like that?
Beg your pardon, ma'am?
The girl.
Was she born a mute?
No.
You know, I think I've finished
here, ma'am. If you'll excuse me,
I think I'll go and see
if Mr. Tuttle needs a hand.
Nicholas!
Nicholas, I'm coming!
- Nicholas?
- What's the matter?
- Why were you crying?
- I wasn't crying. I was reading.
But I just heard you...
Anne!
Anne?
I haven't learned it yet, mummy.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- Why were you crying?
- I wasn't crying.
But I just heard you
a moment ago.
There's no need
to feel ashamed, darling.
I don't.
If I'd been crying, I'd tell you.
Oh, really?
So I imagined it, did I?
No. It was that boy.
What boy?
Victor.
Who's Victor?
The boy who was
here a moment ago.
I told him to let me study,
but he wouldn't stop crying.
I think he's a spoilt brat.
He said we had
to leave the house.
Did he now?
Why was he crying?
Because he doesn't like
this house but he has to live here.
His father's a pianist and...
- Oh, his father's a pianist, is he?
- Yes.
And I've told him he's not allowed
to touch the piano. He isn't, is he?
So, you've spoken
to his father as well?
No, only with Victor. His father
is with the others in the hall.
But I've just come from the hall,
and there's no one there.
They must have gone upstairs.
They're viewing the house.
That'll do, Anne.
That's enough.
Now, why were you crying?
- It was Victor!
- So where is he now?
- He went out through there.
- Would you
mind telling me how a boy can get in
and out of this room if it's locked?
I thought I made
myself quite clear!
No door is to be opened without the
previous one being closed first.
Is that so hard to understand?
This house is like a ship.
The light must be contained
as if it were water,
by opening and closing the doors.
- My children's lives are at stake!
- But, ma'am, I...
Do not argue with me!
Be quiet!
Now which was the last
of you to enter that room?
Lydia?
She hasn't got a key,
I already told you that.
- Well, that leaves you, then.
- But I was
in the hall the whole time.
And then I went out into the garden.
You saw me with your own eyes.
I hope you are not
suggesting that it was me!
Do you think that I would
overlook such a thing
and endanger the life
of my own daughter?
You're not supposed
to read at the table.
Oh, really?
Well, who is going to tell mummy?
You?
Or perhaps... you?
Did you really see
a boy?
Yes, he's called Victor.
- Is he a ghost?
- Don't be stupid.
Ghosts aren't like that.
What are they like?
I've told you a thousand times.
They go about in white sheets
- and carry chains.
- How do you know?
Because I've seen them.
They come out at night.
Fibber! Where?
- You're stupid.
- Not half as much as you.
Well, I don't believe
you saw that boy.
Believe what you like. You'll soon
be begging us to play with you.
Nicholas. Nicholas.
What?
Look.
Why have you
opened the curtains?
- It wasn't me.
- Who was it then?
It was Victor.
He's been doing it all night.
- Liar. I'm going to tell mummy.
- So I'm a liar, am I?
Yes.
Victor, come out behind that curtain
so my stupid brother can see you.
- Leave me alone!
- You don't want to see him now, eh?
You're a cowardly custard,
cowardly custard.
Cowardly, cowardly custard.
Well, I'll just have
to do it myself, then.
That's enough, Victor!
Nicholas, tell him to leave
the curtains alone. He won't listen
- to me.
- Get off my bed, both of you!
- This is our bed.
- No, it's mine.
Anne, please stop
putting on that voice.
You be quiet,
cowardly custard.
Listen, if you don't stop, I'll call
my mother and she'll kick you out.
- You don't know my mother!
- And you don't know my parents.
Anne, I'm going
to tell mummy about you.
Don't be stupid!
Can't you see it's not me?
Victor, touch his cheek
so he knows you're real.
Help! Mummy! Help!
Help! Mummy!
What is it?
- Help!
- What is it?
What? What is it?
She was frightening me
and I told her
to be quiet and...
I'm fed up! Do you hear me?
I am fed up with you!
I didn't do anything!
"Therefore the Lord God sent him
forth from the garden of Eden,
to till the ground
from whence he was taken.
So he drove out the man and placed
at the east of the garden Cherubims
and a flaming sword
which turned every way,
to keep the way
of the tree of life."
There! I've finished.
Very good.
Now you can ask
the Virgin for forgiveness.
What!
That's not what we agreed.
We didn't agree
anything, young lady.
Today you're being punished
and you'll do as I say.
You can't make me ask
the Virgin for forgiveness.
How dare you?
Mummy, I won't ask for forgiveness
for something I didn't do.
You told your brother that there
was someone else in the room!
- There was!
- You're lying!
I am not!
Anne.
Anne, do you remember
the story about Justus and Pastor?
Children who don't tell the truth
end up in Limbo.
That's what you say.
But I read that Limbo is only for
children who haven't been baptised.
And I have.
"And Abraham took the wood
of the burnt offering
and laid it upon Isaac, his son.
And he took the fire in his hand
and the knife, and they went,
both of them together,
and Isaac spake unto Abraham,
his father, and said,
'My father.'And he said,
'Here I am, my son.'And he..."
Did you look in on Nicholas?
Yes, ma'am.
The little angel is fast asleep.
What about Anne?
Is she still on the stairs?
Oh yes, ma'am.
I'd prefer to have her
where I can see her,
but I can't embroider
in such poor light.
How long is this punishment
going to go on? It's been
three days now.
It's up to her.
She's got to learn to swallow
her pride and ask for forgiveness.
Anyway, it's about time
she started to read the Bible.
Well, the priest will be
very pleased to hear that, ma'am.
If he ever deigns
to pay us another visit.
He knows perfectly well
that the children can't go out.
Oh, he told me
yesterday he'd be by,
as soon as possible.
I'm beginning to feel
totally cut off from the world.
And this fog
doesn't exactly help.
It's never lasted
this long before.
Well, that's true, ma'am.
Even the seagulls
have gone quiet.
Anne!
Anne, I can't hear you!
"And Isaac spake unto Abraham,
his father, and said, 'My father."'
Incidentally, Mrs. Mills, I've had
to put up with Lydia running around
above my head. She's been
hurtling backwards and forwards
as if there were three of her.
Would you kindly tell her
it's not necessary
to kick up quite such a rumpus
just to do a little cleaning?
- I couldn't bear another migraine.
- I'll tell her, ma'am.
Thank you.
Now she's really
gone too far. Lydia!
Lydia!
"...on the mount of the Lord
shall be seen. And the angel..."
What's going on up there?
Nothing, mummy, I'm just
reading like you told me.
- Did you hear it as well?
- Hear what?
"And the angel of the Lord
called unto Abraham out of heaven
the second time, and said,
'By myself have
I sworn, saith the Lord..."'
What was that?
I don't know.
Anne, tell me
who's making that noise.
I can't tell you, mummy.
You tell me!
I told you there was someone
in the room and you punished me.
Now I don't know what to say!
Anne, I want the truth!
Tell me if there is
someone upstairs.
There. In that junk room.
Mummy, you're letting
the light in!
She's here.
Mummy, she says she's here.
She's watching us.
She's watching us!
Where did they go?
They just came past here.
Didn't you see them?
Which way did they go?
Over there, over there,
oh, and down there, as well.
They're everywhere.
They say this house is theirs.
And they say they're going
to take the curtains down as well.
- Ma'am, stay calm, please.
- I will not stay clam!
For 5 whole years
during the occupation,
I managed to avoid a single Nazi
ever stepping foot in this house!
And now there is someone here,
under my nose, opening and closing
- the doors.
- Ma'am, this is a very old house.
Why, the floorboards squeak,
and the plumbing clanks, and...
There were voices, I'm telling you.
A boy and 2 women talking together.
Mummy, look!
I did it yesterday.
This is the father,
this is the mother,
this is Victor
and this is the old woman.
What do these numbers stand for?
That's the number
of times I've seen them.
I see the old woman the most.
Oh, God in Heaven!
Mrs. Mills,
go and call Mr. Tuttle. Tell him
we have to search the whole house,
immediately,
before it gets dark.
Yes, ma'am.
There now.
- Mummy...
- Yes, darling. It's all right,
nothing's going to happen
to you while mummy's here.
Look, mummy,
she really scares me.
It's as if she's
not looking at you,
but she can see you.
And she's always around,
saying, "Come with meee..."
- Oh, Anne, don't lie to me.
- Honestly, mummy.
And she asks me things.
Victor told me she's a witch.
What does she ask you?
Things.
Her breath smells.
We have to open
all the curtains.
I don't want any dark corners
- where someone could hide.
- Yes, ma'am.
You both search the right side
and I'll take the left.
Then we'll search upstairs.
Perhaps they are ghosts who lived
in this house before and who...
Don't be stupid.
I've already told you
ghosts go about in white sheets
and carry chains and go...
Anne...
why do you
make up such stories?
I don't.
I read them in books.
Well, you shouldn't believe
everything you read in books.
That's what our mother says.
She says that all this stuff
about ghosts is rubbish.
And then she expects us
to believe everything written
- in the Bible.
- And you don't believe it?
I believe some things.
But, for example, I don't believe
God made the world in seven days.
And I don't believe that Noah got
all those animals into one boat.
Or the Holy Spirit
- is a dove.
- No, I don't believe that either.
- Doves are anything but holy.
- They pooh on our windows.
Have you mentioned
any of this to your mother?
Ma'am?
Yes?
They've searched everywhere, ma'am.
There's no one.
I see.
Mrs. Mills?
Yes, ma'am?
Do you have any idea
what this might be?
- Oh, it's a photograph album, ma'am.
- No, but look, they're all asleep.
Look.
They're not asleep, ma'am.
They're dead.
It's a book of the dead.
In the last century, I believe they
used to take photographs of the dead
in the hope that their souls
would go on living
through the portraits.
There are even group portraits.
And children!
It's macabre.
How could these people
be so superstitious?
Grief over the death
of a loved one
can lead people
to do the strangest things.
Get rid of it.
I don't want it in the house.
Yes, ma'am.
Mrs. Mills, it's cold. Why don't you
come and sit by the fire?
Thank you very much, ma'am.
So, tell me about
when you worked here before.
Did you have to look
after children then as well?
No, I was in charge
of organising the housework.
Were there many servants?
Oh, about fifteen.
Though in the end
there were just
the three of us left.
Why?
My employers moved to London.
They came here less
and less, it being so
out of the way like...
And so gradually
the house just became empty.
Everybody ends up
leaving this damned island.
My family left in the summer
of 1940, just before the invasion.
That was the last
I ever heard of them.
I don't blame them.
Actually, we left too.
Although, you know sometimes
when you leave a place,
it's like it's there with you
all the time.
I always felt like
I never left this house.
Why did you leave?
Oh, on account of the tuberculosis.
The whole area was evacuated.
Was that when Lydia went dumb?
Yes, I think so.
Though you know,
my memory is a bit rusty
- these days, ma'am.
- What happened to her?
Well, suddenly,
one day, she just
stopped talking.
Well, there must
have been a reason.
People don't just stop talking.
These things are always
the result of some sort of trauma.
Something must
have happened to her.
- Did your employers treat her well?
- Oh, they were always
very kind to us.
They treated us just like family.
You know, ma'am,
I think I will go to bed.
I'll never be able
to get up in the morning.
Off you go.
I'm going to stay
here a while longer.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm sorry I was
so hard on you.
Can you forgive me?
Anne.
- Mummy.
- What?
When's daddy coming home?
When the war's over.
Why did he go to war?
I mean,
nobody's done
anything bad to us.
Daddy went...
Daddy went because
he's very brave,
and because he wasn't prepared to
let the Germans tell him what to do.
Why?
Charles...
Where are you?
Mrs. Mills!
What's the matter, ma'am?
The key to the music room!
Give it to me! Quickly!
- What's happening?
- Come on!
Oh, my God!
I checked that room myself.
It was empty.
Now take these tablets, ma'am.
They'll do you good.
And yet I felt as if
there was someone else there.
And it wasn't human.
There is something in this house.
Something diabolic.
Ma'am...
Something which is not...
not at rest.
I know you don't believe it.
You don't believe it, do you?
No, I don't blame you.
I... I used to not
believe those things.
I do believe it, ma'am.
I've always believed
in those things.
Oh, they're not easy
to explain, but they do happen.
We've all heard
stories of the beyond,
now and then.
And I think that, sometimes,
the world...
of the dead gets
mixed up with the world
of the living.
But it's impossible! The Lord would
never allow such an aberration!
The living and the dead, they will
only meet at the end of eternity.
- It says so in the Bible.
- Ma'am,
there isn't always
an answer for everything.
Where are you off to, ma'am?
I'm going to the village
to pay Father Legrand a visit.
If he won't come here, then I shall
go to him. And I'll bring him back.
- Wait till the weather improves.
- I've waited long enough.
Ma'am, the priest told me...
I don't care what he told you!
I want him to tell me personally.
He must come today.
- What are you going to tell him?
- We've searched every room in there.
And now I need them
to be blessed.
Ma'am, please wait.
It's still very early.
- Mr. Tuttle.
- Good morning, ma'am.
I need you to search
the whole garden for gravestones.
- Gravestones?
- When my husband bought this house,
we were told there was
a little cemetery.
I think it was somewhere
over there, amongst the trees.
- I've not seen anything.
- Check carefully.
- They could be overgrown.
- Yes, ma'am.
I need to know if there was
a family buried here.
And if they had
a little boy, Victor.
Now she thinks
the house is haunted.
Do you think it's safe
to let her go?
Oh, don't worry.
The fog won't let her get very far.
Oh, yes, the fog.
The fog... of course.
And when do you think we should
bring all this out into the open?
All in good time,
Mr. Tuttle, all in good time.
Speaking of which...
Charles!
Grace.
You're here!
They... they said
there was no hope.
They said I should
give you up for dead.
They say a lot of things.
Thank you, thank you, God.
Thank you.
Every night
I've prayed for this.
Begging God to bring you back.
To bring the children
their father back. You're here.
But where have you been
all this time?
Out there,
looking for my home.
You're so different.
So different.
Sometimes I bleed.
Ma'am.
Mrs. Mills,
this is my husband.
I'm very pleased
to meet you, sir.
He's very weak.
I want you to prepare
a hot bath and some clean clothes.
And something to eat.
Right away, ma'am.
How are my little ones?
Daddy!
Why did you take so long?
Hello, Nicholas.
I told you, you see!
I told you he'd come back.
- Have you both been well behaved?
- We've been very good.
- Have you been good to your mother?
- Very good.
We study every day
for our First Communion.
Daddy, did you kill anyone?
Here he comes.
Darling, we've prepared
lunch for you.
Are you coming down
or would you prefer that?
When's daddy coming down?
Be patient, Anne.
Daddy is...
not well.
He said he'd seen
lots of dead men.
Mummy, when people die
in the war, where do they go?
Ah, what a question.
It depends.
On what?
Well...
on whether they fought on the side
of the "goodies" or the "baddies."
Your father, for example, fought for
England, on the "goodies"' side.
How do you know who
the "goodies" and the "baddies" are?
That's enough questions. Eat
your food. You'll never go to war.
We'll never go anywhere.
You're not missing out on anything.
You're much better at home with
mummy and daddy, who love you.
And the intruders.
There are no intruders here.
But you said that there were.
No, I said that
there are no intruders here.
And I don't want to hear
another word on the subject.
- But you said...
- No, that is enough!
- Can I say something?
- No!
- Why not?
- Because... because you can't!
Anne, stop breathing like that.
You heard me. Stop it!
Stop breathing!
Right, you go to your room!
Go to your room!
There's no dessert for you today.
Oh, no crying now.
No crying.
Oh, stop that... Here.
Oh, look what an awful face
you've got when you cry.
- I don't care!
- There, there.
You listen to me.
I've seen them too.
You have?
Yes.
Then why don't you tell my mother?
Then maybe she'll believe me.
There are things
your mother doesn't want to hear.
She only believes in what
she was taught.
But don't worry.
Sooner or later,
she'll see them.
And then everything
- will be different.
- How?
Oh, you'll see.
There are going to be some
big surprises.
There are going to be...
changes.
Changes?
Now she is behaving as if
nothing had happened.
What about her daughter?
She's not so stubborn. The children
will be easier to convince.
No, it's the mother who is going
to cause us problems.
Do you think her husband
suspects anything?
No, I don't think
he even knows where he is.
Look what a pretty daughter
I've got.
Mummy made this veil
especially for you.
I look like a bride.
Yes, you do.
Now I need to shorten
the sleeves a little.
- You can take it off now.
- No.
Anne, this dress has to be
spotless for your First Communion.
I promise I won't dirty it.
Just let me wear it for
a little longer. Just a little.
Oh, just a little.
All right.
I'll be back shortly.
No sitting on the floor.
No leaning against the walls.
Monsieur, would you like to dance?
I'd love to.
Charles, you can't go on like this.
You must eat something.
...in the sky.
I don't know
if it's cloudy or bright,
because I only have eyes
for you...
dear...
The moon may be high...
Anne, you need to take
the dress off now.
Anne, are you listening?
Anne?
What did I tell you
about sitting on the floor?
But it's clean.
It makes no difference. Why
can't you ever do as you're told?
What's the matter?
Where is my daughter?
What have you done
with my daughter?
Are you mad?
I am your daughter.
You're not!
You're not
my daughter!
You're not my daughter!
- Ma'am, I heard shouts.
- She wants to kill me!
She won't stop
until she kills us!
She won't stop!
She won't stop until she kills us!
- Hush. Hush, child. Come with me.
- You're wicked! You're wicked!
Wicked!
How is she?
There's no calming her
so I've left her with her father.
She insisted
on speaking with him.
What happened?
Why did you fight?
It wasn't her.
It was the old woman
with the strange eyes.
She was imitating
my daughter's voice.
I'd swear to God that
it wasn't my daughter.
Oh, God.
God help me.
What's the matter with me?
I don't know what's
the matter with me.
You must get some rest.
You can't take on all
the responsibility of this house.
Leave it to us.
We know what has to be done.
What do you mean by that?
What do you mean you know
what has to be done?
Nothing, ma'am.
I was just suggesting...
There's nothing to suggest!
Who do you think you are? You
have no idea what has to be done!
Or do you?
What are these?
The tablets
for the migraine, ma'am.
The ones you always take.
Please, I need to be on my own.
Yes, ma'am.
Come on, child.
Anne told me everything.
I wish I had
an explanation, but I haven't.
At first I thought there was
someone else in the house.
I even thought that
there were ghosts.
I'm not talking about the ghosts.
I'm talking about
what happened that day.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Tell me what happened.
Happened?
I don't know what
happened to me.
The servants had left
during the night.
They hadn't the courage
to tell me to my face.
And they knew
that I couldn't leave the house.
They knew.
Anne.
Anne, what happened?
She hit me.
She went mad...
like she did that day.
Do you remember?
No.
You must forgive me, Charles.
Not me.
The children.
They know that I love them.
They know I'd never hurt them.
I... I'd die first.
What are you going to do?
Are you angry with me?
I came back to say goodbye to my
wife and children. Now I must go.
Go where?
To the front.
The war's over.
The war is not over.
What are you talking about?
You're not going, do you hear me?
You left us once already. You can't!
Why?
Why did you have
to go to that stupid
war that had nothing
to do with us?
Why couldn't you have stayed here
- like the others did?
- The others surrendered.
We all surrendered!
The whole island was occupied!
What did you expect?
What were you trying to prove by
going to war? Your place was here,
with us, your family.
I loved you...
and that was enough for me...
living in this darkness...
in this prison.
But not for you...
I wasn't enough for you.
That's why you left.
It wasn't just the war.
You want to leave me, don't you?
Forgive me, Grace.
Anne!
Nicholas!
Oh, my God!
Wait! Oh, my God!
Where are the curtains?
Mrs. Mills!
Let me see.
Are you alright?
You're alright!
I want my daddy!
Daddy's gone.
It's not true.
Yes, it is!
It is true.
I love you, mummy.
Find the curtains.
Who was it?
Who did this?
Tell me!
You know what's happening here.
You know because it happened
to you too!
Now tell me!
Write it down.
Write it down!
Please.
That attitude
won't solve anything, ma'am.
And anyway she can't write.
- Where are they?
- What?
The curtains!
The curtains my children's lives
depend on! Someone has taken them!
I have noticed, ma'am. There's
no need for you to raise your voice.
Oh, Mr. Tuttle, I was just
on the point of calling you.
Did you know someone's
taken all the curtains?
The curtains?
Oh, dear.
Why should anyone
want to take
all the curtains?
Oh, to let some daylight
into this house, I imagine.
Daylight... of course.
Someone wants
to kill my children!
Now why do you think
the daylight would kill them?
Are you mad?
I told you.
I already told you,
the children are photosensitive!
- The light will kill them!
- Yes, but that was
before.
The condition could have
cleared up by itself.
I mean, if you never
expose them to daylight,
how do you know
they're not cured?
My sister-in-law used to get
terrible attacks of rheumatism
in her legs and back.
Then one fine day,
they disappeared.
I'm going to find those curtains,
and when you have finished helping
me hang them,
you will leave this house.
What about the master, ma'am?
What does he have
to say about all this?
Give me your keys.
I want your keys now.
I know what you want.
You want to frighten us.
You want to get us out,
me and my children.
You've wanted to take over
this house ever since you arrived.
Now, you give me those keys.
I will not ask again.
You should try
and calm down, ma'am.
Give me the keys!
Give them to me!
And now, get out of here.
You know something, Mr. Tuttle?
I think I've reached the end
of my tether. What about you?
Oh, yes.
Definitely.
We'd better go
and uncover the gravestones.
What's mummy doing?
I've already told you.
She's gone mad.
- Liar.
- She's gone mad.
Liar, liar...
She's gone mad.
She's gone mad! She's gone mad!
Liar! Liar! Liar!
Night time.
Where are you going?
I've had enough.
I'm going to the woods
to look for daddy.
Are you going to run away?
If I hang on to the pipe,
I can climb down to the ground.
It's very easy.
If mummy finds out,
you're in for it.
Yes, yes, yes.
Anne, wait!
I want to come
and look for daddy too.
Liar, you just don't want
to be left on your own.
Scaredypants, scaredypants!
Be quiet!
Anne, I think we've got lost.
We still haven't left
the garden yet, silly.
- I'm scared.
- You shouldn't have come then.
- Say something.
- What shall I say?
I don't know. Anything.
Let's see.
My name's Anne and I'm walking.
I'm walking
and my name is Anne.
What's that over there?
I think they're graves.
Don't go near!
Why not?
What if a ghost jumps out?
Graves don't have ghosts.
Only skeletons.
There's something written here.
Let's go.
Wait.
Anne.
What does it say?
You must be strong
now, children.
Nicholas, come here!
Mrs. Mills, please don't
tell mummy we've run away.
Don't speak to them!
Why?
They're dead!
- What?
- They're ghosts. Please come here.
Children!
Nicholas!
Then why aren't they wearing sheets
and clanking chains? You said...
I don't care what I said!
Get away from them!
You're always teasing me and
telling lies, and I'm sick of it.
I'm not teasing you!
I'm telling the truth! Come here!
Quick!
Children!
Run!
Into the house.
Don't come any closer!
Don't move!
Don't trouble yourself, ma'am.
Tuberculosis finished us off
more than half a century ago.
Go away!
- Open the door, ma'am, please.
- What do you want?
Mummy, don't open
- the door, don't...
- We've seen their graves.
Go upstairs and hide.
- Go on!
- I'm scared.
Don't separate.
Anne.
Whatever you do, don't separate.
Go hide. Go! Go!
We've been trying
to make you understand.
Understand what?
About the house.
About the new situation.
What situation?
We must all learn to live
together. The living and
the dead.
If you're dead,
leave us in peace.
Leave us in peace!
In here. Get inside.
And suppose we do leave you,
do you think they will?
Who?
The intruders.
There are no intruders.
They took the curtains down,
oh yes, I assure you it was them.
And now they're
in there, with you
and the children.
Waiting for you!
- No!
- Yes!
And believe me,
sooner or later
they'll find you.
Listen, wait here
and I'll be back in a minute...
Mummy said
we shouldn't separate.
I can't leave her on her own.
Stop breathing like that.
Nicholas, stop
breathing like that.
Stop breathing!
Can't you hear it?
There's someone there.
Come with us, children.
Come with us.
Nicholas?
Anne?
Where are you?
Answer me!
- The intruders have found them.
- There's nothing we can do now.
You'll have to go upstairs
and talk to them.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name,
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses.
Why are you crying, children?
Why don't you want
to be our friends?
Come on, speak to me.
Tell me what happened.
Don't tell her!
"Don't tell her."
If I tell her,
they'll leave us in peace.
Mummy!
"Mummy!"
Why are you crying, children?
What happened in this room?
What did your mother do to you?
Something about a pillow...
Is that how
she killed you?
With a pillow?
She didn't kill us.
Children, if you're dead,
why do you remain in this house?
We're not dead!
Why do you remain in this house?
"We're not dead, we're not
dead."
We're not dead!
We're not...
dead!
Are you all right?
Yes.
Just a bit dizzy, that's all.
What happened?
They made contact.
All three?
Apparently, yes.
The mother and
the two children.
Quite interesting,
don't you think?
Interesting?
I was scared out of my wits!
- Darling, calm down.
- No.
So far we have handled this matter
your way. But now you listen to me.
We can't possibly stay in this house
any longer. It's clear these beings
do not want us to live here.
- We don't know anything about them.
- Yes, we do.
The woman went mad, smothered
her children and then shot herself.
That's quite enough.
- Think of our son.
- There's nothing wrong with Victor.
Yes, there is!
He has nightmares, he says
he has seen that girl. And even
this lady has been possessed
by her. Please,
- let us leave this house.
- All right.
We will leave tomorrow morning.
Thank God for that.
I'll just go
and check on Victor.
- Once again, thank you so much.
- A pleasure.
- I hope we've been of some help.
- Oh, yes, of course.
But I admit that was not the most
pleasant evening of my life.
At first
I couldn't understand
what the pillow
was doing in my hands.
And why you didn't move.
But then I knew.
It had happened.
I'd killed my children.
I got the rifle,
I put it to my forehead...
and I pulled the trigger.
Nothing...
And then I heard
your laughter in the bedroom.
You were playing with the pillows,
as if nothing had happened.
And I thought...
the Lord,
in His great mercy,
was giving me
another chance,
telling me,
"Don't give up,
be strong.
Be a good mother
for them."
But now...
Now...
What does all this mean?
Where are we?
Young Lydia asked
the very same thing
when she realised
the three of us were dead.
And that was the last time
she ever spoke.
But I couldn't
tell you that before now.
Shall I make
a nice cup of tea, ma'am?
The intruders are leaving,
but others will come.
Now, sometimes we'll sense them
and other times we won't.
But that's the way
it's always been...
Ma'am.
Mummy...
daddy died
in the war, didn't he?
- Yes.
- Will we ever see him again?
I don't know.
If we're dead,
where's Limbo?
I don't know
if there is a Limbo.
I'm no wiser than you are.
But I do know
that I love you.
I've always loved you.
And the house is ours.
You say with me.
- This house is ours...
- This house is ours.
Mummy, look.
It doesn't hurt any more.
No one can make us
leave this house.
Come along, Victor.