Oh, wow.
I mean, that was
the only tlme
I ever felt
sure about anythlng.
My whole life never seems
to catch up to that moment.
But to be unsure...
I don't know.
What If there's
no reason In your life
to feel shltty,
but you do anyway?
No enemy to polnt at.
Would he do that? I
I mean, I look at all
the people around me and-
Gabe?
What are you dolng?
You can go In there for hours,
but you can't do anythlng else?
Thls Is bullshlt.
But my whole life never seems
to catch up to that moment.
I mean, what If you have
no reason to feel shltty,
but you do anyway?
Everythlng's your
fucklng enemy.
Let's back up.
How does thls play start?
# When you wake up #
H i.
# Feellng old #
# At thls plano #
# Fllled wlth souls #
# Some strange purse #
# Stuffed nervous wlth gold #
# Can you be where
You want to be? #
# Walk down any street #
# You can flnd #
# Look at any clock #
# Telllng tlme #
# Slng some strange verse #
# From some
Strange song of vlnes #
# And you'll be
Where you want to be #
# I know I can't slng ##
Hey, are you sweating
in crazy places?
I'm talking to you about the
deadline, because right now,
your ass should be
sweating in crazy places.
Can you dig it?
H i, Rocky. Good
morning, and how are you?
What dld you say?
I'm saying that every
little sweat gland
in your body should be on
sweaty overdrive right now
because of these plans
right here on your desk.
Gabrlel, llsten, man, you've
got Masters I nternatlonal
showing up here
any moment,
and they want to see
these revisions done.
Yeah, I'm, uh...
That Lauren
Terrace-you know,
the one with the, uh, tarantula
in her panties for you?
Look, I-I'm almost done.
I'm really,
I'm starting to- See?
Yeah. Gabrlel...
Things and...
I'm almost...
# Having rough sex #
Hello, Diamond Records.
Cari Skaught's office.
Princess Leia, please?
Prlncess Lela...
Chewbacca Richmond
on one.
Hey, Zoom.
Hey, hey, hey.
Do you thlnk
that men are innately boring and
insensitive compared to women?
Do you?
# You are my fetlsh, fetlsh #
Hey, what movle
dld you see?
U h, uh, Startlng Over
with, uh, Burt Reynolds.
U h...
Are you serious?
All right, all right, wait.
J- J ust listen, listen, listen.
Here is the realization.
I think that women are
naturally giving creatures,
and I think that
a man's nature
is to, uh, to take advantage
of that, of that kindness.
Zoom I No, walt,
you got all thls
from a movie about Burt
Reynolds and a chimp?
Am I keeping you
from something?
Actually, I do have a
transvestite punk band
here in the office.
Thelr new album Is called Rock My Labia,
and It's chock-full of
thls klnd of Inslght.
Oh, no. Oh,
wait a second.
U h, I got to
go, legally.
U h, llsten, Zoom,
can I talk to you
later about thls?
'Cause, uh...
Yeah, okay. J
- J ust one last thing.
A play. A play.
I am gonna write a play
about all this stuff.
Great I Wrlte one,
and I'll definitely be
there to see it. Okay.
Love you, Zoom.
Got to go.
Okay, you go
rock your labia,
but you brushing me off
and hanging up on me,
it's gonna be
in the play.
So baslcally you have these
dlfferent women, you know,
and this man.
And, so y-you know how women,
um, can kind of, uh, be
very n-naturally
kind of forgiving,
and men take advantage
of-of that and everything.
And men will hide
themselves in women
and-and they allow it,
because they're just...
Are you out
of your mind?
You're asking me
to represent you,
and you haven't
written a word?
I have not written
a word, no, but-but...
Gabriel, I love
you, honestly I do.
But I represent serious
playwrights, not schmucks.
It all starts
with the writing.
Right, right.
But I thought
if I told you the idea
and you liked the idea...
Gabriel, a
writer writes.
No offense, but if you
want to be a writer,
why don't you go
to writing school?
Hey, I wanna be an astronaut;
you wanna represent me?
I mean, come on.
You come to
me with an idea.
I can't represent
an idea.
And by the way,
I'm not really sure
whether I
understand this idea.
I know it involves a
woman, th-there's a message,
there's a-a
looking glass.
Wrlte It.
What I would do...
If-
Excuse me.
Yeah?
# I have dreamt
Of a place In tlme #
# Where nobody gets annoyed #
# But I must admlt #
# I'm not there yet #
# But somethlng's
Keeplng me golng #
# Maybe there's a world
That I'm stlll to flnd #
# Open up a world
And let me In #
# Then there'll be
A new life to begln #
I think you
should tell her,
you know, 'cause
she loves you.
I couldn't.
She'd be so mad.
No, no, it'll
be fine.
You just say- oh.
She's your wlfe.
Hello, lovely.
Hello.
Listen, she's been bugging me
to go, uh, home and everything.
And so I think I-
She-she might have
lupus, I think.
Oh.
Yeah.
Well, too bad. Winston
can take her home.
You can stay.
Fine by me.
I like Winston.
M m.
See?
Ugh.
Listen, I
don't know.
I keep trying to keep it
together, but at this point,
I think I'm
doing more harm
than good by
belng here.
All right.
But just one minute.
I- There's this
woman down there,
she's one of our biggest
donors. Next to Winston.
Wlll you just
please say hello?
Okay.
Want to come?
Nah. I'll meet you at
the fountain, okay?
Okay.
Love you, Mom.
What about me?
See you later.
You, too.
See you.
Okay.
Want some help?
No, thanks.
Yeah.
Quarters.
There it is,
there it is, there it is,
there It Is.
There you go.
Thank you, thank you.
Ooh, yeah!
I thought you said
you'd meet me
at the fountain?
I'm sorry
I got wet.
But you were nice
to him, too, you know.
Sending him into the party
to get food and stuff.
That's different,
you know.
I mean, you know, he
was, he was hungry.
There we go!
"M ilner, " Daddy?
That's right.
What's a milner?
One who...
I don't know.
It's Scrabble.
You're not supposed
to know what it means.
Look, I-I let you
use " Lassie. "
It's a word.
It's a dog.
Christy's mom broke up
with her girlfriend again.
Really?
I thlnk she really
means It thls tlme.
She moved in with Ms. Weaver,
our new Home Ec teacher.
You and Mom met her.
How do you
keep up wlth
the soap opera of it all?
I thought that she was seeing the, um,
the dykey basketball coach or something.
Dad, the
word's "lesbian. "
You should know that.
It could get you a triple
word score over there.
All rlght, well,
you go ahead.
You're wiping
me out here.
Okay.
Dad, why
were you sad
at Mom's party?
You got to
stop lettlng her
stay up so late
on school nlghts.
Oh, come on.
We were just playing a little Scrabble,
waiting for you
and- you know.
It's educational.
U h-huh.
You know, when you have to
leave early like tonlght,
is supporting me
even a thought?
Yeah, sure
it's a thought.
No, look,
I'm-I'm sorry.
You know how I get
at those thlngs.
I mean, I just
klnd of freak out
a llttle blt.
How'd the rest
of the night go?
Good. Fine.
I'm glad I
hlred Wlnston.
I'd have gone crazy
without Winston.
Yeah, Winston-
he's a good guy.
I was thinking about
setting him up with Cari.
If you want
to do that to hlm.
You just said
he was great.
He is, but she's...
You know, she'd either
get bored or...
The guys she
dates are losers.
Good point.
Hey, why don't you, uh,
why don't you come to bed?
We can do a little
performance art.
Are you ready
for Colorado?
U h, yeah, yeah.
It's, uh...
I don't know. I mean, do
you really think I should go?
J ust the way I've been
feeling and everything-
Maybe we could do Christmas in New York.
We go to my family's every year
for my father, you know that.
And it's always
weird for you.
Is this about
my family?
No, no, no.
'Cause if this is
about my family-
No, no, no. Listen,
I- I'm sorry.
I don't mean that.
It's gonna be great.
I just, uh,
you know,
I just don't...
I don't want
to be a...
prick to be
around, you know.
H mm. Funny, that's never
a concern of yours before.
# There aln't No reason
thlngs Are thls way #
# It's how they always been,
And they Intend to stay #
# I can't explaln why
We llve thls way #
# We do It every day #
# The preacher's On the
podlum Speaklng of salnts #
# Prophets on the sldewalk
Begglng for change #
# Old ladles laughlng
From the flre escape #
# Curslng my name #
# I got a basketful of lemons,
And they all taste the same #
# A wlndow and a plgeon
Wlth a broken wlng #
# You can spend Your whole
life Worklng for somethlng #
# J ust to have It taken away #
# People walk around
Pushlng back thelr death #
Zoom, I do not thlnk
that you're a flake.
Did I say that
he was a flake?
No, you sald he was
sort of a pathetlc boner
for seeing a movie
during work.
Oh, boner, boner!
That's nlce In front
of my Innocent chlld.
No, I mean, I
think it's great.
It just can be great and pathetic.
Well, you know, I know It's
a llttle welrd and everythlng,
but I can't help It.
I was possessed.
J ust like the Close
Encounters with the potatoes.
Hey I
Oh, good,
even Carl's here.
H i.
Hey.
H i, my sweetness.
Hello.
You!
Hello, Mama.
M mm! Let me
through here.
What's for dinner?
Well, we got fish,
rice and veggies.
U h-huh.
The ladies were just feeding me crow.
Good. I like that.
Want some?
Are you
eating those?
We got-Oh,
hey, come on!
Hey, I'm your mother!
Go set the table!
Flve polnts If you get It In hls glass.
Dad says
he's gonna
write a play
about all of us.
Oh. See a movie
today, dear?
No... yeah.
I did. Go
ahead, laugh.
Oh, that
Burt Reynolds.
Ah, yeah,
laugh it up.
Your laughter
glves me strength.
Aw, poor Gabe.
You're all gonna be
in the play, you know.
Oh.
Yeah.
Scared.
Absolutely.
Ooh.
So, Cari...
Oh, no. I, uh...
What? I'm not
that bad, am I?
Yenta!
No, it's just I
have this friend
that I thought you might
be interested in meeting.
Who?
Lord Wlnston.
Royalty?
Winston Lee
Attenborough,
and he is my
new assistant curator.
And he's really cute.
Come on, Lizzie, back me up
here. He's cute, right?
He Is, Dad,
he just Is.
I suppose If Llzzle likes
hlm, I should just marry hlm.
Good.
No, actually, uh,
can't do it, guys,
'cause I'm moving in with someone.
You what?
What?
Yeah, the
dancer, right?
Walt, walt, walt, hold
on. Hold on, dancer, like,
stripper dancer? You're
moving in with a stripper?
Shh! What kind
of dancer?
Ballet. You know, the
guy she met at that party?
Wait. No, no, not Sushi the dancer?
Sachi, schmuck!
What, are
you deaf?
How do you say his name? Sushi?
No, I mean, you know, this is why.
This is why I didn't
want to tell you guys.
It's, like, the relationship's
in its first trimester,
and you know,
I knew
you guys would get all serious
about it and give me shit.
Well, you're the
only person I know that would
just move in with somebody
rather than have
a second date.
Yeah, dating. Yuck.
I think it's great.
And he's a lucky guy.
Yeah.
All right.
It is
present time!
# Da da-da da! #
Thank you.
And for our own
Diane Arbus
in training.
Thank you.
Oh...
Cari, you remembered.
Thank you.
U h, yours isn't
here yet.
Shershi...
You're gonna
get it.
So, Zoom, what Is all
thls about, really?
The-the play, the
movies, everything.
Do you know?
No, I don't.
Well, what does it
feel like?
You know what it is?
It's sort of the opposite
of what it might seem like.
I mean, I... I know
that I should be happy,
but... I don't know.
You know, there's
this weird thing
that happens when
you have a kid.
You just simply do
not allow yourself
to even consider being
anything but happy.
J ust... that's it.
Going to be happy
and everything.
But I don't know-
I mean, I...
when I look back,
you know, and I...
I... you know, I watch
myself step into this life,
and it just kind of feels
like I'm full of shit.
What's full of shit?
Full of shit,
like how?
Like... like... like
your life is living you
instead of the other way around?
Is this about
you and Annie?
Oh, God, no.
I wish.
That'd make it
so much easier.
I would know what to do, you know?
But, uh... what?
Ah, no, wait.
Obviously, everything
is great.
God.
I have an idea.
I enjoy. Feel
comfortable. What?
Why don't you get into
the shopping cart?
All right.
All right, you can
take the bottle.
Here.
All right.
Take the bottle.
Okay. What are we doing?
Where are we going?
We're gonna go
on an adventure.
We're looking for joy,
bliss and identity.
Joy, bliss,
here we come.
All right.
Where are we
going, Zoom?
Thls way.
We're golng thls way?
You want to know...
you want to know
what my play is
gonna be about?
It's going to be about
this evil, vicious woman
who, uh, pushes
her best friend-
this man in a cart- and
then, while it's crashing,
she makes no attempt
to help him at all,
but instead rescues
the bottle of booze.
And I suppose
that you are this man.
That's me- that'd
be me in the play.
Listen, I mean, this
really doesn't have anything
to do with anything,
but I think I might
have crossed a line
with Lauren at work.
What?
What line? Where?
Well, no, no, it's not the line.
I mean, this isn't
about cheating.
It... oh, fuck.
Cheating.
No, that's not me.
Wow. And-And you
don't think that-
all of this is
about that?
But how could it not
be confusing you?
I mean, either you
and Lauren are friends,
or you are more.
M mm.
Touching her vagina
is not nothing.
Oh! Oh!
It's not nothing.
Shh, shh.
Vagina touching
equals confusion.
You know, okay,
okay, I got it.
Thanks.
Jesus.
Look at me.
Come on.
Now, do you
really think that...
that this is about, uh, vagina touching?
Come on.
You know what I think
you should call your play?
H mm?
"Trying to Find Myself
in a Friend's Vagina. "
Shut up.
You stay out of
my friend's vagina.
You shut up and stay out
of your friend's vagina.
Well... I should
stay out altogether.
You vagina-you
got none vagina.
What?
Okay, so I wanted
to give this to you
when the moment
was just right.
When we found more uses
for the word "vagina"
than I ever have
before in my life, okay?
Here.
What?
Your present.
You know, write your fucking play, Zoom.
This will record
your journey.
Wow. Wow.
This is amazing.
This is so cool.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Like this?
U p on your toes.
Let the water get all
the way down In the gulch.
So, like that?
Little soap. Yes.
Yes, yes, and you don't
want faulty presentation.
Right. What do
you hold on to?
U h, 12: 00- tarantula.
Oh.
I can tell
from the pose
that you fellas are feverishly
at work on my project.
Actually, we are
absolutely not at work on your project.
Especially him.
Can I ask how
funny thls looks?
Pretty darn.
I mean, I know why I
put up with you guys,
but how are you dealing
with your other clients?
He's not. Everybody's
plssed at hlm.
Anyway, good-bye,
Gabe.
Good-bye, Lauren.
U h-huh.
Ah, he just...
he...
ah, he's just a
sick bastard.
You know, he's
showing me the, uh...
the shower thingy,
you know?
Now, wait a minute-
you're... you're here.
Yeah. We're having lunch.
Right. Right.
The live one.
The live one you've named
three times already, Lauren.
Okay, you name
five Kl S S records.
Okay, I will.
No, don't.
Never mind.
J ust show me one adult woman who could.
Okay.
Ten Ryan O' Neal movies.
Ten Ryan O' Neal
mo... whoa.
This is so easy.
I'm going to get you started.
Love Story,
Ollver's Story.
Ah, see, this is why I hate
playing this game with you-
'cause you won't even let me guess.
And I had one, too-
a really good one.
The one with the, uh...
the bare-ass jeans.
And you asked
me how I was.
Well, we... we got way
too much going on right now
for me to think about how
I am, but it's not good.
U h, but llsten, you were-you
were supposed to take me
to lunch, and I'm eating
pizza out of my bare hand.
Pizza and Ryan O' Neal-
what the fuck?
I can tell
you're trying not
to "talk-talk. "
Llsten, thls has nothlng to do wlth us.
Everything is
fine, and...
and I have absolutely
no reason to feel-
But you do.
Yeah, but-
All I ever hear
from you Is,
" I have no reason
to feel this way, "
" I have no excuse
to feel that way. "
Haven't you learned anything
from being a New Yorker?
I mean, slnce when do we need
a reason to do anythlng?
You feel shltty,
you feel shltty.
Well, I'm afraid this
is a little bit more
all-encompassing than
just feeling shitty.
Hey. Okay, you
are taking me
to my energy enthusiast
appointment right now.
I should make you
get a treatment.
Your what?
Actually, you should.
I'm worried.
J ust trust me.
Yeah, okay.
I'm... I'm up
for anything.
Here.
Hey, Silvia.
Hey.
Can I go
right back?
Sure.
I'm just here to do
a little energy work.
Yeah, you know, just charge
the batteries a little bit.
Yeah.
Get some juice.
You know.
All righty, then.
Gabriel.
Who are we
seeing tonight?
A band called
Vulvic N uisance.
They're actually
a punk-funk band.
And they're
the latest rage.
Says who?
Says ages
18 to 25.
Actually, I signed
them in a drunken stupor
and now I can't
get rid of them.
They're in my office every day.
So tell
me something-
is that dad of yours ever
gonna write that play?
I think it's going
to be a hit.
You do, huh?
Me, too.
Do you think Mom and Dad are all right?
I think so.
I hope so.
U h-oh, look.
All right, don't
move a muscle.
Someone has to put that
mime out of our misery.
Oh, no.
Oh.
Oh, you got a hole
in your pants, mime.
I nappropriate.
So what do you think of this place?
It's okay.
Wow, how fucking
old are you?
Twelve.
Wicked!
A little over
a decade.
How come guys act
so stupid like that?
You mean, besides being
piss drunk and retarded?
Well, not just him-
like all guys.
Llke, guys In my class
act like that, too.
Most of them
aren't drunk.
Are we talking about
somebody in particular?
Maybe.
Maybe?
All right, here's what you have to do-
you have to see if the guy is an ass
or if he's just
being an ass.
Oy, Rlggsl
Go away, chlef.
I'm coming over there
to smell your fingers.
Yeah, I think
you'll just know.
Boys and glrls,
Vulvlc N ulsancel
Hey, Slutty Sluts,
slng along I
# Oh #
# Look good in latex #
I like your band.
# Get off #
# Having rough sex #
What do you think
they're doing?
They're probably
skating or dancing,
'cause Sushi's turned Cari into
quite the ballet aficionado.
M m. Yeah, definitely.
Yup, they're at the ballet with Sushi.
Yeah.
# You are my fetish #
# Gaze down ##
Is this ready to go?
H mm?
That suitcase-
is it ready?
M m, yeah. Yeah.
What time are you
gonna be back from work?
When?
Tomorrow.
Oh, uh, no,
I'm not going.
I'm just, I'm
gonna call in.
I thought if you didn't finish
the revisions, you couldn't go.
No.
Okay, where to begln?
Maybe start
wlth the women.
Okay, let's
start wlth Annle.
I n Colorado, at grad
school, I met sweet Annle.
And then, bam,
I'm an archltect,
a father, a
husband, and...
Wow, man, Ellzabeth.
That's the only tlme
I've really been sure
about anythlng,
totally present.
My whole life never seems
to catch up to that moment.
But to be unsure, ugh.
I don't know.
What If there's no reason In your life
to feel shltty,
but you do anyway?
No enemy to polnt at?
What do you do then?
I mean, I look at all
the people around me-
Gabe?
What are
you doing?
Working!
Freezing.
Hey. H uh?
Oh, it looks
great, Dad.
It's great to
see you, Gabe-O.
How are you? H uh?
Good.
Annie tells me
you're busy.
I- I mean, you know,
she tells me you're
busy, I know you're busy.
Dad, he's
always busy.
Gabe-O's fine.
I'm not too busy,
not too busy.
How about you?
Oh, how do I look?
Yeah, you look good.
Erik is doing the Happy
Polar Bears Tri Ath
again this year.
You are?
Yes. Yeah, yeah.
Look, it's - Look, it's no big deal.
You do a... you know,
a few K run,
a few K bike,
a K or two ski...
You should do it with me. It'll be fun.
It's very low-key. Why
don't you do it with us?
Oh, wow.
I don't know.
The altitude- I forgot
about what it's like here.
That's a lot of
Ks and stuff.
That's... K, K...
I'm... I'm more of... I'm
not the jolly jogger kind of,
but a little air hockey
tournament, I'm your man.
Air hockey.
Ah, come on.
Are you sure?
You won't...? Annie,
what about you, honey?
I'm in. I'm in.
Yeah?
Okay.
So, Dad says you're
wrltlng a book or somethlng?
A play. Yeah.
You know, you should
do it up here.
Sidney Sheldon's got a
place up here in the summer.
Oh, wow.
What's it about?
It's, um...
It's like, uh, Jesus
Chrlst Superstar.
You know that one?
Only on ice.
What does that mean?
No, it's... it's,
uh... it's...
I'm just kidding.
It's, like, about
relationships.
U m...
It has nothing to do with
Jesus Chrlst Superstar.
H uh.
At all.
What-What kind
of relationships?
You know, just,
just people and-
I got to say that I
like James Bond more than-
All I'm asklng
Is for you to spend tlme wlth my famlly.
Why is that so hard?
You know what this
means to my dad.
All I'm saying is just,
let me just... I...
You know, I'll catch up with you later.
I just want
to be at my best.
Don't make a big
deal, Annie. Come on.
Why did you
come here?
What do you mean?
What? What?
Why did you come?
What favor
dld you thlnk you
were dolng me?
You're rude
to my family.
You talk to them
like they're idiots!
Oh, now, come on, I'm
not rude to your family.
Your family's fine,
all right?
I'm the same as I've always
been with your family.
They just don't get me.
Oh, my God, no.
Sometimes you're just...
Why? Why?
Please tell me why
does my family
not get you?
Give it a rest!
Why? Because you're so goddamn complex?
Aah! Give it
a rest, Annie!
No. Tell mel
Why? Why?
Do I get you?
Oh, do you get me?
No, you don't get me.
What the hell
are you doing?
Sorry.
Oh, that's good.
You all rlght?
Oh, God.
You feel better?
Yes, I do.
Thls Is great.
We're just enterlng
some really nlce klnd
of whlte trash behavlor.
Why don't we punch some
sheetrock walls, Annie,
you know, and have the
cops show up, and...?
Come on.
I know you know
how you've been pushing my buttons.
Yeah, I have.
Yeah.
I think that
I should probably-
go home.
Not what I thought
you were going to say.
Everything okay?
Yeah, flne.
Let's go on
the happy hike.
Well, let's go.
Come on.
Oh.
Look, look, I'm...
I'm tired of
waiting, Rocky.
No, Glenn Masters
called me directly-
not Lauren, but Glenn himself-
to request a new designer.
Yeah, okay.
Gabe left-left and didn't
deliver the designs agaln.
He just, he just left.
He's a distracted guy,
but when I talked to
him, his designs-
Oh, come on,
I've been through this
a thousand
times with him.
No. I'm over it. I'm done.
He knows this is coming.
He knows
this is coming.
No one ever knows
they're gonna be fired,
even if they
say they do.
He's done, over!
I wanted you to
hear it from me.
You're not pissed,
are you?
Oh, no.
No, no. I'm
not, I'm, uh...
I'm glad you were the one to fire me.
I guess I just feel a
bit, uh, stupid, you know?
Embarrassed.
H uh.
I shouldn't be surprised.
M ichael thought
you'd feel that way.
Oh, he did?
Well, fuck him. Tell him
I was totally surprised.
What, uh... What about
Lauren's project? U h...?
Lauren's cool.
Look, your designs
are basically finished.
We're just dealing
with engineering now.
Don't sweat it, man.
H mm?
Fuck it.
Yeah.
U h, listen,
I'm gonna take off, okay?
I just don't-
I want to get some air and
go for a little walk and...
Gabe, Gabe,
are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine, I just
want to... I just want to...
I'll see you.
You call me if
you need anything.
Hey, Noname.
# Noname. #
Gabriel?
Is he in the bathroom writing again?
I don't think so.
Gabe?
Okay.
What is it going to
be, chicken or fish?
Whatever.
No, no, come on,
you're the boss tonight.
I promised.
Mom?
How come you and Dad
are so mad at each other?
Why can't you be like when we
were in Maine for the summer?
We still love
each other.
It's, it's just...
J ust what?
How come the only time you
guys are together is with me?
Oh, baby, is
that true?
Yeah.
Come here.
Look In the fucklng flre.
Dare to go at the
plvotal moments.
Whenever you thlnk It's too
uncomfortable to look at,
look at It, wrlte It.
When Annle sald-
Why did you come?
What favor did
you think
you were dolng me?
Aah, give it
a rest, Annie!
No, tell me.
Why? Why?
Do I get you?
No, you don't get me.
I'm not gonna let us
do this to each other-
not a chance-
so let's dance.
Okay.
What are
you dolng?
Whoa.
Are you drunk?
Listen, I spoke
to, uh, Pamela,
and sh-she was really
impressed with the outline
an-and she said she would
continue to look at what I do,
I mean, if I really go
back and make it great.
She didn't really
exactly say that, but...
U m, what, you
mean the... the play?
Yeah, yeah.
Oh.
Isn't that great?
Yeah, no, tha-that's
great, I just, um...
I just, I- wha-what
does that mean?
Okay, Annie, I want, I want
you to take a look at it
and tell me
what you think.
I want you
to read it, Annie.
U m, I can't.
M m, not yet.
Why not?
It scares me.
It's a stupid
outline of a play.
It's not even a play yet.
It's just...
Okay.
But it's great.
I'm, I'm really
excited for you.
I'll see
you at home.
Okay...
Ja, ja...
Are you ever not smoking,
Saffron Genitalia?
It's Jenetal.
Jenitards?
Jenetal.
You know,
we don't need
your kind of trouble
here in these parts.
What kind of
trouble is that?
It's the kind of trouble
you, you can't flush
because it just
keeps floating.
That's very, very clever.
U h-huh, okay,
so... uh-huh.
Okay, all right, you
want to know how it works?
This is
how it works.
I haven't listened to it yet,
but every time you call me,
I'm golng to llsten to
one less song on the demo.
All rlght?
I promlse I'll
llsten to It.
Okay.
Thank you.
Patience is a virtue.
Hey.
Hl.
What do you think?
H mm...
Eh... eh.
Eh?
Eh, eh, eh, eh, eh, eh.
So...?
She liked it...
and, uh, she might
possibly even rep me.
She said that?
No, she didn't
say that.
She didn't say that
at all, actually.
I'm just, uh,
making it up.
I'm pretending she said
that, but she did like it.
She did?
Yeah.
Fan-fucking-wonderful, man!
Sachi-he's
rubbing off on me.
Ah, ah, okay.
So this is
wonderful news.
What's with
the pouty face?
I- I just saw Annie and she,
she refuses to read it.
She says that
it's scary to her.
Well, I mean,
you do talk constantly
about how the play is
about a man who is lost,
so, you know, how do
you expect her to feel?
Yeah, but, you
know, it's not-
it's, like, symbolic of a, you know, a
- a man
not, not who
lost himself,
but it symbolizes a man who,
you know, is finding himself.
So what's scary
about that?
Well, that's exactly what
she's afraid of maybe, Zoom.
I mean, what is she going to find there?
You just have
to think of it
from her side,
rather than yours.
People do that?
Every day.
Eh, how can you be
so sure, though?
Oh, trust
me, I'm sure.
I'm even afraid of what you're
gonna do to me in the play.
Well, you should be.
You know, they're
good, by the way.
What's their name?
Placenta,
but we are talking them into
changing it to Peacepipe.
Why?
Are you okay?
M r. Richmond?
I'm pretty sure Dr.
Martin will see you now.
M r. Rlchmond,
thanks for coming.
Well, it's a
bit complicated.
We tried to
call your wife
because these things are usually
best handled between us girls,
if you'll pardon
my saying so...
Is she, uh...
is-is she all set?
Does she need...?
Yeah, that's,
that's plenty.
Maybe I've
got a bag.
H mm.
Your dad
seems funny.
At least
he came.
Elizabeth.
Lizard, come on,
please, please.
Lizzy.
Hey.
Hey, what's
going on?
Why did
you do that?
Do what?
Do what?! Bring all that
female stuff to school-
to Dr. Martin's office-
for the whole
world to see!
I'm sorry, I was,
I was worried, Lizzy.
You're such an
asshole sometimes.
Whoa, whoa,
just a minute now.
And you can't put
this in your play.
I'm not one of your
dumb characters.
I'm a person.
Elizabeth-
Not that you care.
Oh, come on, all right,
listen, I know you're upset,
but you can't speak to me
that way, all right?
I put my sweater around me to hide it,
and it fell off in
front of everyone.
I'm fine, Dad,
just forget it.
Hey, what's
going on, huh?
I don't know, I guess I'm
just PM S'ing or something,
you know, like
you and Mom.
God, It just scared
the shlt out of me.
I mean, I was hovering over my body,
watching this, uh,
asshole act like a parent
in a scene from Llttle
House on the Pralrle-
you know, the special
two-hour tampon episode.
I think I
missed that one.
That's what
it was like.
Hey, shh.
Llzzy?
Shh, shh, shh.
She's all right,
she's sleeping.
I was out at a
meeting all day
and I didn't get the message
until it was too late.
Everythlng's okay. I
went down to the school.
I heard.
Is she okay?
Yeah, I mean, I think she was
embarrassed and wanted to die,
but from what I
hear from her,
Zoom talked to her and
she feels fine now.
Good. Thanks for
taking the time.
Surprised you
could fit it in.
Well, uh, yeah,
I mean, I'm her father.
Oh, really, then why
don't you act like it?
I mean, you're more
like her friend.
You're everybody's
goddamn friend.
This isn't about the
school, is it, Annie?
If you want to talk
about some other shit,
that's fine, you know,
we'll talk about it,
but don't insinuate
I'm a bad father.
I was there with her today and...
All right, thank you,
you're a good father.
But it's on your time.
It's when you feel like it.
How could you bring that
up today, of all days?
Cari, come on.
It's okay. You
know what? I...
It's that uncomfortable
houseguest-in-the- middle-of-a-fight thing.
I... I'm gonna get
out of here.
I love you
both, and...
glve my love
to Llzzy, huh?
I'd never let anything get
in the way of Elizabeth.
Didn't know we were
keeping score, Annie.
Come on-
Jesus Christ.
I tried to call you at
Cari's, but you'd already gone.
And I apologized
to her.
It was...
it was rude of me.
Yeah, I went for a
walk; I should've called.
I'm sorry.
Oh, no, no.
It's all right.
Annie, you know,
we used to...
just get along
so much easier.
This isn't us.
I'm a little confused
about what "us" is.
What do you mean?
Well, do we feel like a
husband and wife to you?
We always-
loved each other
too much to-
even think about-
not being together.
If you, uh, if
you removed...
Lizzy from our life,
do you think you...
Oh, but you can't.
You can't.
Lizzy's like...
she's the best
part of us.
I used to always...
I always thought
that with, uh...
with her
between us that-
we could get past
the rest, you know?
But I mean, that's not
fair, especially to her.
M m.
What should we do?
I just wish...
Oh, God, I don't know.
I love you, but...
I am really...
angry...
inside.
We need to get
ourselves back, Annie.
Yeah.
# There's a dream that I see #
# I pray It can be #
# Look cross the land #
# Shake thls land #
# A wlsh #
# Or #
# A command #
# A dream that I see #
# Don't klll It, It's free #
# You're just a man #
# You get what you can #
# We #
# All do #
# What we can #
# So we #
# Can do just one more thlng #
# We #
# Can all #
# Be free #
# Maybe not #
# I n words #
# Wlth a look #
# But wlth your mlnd #
# Llsten to me ##
So, I still
come home and...
expect to see her
there, you know.
Who? Annie
or Lizzy?
Lizzy.
What do you miss most about
having them around the house?
Here's the thlng.
You can love the idea
of being alone
when there's someone
in the other room.
But when you're-you're
alone, it's different.
It's... it's different.
Yeah.
You're alone.
But you know, it's good
for you to be alone.
You're working
it all out.
Drink some
good bad booze.
What is it with
you and bad booze?
Does your body crave it or something?
I think it does.
I think there's...
You know, it's-it's
more immediate.
It just hits faster
than the good stuff.
Yeah, yeah.
I n like one sip.
Hello?
Well, you
sound like hell.
So, how's the
play coming?
U h...
yeah... gee,
you know...
Gabe, you know,
I got to tell you,
I am so impressed
with everything you've
sent me so far, but...
I really need to see
that whole play.
You know, I've-I've never really
done thls klnd of thlng before,
so I don't know if it's...
you know, it's coming together-
I mean, I'm-I'm trying.
But, uh, you know,
the good news Is,
wlth my life
falllng to shlt,
the play seems
to be flourlshlng.
Well, that's good.
I mean, not that your life
is falling to shit, but...
I like to hear
the word "flourlshlng. "
Yeah. Well, you know, the
play's been my therapy,
uh, along wlth actual-
therapy, that Is.
Yeah, you know,
I'm-I'm just wrltlng,
and at thls polnt, I
really don't even care
If anyone sees It.
Gabe, you know, I know you've
been going through hell,
and, look, I mean,
we've all been there,
and oh, blah, blah,
blah, who cares?
And I know, I know,
I keep harping
on all this devotion-to-craft
stuff, but...
just don't get so
Involved In your own shlt
that you forget the favor I'm dolng you.
I am not a therapist.
I am not a writing coach.
I sell plays.
But if I'm involved, I do
care if someone sees this play.
You're hyping me.
You're, you're-you're
trying to give me a pep talk.
Call it what you will,
but don't fuck it up.
Gabe...
I thlnk you've got
a real shot here.
I mean, what can
I tell you?
H uman suffering's
in vogue, but...
Look, If we play
our cards rlght,
we can turn all this male
angst into some money.
I know, that's not
why you're wrltlng It.
But it does make the journey
just a little sweeter.
H m. Are you
the devil?
Oh, I hope so, honey.
So you just keep golng, and you let
that play have its own life,
and you have yours, all right?
Okay.
Wrltlng Ellzabeth's scenes
needs to be done
wlth sensltlvlty.
Put yourself In her
shoes, for Chrlst's sake.
# I am woman,
Watch me grow #
# See me standlng
Toe to toe #
# As I spread
My lovln' arms #
# Across the land #
# But I'm stlll an embryo #
# Wlth a long,
Long way to go #
# U ntll I make my brother #
# U nderstand #
# Whoa, yes, I am wlse #
# But It's wlsdom
Born of paln #
# Yes, I've pald the prlce #
# But look how much
I've galned #
# I am strong #
# Strong #
# I am Invlnclble #
# I nvlnclble #
# I am woman ##
Hello?
It-It ha... it has
been a...
very long time.
I know.
U h, well...
Lizzy, uh, sort of
kind of helped me,
uh, not be so closed-minded,
I guess, and...
Well, yeah,
that sounds great.
Yeah. Especlally the part
where I get to relax.
Okay. Come on, Noname.
Hello! I'm here!
Come on, Noname.
Hey, I'm here!
Got all my stuff!
My typewriter,
dog's typewriter.
Hey!
Sorry.
Oh, what
a surprise!
Oh, you took a cab all
the way from the city?
Yeah, sure did
- well, we stopped, got a bite to eat.
Oh, Mamute, Lauren.
Hello.
Lauren, Mamute.
You are the only guy from
Manhattan who would do that.
Should we invite Mamute in for a kiss?
Yeah, is that cool?
Come on, Noname.
Come on.
You gonna be able
to work here?
Yeah, as long as
you got a good tollet.
Can I talk to you
about somethlng?
I mean, I don't want to
make a big deal out of it
and be all goofy or anything,
but I was just thinking
that, you know,
our special friendship,
that maybe I should...
or we should concentrate
more on the friendship,
less on the special...
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, slow down.
You didn't take a taxi all the way
from New York
to tell me that.
No.
I came here so that I
could be with you and...
and breathe easier.
And I am.
It's great.
I told you where
I was coming from.
So, relax.
No worrles.
You want to sleep
in the guest room?
No.
U h...
Maybe I should.
How's that
for an answer?
I... I think that's
a fine answer.
A wrlter wrltes.
A wrlter wrltes, rlght?
U h, Lauren!
I n the bathroom.
Can you get It?
U h...
U h, uh,
Lauren's phone.
Get your ass back
to the clty, klddo.
I have a perfect producer on the hook.
It's about to
get Interestlng.
And Gabe,
clean yourself up.
U h...
Fuck me.
Hey!
H i.
Have a seat.
So...
they backed out
of the deal.
I'm sorry.
So, what-what-what
does that mean?
We just walt
and see
what comes in,
or what I can maneuver.
It may take
a llttle tlme.
some time.
H uh.
J ust so you know, that sort
of sounds deathly cancerous.
I mean, what the fuck
am I golng to do?
Well, you just
keep on writing.
Oh, come on.
No, you come on I
I can't...
I mean,
Jesus, Gabriel.
I mean, this isn't
some kind of a fluke.
If you're really serious about
this, you just keep at it.
J ust be patient.
This is what I do.
I'm living out of
a suitcase, Pamela.
Gabriel, I love you,
I really do,
but this fucking whining
white guy shit has gotta stop.
You just use thls tlme
to work on your wrltlng,
to prove to yourself
that you are a wrlter.
J ust keep on going.
J ust polish.
Thank you for
the flowers.
# Whenever you need me,
I'll be there #
You gotta just try
shucking the corn.
I don't get-I
don't really get it.
Yeah. It's clear.
I don't think I wanna understand it.
No, no, I... it's
just... that's too weird.
I think... okay,
for a woman,
Don't knock it.
I think maybe yeah, because
it's nice and smooth.
Like, let's say you're going,
you're going down on her,
and she's all wet
and slippery.
Oh, God.
And she-
Oh! Mama loves Daddy,
Mama loves Daddy,
Mama loves Daddy!
No, I... I
honestly don't get
the whole vagina
fascination thing of yours.
I don't get it.
Well, uh,
you wouldn't.
No, I mean, look.
No, no. Freedom's
about choice. Yeah.
Okay, you turn a woman
upside down, what do you get?
Relatively the same thing at both ends.
You turn a man upside down,
honey, you get a choice.
Oh!
Barbecue.
Yes. It's better.
I've done both.
I know.
You? Wh-What
do you mean?
I was with a woman.
J unior year in college,
there's this girl
determined to make me
her little Mandingo
chocolate fantasy.
H uh? And I
wasn't the one
trying to be Tarzan
to her playing Jane.
M iss thing comes
into my room-
she's got nothing
but the robe on-
sits down...
and spreads her legs.
Yeah?
It-It looked like a boiled
egg with a split in it.
Oh, God!
Mommy loves Daddy.
It's ug- You've
got to admit it's-
No, it looked like
M ick Jagger sideways.
You know, like them child-bearing lips?
Got it, I
got it, yeah.
Oh, honey, we're rolling
stone, go roll on home. Oh!
Bartender, can we get
the-the gentleman here
the... a vodka with,
uh... with corn...
With corn.
And a vodka for, uh, me,
with a little... little egg.
Get me a... get
me a big corn.
Or a corn.
H i.
You's a squirrel,
you're gonna get a nut.
H uh?
I don't know, life...
life has a sense of humor.
My dad wanted an
ultra-macho son.
I nstead, he got me.
Spent most of my
childhood trying to...
beat the fabulous
out of me.
To no avail.
# Me and M rs. Jones #
When I... when I got in
trouble, my dad used to say,
"J ust go ahead,
pick the punishment, "
you know, as long as, uh,
you're creative
and as long as he got
to approve it.
So, you know, he would
have me read a book.
Carl and I... as soon
as we got In trouble
or thought we were golng
to get In trouble,
we would just go and
we would get some books.
And we were
inseparable, even then.
And It was so much fun
belng on the roof wlth her,
'cause when... when...
Gabriel, Gabriel.
What?
Wh-who-who are you
right now, man?
You're just like...
you're just like...
you're turning into the
blabbering bar guy.
No, I'm not-
Do you even know that I'm
here? You're just like...
bip, bip, bip, bip.
Good Lord.
You... what are you
talking about?
You've just been talklng
about Carl all day.
No, I... no.
Come on.
No, no, It's cool.
It's great.
You like her,
so that's good.
You guys ever
H umpty Dumpty?
# My favorite song #
Did we ever H umpty Dumpty?
Come on, Rock.
She's my friend. I...
Yeah, we humped once.
I n, uh... high school.
Yeah, it was...
I don't really remember It
very well, but, uh,
one of us puked.
That's the split
egg thing.
I'm sorry. What...
You need to just stop all
the hesitation in your life.
Can I tell
you a story?
Is it a... is it going
to be a... a long story?
Yeah.
Well, first, growing up black and gay...
had its challenges.
Hold on- you're gay?
I could have also
been a dwarf, but...
but that wasn't the
toughest shit I dealt with.
Toughest thing I ever
dealt with in my life
was just
being in love.
You were in love?
Yeah.
Luis, the Greek God
of Spanish Harlem-
174 pounds of
papl chulo-
and-and...
I got up
my courage...
You mean... you mean, you...
you said that you loved him?
And he didn't feel
the same way about me.
Broke my heart.
That's just so depressing.
No. You know what?
I realized...
I had a heart
to break.
All this time, I'd
been emotionally numb,
and now I
was feeling...
I wasn't feeling
what I wanted to feel,
but I was
alive again.
You understand?
And-And-And deep,
honest love like that-
it doesn't
happen every day.
# It hurts so much inside #
Are you talking
about Cari?
I'm talklng
about feellngs.
You've been
talking about Cari.
# Tomorrow, we'll meet
At the same place #
# The same time #
H mm?
# Me and M rs. #
# M rs. Jones #
# M rs. Jones, M rs.
Jones, M rs. Jones ##
Better be
Freddie Mercury.
Zoom.
Hey.
What... what
are you doing?
It's 4: 00 a. m.
You okay?
Yeah.
Oh, yes, I am.
I'm drunk, a little.
Yeah. What happened?
Oh, but I know
what I'm doing.
Where did you go?
H i.
Hey.
Come on, sit down.
I just, uh...
Okay.
Do you want
some coffee?
Yes, please.
No! No.
No, I just want... can you
just listen to me for a second?
'Cause I've been walking
around and thinking about us.
You and Annie?
No.
" Us"- you mean
you and me.
Bingo. Yeah.
Yeah, Annie...
and me, that would
be "them, " right?
Cari, it's always
been there.
I mean, come on.
U h-huh.
See what I'm...?
I'm going to get
us that coffee.
Yeah, no, no, no, Cari.
No, I... I
got to get...
I got to get this all
out at once. I love you.
I love you.
I'm in love with you.
I always have been.
You're in love with me,
and it works.
Okay?
It works.
It's right.
You're sweet,
but you're drunk.
No, no, no.
It's not that.
No, no.
Yeah, you are.
What Is It?
Things okay?
Hey.
Yeah, it's
just Gabe.
Oh.
H i, Gabe.
U m, why don't you
go back to bed?
I'll be up in just a few minutes.
Okay, hon.
Fuck. I didn't know.
What are you doing?
J ust let me...
excuse me.
I'm not...
I'm not kidding.
Now I want
coffee, so...
you're gonna have some,
whether you like it or not.
I'm deadly serlous,
you know.
You-you-you
love me, too.
Of course, I love you.
I'm your best friend, okay?
No, Cari.
I'm talklng about love.
I'm talklng
about everythlng.
J ust-just laughing
and... love!
Like full-throttle,
hugs, kisses,
crying, you know, making
love like we used to.
Like that.
Okay, look...
we had sex one time, and you puked.
That is not burning.
That does not quallfy as romance.
I mean, indigestion,
maybe some bad Yukon Jack.
But burning?
Romance? No.
All rlght, llsten.
Cari, uh, listen.
You know, we were kids.
Right? So...
uh... all right.
Like my-my play.
Okay.
I know, I...
No, just listen,
listen, listen!
I have been listening!
I've heard everything
that you've said.
Now, stop it.
You're drunk.
All right?
Look, I know
you've been going
through a terrible
time, and believe you me,
I feel your pain
as if it were my own,
but Jesus, you don't
come waltzing
into somebody's house-
at 4: 00 in the morning, I might add-
and... and go dictating
love all over the place.
Jesus, Zoom, what...
what did you expect
anyway, really?
Look, we have the best
goddamn thing around,
but I think now
you're confused,
and-and you're...
and you're reaching.
No...
You're afraid.
I'm not afraid anymore.
Is that so?
Yeah, it's so.
So, I see you
have this all
fucking figured out.
It's my fear.
It's my fear that has
been just waiting here
for you to come here
drunk in the middle of
the night to save me?
It doesn't even faze you
how selfish this is,
that you would come in
here gushing your love
all over the place
without even thinking
about how I feel.
You have been married
for years and years,
and my role has been
to be your best friend I
And your wife's best friend
and your daughter's best friend.
I exist... okay?
I exlst.
And goddamn it, I will not be a new way
for you to
experience yourself!
U h, Cari...
fuck me...
Okay, look, I...
I want you
to stay here tonight,
because I don't want
you to go back out there.
But...
I don't want
to talk to you...
until you realize how
fucked up this all is.
You know, just...
sleep it off and
sober up, and-and...
we'll talk
in the morning.
You-You haven't
heard a word I said.
Yes, I have.
I really
would like you
to hear what
I said, okay?
Go on, get
some sleep.
We'll talk later.
And don't throw up
on my blanket.
# Lover #
# There wlll be another one #
# Who'll hover #
# Over you beneath the sun #
# Tomorrow #
# See the thlngs
That never come #
# Today #
# When you see me #
# Fly away #
# Wlthout you #
# Shadow on the thlngs #
# You know #
# Feathers fall #
# Around you #
# And show you
The way to go #
# It's over #
Now wh-what
have you done?
# M mm, mmm #
# Nestled #
# I n your wlngs #
# My llttle one #
# Thls speclal #
# Mornlng brlngs another sun #
# Tomorrow #
# See the thlngs
That never come #
# Today #
# When you see me #
# Fly away #
# Wlthout you #
# Shadow on the thlngs #
# You know #
# Feathers fall #
# Around you #
# Show you the way to go #
# It's over #
# M mm ##
U m...
I'm sorry, Noname.
M ind if I use the bed?
Okay.
Turned my life
inside out.
Almost lost it
all in the park.
U h...
apologized to the dog.
You ready to go to work?
All right.
All systems go.
How's your
play going?
Great!
Really great, I think.
Or it's just a...
a really good version
of shit; I-I don't know.
Am I in it?
U h... yeah.
I mean, yeah, sort of.
I mean, you know, I mean,
the characters aren't...
um, they're different.
Nothing's real
in the play, so...
I bet I'll be able to
tell who everyone is.
Oh, oh, really,
you think so?
Look, let me
just read...
"All I'm asking is
for you to do... "
Sorry. "All I'm
asking for you to do
"is be with my family.
"J ust go on the goddamn
happy hike, Gabe!
You don't have to be happy,
just get off your goddamn ass. "
U m, and then the character
named Gabriel says:
" I think I'm coming down with
something, altitude sickness.
"Or Republican flu.
"J ust go without me.
Maybe I'll catch up. "
What do you think?
It's okay.
Yeah, see, it's all...
It's good.
You're gonna change the
character names, though, right?
Yes. Well, no, it's...
H mm.
Good point.
Do you miss me?
Yeah.
Of course. Always.
And Mom?
Do you miss Mom?
Sure.
This Winston guy,
he seems...
good guy, huh?
Yeah. He's
really nice,
but he's not
there that much.
Yeah.
He seems good
for your mom, yeah?
Hey, you know what?
I'm-I'm kind of hungry.
Are you hungry? You
want to get some dinner?
Dad...
who do you see?
Besides your funny
toilet and Noname and me.
I don't know,
you know? I...
I like just seeing
me and you and Noname.
Why don't you
see Cari?
Why don't
I see Cari?
U hhh, yeah, well,
I don't know,
you might know more
about that than me.
I don't.
She told me
not to worry.
That made me worry.
What else
did she...?
No, you know what,
I don't really want to...
talk about this, is th...
is that okay? Yeah?
I know I'm
just a kid...
But I hate
seeing you alone.
I mean,
you always told me:
"Success is nothing
without someone
to share it with. "
Know what I mean?
Good thing I'm
not successful.
Did I say that?
Actually, Billy Dee Williams
did in Mahogany, but you know.
Ah, right.
I'm serious.
I mean...
being alone is okay,
but being alone with
someone is good, too.
And you, you, you...
smarty, smart.
How did you get
so smart, you?
I guess I got
it from Mom.
Oh, really?
You're probably right.
I'm joking.
"M ultlple Sarcasms,
a stage experience
by Gabriel Richmond"?
You finally
finished this time?
Yeah, but
not totally.
I mean, I don't know, I
like it, I like it a lot,
but it's...
it's kind of...
I don't have anyone to bounce
stuff off, just my dog, so...
Okay, like what
kind of stuff?
I don't know,
like, the other day
I was thinking "douche bag,
" the word "douche bag. "
It's funny, right?
Yeah, it's funny
in a kind of...
sophomoric way, but...
Yeah, or "colostomy bag"
- that's funny.
Ah, see, I like that.
See? Total collaboration.
I just really like
that; that's great.
Am I in it?
'Cause you know if I'm in it,
I'm gonna be easy to spot.
Oh, you think you're gonna
be easy to spot, huh?
No, see, I
made you a...
a dwarf...
named, uh, Rockette.
Fine Negro enters stage left
- that's me, bitch.
Wait, wait, wait!
Okay. Over here.
Go over there.
Ah, perfect!
Again, again!
Come on, try it.
What a dweeb!
And got It I
I know what
you're thinking.
We all got Liza.
The truth is...
It's not that
your timing sucks.
She's my best friend and she thinks
I'm talking about fucking
up our relationship.
You're just drunk.
But pure love
is... scary.
We are soul mates.
Very self-serving.
You should have no other
choices, but you do...
Hey.
Hey I
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
This is definitely
the fun part.
I am holding what I
hope will guarantee you
at least 14
minutes of fame.
And I got
enough copies
for you to send to anybody
who's ever fucked you over.
Oh, It's what we call
"I told you so" coples.
What...? Oh.
It's pretty
exciting, huh?
Yeah. So, look who I ran
into on the street outside.
Hey.
I'll just let you two
alone to enjoy the moment.
I gotta be
going, anyway.
Oh, Gabriel, I want to
see you back at the office.
The producers want to take
us out to dlnner tonlght,
which is a
very good sign.
When a play opens,
they either send you flowers
with a condescending note,
or they take you out
to dinner.
Dlnner means
you're a hlt.
Dinner's good.
All right, well, see you later.
Hey, Noname,
guess who's here?
Look who's
here, yeah.
Ohhh. So you
were there, huh?
U h, yeah.
Hey, pooh, what's
new with you, huh?
How you doing?
You-You saw it?
The play's
really good.
Some of it
hurt, but...
Of course, I was there.
No, actually, I knew you
were there. Lizzy told me.
Hey, dld you want some,
uh, tea, or somethlng?
U h, no, no, um...
U m, Winston and Lizzy
are waiting for me
at the gallery.
Oh, okay.
How's Winston?
Good.
You saw it.
You liked it?
I did.
You did it. I mean, you did it.
Yeah, yeah,
I did it.
Yeah.
Only at the expense
of everything.
You look good.
Happy.
You seem happy.
Yeah, I am.
And proud, too,
I guess, that I...
you know, that
I did this.
Well, you should be.
Wanna get married?
Oh.
Yeah.
Oh, I thought I'd see
Cari at the theater,
and then Llzzy sald
that there was-
I don't know-what,
a misunderstanding?
I mean, I haven't seen
her for a while myself.
A misunder... Well,
I guess I misunderstood
the mlsunderstandlng. No.
Well, whatever it is,
I'm sorry.
So, uh, you were in
the neighborhood?
Well, I drop Lizzy off,
you pick her up, and
I've wanted to call
for a while,
and I just...
wanted to tell you
how happy I am for you.
Thank you.
Annie, listen,
I realize that...
all along I really should
have been just so much more...
U m, no, no, don't.
I know.
Oh.
You, take
care of hlm.
Not a word.
If you could
wrlte It over...
Oh, boy.
would you be
less selflsh?
More brave?
Or would you
do It the same?
Gabrlel-
walks over to Mari,
cutting her off before
she can say anything.
I know what
you're thinking.
"Where was he ten years ago?" Right?
Wrong.
Think about what Ann and
I got out of the marriage.
We all got Liza.
She's such a
beautiful girl.
And you loved Ann
as much as I did.
I think that we all got
most of our immature bugs out
over the last ten years.
We weren't hiding
from the truth.
We were waiting for
the truth to find us.
Sorry.
Are you serious?
Is this really the schmaltz
you're gonna throw at me?
It's pretty
corny, huh?
We weren't hiding
from the truth.
It's just that the
lie got bigger.
Hey, guys.
How's it going?
Yeah, this
is a bitch.
Why don't you
let me try?
I love you,
and I'm sure of it.
I'm sure of
it forever.
When I wake up
hung over tomorrow,
I'll be sure of it.
And I'll tell you
the same tomorrow,
tell you the
same next week,
I'll tell you
the same next year.
I love you forever,
and I am sure of it.
and I am sure of It.
I love you... forever.
And I'm sure of It.
This is working?
I'm feellng slck
from all that
fake stage booze.
Why don't you
flll In for me
for the sex scene?
All right.
I thlnk I'm In love
wlth both of you.
Can we have
a three-way?
I guess that's It.
Happy ever after.
So thls Is
how It works.
# Nestled In your wlngs
My llttle one #
# Thls speclal mornlng
Brlngs another sun #
# Tomorrow #
"Zoom...
"Now I have never been more sober.
# Today #
For the past
few months... "
# When you see me
Fly away wlthout you #
# Shadow on the thlngs
You know #
# Feathers fall around you #
# And show you
The way to go #
# It's over #
# H mm, mm-mm-mm ##
# I llsten to the wlnd,
To the wlnd of my soul #
Captaln and Tennllle.
Looks more like
Gllllgan's Island to me.
You in three years.
What would
you change?
Would you do any of It
dlfferently If you could?
# I've sat upon
The settlng sun #
If you could
wrlte It over?
Hey.
H i.
# Never #
# I never
Wanted water once #
# No, never,
never, never #
M mm.
# I llsten to my words,
But they fall far below #
# Yeah, I let my muslc take me
Where my heart wants to go #
# I swam upon
The devll's lake #
# But never, never,
Ever, never #
# I'll never make
The same mlstake #
# No, never, never, never ##
# I just need
To know your name #
# That's all I want #
# Could you tell me
How to call? #
# That's all I want #
# Can't Imaglne anythlng
That could be so cool #
# All just a matter
Of all I want #
# Would you care
To have me In? #
# That's all I want #
# Could you flx me
Somethlng nlce? #
# That's all I want #
# Can't Imaglne anythlng
That could be so cool #
# All just a matter
Of all I want #
# I want and need #
# All the love
That you can glve me #
# I want the deed To your
heart, If You're wllllng #
# Can I tell you
How I feel? #
# That's all I want #
# I just need
To have you near #
# That's all I want #
# I want and need #
# All the love
That you can glve me #
# I want the deed To your
heart, If You're wllllng #
# Would you lead me
To your room? #
# That's all I want #
# Can I stay
Wlth you tonlght? #
# That's all I want #
# That's all I want ##