SOCIAL PSYCHOLOGY
TAUGHT US AN IMPORTANT LESSON
IT'S NOT A PERSON'S CHARACTER
THAT DETERMINES HOW THEY ACT,
BUT THE SITUATION IN WHICH THEY
FIND THEMSELVES
STANLEY MILGRAN (1974)
SOCIAL PSYCHOLOGIST
(Song) "Dendê's hill is tough to invade"
"We'll have a lot of fun if they even try"
"I'll tell ya how it is around here"
"We make it hard on them, even the DEA"
"Even the BOPE shivers when marching uphill"
"Cause we give them hell, be the Army, State or Military Police"
"I offer my props to my friends"
"Dendê's hill is also land of God."
"Have Faith! DJ!"
My city has over 700 slums.
Most of them dominated by
drug dealers, armed to the teeth.
They carry AR15,
Pisto-UZI, HK and more...
In the rest of the world, these
weapons are used for wars.
In Rio, they're the
weapons for crime.
A 7.62 round can pierce a car
as if it was made of paper.
It's foolish to believe that in
such a city...
...the cops would go to the slums
just to enforce the law.
Cops have their families, too.
They're afraid to die.
- So, where to now?
- This way, come on!
What happened here
was inevitable.
The gangs and the police
had to come to an agreement.
After all, nobody wants
to die in vain.
The pigs are coming,
Marcinho!
They're here for their pay.
Fumaca, give them the money.
You two, cover them!
In Rio, peace is based
on a delicate balance...
...between the drug lord’s
bullets and policemen's corruption.
Honesty is not part
of this game.
When honest cops go
to the slums...
...terrible things happen.
- Are they still inside the car?
- Can you see Fabio?
- You won't need your gun!
- You'll leave me unarmed?
Get out! Get the fuck out!
- Can you see Fabio?
- Calm down!
Do you see him?
- Are you seeing them?
- Calm down!
What's up, Oliveira?
Back here again?
Where's our money?
Shit!
What's going on?
Wait!
- Oh fuck...
- Have you seen Fabio?
- Calm down, man.
- What? Tell me!
In Rio, every policeman
has to choose.
Between being corrupt
and looking the other way.
Or going to war.
That night Neto y Matias
chose the same...
...I did ten years ago.
They chose going to war.
Fuck! Who did you
shoot, man?
- Who did you shoot?
- Come on! Move!
- Shit! Who's shooting?
- There're two cops!
Shit!
They're coming this way!
Fuck!
They think they can
mess with us?
Fuck!
Run!
- Shit!
- We're outnumbered!
- Keep shooting!
- We're going to die!
Neto and Matias didn't
have any chance.
Normal policemen are
not trained for war.
I don't have any bullets left!
Cool it!
Let's be careful.
A lot of people are at that party.
We have to be careful.
Maybe there're some policemen.
I'm not a regular cop.
I'm BOPE, a special squad
in Rio
- Who's familiar with Babilonia?
- I am.
- Ok, you'll lead us
- We'll go by the main road.
In theory, we're all
part of the police system.
In practice we're
completely different.
Our symbol shows
who we are.
Our uniform is not blue,
but black.
Nobody goes in!
None of you!
Everybody stays here!
BOPE always gets called in when
other forces are in trouble.
And this always happens
in Rio.
You think we're stupid
enough to go in?
I'm Captain Nascimento.
BOPE's Alpha leader.
I'd been at war for a few years.
I was getting tired of it.
6 MONTHS BEFORE
Honey, I'd like to be home with you,
but I have to work.
Do you hear the heart beating?
Let me listen.
It's strong, and very fast.
I have to go back to
work, honey.
Don't worry, I'll put it
in the oven.
I love you too.
I don't know what I hated most,
the drug lords or the corrupt cops...
How are you, Pompeu?
- Did you bring the guns?
- Yeah.
The police force used to have
around 30.000 men.
With those numbers, they
could've ended the drug trade.
But they weren't properly equipped
and their salaries were low.
People like that
didn't care.
I'd love to shoot at them.
Which ones Captain?
Just tell me.
Those fucking cops.
BOPE only had a hundred men.
For each gun that was found,
three more were sold on the streets.
14, let them go in.
We'll get them on their way out.
If I shoot, I may also
hit the cop.
- Both of them?
- Of course.
Then, shoot...
To me, the ones that helped
the gangs were just as bad.
I'll admit it.
I had bad temper.
My life was getting more complicated
every day.
- Good morning!
- Good morning, honey!
- Let me bring...
- Sit down, I'll take them.
No honey, I have to go.
I have to work early.
You just got here and you're
going again?
- I didn't have a good night.
- How's the baby?
When I worry, he knows and
I don't gain weight.
What do you want
me to do?
If I'd known it would be like this,
I wouldn't have gotten pregnant.
Bye!
Wait, at least eat a sandwich.
Beto!
In war, there's always a
price to be paid.
And when it's too high,
it's time to get out.
This is where Neto and Matias
came in the picture.
Captain Fabio,
Maintenance Chief.
Captain Oliveira,
3rd District Chief.
They started the same war,
in their own districts.
I was also impressed
on the first day.
Welcome, Lieutenants!
From now on,
you're under my orders.
Each day, my men and
I will evaluate you.
I'm honored to be in front
of these men,
who are not only part of one big family,
but are also the very best officers.
Neto and Matias believed
everything.
They were angels.
But I needed people like them.
Actually, I needed
one to have the brains...
...and the other one,
the heart.
It would've been great to have
both in one person.
But who said life was easy?
You'll work here, Neto.
- Is this the car repair shop?
- Yeah, is that a problem?
Can't you put me somewhere else?
I don't know anything about cars!
There're 46 cars and 12 motorcycles.
We need all of them
to be working.
- Captain!
- At ease.
These two are your
assistants.
- Car 249 will be ready today.
- Finally, Tiao!
Yeah, but we're still waiting for the spare parts.
So I took some parts from this one.
But it's new!
You're going to take it apart?
There're some good parts here.
I've already fixed two cars.
Whatever, Tiao!
It doesn't matter to me.
This is the rookie.
- Sir!
- Lieutenant!
- At ease.
- You too.
- Have a sandwich, coffee, or water.
- I'm not hungry.
Get to work, I need this
car today.
- Without the spare parts?
- I don't care. It has to work.
Neto was impulsive,
he acted without thinking.
Matias thought too much
before acting.
You see these piles of papers?
They're all unsolved crimes.
In Neto's hands,
they would've burned.
In Matias' hands, they
are statistics.
This is Lieutenant Matias,
your new boss.
- How are you boss!
- Lieutenant, your assistants.
Corporal Bruno and Private Machado,
you have to fix the radios.
- And organize the files?
- Yes, sir.
- Your desk is over there.
- Sorry, boss.
Let me know if you need anything.
Carry on.
Neither one of them
had my expertise.
But one of them would have
to replace me.
Listen...
Matias was smart and hardworking.
In Brazil, a poor black man doesn't
have many opportunities.
But Matias didn't care about that.
He wanted to be a lawyer.
So he enrolled in Rio's
best law school.
Groups of four!
Then, choose one of these.
I want you to read Foucault.
We're only three,
we need one more.
It was a privilege for a cop
to belong to the establishment.
Matias was very naive. He thought
studying law would help him enforce it.
He thought cops and lawyers
had the same mission.
I'll hand it in anyway
The professor won't notice.
But, to be part of my team,
he would have to be realistic.
- Sociology?
- Yeah, what's your name?
- Andre.
- Andre what?
- Andre Matias, why?
- You're in our group.
I'll explain in a second.
Discipline and Punish by Foucault.
Hi, Maria!
Dudu and Roberta.
If you're a BOPE officer,
you have to set certain limits.
You know the Pope is
coming to Rio?
He wants to stay at the
Bishop's house.
That's quite close to the
Turano slums.
We have to guarantee him a
peaceful stay.
Turano is a war zone!
I would pay for him to stay
at the Copacabana Hotel.
I already tried to convince
the governor...
...but not even God can change
the Pope's mind.
He'll just stay there for
that night.
He can't hear any gunshots,
we have three months to clean up.
- We'll go at night.
- Are you sure?
If we go every night,
they'll wait for us and kill us.
- There'll be a lot of dead people!
- Nascimento!
We'll start tomorrow.
Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
- You may go now.
I know it's not the Pope's fault,
but he's already been here twice.
Doesn't he know how things
work here?
No politician wants the
Pope to get shot in their city.
If the Pope wanted to
stay near a slum...
What would the governor do?
Would he take that risk?
Of course not. He'll call
in BOPE.
Stop that Neto.
I'm trying to study.
Take a break.
Let's go for a ride.
Are you going to use your
car tomorrow?
- What do you need it for?
- I'm going to the Prazeres slum.
Are you crazy?
What for?
I'm going to meet my classmates
over there at an NGO.
You're a cop, they'll kill you.
Calm down Neto
No one knows I'm a cop.
Be careful.
The Pope needed BOPE.
BOPE needed me.
And I needed to find
a replacement.
It wasn't going to
be easy.
I'd have to keep visiting
the slums.
But I'd go dressed in black
and carrying my gun.
I didn't mind that Matias
was studying.
The problem was that he didn't
know cops were different.
Hi Andre!
I'm glad you came!
This is Rose.
And Elena.
This one is cuter than
the other guy.
You're being very flirty, Rose.
That's why I came here.
Don't keep staring, bye!
Sorry I made you come here.
This is the office
and this is Rodrigues.
Rodrigues, Andre.
He represents the senator that founded
this and he's a good friend of mine.
Do you have a candidate?
Now you do!
Senator Magalhaes. Number 4-5-1.
Take some to give away.
5 minus 4 is 1. 4 plus 1 is 5
Don't forget!
It's hard to resist.
Who can resist a pretty girl
with good intentions?
Who wouldn't want to
get in her group?
Hi Romerito!
This is Andre.
But a cop has to set limits.
- Maria, can we go to the arcade?
- Not today, I have to work.
- Don't you have homework?
- Yeah, but I'll do it later.
But you promised you'd
study!
- I know.
- After rehearsal, you'll go home.
- Okay.
- Now, go back to class.
- Does he have problems at school?
- He's not doing very well.
- You know why?
- He doesn't like to study.
Maybe it's not that.
I don't know how Matias didn't realize
what he was getting into.
You can't be a cop and be
popular at the same time.
Foucault believed the power's
structure created the law.
It's not bound by social contract.
Understand?
Power institutionalizes
the different methods...
...that'll be used to discipline
and punish criminals.
As they used to do in the
old prisons.
I'm high.
Historically, with these institutions
the state could impose...
- Here, Andre.
- No, thanks. I don't like it.
- One puff?
- No, thanks.
Give it to me, Roberta.
- It's all I have.
- It's good!
You did a good job!
This project is due
next week.
- Did you do your part, Dudu?
- Of course.
Matias shouldn't have
been there.
But since he was there, he should've
arrested them under the 6368 law.
He was just starting his career
and he was already doing wrong.
- Guys!
- What's going on?
- I think we did a good job.
- Romerito.
- Weren't you going to study?
- Yeah.
- Look, he failed!
- He can't even see the marble.
- Let me take you home.
- One second.
- Can you lend me your hand?
- What are you doing?
I think you're right.
He looks to the opposite side.
Let's see how you do.
What letter is this?
- It's an "A".
- Good.
- Now, what letter is this?
- I don't know.
- It's also an "A".
- Really?
The boy needs glasses.
Did you notice?
Is that why he's doing poorly?
I had the same problem when
I was his age.
Let's go tell your mom.
- Come with us, Andre.
- Where? Upstairs?
To be a BOPE captain,
Matias would have to act quickly.
Just as the gangsters do.
They won't make fun of you and
you'll have good grades.
Tinho, Bica...
What's up?
- I wrote the test.
- Did you pass?
- Easy.
- You see? Studying helps.
Don't worry.
Here, they have social conscience.
Relax.
- What's happening?
- Bye, Roberta!
- Glasses are for nerds.
- Andre uses glasses.
- Maria, I have to go.
- Why so early, Andre?
I have to return my
friend's car.
That's too bad.
I'll take the boy to buy his
glasses another day.
No, Andre, we'll take
care of it.
Somebody helped me when I was
a kid, so now I'll do the same.
- Ok, I'll see you!
- Bye!
No NGO can be run without
the drug lordÂ’s help.
This talk about "social conscience"
was just crap.
To me, a drug dealer was
a drug dealer.
- What's up, Baiano?
- Hi!
I know how Baiano's story ended,
but not how it started.
He probably had a
bad childhood.
It's not an excuse, but that's how
most of them become gangsters.
- Hey, goldilocks?
- I think it snowed.
- You have the money?
- Here.
Xaveco, he gave me two kilos.
The bad thing is that rich kids
also end up as drug dealers.
For me, there's no excuse.
- Hey, what's new?
- Nothing, just freezing to death.
- Bruno! How are you?
- Hi!
- Hey!
- How are you?
- Marcio, I have the good stuff.
- Come in.
Patty, how are you?
I'll be back in a minute.
Here it is.
- Is this all you have?
- Shit!
- It's hard to get it.
- Next time bring more.
There's enough for two kilos.
Get more because people are
getting high like crazy.
I always ask myself how
many kids we lose to drugs.
So many rich kids dealing drugs.
Our goal is to find the weapons,
we'll use channel two.
Azevedo's team will go to
the Bishop's house.
- Renan's team will go to Tamandare street.
- Yes, sir.
Nascimento, do you know
117 street?
Captain Nascimento?
Do you know where it is?
I know that street, Captain.
It's close to the university
and it's full with students.
I already told you this
was a bad idea.
Nascimento, these are our orders.
We'll reunite at the center
of the slum.
- Understood?
- Skulls!
For me, strategy is a good idea
only when it works.
But, Operation Holiness
was quite stupid.
I couldn't be reckless.
I was going to be a father.
I didn't want to die for
no reason.
- Get down!
- On the floor!
- Down!
Are you ok, Captain?
- Where's the dealer?
- It's one of them, sir.
Line them up!
Quickly!
I'm only going to ask
this once!
Who's the dealer?
Who is it?
- I'm a student!
- You're what?
- A student!
- Just a student?
Ok, come here.
Look at your friend.
Look closely.
You see this hole?
Who killed him?
Who?
- I don't know.
- I think you do.
Tell me!
It was one of you!
One of us?
You killed him!
Faggot!
You finance this shit!
Fucking drug addict!
We came here to clean up
your mess.
You give them money!
Cowards!
Who's the dealer?
0-7, bring the lookout.
Let's see.
Now we'll see.
Tell me!
Come on!
Who is it?
Tell me now!
The one with the jacket?
Take him and the drugs to
headquarters.
Captain, are you ok?
Let him go.
Go!
To conclude, we believe the
Brazilian laws...
...create a web of power...
...that unfortunately,
...always end up protecting the rich.
Therefore, punishing
the poor.
Good!
I think Maria and her group...
...showed us that abuse of power...
...helps to create bad institutions.
Who can give me an example?
- Police?
- Ok.
Tell us why.
Everybody knows the police
go to the slums...
...to get money from the people.
So, Edu, the police is against
poor people.
And against those who are
forced into committing crime.
Professor? I heard what
Edu said, but...
I don't think the police targets
only...
...poor people.
We're also victims.
The middle and upper classes.
Once, Maria and I were going to
Buzios, and they stopped us.
The policemen were very
aggressive.
Did they beat you?
No, they pointed their
guns at us.
Settle down!
- Go on.
- My father is a judge.
He says the police go to
the slums...
...and kills everybody, just like in the
Candelaria Massacre.
They're not only corrupt, but
cowards as well.
Calm down!
Matias wants to say something.
Professor, everybody here has a superficial
idea of what goes on.
- They're poorly informed.
- Let him speak!
I know there's corruption, but there're
many honest policemen as well.
- Are you crazy?
- You're wrong, Andre.
Dudu is right.
Who hasn't been detained?
- It's routine.
- No.
They only want our money!
I've heard on the news that
in the slums...
...they shoot first and ask
questions later.
It's not like that.
Let him finish.
I have a friend who's a policeman
and his best friend as well.
They're honest.
I mean, sometimes they have
to be tough.
You're crazy!
What did you smoke?
You have no idea how many kids
die because of drug dealing.
You can't see that from your
nice apartments.
All you know is what you see
and read from the media.
That'll be all for today.
Mr. Nascimento?
Were you in charge of the
latest operation?
Yes.
I wanted to ask if you could allow
me to burry my son.
Your son was involved
with drugs.
Yes, he was the lookout.
- We didn't kill him.
- But you let him go, right?
Did you think they were
going to forgive him?
The gangsters kill those
who make mistakes.
And I knew that.
That mother made me
feel guilty.
And this was dangerous for
a BOPE officer.
Was he your only son?
Yes.
It was time to find my
replacement.
- Battery.
- Sure.
- And a carburetor.
- Wait, let him finish.
Brakes, clutch,
oil filters...
...and a broken windshield.
Sir, this one needs a carburetor.
- Carburetor, ok
- That's correct, sir.
This car doesn't have a carburetor.
It has an electronic injection.
- Does it have one or not?
- No.
- Listen! It has one!
- Are you kidding?
- Of course not.
- It has a damn carburetor.
- No.
Look, here it is.
He's right, sir.
It has one.
That's because the original
engine was replaced.
Everything is loose.
What?
Some cop sold the original engine
and replaced it with an old one.
- Who?
- I don't know, sir.
Forget it.
This happens all the time.
The other day, somebody
stole a radio.
Are they crazy?
If they steal they can go to jail.
- Yes, of course.
- Are you listening to me? Jesus!
If the police had any brains...
...they wouldn't have allowed somebody
like Neto to be in charge...
Neto was just like me.
When he had a mission,
he'd never quit.
Such bad luck.
- I have a problem, sir.
- What is it? I'm in a hurry.
A policeman changed the car engine,
right under our noses.
- Do you know who?
- No, but...
Ok, rookie. I'll tell the Commander to
open an investigation.
- And you'll be in charge.
- Me?
But I have to fix these cars,
I need new parts.
Just make sure the Commander's
motorcycle works.
- That's your priority!
- Yes, sir.
- Captain.
- What is it?
These are the parts that
we're missing.
They're too many!
I'll take a look.
Why don't you ask Fabio
for help?
- Can't you help me, sir?
- Dismissed!
What would the corrupt cops do?
They'd tell him to work the system.
Neto, I'll include you,
but don't forget my part.
Captain, I need to fix the cars,
I didn't come here to be a mechanic.
- Sir, where are we going?
- Follow our damn route.
The first time is always for
a good cause.
Once you steal for the police, you're
also going to do it for your family.
That's how the system
works.
When citizens ask for a police
car to watch out for their bakery...
...or a bar, they have to pay.
I'm here for my "protection pay"
Are you going to pay today?
Yes, Captain.
But I already paid.
- You didn't give me anything!
- I already paid Oliveira's men.
Oliveira?
Sir, If I also have to pay you,
I'll go broke.
No, I'll break you.
I protect you and you
pay Oliveira?
Talk to him, you work together.
Let's go, Neto
- How much for the beer?
- It's on the house.
No, I want to pay.
Take it.
The policemen ended up
charging for everything.
For doing their job
and for looking the other way.
That guy is giving tickets
to my customers.
I can't give you new parts
with this.
- Who ordered this?
- My parts! I need a battery.
Look at him! He's giving tickets.
Come here!
- What's wrong Captain?
- Come here.
This is my area
Why are you giving tickets?
- I'm following orders.
- From whom?
- From Bira.
- Bira?
- Bira, come here!
- I can't right now!
An example...
The government was so bankrupt,
it couldn't even buy cranes.
So they had to rent them from
an independent contractor.
Come here!
Wait!
The cranes would give so
much damn profit...
...so the system decided
to absorb them.
You can't tow away cars here.
I work with him.
Captain, this is Oliveira's man.
Here, we work with him.
- And my parts?
- Wait.
Oliveira?
This is Captain Fabio.
I came for some spare parts, but
I learned that this is your area.
Commander, it's Fabio.
He's messing with our arrangement.
Cut his wings.
Go to hell, Fabio.
This is my area now.
- Your area?
- Yeah, get used to it.
Tell him about my parts!
Hello? This idiot hung up on me!
And my parts?
Can't you at least get me
a battery?
- Isn't this the Commander's motorcycle?
- He comes for his pay on Fridays.
That's why the motorcycle
always has to work.
- Shit, now I understand!
- Yes, we use it for our payment.
Now the Commander wants
it all.
The system was so corrupt, that
everybody was stealing from somebody else.
Sergeant, my vacation time
is coming next month.
- My wife and I will go away.
- That's nice!
I'd like to finish the paperwork,
so I can go.
I'm sorry, but I can't.
I have 40 policemen before you.
And our district needs you.
Maybe I can talk to the boss
to see if he'll let you go.
- I have to follow procedure.
- But, Sergeant...
I haven't taken vacation
in four years.
- I have to follow rules.
- Maybe I can help you.
I want to help you, but you
also have to help me.
Corporal Paulo, do you want to be happy?
First, you have to make me happy!
Am I right?
You have to make me happy.
Understood, sir.
- Permission to leave, Sergeant.
- Go ahead.
This is a serious accusation.
- He tried to bribe you.
- Can you prove it?
If you can't, they're just rumors.
Listen rookie, you do your job
and I'll do mine.
- Understood?
- Yes, sir.
Dismissed.
Neto, wanted to work
for the police.
But he ended just like me.
Working against them.
Honey, are you coming upstairs?
Are you ok?
You don't feel well?
Beto!
Is everything ok?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
- I can't breathe.
- Calm down, honey.
- My arm is numb.
- It's not your heart.
It's stress, trust me.
- Nascimento, your test results are fine.
- Are you sure?
I have a family history of
heart attacks.
My father died from a
heart attack.
Your heart is fine.
Sometimes I feel a buzzing sound in my ear,
and my hands shake as well.
Your problem is not physical.
You have too much stress.
I'm referring you to a psychiatrist.
- Psychiatrist?
- It's harmless.
When Matias defended them,
he didn't know how rotten they were.
He studied the criminal reports
for two months.
And he came up with a
plan to place...
...police cars in strategic places.
But efficiency didn't work
well in this district.
Sometimes it seemed stopping
crime...
...was the Commander's
least important priority.
Shit, Estevao!
This report is going to kill me!
Twelve homicides in one month?
I can't report this.
Commander, I checked your report
and I thought it was ok.
- You want to ruin me?
- No, sir.
Then, go get Fabio.
And these four dead bodies?
The report was correct.
Didn't you see the graphics?
I don't care about numbers.
Now this idiot wants to tell me
where to put patrol cars?
When there was a crime in a specific district,
the Commander was responsible for solving it.
But that was a tough job.
- You wanted to see me, sir?
- Yes.
- Something wrong?
I want you to explain the dead
bodies in Tabajara.
It wasn't my fault.
I did everything you told me.
No bodies were found in District 19.
This was in District 2, understood?
Yes.
It's easier to change the scene of the crime
than to find the criminal.
There were many corrupt commanders
that changed the numbers...
...leaving dead bodies in
other districts.
But on some nights, it was just
like the musical chair game.
The bodies are in district 19.
Understood?
Sir, I took the bodies
but they returned them...
- I don't want to hear it.
- But, Commander...
- Enough!
- Yes, sir.
You have to rewrite the report.
Look,
"Body found on the beach"
He drowned by the beach,
not our problem.
- But there was a gun wound.
- Are you a judge?
- No, sir.
- I want a new report by Monday.
Because this one never existed.
If you don't talk, I can't
help you.
Well...
It's not easy to open up.
I don't know...
What if you tell my superiors
everything I say?
It's better if you talk to one
of my friends...
...who's going to be a father and
has big problems.
Captain...
I can't help you unless you tell
me what your problem is.
And this is not a confessionary.
It's the Psychiatric Unit.
Between you and I...
...if I had to tell everything...
...there wouldn't be any
policemen in Rio.
So, you decide.
Will you tell me or not?
Excuse me.
Captain, I'll replace you as
soon as I can.
I need you for the Pope
operation.
I gave you a task,
so now, go and do it.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
Dismissed.
Call it fate, but...
...the same day I had lost
hope of leaving BOPE...
...was the day when Neto
came in with his plan.
- Hi Neto!
- Do you have my car keys?
What are you doing?
You ruining my map!
I found a way to get the
cars fixed.
Let's go, we need to tell Fabio.
- What?
- Follow me.
You're going crazy!
The Commander is ruining everything.
What's that?
I'm broke.
He's taking everything.
Oliveira is taking everything.
Does this club pay you?
Yeah, so what?
I don't go stealing from the slums.
So I can get shot for 500
dollars a month.
I can't believe this!
I was good before.
I was honest.
But the Commander is taking
everything.
- The gangsters pay him?
- You're so naive.
Haven't you seen his men going
to the slums every week?
They go to collect their money.
How much?
At least six a week.
Maybe more.
That asshole gets a lot
of money!
I know how we can get
that money.
- What do I have to do?
- How?
You want to keep the money?
No! We'll use the money to
repair the cars.
- Ok, but how much am I getting?
- You want to get back at the Commander?
Are you kidding?
You're the ones who want to ruin me.
- I'm going to the bathroom.
- Wait a minute, Fabio.
Andre, you won't back down
on me.
The timing was perfect.
It took Matias 40 minutes to get...
to the Commander's best place.
This is where Neto would
come in.
- Try again, see if works.
- Hurry up, I'm late.
- Try again.
- I'm late.
You think it's easy?
You fix it.
- I think it'll work.
- Yeah?
It's very late.
It'll take some time to fix it.
Hurry up and talk to Paulo.
He'll fix it.
By the time he left,
Matias already had the cash.
How are you, Santos?
Feeling better?
What do you mean?
Your friend came and said
you were sick.
- Me?
- Yeah, we gave him the money.
Who?
He said the Commander sent him,
so we gave him the money.
Son of a bitch!
It was a brilliant plan.
What could the Commander do?
Call the police?
Neto worked the system
perfectly.
It was a brilliant plan but
also very risky.
The Commander wasn't going
to like this.
At least Neto fought fire
with fire.
Matias kept making the
same mistakes.
There's Andre.
Let's go talk to him.
- No, I'm busy.
- Me too.
- See you!
- Bye!
- Where've you been hiding?
- Hi!
Look who just arrived.
Shit, they're going to arrest us!
What's up guys?
- Mary!
- Maria!
- Everything ok?
- Where were you?
We lost track of time.
- You look very pretty.
- You too.
- Who wants to dance?
- We're a bit busy.
- Let's dance.
- Ok, I'll see you later.
Only because we have
nice apartments!
Yeah, I'm going with him
for little while.
As long as he doesn't end
up messing with us.
I think somebody's messing
with me.
It doesn't matter.
Let's keep dancing.
They ask you to obey
and respond
They ask for your cooperation
and respect
Police for those who need it
What do you need the
police for?
Police for those who need it
What do you need the
police for?
Too much salt,
you have to put potatoes.
When the Commander heard he'd
been robbed, he couldn't complain.
So he used this situation
to get revenge.
The Cornell couldn't complain.
He placed Matias as a cook.
Neto got stuck in the
repair shop.
What are you doing here,
Paulo?
They cancelled my vacations,
so I wouldn't complain.
And the shop?
But without their best mechanic.
Guava jam?
Neto, I told you this wouldn't
end well.
The Commander was sure you
were following orders.
From somebody high up who knew
the system quite well.
Fabio!
- Yes, sir.
- Come here.
- Are you working tonight?
- Yes, sir.
I want you to watch
the party at Babilonia.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
- Yes, sir.
- Tonight.
- Tonight?
- Yes, sir.
The Commander would punish
him the most...
...otherwise, the story of Neto and Matias
would've been quite different.
Honey, it's moving!
It's the most beautiful
thing I've seen.
Too bad you're not here.
I want you to hear the
heart beat.
Every time I thought of my son,
it would remind me of that kid's mother.
Must be really hard not being
able to burry your own son.
Get dressed! We're leaving!
- Where are we going, Captain?
- To Turano.
We're going to find
that kid's body.
The Cornell asked me to do this.
If we do a good job, we'll get
lots of money.
Don't tell the rookie, otherwise
he'll rob us.
What are you doing
with this rifle?
You think you're going to
the slum with me?
- You stay here, I'm in charge.
- Ok, no problem.
Captain, the brigade will
go with Cabral.
- The Commander told me to stay.
- No, you come with me.
Rookie, put down that rifle and go fix
the Commander's motorcycle.
Let's go, Fabio. Hurry up.
Neto, did you do what
we said?
- Yeah, why?
- Captain, let's go!
I'm coming.
I think they'll kill me.
- Matias.
- What's wrong?
- They already found out.
- What happened?
They think Fabio did it.
- What do we do?
- Come with me.
- You're in charge, Paulo.
- But, Lieutenant.
Get down!
- Do you see Fabio?
- Relax.
- What's going on?
- Calm down!
What's going on?
- You won't need this.
- You'll leave me unarmed?
Get out!
- Where's Fabio?
- Relax, I'll find him.
- You see him?
- Shut up!
What's up, Oliveira?
Back here again?
Where's our money?
They weren't going to shoot Fabio
in front of everybody.
But Neto saw the gangster
reaching for his gun.
Neto had a very restless finger, and he
thought the guy was going to grab his gun.
- Who did you shoot?
- Let's go.
Fuck!
What the hell ?
Fuck! They've gone crazy!
They're shooting at each other!
Cover me!
Do something.
I'm running out of bullets.
I just have one left.
Shit, the answering machine.
- Leave the message.
- Fucking idiot!
If Cabral gets promoted...
...that's one more district which would
mean even more money.
- How much more?
- Excuse me.
Commander, we need help!
We're outnumbered!
Call BOPE!
- Captain!
- What's wrong?
The police is getting hit at
Babilonia, they already killed one.
There's nobody.
They're all busy.
- What do I do?
- God!
Son, I'm no rush.
I can stay all night.
- Where's the lookout?
- I don't know!
You're in charge and you
don't know?
I'm not a dealer, boss.
I don't know.
We'll have to put on the
bag again.
- It's cold Captain.
- Throw water on his face.
Wake up, you idiot!
0-1, Babilonia is priority.
The police is outnumbered.
Understood, Carvalho.
We're on our way.
We'll go clean up your shit.
We'll go to Babilonia.
- What about him?
- Charge him on the Pope operation.
Shoot!
Keep shooting!
We're going to die!
- Shoot them!
- They're lost!
They're shooting at us
from below.
They can't get us from there.
Lower, Matias.
Shoot, you idiot!
- BOPE is here
- Everybody stay here!
Stay here!
- We're going to die, Neto.
- Shoot them!
- I don't have any more bullets!
- Then, stay down.
Shoot!
Shoot, Careca!
Fuck!
Shit!
They're coming towards us.
- Get down! Throw your gun!
- I'm a cop.
- We're policemen!
- Throw your guns!
- It's just you two?
- Yeah.
Come here, sit down.
Check the perimeter.
0-1, they're only two.
Bocao, check who we have.
- Marcinho, the drug czar.
- We have to take him.
- Are you ok?
- Yes, sir.
- Are you hurt?
- No, sir.
- Were you hit?
Tonight you'll learn to
carry corpses.
Yes, sir.
- What are you waiting for?
- Nothing, sir.
- Grab him.
- Lift him up.
Wait.
Hi, honey.
Did your water break?
Are you sure?
Calm down, remember what
the doctor said?
Don't rush, I'm on my way.
- 0-2.
- Sir?
You're in charge, let's just take this body.
I'm going to have a son!
Congratulations, Captain!
Quick!
God, this is a heavy one!
If you hadn't shown up, I would've
been killed.
- BOPE brought your gun.
- Help us with the body.
Let us through!
Get the fuck out of
here!
- Sergeant?
- What is it Lieutenant?
How can I join BOPE?
- You have to be selected.
- How?
Check the bulletin at the
police station.
- Thank you.
- Let's go.
Look at this, Carvalho.
- Commander.
- At ease.
- Sorry I'm late.
- No problem.
Tell me, boy or girl?
Boy, Rafael.
- What's this, Renan?
- Conjunctivitis.
- It looks awful.
- Put on your glasses.
Listen, this is a gift...
...not for you.
For your son.
It's time to pick your replacements.
Ok!
This will be BOPE's best
training camp.
I'm sure it will be.
Let's start,
number one, here.
- Yes, Andre Pedrosa.
- He receives payments.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
He's fucked.
He won't make it.
Commander, I also know Olavo.
He's as dirty as the
rest of them.
What about Fabio?
I've heard of him.
Let's skip Fabio.
I've already heard of him.
He's Captain, isn't he?
- Fabio Barbosa.
- He's heavy duty.
He's been a pimp in Copacabana.
- I'll take care of him.
- Renan?
- Can you see?
- Yes, sir.
The guy looks like Batman.
Renan, where are the
two rookies?
The ones you rescued?
I think they're ok.
- Let's see what they have.
- Listen.
I don't want hear of a
busted eardrum.
Or of some fingercuts.
Is that clear?
The guy's hand was an accident.
He grabbed the sable at
the wrong time.
- And the eardrum, Carvalho...
- It was an accident, Commander.
An accident?
He deserved it, Commander.
A BOPE officer could not go out
with a friend of a drug dealer.
Matias was confused.
He wanted to be a cop, but he also
wanted to be a lawyer.
If Matias was a true policeman,
he would've told his girlfriend.
But he made up a trip and asked
her for help getting a practicum.
He's been working with us
for almost a year.
He's done very well,
he solved all our problems.
Ok, listen...
He's away right now, could you do
the interview in two weeks?
Ok, great!
I was sure Matias would quit...
...halfway during training camp.
I got Matias a practicum!
It's best you get another
boyfriend.
What happened?
Is everything ok, Baiano?
You tell me.
Do you recognize anybody
in this picture?
You don't recognize this
piece of shit?
- It can't be him, Baiano.
- It can't be him!
He killed a friend of mine.
He killed one of us.
- What will happen now?
- Calm down.
Look Baiano, we have nothing
to do with this.
- I brought Matias.
- Maria didn't know he was a cop.
- I just found out now.
- We didn't know.
Don't fuck with me!
Let me tell you something,
these pigs are our enemies.
- Nobody knew.
- Shut up! I'm not finished.
Who do you think protects the slums?
The police?
Answer!
- The command.
- That's right, bitch.
And I'm the boss.
If you want to be here, you
need my blessing.
- We know.
- Which side are you on, pretty boy?
- Pretty boy?
- With you!
- We're all in this together!
- That's right, together!
It's us, Baiano.
I'll make you pay for this.
- Let's go.
- Shut up!
- Calm down!
- Xaveco, burn it.
- What's this?
- Son of a bitch!
You have to be honest with me.
If not, there'll be trouble.
Keep the paper.
Let's go.
Neto signed up because
he liked war.
Matias did it because he
believed in the law.
And the corrupt policeman?
Fabio was running away from the Commander.
Poor bastard!
He didn't know that I would
be much worse.
JULY 1997
TWO MONTHS BEFORE THE POPE'S VISIT
You're here on your
own free will.
Nobody...
...forced you to come here.
You're not welcomed here.
Prepare your souls...
...because your bodies belong
to us now.
I now declare the beginning of
the BOPE training camp.
You'll never survive.
Skulls, forward.
Idiots!
Sick bastards!
Some people see BOPE
as a cult.
But, it has to be that way.
- Ask me to leave! Beg me!
- No, sir!
We would train our men to resist
pain and humiliation.
To get in, they'd have to prove
they could handle pressure.
- Go back where you came from.
- No, sir.
- Go back to your district.
You think nobody knows that
gangs pay you?
That you get money from
the dealers?
You know why your number
is 0-1?
Because you'll be the first
one to quit.
I'll make you quit!
- Ask me to leave!
- No, sir.
If you don't do it, we'll
crush you.
- Beg, you idiot!
- Ok, I give up!
- 0-1 gave up.
- Skulls.
Of 100 policemen, 5 would stay.
When I got in, only three
of us passed.
Not even the Israeli army
trained like us.
The BOPE soldiers killed
guerrillas.
With knives in our mouth,
we would scalp them.
And we would
kill them with rifles.
The BOPE soldiers defend
Brazil's honor.
To fight against drugs...
...you'd have to be willing to
risk everything.
The concept of strategy...
...comes from the Greek
"strategia".
In Latin.
In French.
- Are you writing this down?
- Yes, sir.
It'll be on the exam.
In English.
In German.
In Italian.
In Spanish.
Coordinator.
- What is it?
- 0-5 fell asleep.
- 0-5.
- Yes, sir.
Take this, please.
0-5, if you drop that grenade,
you'll kill us all.
You'll blow up your classmates
and my assistants.
And you'll kill me, too.
- Are you going to fall asleep?
- No, sir.
We're counting on you, sir.
Now...
...I'll continue.
The concept of strategy.
In Greek.
In Latin.
In French.
- Team leader!
- Yes, sir.
- Are you ready to eat?
- How much time do you need?
- 10 minutes, sir.
You're kidding!
Team leader, you're a fool.
You all have ten seconds
for eating.
Don't touch the food
until I say so.
When you're done, I want to see
the ground clean.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
- Now, go!
- Fast!
- Three seconds have gone by.
- 0-2, you're not eating.
- Time's up.
- Finished.
What is this food doing
here?
We didn't have time, sir.
0-6, do you think it's fair,
in a country like Brazil...
...where people are starving
to death...
...to leave food on the ground
because it looks gross?
- No, sir.
- Why didn't you eat, 0-2?
- I couldn't get to it, sir.
- And now, 0-2?
Yes, sir.
So, get on your knees
and eat it now!
I want you to eat
everything, 0-2.
- No bullshit!
- Yes, sir.
If you don't eat it all,
everybody will stay up all night...
...in the water, 0-2.
Are you feeling sick, 0-2?
0-2, if you vomit on your
classmates' food...
...they'll have to eat your
vomit.
- Sir, I'll eat it.
- Everybody eat! Now!
- Fast!
- Eat!
It's 0-2's fault!
I want the ground to
be clean.
Men in black, what is
your mission?
Take away the devil that
dresses in blue.
Men in black, what is
your mission?
Go to the slums and take
those people...
Stop singing!
Leader...
...this is the worst group I've
seen in my life.
Go on.
Stop singing but not marching.
Out of the water, now!
The first stage in the
course was hard.
The idea is, to first get rid of the
weak, and then the corrupt.
Me? I'd prefer to get rid of
the corrupt first.
- 14, lend him your ointment.
- I don't have any left.
- Wake up 0-2!
- No, let me sleep!
- Take off those boots.
- I can't.
If I do, I won't be able to put
them back on.
- Take them off!
- Wet feet will make you sick.
Your feet are in bad shape.
Take them off.
Attention, 0-2!
- I have news for you.
- Yes, sir.
You're the new leader.
You have one minute to line
up your unit.
- Yes, sir.
- Quick!
Line up, you idiots!
- 23, fast!
- 20 seconds, 0-2.
- 20 seconds!
- Yes, sir.
- Are they lined up?
Look back there.
- Is this a formation?
- Attention, brigade!
The brigade is lined up.
- Is this a formation?
- Yes, sir.
- Are you sure?
Look at your shoelaces!
You animal!
- 0-2, follow me!
- Yes, sir.
Move!
- 0-2.
- Yes, sir.
- You see that boat?
You see?
Since your shoelaces are loose...
- Why don't you go barefooted and bring it here?
- Yes, sir.
- You think you can do it?
0-2.
You know why you can't do
what I ordered you?
- Sir?
- It's not because you're weak.
It's because you need to
have heart, 0-2.
You have to have integrity.
Something you don't have.
You should be with your whores,
with pimps.
At the abortion clinics.
We don't like corrupt cops.
Corrupt cops don't belong
here.
- Are you getting the boat?
- Yes, sir.
- Will you bring it to me?
Let's see if you can
do it.
Give up 0-2.
You're weak!
Ask to leave, you'll never
make it.
Quit, you shithead!
- I can't, Captain.
- Don't listen to him 0-2!
I can't go on.
I can't go on, Captain.
I quit.
Louder.
So everybody can see how
weak you are.
- I give up!
- There it is, you piece of shit!
Attention brigade!
At ease!
Facing the instructors.
Special Operations!
- You'll never be one of us.
- Never!
Attention, 12!
Yes, sir!
You're the leader, 12.
I give up, sir!
You're making us very happy.
Thanks, gentlemen!
Thank you very much!
Attention 0-8.
Our farewell ceremony
was humiliating.
But it was wonderful.
Fuck the weak and
the corrupt.
After the first stage, only
eight were left.
It was time to pick my
replacement.
Matias surprised me.
He passed the first stage.
But he made the mistake of
going back to school.
- You know who told me?
- Wait, what happened?
The slum leader!
You don't know what happens.
You know how long it took me to
set up the NGO?
How much work?
Do you know?
Calm down, Maria.
No! You had no right risking...
...my life like that.
- Don't yell.
- They threatened me, Andre.
You don't understand,
they threatened me.
- Can I speak?
- No, you put me in danger.
My friends are in danger.
- I couldn't tell you.
- I can't trust you anymore.
You fucking son of a bitch!
I couldn't tell you.
Wait!
Maria!
Tell me if I'm doing something
wrong.
- He's very quiet.
- Not too loose...
- Not too tight.
- But, I can leave it loose.
Choosing a replacement for
a captain like me...
...wasn't as easy as
it seemed.
- Is there anybody good?
- There's one.
- Really?
- Yeah, he's a maniac.
Just like me when I
started.
Picking the best soldier from the
group wasn't good enough.
He'd have to do my job.
I couldn't leave my men...
...without making sure they'd
be taken care of.
These are good news.
I think I'll leave in a month
or so.
Only three ranking officers passed
the first stage.
Azevedo was the first one to
choose his replacement.
Move closer to the target!
So I had to choose between
Neto and Matias.
Fire!
Holster, your gun!
Good job, 0-6.
It's easy if you use
my gun.
Skulls!
Let's take a look at the
other four.
- 23, where's your strap?
- It fell, sir.
At this stage of the game...
you don't have your strap?
What are you going to do
if your partner gets shot?
- Throw your weapon to the ground?
- No, sir.
- Throw it?
Put on the damn strap!
- Yes, sir.
- God!
Fuck!
Twenty years in this course!
We teach our men how
to raid the slums...
...to surprise the gangsters.
They can't know how we got there.
When we go, we get there at
night and by surprise.
- With the zero-five strategy!
- Let's go 0-6!
Quick! Get down!
BOPE troops don't enter the
slums shooting away.
They go forward, safely, strategically
moving in groups.
Easy, 0-6.
Slow.
Slow, what do you
do now?
Check the area, then you move.
Good, 0-6.
Very good.
Check and move.
Go forward.
Like that!
Calm down.
What do you do next? Wait.
Did the reinforcement
arrive? Yes.
All hell can break loose,
but you stay calm.
- Looking forward, are you ready?
- Yes.
Ok, go.
If you can move, do it.
Like that, 0-6!
Very good!
Breaking into the slums
is a work of art.
It can't be learned only
in theory.
Once we practiced it, we would
do it for real.
It was real.
- Fuck! Police!
- Get inside!
Captain!
- The lookout ran over there.
- Alone?
Yes.
- I'm going to...
- Wait!
I'm going!
Come back, you idiot!
Mistakes were not allowed
in these operations.
Our men in black go to
the slums to kill.
Not to be killed.
My replacement would
have to know this.
- What's wrong Lieutenant?
- Move!
To the roof, Renan!
The roof!
Come back, you idiot!
Get your ass over here!
Come back!
You don't deserve this
uniform.
You're not a skull,
you're a fool.
Are you listening?
You're a fool.
What are you taking?
It's nothing.
- Let me see.
- Everybody takes them.
It's ok.
You won't have to take
them anymore.
You're leaving soon, things
will get better.
Am I leaving?
- Leaving from where?
- BOPE.
Aren't you?
What's wrong?
Aren't you quitting?
Everything's been taken care of.
What happened?
I chose the wrong man.
- What?
- I chose the wrong man, I made a mistake.
Azevedo picked well
and I chose the maniac.
- But now you have a son.
- So what? Azevedo has two.
Quiet!
The baby is sleeping.
There was something that bothered
me more than making mistakes...
Don't dismiss the kid.
Give him another chance.
...and that was having Rosane
tell me what to do.
When is graduation?
Come on honey, everything
will be ok.
The worst thing was that sometimes
I took her advice.
- This is what I want.
- This? Are you sure?
Look at the book.
- There's an indian...
- No indian!
I want the knife and skull.
Hands up in the air,
to the wall!
When our men graduate,
they're all hyped up.
Neto was the most bloodthirsty.
He signed up for
Operation Holiness.
He wanted to guarantee
a quiet night for the Pope.
And as part of my group...
...he killed thirty gangsters
during the first week.
Even though we prepare our
men for warfare...
...some people may think
we're inhumane.
But the drug dealers are armed,
so there is no choice.
Every BOPE officer knows this.
Now, even Matias was
learning this.
And you know what? It was time to
confront these drug addicts.
I'll see you!
Come here, you idiot!
Come!
- Calm down!
- I want to talk to you.
I won't arrest you, for now.
You don't scare me.
Wipe that smile off
your face.
- You see these glasses?
- Yeah.
They're Romerito's.
Leave them!
You don't deserve to help him,
so I'll give these to him.
If you go to the slum
you'll get killed.
I don't hang around drug
addicts or scumbag like you.
This is what you'll do.
Tell the boy to go to the arcade
tomorrow at noon.
- No, ask Maria to do it.
- Wait! Are you crazy?
If you don't do it, I'll
arrest you.
You understand this?
You think I don't know what
you sell at school?
Tomorrow at noon.
I'll get you a new nose...
...because you're sniffing a
lot of this stuff.
It's us.
Xaveco.
Here, goldilocks.
I'm not taking anything
today, Baiano.
- The situation at school is bad.
- Are you kidding? Why?
That fucking cop!
He said he'd arrest me.
Which one?
- Which one, boss?
- Who?
- Tell me what's going on.
- It's nonsense.
What nonsense?
What nonsense, you asshole?
- Neto!
- What's up, Andre?
- I have a message for you.
- Which one?
From the lawyer's office.
To confirm your interview and
I told them you'd go.
Maria arranged this. I don't need any
favors from her.
Are you crazy, Andre?
Don't be a fool, this is your chance.
You have to get that job!
What's wrong?
Don't stutter, you idiot.
- Spit it out!
- Good!
- There's a boy at the NGO.
- Fuck it!
The cop wants to help him.
I can't, I have to give
Romerito his glasses.
The boy was born blind.
Can't he wait one more day?
What's he going to do?
Tell me everything.
I'll tell you!
- Is he bringing them here?
- No, not here.
You know I have to do it.
Where are you going to
see him?
- At the arcade.
- What time?
- Tell me, damn it!
- At noon.
Years later, Matias told me...
...he wouldn't have gone if Neto
had not persisted.
Deep down, he wanted to be
a lawyer.
What are your plans after
you finish school?
I'd like to specialize in criminal law.
I hadn't made a mistake when I
chose my replacement.
Do you have another coin?
Are you losing or winning?
- Losing.
- You have to win.
Ze, give him another one.
- Romerito!
- He's here! Let's go boss!
Calm down.
There's a kid here, relax.
- Are you Romerito?
- Yes, sir.
I have something for you.
Now you'll see better.
- Where's Andre?
- Working, try them on.
- Very nice!
- Now you look like a grown man.
Stop kidding around.
Sir, I think you'd better go.
Get in!
Don't shoot.
I'll finish off this scumbag.
What the fuck is this?
What the fuck?
Fuck!
This asshole is BOPE!
Let's go!
Baiano knew that if Neto died,
he'd also be dead.
If he killed a BOPE officer,
he'd be sentenced to death.
But the dealers didn't make
things any easier.
Baiano had warned them he didn't
want any policemen in his slum.
He would make them pay.
But those rich students with social
conscience didn't understand this.
They just didn't understand
this.
What the fuck...
You can't come in like this!
- Shut up!
- Fuck!
Put down the gun, Tinho.
What's wrong?
Can you tell me where I
can find Matias?
He's over there.
He'll make it, Carvalho.
- But, Nascimento.
- He'll make it.
- He was shot twice in the back.
- Yeah, but he'll survive.
What do you want?
- Is your friend ok?
- No.
I went to the police station, they said
there's nothing they can do.
- And Romerito? How is he?
- Fine, he's staying with me.
But...
They took Roberta and
Rodrigues.
Don't worry, Baiano has
a social conscience.
Andre, I'm serious.
Rodrigues was bleeding.
You told me you were an
honest cop?
Now it's ok for me to be
a cop?
It doesn't matter, I'm sure your
friends are dead by now.
Don't do it!
- For God's sake!
- I warned you, didn't I?
Burn this asshole.
- Burn him!
- Burn, asshole!
- No!
- Light it up.
Everything ok?
Don't talk again about my job.
What?
No more talking about my job
in this house!
Understood?
I give the orders.
Not one more word about
my team.
Is that clear?
Understood?
I give the fucking orders here!
Listen, go and stay with your mom.
Come back when I tell you to.
Where are you going?
Tell me.
I'll stay around here.
Two bodies were found at
the Prazeres slum.
It's believed that the bodies belong to
the student Roberta Fontes...
...daughter of the businessman
Alceu Fontes.
And to the social worker
Pedro Rodrigues.
Our reporter Ana Luiza is interviewing
the Secretary of Security...
...who just gave a press
conference.
Is this Fontes' body?
We have to wait until we have the
report in order to be sure.
We're doing what we can
to help the families.
- What's wrong aunty?
- Are you ok?
Fire!
For Matias, Neto's death was
a complete tragedy.
They'd been friends since
they were little kids.
I thought I could use
his pain...
...to complete my mission.
- What are you doing here?
- I didn't come to argue.
I only asked what you
were doing here.
I think I can help you.
How?
I know somebody who can help.
Who?
I'll tell you if you promise me
that you won't hurt her.
Of course, who is it?
Rosa.
Now this bitch will talk.
Tell us!
- Where's your fucking boyfriend?
- I don't know.
- Where the fuck is he?
Where is he?
- I don't know.
- Tell us!
Where is he? Fuck!
- You think I'm playing?
- Tell us!
Speak!
Where?
Hands in the air!
Look at me.
Don't do anything!
- Where's Baiano?
- I don't know.
- Fuck! Where's Baiano?
- Quick! Tell me!
Matias, you have to persist with
these guys, understood?
Where the fuck is Baiano?
Son of a bitch!
- Where's Baiano?
- Where is he?
Where is he?
I didn't know the playboy was
one of you guys.
Which playboy?
Captain, I know who he's
talking about.
It's funny, but here, nobody complains
when a cop gets killed.
They only do when it affects
rich people.
When I see these kids
protesting...
...I feel like beating
them up.
- Son of a bitch!
- Enough!
- What are you doing?
- Let me go!
- Enough!
- Son of a bitch!
- Go away!
- Let go of me!
- Enough!
- He killed my friend!
- Let go of me!
- Enough, Matias!
- Let me go!
Are you going to hit a cop?
You're going to hit me now?
Fucking scumbag!
You're just like him!
A bunch of bourgeois shitheads!
Go away, Andre!
Get lost!
What? Bitch!
You're just like him!
A bunch of fucking drug
addicts!
Matias not only wanted revenge...
...now he was becoming
a true BOPE officer.
- Open the fucking door!
- Easy! Put the gun down!
Where are the drugs?
Where? Fuck!
Son of a bitch!
Where the fuck is it?
- Where's the stuff?
- Ok.
Go and get it, asshole.
Fucker!
Hurry up!
Come on!
My mission was no longer
safeguarding the Pope's stay.
Neto had already
done that.
I had to go back home
and find a good replacement.
But before, I had to
get Baiano.
What I was doing
wasn't good.
Get up, against the wall!
Take off your shirt!
I couldn't go to
innocent peoples' homes.
This was very important
for me.
Nothing was going
to stop me.
Andre, let's go and check
up there.
There're no drug dealers
upstairs.
We'll have to go
door to door.
Open up!
Police!
Hands on the table!
Wake up you bum!
Get up!
- Good morning!
- Good morning, sir!
- Can I check your bedroom?
- Yes, sir.
- May I?
- Of course.
0-4, could you look in
the closet?
Look what I found, 0-1.
Those shoes cost more than
what we earn in a month.
- Where did you get them?
- I won them, sir.
Now you lost them.
Let's go.
We'll be in trouble, Captain.
People are watching us.
- We're creating problems.
- Renan, this kid killed Neto.
I came to get him
and it'll be finished today.
- You want to leave?
- We'll end up at the station.
You want to go? No problem.
Take your team.
If you're so worried,
take them.
- Let's go, Renan.
- Ok, let's go.
Are you a student?
Can you fly?
Come here.
On your knees!
Look, I don't want to
hurt you.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
- Where's Baiano?
- I don't know sir.
Tell us!
You want to be a tough guy?
You want the bag on your head?
Put him on his knees.
- Where is he? Tell me!
- I don't know.
Put the bag on!
- Where's Baiano?
- I don't know, sir.
Where is he, you son
of a bitch?
Where?
- I don't know, sir
- Captain, he's not talking.
- Take off his pants.
- Yes, sir.
- Fuck!
- Talk, you motherfucker!
What an ass!
Give me that!
Pull down his pants!
Are you going to tell us?
- Ok, I'll talk.
- Are you going to tell us?
- Yes.
- Come on, take him away.
Shit, Xaveco.
Something's wrong.
Calm down, boss.
You have to be alert.
Something's wrong.
It's too quiet.
- Everything is ok, boss.
- It's not ok.
Bring me some water
and have a look around.
All clear, Captain!
Listen, boss.
I can give you 30 dollars,
if you take me to the hospital.
It's over, motherfucker.
You're going to die.
- Not in the face!
- What?
Not in the face, for the funeral.
I already had Baiano.
0-7, give me the 12" one.
Let the kid go.
I just needed to see Matias'
heart.
Then, my mission would be
accomplished.
And I could go back
to my family.
Knowing that my replacement
deserved to have my job.
He's all yours.
Wait.
Not in the face!