[Epic instrumental music]
[Screams]
[Mob shouting and yelling angrily]
[Epic instrumental music continues]
[Screams]
It's alive.
It's alive. It's alive!
[Mob shouting and yelling angrily]
[Ominous instrumental music]
[Mob grunts and yells in unison]
There he is! Hit it again!
Success!
Count, it's just you.
I was beginning
to lose faith, Victor.
A pity your moment of triumph
is being spoiled...
over a little thing
like grave robbery.
Yes.
[Pants] I must escape this place.
DRACULA: Where are you going to run,
Victor?
Your peculiar experiments
have made you unwelcome...
in most of the civilized world.
I'll take him away, far away,
where no one will ever find him.
DRACULA: No, no, Victor.
The time has come
for me to take command of him.
What are you saying?
Why do you think I brought you here?
Gave you this castle?
- Equipped your laboratory?
- You said...
- You said you believed in my work.
- And I do.
But now that it is,
as you yourself have said...
a triumph of science...
over God...
it must now serve my purpose.
What purpose?
[Yelling in unison]
[Mob roaring]
Good God!
I would kill myself
before helping in such a task.
[Growls and moans]
Feel free. I don't actually need you
anymore, Victor.
I just need him.
He is the key.
I could never allow him
to be used for such evil.
I could.
In fact,
my brides are insisting upon it.
[Loud, angry snarl]
lgor, help me!
IGOR: You have been
so kind to me, Doctor...
caring, thoughtful.
But he pays me.
VICTOR: Stay back.
You can't kill me, Victor.
I'm already dead.
[Chuckles]
[Victor screams]
[Ominous instrumental music]
[Growls and roars]
[Ominous instrumental music continues]
[Roars]
[Frankenstein growls and pants]
[Ominous instrumental music]
[Mob shouting and yelling distantly]
Dr. Frankenstein!
[Mob shouting and yelling angrily]
Look, it's headed for the windmill!
Come on!
[Dracula roars]
[Mob shouting and yelling angrily]
[Frankenstein growls and snarls]
Burn it! Burn it down!
[lntense instrumental music]
[Frankenstein growls and snarls]
[Yells angrily]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Roars in anguish]
[Gasps]
[Ominous instrumental music]
Vampires.
- Run for your lives!
- Vampires!
[Mob yells in panic]
[Ominous instrumental music continues]
[Pants and whimpers]
Father.
[Roars in anguish]
[Brides shriek and wail]
[lntense instrumental music]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Young woman shrieks in the distance]
[Fast-paced instrumental music continues]
[Man laughing in the distance]
[Snarls]
VAN HELSING: Evening.
You're a big one.
You'll be hard to digest.
I'd hate to be such a nuisance.
[Mr. Hyde growls]
I missed you in London.
No, you bloody did not!
You got me good.
Dr. Jekyll, you're wanted
by the Knights of the Holy Order...
It's Mr. Hyde now.
...for the murder of 12 men,
six women, four...
...children, three goats, and
a rather nasty massacre of poultry!
So you're the great Van Helsing.
And you're a deranged psychopath.
We all have our little problems.
My superiors would like for me
to take you alive...
so that they may extricate
your better half.
[Grunts] I bet they bloody would.
Personally, I'd rather just kill you
and call it a day.
But let's make it your decision,
shall we?
Do let's.
MR. HYDE: Here I come...
ready or not!
[Screaming] The bell!
[Whizzing of power saw]
[Grunts]
[Exclaims in surprise]
[Mr. Hyde howls in pain]
MR. HYDE: No, no.
[Grunts]
I'll bet that's upsetting.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Paris!
Come here.
I think you'll find the view
over here rather spectacular.
It's been a pleasure knowing you.
Au revoir!
[Mr. Hyde groaning]
[Heroic instrumental music]
Oh, no.
[Tense instrumental music]
My turn.
[Mr. Hyde screaming]
[ln Latin]
May he rest in peace.
[Concerned chatter]
[Mysterious instrumental music]
Van Helsing.
You murderer!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Bless me, Father, for I have...
CARDINAL: Sinned. Yes, I know.
You're very good at that.
You shattered the Rose Window.
Not to split hairs, sir,
but Mr. Hyde did the shattering.
13th century. Over 600 years old.
- I wish you a week in hell for that.
- It would be a nice reprieve.
Don't get me wrong.
Your results are unquestionable...
but your methods
attract far too much attention.
"Wanted" posters?
We are not pleased.
Do you think I like being
the most wanted man in Europe?
Why don't you and the Order
do something about it?
Because we do not exist.
Well, then neither do I.
CARDINAL: When we found you crawling up
the steps of this church, half-dead...
it was clear to all of us that
you had been sent to do God's work.
- Why can't he do it himself?
- Don't blaspheme.
You already lost your memory
as a penance for past sins.
CARDINAL: If you wish to recover it...
I suggest you continue
to heed the call.
Without us,
the world would be in darkness.
Governments and empires
come and go...
but we have kept mankind safe
since time immemorial.
CARDINAL: We are the last defense
against evil.
CARDINAL: An evil that the rest of mankind
has no idea even exists.
To you, these monsters are
just evil beings to be vanquished.
I'm the one standing there
when they die...
and become the men they once were.
For you, my good son,
this is all a test of faith.
And now,
we need you to go to the East.
To the far side of Romania.
An accursed land...
terrorized by all sorts
of nightmarish creatures.
CARDINAL: Lorded over
by a certain Count Dracula.
VAN HELSING: Dracula?
CARDINAL: Yes.
You've never faced one
like this before.
Our story begins 450 years ago...
when a Transylvanian knight
named Valerious the Elder...
promised God that his family
would never rest nor enter heaven...
until they vanquished Dracula
from their land.
They have not succeeded...
and they are running out of family.
CARDINAL: His descendant Boris Valerious,
King of the Gypsies.
He disappeared almost 12 months ago.
CARDINAL: His only son, Prince Velkan,
and his daughter, Princess Anna.
CARDINAL: If the two of them are killed
before Dracula is vanquished...
nine generations of their family...
will never enter
the gates of St. Peter.
For more than four centuries...
this family has defended
our left flank.
They gave their lives.
We cannot let them
slip into purgatory.
So you're sending me into hell.
In a manner.
Valerious the Elder left this here
400 years ago.
We don't know its purpose...
but he would not have
left it lightly.
The Latin inscription translates as:
"In the name of God,
open this door."
There is an insignia.
Yes, it matches your ring.
I think that in Transylvania
you may find the answer you seek.
[Soft instrumental music]
CARL: Faster, please. Faster!
Faster! Faster! Faster!
[Man screaming]
Getting there.
- Carl!
- There you are.
Did you bring Mr. Hyde back,
or did you kill him?
You killed him, didn't you?
That's why they get so annoyed.
When they ask you to bring someone
back, they don't mean as a corpse.
CARL: All right, you're in a mood.
Come on.
I have some things that'll
put the bit back in your mouth.
Any idiot can make a sword.
Sorry, Father.
VAN HELSING: Come along, Carl.
CARL: Here, take this:
Rings of garlic, holy water...
silver stake, crucifix.
Why can't I have one of those?
You've never gone after vampires
before now, have you?
Vampires, gargoyles, warlocks,
they're all the same.
VAN HELSING: Best when cooked well.
No, they're not all the same.
A vampire is nothing like a warlock.
My granny could kill a warlock.
Carl, you've never even been
out of the abbey.
- How do you know about vampires?
- I read.
Here's something new.
Glycerin 48.
[Monks screaming]
CARL: Sorry!
MULLAH: What in Allah's name
is wrong with you?
The air around here
is thick with envy.
This is my latest invention.
It's gas-propelled.
Capable of catapulting arrows
in rapid succession...
at tremendous velocity.
Just pull the trigger and hold on.
I've heard the stories
from Transylvania.
Trust me, you'll need this.
A work of certifiable genius.
- lf you don't say so yourself.
- No, I did say so myself.
I'm a veritable cornucopia
of talent.
Did you invent this?
I've been working on that
for 12 years.
It's compressed magma
from Mt. Vesuvius...
with pure alkaline
from the Gobi Desert.
- It's one of a kind.
- What's it for?
I don't know,
but I'm sure it'll come in handy.
Twelve years,
and you don't know what it does?
I didn't say that.
I said I didn't know what it's for.
What it does
is to create a light source...
equal to the intensity of the sun.
This will come in handy how?
I don't know.
You can blind your enemies.
Charbroil a herd
of charging wildebeest.
Use your imagination.
No, I'm gonna use yours.
That's why you're coming with me.
CARL: Holy hell be damned I am!
VAN HELSING: You cursed.
Not very well, but you're a monk.
You shouldn't curse at all.
Actually, I'm still just a friar.
I can curse all I want...
damn it!
The Cardinal has ordered you
to keep me alive.
- For as long as possible.
- But I'm not a field man.
CARL: I don't want to go to Transylvania.
[Slow eerie instrumental music]
[Loud growling]
Come on.
Dracula unleashed you for a reason.
[Ferocious snarling]
[lntense instrumental music]
Pull me up!
It's stuck!
[Heroic instrumental music]
- No, Anna, it will kill you!
- That's my brother out there.
Cut the rope! Cut it now!
Velkan!
[lntense instrumental music]
My gun! Find my gun!
Find Velkan's gun.
It has to be the silver bullets.
Anna, hurry!
Hurry!
Move.
VELKAN: Anna, look out!
Run!
[Eerie instrumental music]
[Velkan cries out]
Velkan.
God...
help us.
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Fast-paced instrumental music continues]
CARL: So, what do you remember?
VAN HELSING: Not now, Carl.
There must be something.
I remember fighting the Romans
at Masada.
- That was in 73 A.D.
- You asked.
CARL: What are we doing here?
Why is it so important
to kill this Dracula, anyway?
- Because he's the son of the Devil.
- I mean, besides that.
If we kill him, anything bitten
or created by him will also die.
I mean, besides that.
Welcome to Transylvania.
- Is it always like this?
- Pretty much.
ANNA: You, turn around.
- Let me see your faces.
- Why?
Because we don't trust strangers.
Strangers don't last long here.
5'7"by 2'3".
Gentlemen, you will now be disarmed.
You can try.
ANNA: You refuse to obey our laws?
- The laws of men mean little to me.
- Fine.
Kill them.
- I'm here to help you.
- I don't need any help.
Really?
[Hissing and shrieking]
[Villagers screaming]
Everybody inside!
Hide the children!
[lntense instrumental music]
[Hisses angrily]
VAN HELSING: Stay here.
You stay here.
They're trying to kill me.
[lntense instrumental music continues]
[Hissing]
- Marishka, kill the stranger.
- Love to.
ANNA: Run!
Carl, it's not working.
CARL: Try aiming at their hearts.
[lntense instrumental music continues]
It's the sun.
[Eerie instrumental music]
Van Helsing.
[lntense instrumental music resumes]
Do you like to fly, Anna?
[Aleera cackles]
[lntense instrumental music continues]
[Cries out in pain]
Hello, Anna.
[Hisses]
Nice to see you, too, Aleera.
[Low growling]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Did I do something to you
in a past life?
Don't play coy with me, Princess.
I know what lurks
in your lusting heart.
I hope you have a heart, Aleera...
because someday I'm going to drive
a stake through it.
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
CARL: This should do the trick.
Holy water!
Stop your teasing, Marishka,
and finish him.
Too bad. So sad.
The church!
Thirty years old.
Perfectly aged.
Hello, Anna, my dear.
[Eerie instrumental music]
The last of the Valerious.
[Roars]
[Shrieks]
[Laughing maniacally]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
I can feel fresh blood
rushing through her veins.
Here she comes!
I want first bite.
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
[Shrieking]
[Screams in agony]
[Cow mooing]
[Soft, slow instrumental music]
VILLAGER #1: He killed a bride!
VILLAGER #2: He killed Marishka!
VILLAGER #3: You killed Marishka!
VILLAGER #4: You killed a vampire!
CARL: But isn't that a good thing?
Vampires only kill what they need
to survive.
One or two people a month.
Now they will kill for revenge.
[Villagers shouting angrily]
- Are you always this popular?
- Pretty much.
So what name, my good sir,
do I carve on your gravestone?
His name is Van Helsing.
[Chatter in awe]
Your reputation precedes you.
Next time stay close.
You're no good to me dead.
Well, I'll say this for you.
You've got courage.
He's the first one to kill a vampire
in over 100 years.
I'd say that's earned him a drink.
Marishka!
[Wailing]
DRACULA: Why can't they just
leave us alone?
We never kill more than our fill
and less than our share.
Can they say the same?
Did I not stress
how important it was...
to be finished
with Anna Valerious...
before she destroys
what we are trying to create?
VERONA: We lost Marishka.
ALEERA: Master.
There, there, my darlings.
Do not worry.
- I shall find another bride.
- What?
[Aleera gasps]
- Do we mean so little to you?
- Have you no heart?
No, I have no heart! I feel no love!
Nor fear...
nor joy...
nor sorrow!
I am hollow.
And I will live forever.
- My Lord.
- It is not so bad.
DRACULA: I am at war with the world...
and every living soul in it.
But soon
the final battle will begin.
I must go and find out
who our new visitor is.
[Werewolf howling ferociously]
You will have to make
a little apéritif out of him.
We are much too close to success
to be interrupted now.
ALEERA: No!
VERONA: The last experiment was a failure!
Please, say you will not try again.
My heart could not bear the sorrow
if we fail again.
[Roars angrily]
[Whimper and sob]
Come.
DRACULA: Do not fear me.
Everybody else fears me.
Not my brides.
[Werewolf howls angrily]
DRACULA: lgor.
Yes, master.
Why do you torment that thing so?
It's what I do.
Remember, lgor, "Do unto others..."
Before they do unto me, master.
Now go, all of you!
To Castle Frankenstein!
ALEERA: Yes, we will try again.
- So, how did you get here?
- We came by sea.
ANNA: Really? The sea?
CARL: Well, yes.
ANNA: The Adriatic Sea?
VAN HELSING: Where do I find Dracula?
ANNA: He used to live in this very house
four centuries ago.
No one knows where he lives now.
Father would stare at that painting
for hours...
Iooking for Dracula's lair.
ANNA: So that's why you've come?
VAN HELSING: I can help you.
- No one can help me.
- I can try.
You can die trying.
All of my family has.
ANNA: I can handle this myself.
VAN HELSING: So I noticed.
The vampires attacked in daylight.
They never do that.
I was unprepared.
It won't happen again.
So why did they attack in daylight?
Clearly they wanted
to catch me off guard.
They seem almost desperate
to finish off my family.
- Why is that? Why now?
- You ask a lot of questions.
Usually I ask only two:
What are we dealing with?
How do I kill it?
My father spent most of his life
looking for answers year after year.
Tearing through the tower,
combing through the family archives.
- Carl, the tower. Start there.
- Right.
The only way to save your family is
to stay alive till Dracula's killed.
And who will kill him if not me?
Who will show courage if not me?
Go alone and you'll be outmanned
and outpositioned.
And you can't see in the dark.
In the morning, we will hunt him...
but we'll do it together.
[Soft, tense instrumental music]
Some say you're a murderer,
Mr. Van Helsing.
Others say you're a holy man.
Which is it?
It's a bit of both, I think.
- I promised you a drink.
- Yes, you did.
The bar is down the hall.
Help yourself.
ANNA: As for me, I'm going to finish this
once and for all.
VAN HELSING: Sorry you've to carry
this burden alone.
On the contrary,
I would wish for it no other way.
I'm sorry about your father
and brother.
I will see them again.
We Transylvanians always look
on the brighter side of death.
- There's a brighter side of death?
- Yes. It's just harder to see.
I'm sorry about that, too.
Van Helsing!
[Metallic clanging]
Van Helsing?
[Eerie instrumental music]
[Banging]
[Eerie instrumental music continues]
[Thudding]
[Roars]
[Eerie instrumental music continues]
- Velkan?
- Anna.
Oh, my God, you're alive.
No. Anna, I only have a moment.
ANNA: But there's a werewolf...
VELKAN: Listen to me!
I know Dracula's secret.
He has a...
[Grunts and gasps]
ANNA: Velkan?
VELKAN: Please.
No!
Run, Anna.
[lntense instrumental music]
VAN HELSING: Anna!
Are you all right?
Anna!
[lntense instrumental music continues]
Why does it smell
like wet dog in here?
Werewolf!
Right. You'll be needing
silver bullets, then.
VAN HELSING: Well done.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Who's hunting whom?
Nice night.
This is a bit tight for me.
But for you it's a perfect fit.
TOP HAT: What a coincidence.
TOP HAT: I see the wolf man
hasn't killed you yet.
VAN HELSING: Don't worry, he's getting to it.
VAN HELSING: You don't seem bothered.
TOP HAT: I'm no threat to him.
I'm just the one
who cleans up after him...
if you get my meaning.
Little late to be digging graves,
isn't it?
Never too late to dig graves.
You never know
when you'll need a fresh one.
Oh, sorry. It's just my nature.
[Ferocious roaring]
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
- Move!
- No!
VAN HELSING: Why?
ANNA: You're choking me!
- Give me a reason not to.
- I can't. If people knew...
He's not your brother anymore, Anna!
- You knew?
- Yes.
Before or after I stopped you
from shooting him?
Before.
And still you tried to kill him!
He's a werewolf!
He's gonna kill people!
He can't help it!
It's not his fault!
I know, but he'll do it anyway!
Do you understand forgiveness?
Yes. I ask for it often.
They say Dracula has a cure.
If there's a chance
I can save my brother...
- I'm going after it.
- No.
- I need to find Dracula.
- And I need to find my brother!
He gave his life for me.
He's the only family I have left.
I despise Dracula
more than you can ever imagine.
He has taken everything from me,
leaving me alone in this world.
[Sentimental instrumental music]
To have memories
of those you loved and lost...
is perhaps harder
than to have no memories at all.
All right.
We'll look for your brother.
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
- Igor.
- Yes, master.
- How long before we are ready?
- Soon, master. Very soon.
It is difficult
without the good doctor...
but the Dwergi, they are doing well?
[ln Hungarian]
No!
Good.
ANNA: For me, this is all personal.
It's all about family and honour.
Why do you do it, this job of yours?
What do you hope to get out of it?
I don't know.
Maybe some self-realization.
What have you got out of it so far?
Nightmares.
Werewolves only shed
before the first full moon.
Before the curse
has completely consumed them.
[Thunder rumbling]
VAN HELSING: What is this place?
ANNA: Castle Frankenstein.
ANNA: But it should be abandoned.
I don't understand.
The man who lived here
was killed a year ago.
- A grave robber, among other things.
- A year ago.
It was just after that
that your father went missing.
ANNA: Yes. He was looking for Dracula.
He was on his way to the sea.
I have never been to the sea.
I'll bet it's beautiful.
[Sentimental instrumental music]
[Roars]
Werewolves are such a nuisance
during their first full moon.
So hard to control.
I send you on a simple errand...
to find out
who our new visitor is...
and you have to stop
for a little chat with your sister.
Leave her out of this, Count.
She doesn't know your secret.
And I am soon to take it
to my grave.
DRACULA: Don't wish for death so quickly.
I intend for you to be quite useful.
VELKAN: I would rather die than help you.
Don't be boring.
Everyone who says that dies.
Besides, tonight...
after the final stroke
of midnight...
you will have no choice
but to obey me.
Look familiar?
Father?
No!
He proved useless.
But I'm hoping, with werewolf venom
running through your veins...
you will be of greater benefit!
I may have failed to kill you,
Count, but my sister will not.
[Tense instrumental music]
VELKAN: Never!
[Thunder rumbling]
[Dwergi chattering]
ANNA: Dwergi.
VAN HELSING: Dwergi?
Dracula's servants.
Industrious but extremely vicious.
If you get the chance to kill one,
do it...
- because they'll do worse to you.
- Right.
[Dwergi chattering]
They say they're using my brother
in some sort of experiment.
My brother is still battling
the sickness within him.
- There's still hope.
- Anna.
There is no hope for your brother.
But we can still protect others
by killing Dracula.
[Tense instrumental music]
Let us begin!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[ln Hungarian]
IGOR: No slacking! Up!
VAN HELSING: You ever see these things?
ANNA: No.
ANNA: What do you think they are?
VAN HELSING: Offspring.
ANNA: What?
VAN HELSING: A man with
three gorgeous women for 400 years.
Yes, vampires are the walking dead.
It only makes sense
their children are born dead.
He's obviously trying
to bring them to life.
[Clears throat] Ladies first.
Dracula and his brides only kill
one or two people a month.
If he brings
all these things to life...
[Thunder rumbling]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
DRACULA: Throw the switches!
IGOR: Yes, master.
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
[Heartbeat thumping]
What are you doing?
I want to see what we're up against.
So this is what you get
when vampires mate.
[Hissing]
Come on!
They need to feed.
Teach them how. Teach them!
[Shrieking]
And beg the Devil...
that this time they stay alive.
[lntense instrumental music]
- This is where I come in.
- No, wait!
Now that I have your attention...
[lntense instrumental music continues]
CARL: Yes, well, that's interesting.
[Strange low howling]
That's not good. Must warn somebody.
I can tell the character of a man
by the sound of his heartbeat.
Usually when I approach...
I can almost dance to the beat.
Strange that yours is so steady.
[ln Hungarian]
IGOR: Hurry up!
IGOR: We must keep
the atmosphere electrified!
Accelerate the generators!
Power the dynamos!
We are losing power.
The human is insufficient.
[Screaming in agony]
Velkan.
[Dogs barking in the distance]
[Distant screeching]
Oh, my God.
[Villagers screaming in panic]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Feed, my darlings! Feed!
[ln Latin]
May he rest in peace.
Hello, Gabriel.
[Tense instrumental music]
[Dwergi shouting]
We must not lose
the master's progeny!
Is this your silver stake?
How long has it been?
300, 400 years?
You don't remember, do you?
Exactly what is it
I should be remembering?
You are the great Van Helsing.
Trained by monks and mullahs
from Tibet to Istanbul.
Protected by Rome herself.
But, like me, hunted by all others.
The Knights of the Holy Order
know all about you.
It's no surprise
you would know about me.
Yes, but it's much more than this.
[Dracula laughs]
We have such history,
you and I, Gabriel.
DRACULA: Have you ever wondered why
you have such horrible nightmares?
Horrific scenes
of ancient battles past.
How do you know me?
[Tense instrumental music continues]
- Velkan.
- Anna.
No. Don't unstrap me.
Don't unstrap me!
No, you must not! No! Stop!
Stop it.
I'm getting you out of here.
Velkan, it's all right.
I'm taking you home.
[Velkan roars in the distance]
So would you like me
to refresh your memory a little?
A few details from your sordid past.
Perhaps that is a conversation
for another time.
Allow me to reintroduce myself.
I am Count Vladislaus Dragulia.
Born 1422.
Murdered 1462.
Help me!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Victims scream]
[Hissing]
[Wail and shriek in horror]
[Brides wail in the distance]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
I think
we've overstayed our welcome.
[Growls and snarls]
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
MAN #1: Have you found the children?
MAN #2: Not yet.
- What happened?
- They just died.
How can I ever repay you?
[Whispers]
But you can't do that.
You are a monk.
Well, actually I'm just a friar.
IGOR: I am sorry, master.
We try and we try...
but I fear we are not so smart
as Dr. Frankenstein.
Truly.
It would appear the good doctor
took the key to life to his grave.
Hunt them down.
Kill them both.
ANNA: A silver stake? A crucifix?
ANNA: What, did you think
we haven't tried everything before?
ANNA: We've shot him, stabbed him,
clubbed him...
sprayed him with holy water,
staked him through the heart...
and still he lives!
Do you understand?
No one knows how to kill Dracula.
Well, I could have used
that information a little earlier.
Don't give me that look.
You were right. I'm sorry.
He's not my brother anymore.
[Sentimental instrumental music]
Do you have any family,
Mr. Van Helsing?
Not sure.
I hope to find out someday.
That's what keeps me going.
- Here's to what keeps you going.
- Absinthe. Strong stuff.
Don't let it touch your tongue.
It'll knock you on your...
[Both screaming]
Vampire.
Vampires!
Now I remember.
[Mysterious instrumental music]
"Even a man who is pure in heart
And says his prayers by night
"May become a wolf
when the wolfbane blooms
"And the moon is shining bright
"Or crave another's blood
when the sun goes down
"And his body takes to flight"
[Clock chiming]
[Anna groaning]
[Gasps]
There's something down here.
VAN HELSING: And it's carnivorous.
VAN HELSING: Whatever it is,
it appears to be human.
I'd say he's a size 17.
Around 360 pounds.
8.5 to 9 feet tall.
He has a bad gimp in his right leg
and three copper teeth.
How do you know he has copper teeth?
Because he's standing
right behind you. Move!
[Fast-paced tense instrumental music]
Oh, my God!
The Frankenstein monster!
Monster? Who's the monster here?
[Frankenstein roars]
I have done nothing wrong...
and yet you and your kind
all wish me dead!
[Screams in agony]
What do you want?
To exist.
[Frankenstein screaming]
Don't!
- We must kill it.
- Wait.
If you value your lives
and the lives of your kind...
- you will kill me.
- No.
If Dracula finds me...
I am the key to my father's machine.
The key to life.
Life for Dracula's children.
He already awakened them last night.
FRANKENSTEIN: Two.
And those were from only one bride.
From one single birthing.
And they died
as they did the last time he tried.
Only with me
can he give them lasting life.
There are more?
More of those things?
Thousands.
Thousands more.
[Soft instrumental music]
VAN HELSING: No.
ANNA: You heard what he said.
My life, my job is to vanquish evil.
I can sense evil.
VAN HELSING: This thing, man,
whatever it is...
evil may have created it,
may have left its mark on it.
But evil does not rule it,
so I cannot kill it.
- I can.
- Not while I'm here.
Anna.
Your family has spent 400 years
trying to kill Dracula.
Maybe this poor creature
can help us find a way.
[Werewolf growling]
Oh, my God. He's seen us.
Now they'll come for him.
Neither you nor I
will be able to stop them.
If I can get him to Rome,
we can protect him there.
And then the painting came alive...
and the two creatures
attacked each other.
- What does it mean?
- I don't know.
Listen, Carl, whatever you do,
don't stare at him.
I'm staring at him.
Is that a man?
VAN HELSING: Actually, seven men.
Parts, anyway.
By exposing me,
you have condemned me!
Me and all of humanity!
Nothing is faster
than Transylvanian horses.
Not even a werewolf.
Anything else, you're on your own.
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
- Let me go.
- Where are you going to go?
I don't know
if you've seen a mirror lately...
but you kind of stick out
in a crowd.
[Fast-paced instrumental music intensifies]
[Eerie screeching]
[Hissing]
[Fast-paced instrumental music continues]
We must not let the creature
be destroyed!
Save him! Save the monster!
[Fast-paced instrumental music continues]
[Gasps]
VERONA: Stakes!
No!
[Grunts]
CARL: Oh, my God.
What are you doing out here?
Right.
Don't let go!
[Van Helsing yelling for help]
I can help!
You won't kill me?
Only if you don't hurry!
[Fast-paced instrumental music continues]
[Ferocious growling]
[Roaring]
Jump!
[lntense instrumental music]
Velkan.
[Whispers] Velkan.
Anna...
forgive me.
I will see you again.
[Sentimental instrumental music]
ANNA: You killed him.
Now you know
why they call me murderer.
Oh, my God.
You've been bitten.
[Groaning]
[Ominous instrumental music]
Anna!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Aleera cackles triumphantly]
Anna.
[Clicking her tongue]
So much trouble to my master.
So much trouble.
What do you want?
ALEERA: The master commands a trade.
The monster for the Princess.
Somewhere public. Lots of people.
A place where your master
will be less inclined...
to expose his other side.
Tomorrow night is All Hallows' Eve.
Here in Budapest there is
a wonderful masquerade ball.
[Cackles and shrieks with glee]
[Slow instrumental music]
- Are you all right?
- No.
[Roars in horror]
He has been bitten.
FRANKENSTEIN: Bitten by a werewolf.
Now you will become that which
you have hunted so passionately.
I am sorry.
May others be as passionate
in their hunting of you.
VAN HELSING: Well,
they won't find him in here.
I'm sure this is some sort of sin.
VAN HELSING: God will forgive us.
We need to save Anna.
You don't think
the hat's a bit much?
VAN HELSING: Carl, help me!
CARL: Right.
CARL: How many commandments
can we break in one day?
CARL: Anyway, according to the book...
you won't turn into a werewolf until
the rising of your first full moon.
CARL: That's two nights from now.
CARL: You'll still be able
to fight Dracula's hold over you...
until the final stroke of midnight.
VAN HELSING: So I have nothing
to worry about.
CARL: My God, you should be terrified.
VAN HELSING: Thanks.
CARL: Sorry.
CARL: We still have 48 hours
to find a solution.
You sure he can't get out of there?
VAN HELSING: Not without
some help from the dead.
[Ominous instrumental music]
[Band playing ballroom music]
[Singing an eerie opera]
How does it feel
to be a puppet on my string?
I won't let you trade me, Count.
I have no intention of trading you.
DRACULA: And if I know Van Helsing,
which I do...
he is not planning on
making a trade, either.
Neither of us
has ever settled for half.
There they are.
You make my skin crawl.
This is not all I could do
with your skin.
[Band continues playing ballroom music]
Carl, I need you to do something.
I'm not gonna like this, am I?
DRACULA: Don't we make a lovely couple?
Oh, my God.
DRACULA: I am looking
for a new bride, Anna.
Someone strong and beautiful.
One brief moment of pain...
and we can be together forever.
You have no heartbeat.
DRACULA: Perhaps it just needs...
to be rekindled.
[Snarls]
Anna. Anna!
VAN HELSING: Wake up.
DRACULA: Gabriel.
Oh, Gabriel.
Welcome to my summer palace.
Master! Look, master!
We have him, master.
We have him!
You wretched undead...
I shall have my revenge!
"Though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of death...
"I shall fear no evil."
You are nothing but damned bones...
and damned souls...
and will burn in the flames of Hell!
[Ominous instrumental music]
Now that everything
is as it should be...
ladies and gentlemen,
I give to you...
Van Helsing!
Come on.
Yes!
[Ominous instrumental music continues]
Now I know what it's for.
- Where are we going?
- Through that window!
[All gasping]
Carl, you're a genius!
A genius with access
to unstable chemicals.
Say goodbye to your friends.
[Chuckles sinisterly]
I'll find you!
I'll get you back and set you free!
I swear to God!
[Aleera cackles distantly]
- I must save him.
- No, you can't.
Why?
I cabled Rome earlier
to apprise them of our situation.
What did they say?
CARL: Even if you kill Dracula...
Rome orders you to destroy
Frankenstein as well.
He isn't evil.
But they say he isn't human, either.
Do they know him? Have they spoken
to him? Who are they to judge?
They want you to destroy him so he
can never be used to harm humanity.
What of me? Did you tell them
what I'm to become?
VAN HELSING: Did they tell you
how to kill me?
The correct angle of the stake
as it enters my heart?
The exact measure of silver
in each bullet?
ANNA: Stop!
CARL: No, I left you out!
[Ominous instrumental music]
I'm sorry.
It's starting.
They must have taken
all the equipment to Dracula's lair.
Wherever that is.
Look, there's still time.
Dracula can't bring his children
to life until the sun sets.
The sun sets in two hours.
We've been looking for him
for more than 400 years!
Yes, well, I wasn't around
for those 400 years, now, was I?
VAN HELSING: Okay, Carl,
what have you learned?
That Count Dracula was actually
the son of Valerious the Elder.
The son of your ancestor.
Everybody knows that. What else?
All right.
Well, according to this rubbing...
it all started
when Dracula was murdered.
VAN HELSING: Do you know
who murdered him?
CARL: No, there's just some vague reference
to the Left Hand of God.
And in 1462, when Dracula died...
- he made a covenant with the Devil.
- And was given a new life.
But the only way he could sustain
that life was by drinking blood.
Excuse me. Are you going to
let me tell the story?
BOTH: Sorry.
And your ancestor,
having sired this evil creature...
went to Rome to seek forgiveness.
That's when the bargain was made.
He was to kill Dracula...
in return for eternal salvation
of his entire family...
right down the line
all the way to you.
ANNA: But he couldn't do it.
As evil as Dracula was, my ancestor
couldn't kill his own son.
So he banished him
to an icy fortress...
sending him through a door
from which there was no return.
- And then the Devil gave him wings.
- Yes.
- All right, so where is this door?
- I don't know.
But when your ancestor couldn't
kill his son, he left clues.
So that future generations
might do it for him.
That must be what my father
was looking for in here.
Clues to the door's location.
The door.
Of course.
You said your father spent hours...
staring at this painting,
trying to find the lair.
I think you were right.
Quite literally.
I think this is the door.
He just didn't know how to open it.
Look. A Latin inscription.
CARL: Maybe it works
like the painting in the tower.
If this were a door, my father
would have opened it long ago.
I can't finish the inscription.
There's a piece missing.
[Mysterious instrumental music]
- Your father didn't have this.
- Where did you get that?
VAN HELSING: Carl, finish it.
[ln Latin]
In the name of God, open this door.
A mirror.
Dracula has no reflection
in the mirror.
But why?
Maybe, to Dracula
it's not a mirror at all.
It's cold. And it's snowing.
VAN HELSING: See you on the other side.
Be careful.
[Mysterious instrumental music continues]
Castle Dracula.
[Ominous instrumental music]
CARL: Do we have a plan?
CARL: Doesn't have to be
Wellington's at Waterloo...
but some sort of plan would be nice.
VAN HELSING: We're going to stop Dracula.
ANNA: And kill anything
in our way.
CARL: Well, you let me know how that goes.
Well, as grateful as I am
to be out of the cold...
that doesn't seem like a good thing.
[Snarls]
We'd better get moving.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
CARL: So are all of those...
ANNA: Yes.
- And inside them are...
- Yes.
Igor do this! lgor do that!
How did you find...
It's impossible!
- Please don't kill me!
- Why not?
Well, I...
[Frankenstein screaming]
[Loud roaring]
My master has awakened.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
- There is a cure.
- What?
Dracula. He has a cure to remove
the curse of the werewolf!
Go, find the cure! Save yourself!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
ANNA: Come on. You heard him.
Let's find it.
Wait. Why does Dracula have a cure?
- I don't care!
- I do.
Why does he need one? Why?
Because the only thing
that can kill him is a werewolf.
The painting. That's what it meant.
ANNA: Dracula's been using werewolves
to do his bidding for centuries.
Yes, but if one ever had the will
to turn on him, he'd need a cure...
to remove the curse and
make him human before it bit him.
You're going to take these two...
- and lead them to the antidote.
- No, I'm not.
Yes, I am.
Here's the plan. When the bell
begins to toll midnight...
you'll be able to kill Dracula.
We just need to find the cure...
and get it into you
before the final stroke.
Are you insane?
What kind of plan is that?
If they even suspect you
of misleading them...
clip off one of his fingers.
- I'll clip off something.
- The tower over there...
- that's where it is.
- And what about the other tower?
- Give me that!
- That is where...
we reassembled the laboratory.
Would I lie to you?
Not if you wanted to live.
Now, if I'm not cured by
the twelfth stroke of midnight...
- I don't think I could.
- You must.
Come on.
I don't like this plan.
We don't have a choice.
Just don't get killed.
You still don't understand.
It doesn't matter
what happens to me.
We must save my family.
If you're late, run like hell.
Don't be late.
[Sentimental instrumental music]
Now go. Go.
[Sentimental instrumental music intensifies]
FRANKENSTEIN: Get off me,
you vermin from hell!
What are you complaining about?
This is why you were made!
To prove that God is not
the only one who can create life!
And now you must give that life
to my children.
Up!
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
There it is.
I'll go first.
[Mysterious instrumental music]
Carl!
Stay as long as you like.
You try to get lgor. Igor get you!
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Gasps]
- Go ahead. Grab it.
- You go ahead and grab it.
If there's one thing I've learned...
it's never to be the first to stick
your hand in a viscous material.
[Hisses]
- Did I scare you?
- No.
Then maybe I need
to try a little harder.
[Giggles]
[Shrieks in pain]
Viscous material!
What did I tell you?
Get it!
Hot.
- Come on!
- Yes.
We've got to get the antidote
to Van Helsing! Go!
You can't go until I say you can go!
Keep running, Carl!
And I'll say you can go
when you're dead!
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Giggles menacingly]
[lntense instrumental music]
CARL: Oh, my God!
What are you doing?
You must find the cure!
- My friends are doing it for me.
- Friends.
Yes. You want one?
I can't unscrew the bolts.
This is gonna hurt.
I am accustomed to pain.
It lets you know you're alive.
[Howls in pain]
[lntense instrumental music continues]
Give me life!
One more bolt
and my young will live.
VAN HELSING: You're almost out, my friend!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Heartbeat thumping]
[Aleera cackles]
Help me!
But you're supposed to die.
I want to live.
All right!
Be happy in the knowledge...
that I shall weep
over your dead body.
Hang on!
I'll swing you loose!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Screams]
[Screaming in agony]
You are too late, my friend.
My children live.
Then the only way to kill them
is to kill you.
Correct.
So be it.
[Clock chiming]
One.
No, this cannot be.
[Laughs sinisterly]
We are both part of
the same grand game, Gabriel.
But we need not find ourselves
on opposite sides of the board.
[lntense instrumental music]
[Aleera shrieks in pain]
Go! Go and help Van Helsing!
Now!
Thank you.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Oh, my God!
Anna, I need a little help!
Hurry!
ANNA: Throw it to me, Carl!
Yes!
You are being used, Gabriel,
as was I.
But I escaped. So can you.
ALEERA: Anna, my love...
it is your blood
that shall keep me beautiful.
What do you think of that?
[Screaming in sudden pain]
I think if you're going to
kill someone, kill them.
Don't stand there talking about it.
[Shrieking in pain]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Don't you understand?
We could be friends. Partners!
Brothers-in-arms!
Did I mention that it was you
who murdered me?
It must be such a burden.
Such a curse...
to be the Left Hand of God.
All I want is life, Gabriel.
The continuation of my kind.
And perhaps the return of my ring.
Don't be afraid, Gabriel.
Don't be afraid.
I shall give you back your life,
your memory.
Some things
are better left forgotten.
[Dramatic instrumental music continues]
For God!
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
God forgive me.
She's dead.
[Howling loudly]
[Melancholic instrumental music]
[Slow instrumental music]
[ln Latin]
CARL: "Eternal rest grant unto her,
Oh, Lord, and let perpetual light...
"shine upon her.
On her soul and the souls of all...
"On her soul and the souls of all...
"the dead faithful have mercy..."
[Slow instrumental music continues]
[Choir music]
[Sentimental instrumental music]
[Epic instrumental music]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
Subtitle by Snitch Company®