Dan...
Maybe it's the wind.
No!
Stop!
Please! Stop!
Tucker!
You have a week, Evans.
Then we burn the house.
William?
Hey! William!
Out. Out!
William!
God damn it, William!
God damn it!
Put that down!
- Come here!
- Let go!
Let go!
lt's the last feed we got!
l'll take care of this.
No, you won't.
Herd's over the ridge by now.
You go get cleaned up.
You lied to me, Dan.
You told me we made payments to Hollander.
We did...some.
How do you think
we bought feed, Alice?
Three months water?
Medicine for Mark?
l had a choice between
our family and paying it down.
We're supposed to make
decisions together.
Would you have made it any different?
Alice, we can't make it rain together.
Or turn the dust into grass.
Can't stop Hollander from selling
our land to the railroad, either.
lt's too bad the doctors at Essex
saved so much of my leg.
l read that the pension act
pays by the pound now.
Stop looking at me like that.
You gonna tell the marshal
what those men did?
Marshal ain't doing shit.
- William.
- First thing, Mark,
l'm gonna take you boys, and
we're gonna round up the herd,
and then l'm goin' into town.
What are you gonna do in town?
l'm gonna tell Hollander to make this right.
l'm gonna tell him...
to pay for a new barn.
Maybe we should
just shoot him like Will says.
Coach is headed for Bisbee, Boss.
Girded with iron, Pinks on top,
double shotguns,
and a Gatling.
You shoulda let me save the feed.
You gonna hock that?
Someday, William...
you walk in my shoes,
you might understand.
l ain't ever walking in your shoes.
Tracks over here.
Here we go.
- Kenny, here we go.
- Here they come.
Pull that way!
Now that one!
Use the gun.
Don't let 'em get it.
Mark, stay near.
Mark!
God damn!
Giddyap!
Get down. Now!
l got more!
Here l come!
Knock on 'em, Nonnie.
Knock on 'em.
Keep 'em goin'.
Pull up. Pull up.
Pull up!
Morning, Pinkerton.
Name's Charlie Prince.
l expect you heard of me.
Well, l heard of a...
balled-up whore named...
Charlie Princess.
That you, missy?
l hate Pinkertons.
Byron McElroy.
When did your hair
turn all gray, Byron?
Go to hell, Ben Wade.
Well, would you look at all this?
Y'all spared no expense this time, Byron.
l gotta say, though,
it's probably cheaper
just to let me rob the damn thing.
lf you're gonna kill me,
just as soon get to it.
l ain't gonna kill you.
Not like this.
Won't change a thing, lettin' me live.
l'll come for you.
l'd be disappointed if you didn't.
- She's lit!
All right, boys.
There you go.
lt's full.
All right. There you go.
Come on, give me one.
One more.
l'll ask you
to put down the money.
You step back!
You men step back!
All of you step back right now,
or this man dies!
Not a smart move, friend.
Shit.
He's fast.
Well, Tommy...
it seems that
there was a Pinkerton...
inside that coach
that wasn't quite dead yet.
Now, l know Charlie told you,
because...
we done got but a few rules in this outfit.
And this is what happens
when you put us all at risk.
Mark, look at me.
Look at me.
Keep lookin' at me.
Back up quietly.
Back-- William!
William, look at me.
Back up.
Morning.
Those are my cattle.
l want 'em back.
Careful, rancher,
that's Ben Wade you're talking to.
Well, l need 'em back.
They're all l got.
l don't need your cattle.
But l will be needin' them horses.
So you don't go doing nothing... foolish.
Campos.
You'll find them on the road to Bisbee.
Boys.
They're probably
just running late, Mr. Butterfield.
Pinkertons don't run late.
That's why they're paid $18 a day.
Get me on my feet.
l think you're in pretty bad shape, mister.
- You should--
- Just get me on my damn feet.
Mark, William, get me some of them boards.
Can l help you?
l think maybe...
a coach headed for here got itself held up
in the canyon about 10 miles back...
God damn it.
...by Mr. Ben Wade himself.
How did you know it was Wade?
lt's been him the last 21 times, Marshal.
l saw a Mexican sharpshooter
and an Apache.
- God damn it. Jesus Christ.
- And l've been told--
Did you see The Hand of God?
- What's that?
- His pistol.
Why the hell didn't
you do something?
They had a lot of weapons, mister...
and they were shootin' bullets.
Let's go. We're wasting time.
Where you from, anyway?
Tom Conrad bought
a thousand head in Mexico.
Hired us to drive 'em in.
Let's go.
Come on, boys.
Something's going on
with the railroad man.
Ma'am? Some whiskey for my friends.
Let's go.
- The bar's closed.
- Already?
Here's to the four we lost in battle.
And here's to the boss,
who...
had to say good-bye
to Tommy Darden today.
And that's too bad.
Proverbs 13:3.
''He that keepeth his mouth,
''keepeth his life.
''He that opens his lips too wide
shall bring on his own destruction.''
Amen.
Tommy was weak.
Tommy was stupid.
Tommy is dead.
l'd drink to that.
Sutherland.
Jorgensen.
Campos.
Jackson.
Kinter.
Marshal's only half stupid.
He's gonna be back soon.
They're going across the border.
l won't be far.
l'll wait for you.
All right, Charlie.
l've seen you someplace before.
Have you?
You ever work for
a blind lrishman in Leadville?
l was a singer.
The best time l ever had
in my whole life.
What made you quit?
Got to coughing.
Doctor said l should find a drier climate.
You know, l spent more money
in that joint than l could tell you.
Do you remember a girl?
Her name was Velvet.
Nobody forgets Velvet.
You look kinda skinny.
l feel skinny.
That's all right.
l don't mind skinny girls.
Long as they got green eyes
to make up for it.
Have you got green eyes?
That's all right.
They don't have to be green.
Do you think they lied?
Do you think they stole our horses?
They don't need our shit horses.
Watch your mouth.
l'll take him into town on my own.
You boys go round up the herd.
Don't push them too hard.
l can't afford any more dropping.
Mister, we're gonna have to lift you up
to get you on top of that horse.
Here comes the Cavalry.
Do as l said.
ls he from the coach?
Only one who made it.
Mr. McElroy, can you hear me?
lt was Ben Wade.
Mr. Mc--
This man needs attention.
You see which way he rode, Evans?
Looked like they were headed to Bisbee.
You know...
there's a little town
just south of the border...
pretty little pueblucho
down by the river.
Folks would pay good money
to hear a white woman sing.
Yeah.
lmagine me shinning
on down to Mexico
with Ben Wade on my arm.
l'm not wanted in Mexico.
Jump out that back window with me now.
You're crazy.
You the doctor?
Yes.
Coach got held up.
Get him on the table.
- What's his name?
- Byron McElroy.
He's a bounty hunter
under contract with the Pinkertons.
You've lost a lot of blood, Mr. McElroy.
That bullet's still in there.
Well, get it out.
All right.
Now, what l'm about to do
is gonna hurt like a son of a bitch.
Ain't the first time l been shot.
Hold him, please.
Don't touch me.
All right.
What the fuck kind
of doctor are you, anyway?
lt's nice to have a conversation
with a patient for a change.
You see anything down there?
Marshal.
Wade's horse.
Take the back.
We'll take the front.
What the hell are they looking for?
Ben Wade.
He held up the payroll coach.
l want to talk, Mr. Hollander.
Ben Wade in Bisbee.
Shit.
We're movin' up.
Mr. Hollander?
Tucker, go on to the saloon.
You got no right
to do what you done.
You hear me?
That's my land.
Come next week it's not, Evans.
You borrowed a good deal of money
and l got rights to recompense.
But you dammed up my creek.
You shut off my water.
How'd you expect me
to pay off my debts if you can't--
Before the water touches your land,
it resides and flows on mine.
And as such, l can do with it
as l fuckin' please.
Go home and pack up.
Can you--
Can you just
let me get to spring?
l can turn the corner.
Sometimes a man has to be
big enough to see how small he is.
Railroad's coming, Dan.
Your land's worth more with you off it.
Hollander!
You look a little bent, rancher.
You come to wake some snakes?
Dan, would you like a drink?
No, thanks.
You got your horses back, didn't you?
And your cattle?
Yeah, l got my horses back.
But you killed two of my herd.
Well, they died for a good cause.
You know...
them beeves of yours,
they wouldn't even have fed a hungry dog.
l tell you what.
That should cover it.
How much you get for a day's work?
$2 when l hire out.
Well, there are $2 for a half a day.
You took up my boys' time, too.
You're right, l did.
Anything else you wanna get paid for, Dan?
You can give me $5 extra.
And what's that for?
For making me nervous.
Hands up, Ben Wade.
Boss! Boss!
Hey, Boss!
Gimme your hands, Mr. Wade.
- Tucker, take his gun.
- Gimme that.
Ben Wade...
captured in Bisbee.
Be careful with that thing.
That gun's got a curse on it.
- Laugh while you can.
- Crawley, go get the wagon.
Make sure every weapon we got
is shoot-ready.
l'll meet you out front of the office.
We gotta get him outta here.
Sure thing.
l think we should shoot him right now.
Put a bullet right in his noggin.
Do that...
everybody in this
shit-piss little town
will be dead by morning.
22 robberies.
Over $400,000 in losses.
More in delays.
The Southern Pacific will have Ben Wade
convicted in a federal court.
Hanged in public.
An example made.
And we will pay to make it happen.
Y'all notice he didn't mention
any of the lives l've taken.
l need three more men.
You can have Tucker.
Good.
l'm coming.
You only need one.
You're wounded, Mr. McElroy.
l rode in here.
Sure as hell can ride out.
He goes, Potter's coming.
What?
Doc can't shoot shit.
l was best shot in my regiment.
l'll come...
for $200.
You fight for the North or the South?
North.
We're Southern in name,
but Chicago owned.
Fine. $200.
Let's go.
- Thank you.
- Thank me when it's done.
What's goin' on?
This town's gonna burn!
- Let's get him, Mark!
- Cover me!
Shoot!
Get him!
Get in the coach.
God damn it.
Evans, Crawley, Tucker,
you need to mount up now.
Head for Evans Ranch.
l'll meet you there with the coach.
How long does he have to be here?
An hour...
to make sure his outfit takes the bait.
Hello, there!
Evans! Can you give me a hand with this?
Whatever your wife's cooking in there,
it smells good, Evans.
Let's go.
Good driving, Marshal.
Remind me not to play poker
in this town.
All right, Marshal.
Give us a count.
One, two, three.
Good luck.
You're gonna check on my family
when you come back, right?
First thing.
Let's go.
Ma'am.
Byron...
what an unpleasant surprise.
What happens if they
catch the wagon?
Well...
you saw where his man was.
He's still gotta go fetch the outfit.
Marshal's got a fast rig.
They should reach
the fort before dawn.
His gang can't do anything
in front of the whole 6th Cavalry.
Did you have something
to do with that?
l hope you're proud of yourself.
Just doin' my job, Doc.
Thanks, son.
We always wait to say grace.
We don't presume to teach
other people manners.
Aren't we supposed to say
grace for murderers, too?
Grace is for everyone, dear.
- Then why don't we say it?
- Mark.
l'd like to hear it.
God our Father, Lord, and Savior,
thank You for Your love and favor.
Please bless this drink
and food, we pray.
Bless all who shares with us today.
Amen.
lf my pa wants to, he could shoot you dead.
He can shoot a jackrabbit at 50 yards.
Shooting an animal's a lot different
than, uh, shooting a man, son.
No, it isn't.
Not in my opinion.
We could ask Byron here.
Now, Byron, he's killed dozens of people:
men and women and children,
miners, Apache.
Not a soul taken
didn't deserve what it got.
Every way of man is right
in his own eyes, Byron.
The Lord ponders the heart.
Proverbs 21 .
Dan.
You eat more when you're
nervous, Mr. Butterfield?
Oh, why, thank you, Dan.
That would be pleasant
and kind of you.
Much appreciated.
You can cut that up for me.
Oh, can you cut the fat off there?
l don't particularly like the fat at all.
l just...
And the--
And the gristle.
l don't like the gristle.
You mind if l ask you how you got
that hitch in your step, Dan?
Don't tell him nothing, Mr. Evans.
Where were you stationed?
Second Company Sharpshooters
out of Lynnfield, Massachusetts.
My father was defending the U.S. capitol
in the District of Columbia.
ls that so?
Well, Dan,
tell me the story
of how you lost your leg.
Did it get shot off, cut off?
The lndians steal it?
There's something moving
out there in the grass.
There ain't nothing.
l think l saw something over the ridge.
What if they caught
the coach already?
What if they already know
it's Crawley inside?
You ever been to San Francisco?
lf it's all right by you, Mr. Wade,
l'd rather we not talk.
So you've never been to San Francisco.
No.
l knew a girl there.
She was the daughter
of a sea captain.
She had the most
beautiful green eyes,
about the greenest eyes l ever saw.
Like yours.
And l'd stare deep into them.
They'd just change color in front of me.
All the colors of the sea.
What did you say your name was again?
Alice?
Alice.
For God's sake.
He's killed more men
than the drought.
He's not what l expected.
He's--
He's dangerous.
Dangerous is what he is, Alice.
l don't want you or the boys talking to him.
You can change your mind, Dan.
No one will think less of you.
No one can think less of me.
Six months from now,
everything's going to be green.
The cows are going to be fat.
We might even see the steam
from the train coming over the ridge.
We'll be all right.
But we won't make it
through the next six days
if l don't do this.
Sorry, Dan.
McElroy says five minutes.
You think he's too much for me?
He's a killer, Daniel.
Then someone ought
to have the decency
to bring him to justice.
What are you thinking?
l'm not out there alone, you know.
Have a little faith in me.
Ben Wade has a gang,
and they're out there tonight somewhere.
lf l don't go, we got
to pack up and leave,
and God knows where,
without a prayer, dirt-poor.
Now l'm tired, Alice.
l am tired of watching
my boys go hungry.
l'm tired of the way
that they look at me.
l'm tired of the way that you don't.
l've been standing on one leg
for three damn years,
waiting for God to do me a favor.
And He ain't listening.
Mr. Evans.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
This is my horse now.
Come on over here.
Come on.
Don't you be any trouble, Mark.
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
William.
l want to come with you.
Well, you can't.
l could help.
You're 1 4 years old.
Look, l can ride faster and shoot better
than any one of them.
The Pinkerton's hurt,
Potter's no good,
that railroad man's dead weight,
and that other bastard--
William.
l don't have time to argue.
l need you here.
That's that.
So, boys, where are we headed?
Ain't none of your business
where we're headed, Wade.
You're a prisoner.
You don't speak,
you don't piss,
you don't goddamn breathe
unless we say so.
You understand that?
We're taking you to Contention.
Putting you on the 3:10 to Yuma
day after tomorrow.
You shouldn't have told him that.
Relax, friend.
Now if we get separated,
l know where to meet up.
l'd like to thank you
for your hospitality, ma'am.
Hope l can send
your husband back all right.
What did Ben Wade mean
about sending Pa back all right?
Was he saying he was gonna kill him?
Ben Wade don't have to lift a finger.
His gang will do it for him.
Your father can take care of himself.
So...
were you conscripted
into Lincoln's army, Mr. Evans,
or did you volunteer?
Neither.
Maybe both.
What does that mean?
Means l was a volunteer
in the Massachusetts State Guard.
Then, in '62,
the federal government
was running low on men,
so they called in the state militias
to protect Washington.
And that's when you got hurt.
What are you doing out here, Dan?
You got a family to protect.
You're not a lawman.
You don't work for the railroad
like Mr. Shiny Shoes over there.
You're not a Pinkerton.
Maybe l don't like the idea
of men like you on the loose.
lt's man's nature
to take what he wants, Dan.
That's how we're born.
Well, l make an honest living.
lt might be honest,
but l don't think it's much of a living.
You must be hurting bad
for money to take this job.
Go to sleep.
l imagine debt puts
a lot of pressure on a marriage.
You imagine?
What would you know about marriage?
We can't all be cutthroats and thieves.
l know if l was lucky enough
to have a wife like Alice,
l'd treat her a whole lot
better than you do, Dan.
l'd feed her better,
buy her pretty dresses,
wouldn't make her work so hard.
Yeah, l'll bet Alice was a real pretty girl
before she married you.
Shut up about my wife.
You shut up about her.
You say one more word,
and l'll cut you down right here.
Right here.
l like this side of you, Dan.
Mr. Evans.
Okay.
lt's my watch now.
They're gonna hang me
in the mornin'
Before the night is done
They're gonna hang me
in the mornin'
l'll never see the sun
l suppose it's too much
to ask for a little quiet.
The way l figured it
is l'd be asleep
in my own bed right now
if it weren't for you.
So if l got to be up,
well, then, you're damn well
gonna be up with me, too,
Ben Wade.
They're gonna hang me
in the mornin'
Before the night is done
Hang me in the mornin'
l'll never see the sun
Son of a bitch!
Enough.
Enough!
That's enough, McElroy.
We have to bury him.
Take the time to dig one grave,
might as well dig one for yourself.
Let's go.
Mount up.
Gonna hang me in the mornin'
l'll never see the sun
Don't you worry there, Boss.
We're gonna get you
outta there in a second.
Charlie!
Wait! Wait!
Sutherland.
Jackson.
No.
Don't do this.
- Where is he?
- Open the door.
Open the door.
Let me outta here, God damn it.
- Where did they take him?
- l don't know.
Mister...
you better tell me...
where they took him...
or you will burn.
Contention.
All right?
They're going to Contention.
They're gonna put him
on the 3:10 to Yuma Prison tomorrow.
Let me outta here!
Contention is...
80 miles back the other way.
We'd have to about kill our horses.
So we'll buy new ones.
Charlie...
it's his own fault he got caught.
He made a mistake.
You think you could do
a better job leading this crew?
Maybe.
You forgotten what he done for us.
We're going to Contention.
Can't say I didn't warn you.
There's a shortcut we could take.
Shortcut?
Through the pass.
Takes you right through to Contention.
Why didn't you say something before?
That's Apache country.
I thought the government gave them land.
These are the ones refused to go.
I wouldn't take that pass.
Oh, you'd like us to take the long way?
- That's right.
- And let your boys catch us?
Mr. Butterfield, the Apache
that live in that pass
are the ones that stayed to fight.
They enjoy killing.
You ain't gonna make it.
We'll take our chances.
Something on your mind, Dan?
Why'd you kill Tucker?
Why not me?
Or Butterfield?
Well, Tucker took my horse.
Did you like him, Dan?
No.
He told me he burnt down your barn.
He was an asshole...
but wishing him dead and killing him
are two different things.
Your conscience is sensitive, Dan.
I don't think it's my favorite part of you.
Button it up, Mr. Wade.
You wanna talk to somebody,
talk to me.
I don't like talking to you, Byron.
Not when I have the gun.
No, that ain't it.
I just don't find you that interesting.
Laugh it up, Doc,
till he guts you like a fish.
Byron's like a song with one note.
You ever read another book
in your life, Byron,
besides the Bible?
No need.
Byron acts pious.
Few years ago, when he was
under contract to Central,
I seen him and a bunch of other Pinks
mow down 32 Apache
women and children.
Renegades...
gunning down railroad men
and their families.
Picking 'em off the road one by one.
Scalping 'em.
There was young ones running
around crying and screaming.
No more than three years old.
And his boys shot 'em all
then pushed 'em into a ditch.
Some of them was still crying.
But I guess Byron figured
that Jesus wouldn't mind.
Apparently Jesus don't like the Apache.
Keep on talking...
all the way to Yuma,
right up them steps,
to the rope,
straight to Hell.
Day I die, Byron,
I'm getting sprung from Hell.
I might feel the same,
if I come from the seed
of a drunk gravedigger
and the rancid womb of a whore.
Drop it, Dan Evans.
Drop it.
Toss that to the ground, Doc.
Mr. Butterfield.
Now I believe, Dan,
you're carrying a pistol as well.
I'd appreciate it if you take that out
and drop it on the ground.
Thank you.
Now, I always liked you, Byron.
But you never knew
when to shut up.
Even bad men love their mamas.
Now I think it's time
for everybody to go home.
Don't you move, Mr. Wade.
Let go of that shotgun.
William...
what the hell
are you doing here?
Now, I don't think
you gonna shoot a man
you admire in the back
of the head, boy.
Dan, tell your boy it's over.
You think you can keep
your gun on him, William?
I'm doing a damn sight
better than you did.
You ever been to Dodge City?
No.
Stop talking to him.
The way you're shuffling those cards,
I took you for a pro.
I practice a lot.
I can tell.
You ever been to Dodge?
Yes, indeed.
Meanest, most beautiful
dirty city there ever was.
Saloon was just overflowing
with cattle drivers, and road agents,
prospectors, gunslingers,
gamblers, and women.
Women who'll do things to you
you'll never forget.
They'll give you a disease you'll never forget.
Money in your pocket in Dodge City,
you can have everything
a man ever wished for.
Everything a man comes to need.
I got there on my own as a boy
not much bigger than you.
And how many men
you killed since then, Wade?
How many families you destroyed?
Quite a few.
Is it true that you dynamited
a wagon full of prospectors
in the Western Territories last spring?
No, that's a lie.
It was a train full.
Well, Dan...
I gotta take a piss.
You know, I thought
he was gonna shoot me
back at the ravine.
I really thought
he was gonna do it.
You know, there's
a wildness in his eyes.
- It reminds me of...
- He's gonna be nothing like you, Wade.
William's got a head start
on the path of decency.
Yeah, that's why I don't mess around
with doing anything good, Dan.
You do one good deed
for somebody...
I imagine it's habit-forming.
Something decent.
See that grateful look in their eyes,
imagine it makes you feel
like Christ Hisself.
All right, I had enough
of this, Wade.
Come on, let's go.
William!
- There's three of 'em.
- Yours?
If they were mine, you'd be dead.
Give me that gun, Wade.
Wade?
Wade!
I told you not to come this way.
It was McElroy's decision.
I told you there'd be trouble.
Give me the keys to the handcuffs.
Easy...
Easy now.
Where is he?
He's gone.
He took the horses with him.
I found this in the grass.
What's the quickest way
out of the pass?
He'll be looking for help getting his cuffs off.
We're going after him?
Well, there ain't no reward
for getting him halfway
to that train, is there?
I got to be honest with y'all.
I like some of their food.
As for wanting $40 a month, now,
like them Irish up north...
Goddamn Coolies.
They'll work just fine
with my left boot up their ass.
Well, if could teach
a monkey to lay track...
Well, what we need
is some Negroes
brung in here, Mr. Boles.
Show these Chinamen
what real work is.
Holy Christ.
- Who's that?
- That's him.
You, help me with the handcuffs.
Break the chain.
Use the hammer.
I got five guns on you
out here, Ben Wade!
Best come on out!
Our horses.
What in the hell's going on here?
Mr. Butterfield, all finished in Bisbee?
Mr. Boles.
Better hurry. We're making the last blasts
through the mountains this week.
That's my prisoner.
I'm taking him to Contention,
putting him on the prison train to Yuma.
What prisoner?
Come now, Mr. Boles,
that's Ben Wade you have there.
Ben Wade gunned down my kid brother
in front of me
six years ago in Abilene.
Your brother was a lyin', bilkin' card sharp.
That is, if he's the asshole I remember.
Could, of course, been some other
asshole I killed that I forgot about.
You can't do that.
That's immoral.
Moral ain't got a damn thing to do with it.
I was expecting to collect
a $200 reward for that man.
I'm delivering him to Contention.
I need that money.
Need it bad enough to die?
Well, at least let us take our horses.
I got no problem with that...
as long as you ride away, mister.
Nice knowing you, Dan.
Did you see me get that one
with the shovel?
Doc.
Doc!
Dan!
God damn it!
Did we make it?
Did we get away?
Yeah, Doc.
We did.
Thanks to you.
We need a place to lay low.
Keep him outta sight
till the train comes.
There's a hotel up here.
I'll check us in.
You ride around back.
All right.
Follow me.
Hello, gentlemen.
Hey, William, you go keep
a watch at the railhead.
If you see them coming...
I'll let you know.
And William?
There's a Can-Can on the hour
if you're interested.
It's the bridal suite.
Hope you don't mind.
It's all they had.
Well, well.
That looks like rain clouds over Bisbee.
You still need that $200, Dan?
Shut up.
Mr. Evans, you continue
to give me great confidence.
Well, it ain't 3:10 yet.
I'm gonna go see about the marshal.
Come on, move.
Let's go.
We're looking for a group escorting an outlaw
by the name of Ben Wade.
Yeah, we been chasing him
through these tunnels.
Who are you?
What's it to you?
Ben Wade killed my brother.
Then your brother must be famous.
You boys some kind of posse?
I hate posses.
So this is the bridal suite.
Now, I wonder how many brides
have taken in this view.
What are you gonna do
with your $200 now, Dan?
Now that the rains are coming?
I owe people money, Wade.
That drought left me in the hole.
Well, what do you think
about double that amount?
You could pay your debts,
buy a hundred more cows,
build a new barn.
How you reckon
I'm gonna do that?
Just lay down your gun
and let me walk out the door.
It's worth $400 to me.
Is that what you reckon my price is?
No.
No, I reckon it's a thousand.
$1,000.
Now, there's 10 times that amount
in Butterfield's coach.
Oh, yeah?
You want my cut, Dan?
It's all yours.
Isn't that kind of reckless of you, Wade?
Seeing as, uh...
you're so sure that, uh,
your crew's coming to get you?
Oh, they're coming, Dan.
Sure as God's vengeance,
they're coming.
But I just like to do things easy.
Imagine what you could do
with a thousand dollars, Dan.
You could hire
a couple of ranch hands.
Your boys could go to school,
grow up smart.
What about Alice?
She would be the proud wife
of a bona fide Arizona rancher.
All you got to do is say yes.
Well...
would you give me a bank note, Wade?
Or maybe you'd be kind enough
to make a deposit for me.
Cash.
Well, you... you tell me, Wade.
How would I account for...
for that amount of money?
And what would I tell people
when I spend it?
That, uh...
That you got the jump on me,
you escaped, and somehow I got a fortune?
No. How dumb do you think people are?
Nobody needs to know.
You know what?
Would you do me a favor?
Don't talk to me for a while.
You mean we're still not friends?
No.
No, we're not.
Come five minutes to three,
we're gonna be a hell
of a lot closer than you think.
They're gonna hang me
In the mornin'
Before the night is done
They're gonna hang me
In the mornin'
I'll never see the sun
Who is it?
It's me, Dan.
I brought help.
You been gone a long time,
Mr. Butterfield.
How do I know somebody
ain't got a gun on you out there?
Dan, this is Marshal Will Doane.
- Marshal.
- Mr. Evans.
Two of my finest men:
Harvey Pell...
Sam Fuller.
I'm sorry about all that, Marshal.
- I really am grateful for the help.
- Don't mention it.
So you fellas really gonna
help put me on this train?
It may not seem like it, Mr. Wade,
but we got law and order in this town,
just like any other.
Well, that's very reassuring, Marshal.
How much is Butterfield paying you?
That's none of your business.
You gonna come with us?
Oh, I'll be walking with you...
every step of the way.
You have my word on that, Dan.
So there's five of us.
Five is good.
It ain't enough.
It ain't nearly enough.
- Pa!
- That's my boy.
They're coming.
They're coming this way.
I seen 'em.
- Where?
- About a mile out. Same way we come.
- How many are there?
- Seven. Eight.
Which is it, boy?
Seven or eight?
Seven.
Folks, sorry to bother you,
but I'm gonna need you all
to move outside
as quickly as possible.
That's it, folks.
Thank you very much.
That's it.
Move along, folks.
Move along.
Come on, now!
Hey! Get out of my way!
Right there.
There sure are a lot of 'em.
I didn't figure on it
being the whole gang.
Boss.
Boss?
Boss, you in there?
What do you want me to tell him?
You tell him you'll write him
a letter every day from Yuma.
You be careful, Wade.
Charlie. Boys.
- Hey, Boss.
- Yeah?
Charlie, why don't you take the boys
down to the saloon
and buy 'em a drink.
You okay?
Oh, I'm fine. I'm just sittin' up here
with my four new friends.
Hey...
That's enough.
Thank you, Charlie. Boys.
Listen up!
That's Ben Wade
they have up there.
Ben... Wade!
Now...
the Railroad intends...
to put him on the 3:10 to Yuma...
and hang him.
What's he doing?
We will give you 200 cash dollars
to any man who shoots
any one of his captors.
How much?
200 cash dollars guaranteed!
$200 guaranteed!
- Right here. You got me.
- Hand it over.
I'll tell you now, mister.
I'll take 200.
Give me the money.
Well, you gotta shoot 'em first.
There's gotta be 30, 40
more guns out there now.
Oh, to hell with this.
- Now just a minute, Marshal.
- Look, look.
If it's a fair fight, well, sure.
I'd stay for that.
A fair fight, that...
That's a man's duty, but...
there's only five of us.
I'm sorry, mister,
but I'm not gonna die here today.
And neither are my men.
Marshal...
forgot this.
Marshal!
Marshal, what's the...
Now, you see, Dan...
generally, pretty much
everyone wants to live.
- I'll double your money.
- Let's go, boys.
Please. Do you wanna see us
shot down in the street?
This thing happened in Bisbee.
That means Butterfield, too.
Why bring your troubles to Contention?
We've got families.
Every one of us is a family man.
I'm a family man, too.
He's gonna walk out on you.
Then you best get out
like the rest of us.
He's gonna come back up here,
and he's gonna walk out on you.
Now what you gotta figure
is why you and your boy
are gonna die.
Because Butterfield's railroad
lost some money?
Is that all of 'em?
- Get inside!
- Get a doctor!
Almost.
Your move, General.
What do you expect him to say?
I expect him to say something
that makes sense.
Something that might
save the two of you.
Take a look, Dan.
What's the matter?
You don't wanna see?
I'll see 'em soon enough.
What about you, kid?
You wanna look?
You stay away from
the window, William.
Go on, take a look.
Animals, all of 'em.
Campos, stand guard.
Jackson, back door.
They're gonna kill you
and your father, William.
They're gonna laugh while they do it.
I think you know that.
Call 'em off.
Why should I?
Because you're not all bad.
Yes, I am.
You saved us from those Indians.
I saved myself.
You got us through the tunnels.
You helped us get away.
If I'd had a gun in them tunnels,
I would have used it on you.
I don't believe you.
Kid, I wouldn't last five minutes
leading an outfit like that
if I wasn't as rotten as hell.
Dan?
I can't do it, Dan.
And if I can't do it,
you shouldn't do it, either.
They say discretion
is the better part of valor.
If you think you have
an obligation to me
or to the Railroad,
I assure you, you do not.
I'm releasing you.
It's just you left, Dan.
Just you and your boy.
Maybe he's right, Pa.
Maybe we should go home.
Well, what did Doc Potter
give his life for, William?
And McElroy?
Little red ants on a hill.
I'll pay you the 200, Dan, right now,
and you can walk away.
You know, this whole ride,
that's been nagging on me.
That's what the government
gave me for my leg.
$198.36.
And the funny thing is that...
when you think about it,
which I have been lately,
was they weren't paying me
to walk away.
They were paying me
so they could walk away.
Don't muddy the past
and the present, Dan.
No, no, no, Wade.
I'm seeing the world the way it is.
If you take him to the train, Pa,
I'm going with you.
No, Mr. Butterfield's
gonna take you home.
- No, I'm not going anywhere with him.
- Yes, you are.
I'm staying here with you.
You're gonna hold up
in a room across the hall.
You're gonna wait until we leave.
I'll get him to Bisbee, Dan.
I promise you.
Oh, you're gonna promise me
a lot more than that, Butterfield.
I want guarantees that Hollander
and his boys
will never set foot
on my land again,
and that my water's gonna flow.
And I expect you to hand my wife
1,000 cash dollars when you see her.
You got money to spare.
I can deliver that.
Just get him on the train.
You heard him?
I heard him.
William, I want you
to give this back to your mother.
I want you to tell her that it helped me
find what was right.
Pa...
I can't.
I can't just leave you.
I'm gonna be a day
behind you, William.
Unless something happens,
and if it does,
I need a man at the ranch
to run things,
protect our family, and I know
that you can do that
because you've become
a fine man, William.
You've become a fine man.
You got all the best parts of me.
What few there are.
And you just remember
that your old man
walked Ben Wade to that station
when nobody else would.
You know, squeezing that watch
won't stop time.
Don't get so scared.
You might back a bad move.
You ever read the Bible, Dan?
I read it one time.
I was eight years old.
My daddy just got hisself
killed over a shot of whiskey,
and my mama said,
"We're going back East to start over."
So she gave me a Bible,
sat me down in the train station,
told me to read it.
She was gonna get our tickets.
Well, I did what she said.
I read that Bible
from cover to cover.
It took me three days.
She never came back.
It's time.
It's a half mile
to the station from here, Dan.
I guess we're walking.
There he is!
Go and flush him out!
Let's get to it.
Lucky.
Dan.
Thanks.
Move.
Come on!
Might not get a chance
to use those Scofields, Charlie.
Perhaps you can explain to me
the next portion of your plan, Dan.
I think I got him!
Hey. Hey!
Not the black hat!
The rancher,
you dumb-shits!
The rancher!
The ranch...
Charlie!
Get back! Get back!
Boss.
Boss!
Let's go.
The white door.
Move it!
All right.
I ain't doing this
no more, Dan.
I'm getting you
on that train, Wade.
Your son went back!
The boy's gone, hero.
Ain't nobody watching no more.
You still got that one good leg.
Why don't you use it
to get on home?
Charlie!
Charlie Prince!
Yeah, Boss!
Hold your fire.
- I'm walking out.
- Hold your fire!
I ain't never been no hero, Wade.
The only battle I seen,
we was in retreat.
My foot got shot off
by one of my own men.
You try telling that story to your boy.
See how he looks at you then.
Boss! Boss!
Okay, Dan.
Son.
They're on the roofs!
Boss!
Boss! Drop!
- Can you make this?
- Yeah.
Come on.
Come on!
Go! Run!
Spread out!
What time is it?
About 10 past 3.
Where's the 3:10 to Yuma?
Running late, I suppose.
How late?
Beats me.
Gets here when it gets here.
Goddamn trains.
Never can rely on 'em, huh?
By the window!
You know...
I ain't stubborn.
Excuse me?
You said I was stubborn
for keeping my family
on a dying ranch.
It's my son Mark.
The young one?
He got tuberculosis when he was 2.
The doctor said he'd die
if he didn't have a dry climate, so...
Why are you telling me this?
I don't know.
I guess I just...
wanted you to know
that I ain't stubborn is all.
Well, as long as we're
making confessions...
Yeah?
I've been to Yuma Prison before.
Twice.
Escaped twice, too.
First car, sliding door.
They'll be coming!
Yeah!
I got a prisoner to go to Yuma!
Well, you did it, Dan.
No!
Pa.
For a one-leg rancher...
he's one tough son of a bitch.
Yeah.
You done it, Pa.
You done it.
You got him on the train.
Pa.