Hot weather.
Land here it feels like
dog's stool.
You know, huh?
Fuck!
Smashed.
There are men of military force, are
call, pay attention to the convoy. Replace.
If she reported troop movements
please shoot. Your turn. Replace.
Maybe he called his wife.
He dropped.
One Moment. There were women and children, within 200
yard, moving towards the convoy.
His arm is not moving.
He was carrying something.
He pulls out a grenade. RKG grenade Russia.
I think he gave it to the boy.
- Women and children?
- Did you see it?
Can insure?
Negative. You know ROE.
Your turn.
- They will menggorengmu if you're wrong.
They will put you in jail.
- Fuck.
You managed to hit it.
Back here.
Never leave
rifle on the ground.
Yes, Sir.
Good shot.
You're talented.
One day you will be a great hunter.
Listen to this book, several times.
That judgment ..
for the trust.
Time where we have to do it.
We can not see with his eyes.
So we do not know the glory of his plans.
Our eyes see
like the reflection in the glass.
- The day we arrived ...
- Why are you doing this?
We will see it clearly.
And understand the mystery of how.
Let's pray.
There are 3 types of people in this world.
Sheep, wolf and sheepdog.
Some people believe
the devil does not exist in the world--
And if hatred appeared at their door
do not know how to protect themselves.
It was a sheep.
Then there are the predators. They use violence
to prey on the weak.
They are wolves.
Then there are those
blessed with talent aggression
and protect the flock.
They are a rare breed of living
to face serigala--
They sheepdog.
We do not raise sheep in this family
and I will menghajarjika you
into a wolf.
- Wayne--
But we protect our herd.
And if someone tried to fight
or protect your sister you get
my permission to finish.
He attacked Jeff.
Is that true?
- Yes, Sir. True.
And you finish it?
You know who you are.
You know your goals.
There is not anyone there.
You come out with a waist belt.
-What Should you do?
- Sleeping with it.
-I Will wear it and see make
Sarah mood changed.
Strong -Angin make her mood changed.
Is that what they say?
- You know what they call it when SMA--
Sarah menghisap--
- Do not say.
Jeez, Chris.
That recompense.
-There Are two women ...
- He was watching.
- Wait till you see this.
- Yes I Do.
Hey, babe who wants
rodeo star?
What the hell?
You said he did not come home until tomorrow.
- I said what?
- Do not bother him.
He did not do anything.
Chris, do not disturb him!
Leave him alone!
Fuck, what's wrong with you ?!
- He does not know, okay?
-What Does he know?
- You do not know?
-I Take my hat.
He does not know.
- You do not know?
-What Is wrong with you ?!
Why did you do it
to everyone?
Go away from here!
What is wrong with you!
- Run Out.
-I Do not know what you expect of me.
You brought me here and out
together with your sister every weekend!
Why do you think I do this?
I'm doing this to get attention!
Take your things and get out.
Okay. Screw you!
Do you think you could be a rodeo cowboy for?
You're not a cowboy. you just
farm administrators.
And you lower!
Do not say.
Oh My.
I do not understand what you said.
We had to travel to another state.
Different city every weekend.
- Can not stay here.
- Maybe he's right.
- But he's right.
- True matter what, Chris?
He's not true. We cowboy.
Living in a dream.
Friend, friend see this.
- You're from Texas?
- Yes, Sir.
- You're a patriot.
- Yes I Do.
- And you're angry.
-I Want to serve.
- Fight?
- Yes, Sir.
Meet the elite fighters.
- Seals?
- Sea, air and land.
-I Less able to swim, sir.
- This is not for a broken heart.
- Most people will stop.
-I Do not most people, sir.
I did not stop.
Lift your legs!
Thank this!
It was the first time.
If you are swept away, you're going to die!
Do not turn your face from me.
View and accept this.
Old old are you, huh?
Did you join the Navy
because they want to have fun in the Noah Ark?
- How old are you?
30! You've dusty and disappeared.
- 30 years.
We will do it again.
We're going to be a fighter.
I never see him.
I came to confront terrorists.
Who did it?
I do not know.
-Do I ask you?
- Do Not.
See yourself.
You bastard! That's what I said.
Biggles, the name now.
And the tickets very difficult.
What are you doing here if
you hate water?
Never mind, sir.
I'm not black.
- Do Not?
-I New black. We ran slow,
low jump and swim.
And I made a proud white skin!
That people who quit!
You say goodbye.
If he stops here,
He stopped on the battlefield.
When everything is in trouble,
he will not pull you out.
I'm looking for a knight.
I can not hear?
You want to call your parents?
Maybe they can replace you.
This is a game.
That's what I'm talking about.
- Where are you?
We will survive, sir!
They are warm!
Give her speech.
How about you, old man?
How are you?
Dangerous.
I felt dangerous.
- He feels dangerous.
Log In!
Oh yes it penyiksaanmu!
Once more.
If you want the target, use this.
- Hello.
- Hi There.
-How Are you?
- Okay, thank you.
- Can I buy you a drink?
-What Made you drink
higher 6 inches and charming?
Does not make you married?
I'm watching you.
Do not be a loser.
Go home.
That might leather pants.
Oh yes?
What to wear pants women
so as not to be disturbed?
Maybe Corduroy.
What's wrong with kalian--
suddenly single after 3 beers?
Which occurred after the third beer
is the fourth beer.
Very good.
- Red-neck real.
-I Am not a red-neck,
I Texans.
-What's The difference?
- We rode horses,
they rode his cousin.
What do you do before?
-I Polish dolphins. they should
polished or broken skin.
-Do I look stupid to you?
No, you look sad.
Am I high enough to
buy you a drink?
Not until you tell me your job.
- Okay, how about this ..
One glass for one question.
- How Do?
- Ok.
Okay asked.
You're military. Which branch?
I just completed the BUD / S.
- Are you kidding? You Seal?
- Yes, ma'am.
That's two questions.
Shit.
I do not mean to do it.
Okay, honestly.
I know about all of you.
My sister is engaged to Seal.
- Is It True?
- Yes I Do.
What do you mean you know
all about us?
You're a bunch of arrogant, selfish
he who thinks can lie
and do as you please.
I never dated SEAL.
What do you mean selfish?
I am devoted to my country.
- Why?
- Because this is the best country on earth
and I deserve to be protected.
I'm sorry this happened to your sister
but it was not me.
Nice to meet you.
- Where are you going?
-I Will go home, you say no
be dating SEAL.
I said I'd never marry.
Hello, nice to meet you?
- What is your name?
- Taya.
Taya.
I'm Chris Kyle.
Nice to meet you.
You're very selfish thought could
protect us all, right Chris?
Our commander says
there are three things that should we worry about:
ego, alcohol and women.
Sounds like you are being attacked.
You are beautiful.
So you ...
I got you.
I'm not going home with you
so do not think about it.
Feel the air filling every cell
in the body.
This is our ritual.
We mastered the breath, we master
mind kita--
pull the trigger will
become unconscious effort.
You will notice
but not directing it.
When you exhale,
regarded as pause,
and the space between heartbeats.
Hey this Taya, I can not
pick up the phone. Leave It
message and call you back.
Hey it's me. men who
shoes you muntahi.
I think you do not receive
my last message. Or previous message.
- So I was thinking ...
- You think what?
Hey, how are you?
How are you?
- Okay.
- Well ... okay ...
What are you doing?
Being lazy.
Do you?
I just wanted to talk to you.
Small binoculars, a little escape. If you
mengeker buttons, may
missed 2 inches.
If mengeker shirt, maybe
missed 2 feet.
You better shut it, Kyle.
Yes, Sir.
I'll play it.
- You like that one?
- That one.
- This is your prize.
- Thank you sir.
- Thank you. Hello.
- Good afternoon.
Looks good with you.
Have you always wanted to be a soldier?
- No, I want to be a cowboy
I did it and felt need anything else.
- So you start to save women
of the bar?
I saved the bar it from you.
Do you like country music?
Only when I'm depressed.
-I Love children. You like?
- One day.
My mother said I had a nose for
choose the wrong man.
That's a bad thing to say
to a woman.
He was right.
That brought you here.
Make yourself a present.
I like it.
Do you ever think that happened?
I do not know.
I wish I could do the job.
Do we see the same target?
You spit in the dust.
Do not worry, we can use
substitute for people who
can not shoot.
Oh shit!
- You're shaking.
-I Know.
- We do not need to do this.
- No, I would.
- Yes I Do.
-I Want to feel it.
You close your eyes?
If I close my eyes,
can not see the target.
There was nothing there
except the target.
- Negative. There's something there.
Come Here.
Give me 50 push-ups, Kyle.
I'm a better shot.
- Oh Lord, Chris. Do Not.
-What Is wrong?
- You just know me.
- Yes I Do.
What are you scared of?
Nothing.
Everything. I do not know.
What if it did not work?
We'll get married and
start a family.
You've planned it, right.
I finished. I love you.
You need a ring if you want to speak strong
like that.
- Ok.
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. and Mrs. Chris Kyle.
What happened to your neck?
No makeup neck.
Percayajika you say that?
What?
Because they.
- Oh, God.
Cheers.
What he said, Chief?
We just received a call.
Task!
Yes I Do!
Yeah, wow!
- Let them.
-I Am very scared.
Nothing to be afraid of.
It's part of the plan.
Your heart beats.
Because I'm going to go to war.
Welcome to Fallujah.
The new wild west in the middle east old.
AQL put up the price of your head and
extremists from around the world come
to the border to collect.
You sniper paired with
someone who take care of you and keep
Marines were checking the position.
Your duty to protect
Marines whatever it takes.
The city has been evacuated. Militias are still
was here
wants to kill you.
Bring them home safely.
We can go home.
Run Out. Run Out.
Lower your head, Tex.
Muj also got a sniper.
Sniper will not be aiming for your head.
They have a sniper
who could shoot the head
from a distance of 500 yards.
They called Mustafa.
He followed the Olympics.
There is a sniper shooting in the Olympics?
There were women and children within 200 yards
towards the convoy.
His arms were silent, he brings something.
He brought a grenade Russia
and given to the child.
Do you see it? Can insure?
- Negative.
You know ROE. Your turn.
- If one of them will menggorengmu.
Wanitajalang jerk!
Good shot, Tex.
Nice One.
Received. Nice AL.
- Damn.
- Do not touch me.
Where is everyone?
- Train the soldiers Hajj.
- Why do not you there?
I have a problem.
- Do you still read comics?
This graphic novel, bro.
There is a difference.
I heard you shot someone.
You made it?
Is It True?
There is a child who has not had feathers
The cock
His mother gave grenade
send out for
Marines killed.
I've never seen it before.
Yeah, but you know the kid
can kill 10 Marines, huh?
You're doing your job.
End of story.
This is not like the way I do it.
Fuck! What the hell!
Are you watching, Einstein?
You can thank him later.
Moving On!
Fast.
There is a car bomb!
Hold your fire!
Keep an eye on the roof!
There were shot.
Visible enemy snipers.
Location R155704.
Stinks here.
You protect us.
That's a good shot.
- Clean, right?
- True.
Enemy sniper sneaked in.
Yes, it will not happen again.
Should not happen again.
There is a hot entrusted quarter mile away.
I will make a report.
- How much do you get?
-I Can be six.
No, I can be eight,
but they dragged two people.
- You can be six?
- Yes, why?
- You can be more than the others.
- Yes, but they can be one of us.
You can not shoot what
can not you see.
- His wife told him to bring the Qur'an.
-I Do not know the form of the Qur'an.
But I can describe what he was carrying.
Metal objects, firing bullets 7.62,
and looks like the AK-47.
So what does he bring?
He came.
Ladies and gentlemen, listen up.
There is a legend among us.
Give him a big applause.
The legend is already making a record.
He killed 100 people with one shot.
One shot of a man.
He '' blow '' 100 men.
And he's still single.
Oh My.
Competition throw food? Come on.
The only way to make silent.
Did you kill people?
Not the way to start a conversation, dear.
Do not behave like that to me.
I want you to tell me everything.
There are some things that are not
can be said on the phone.
You make me pregnant and I sat
alone install cots ...
... and you can not talk to me?
That's your big plan?
All is fine there?
I can not stop thinking about
the pink dress.
His name evening dress.
Yes I Do.
Three days is not counted as a honeymoon.
It was three days of fun.
-I Miss you.
-I Missed you.
- You want me to talk naughty to you?
- Yes, wait a minute.
I was holding a rifle.
You must decide which
more importantly, dear.
You really are lust.
I'm fat and horny.
That's disgusting.
Although the weight is 150 pounds,
I still want to make love to you.
- Really romantic.
- What about my son?
- No one said he was a man.
- You two would be amazing.
How do you know?
I know. I can see it.
- I hope you're right.
-I Am right.
-Ayahmu Contacted you?
-I Do not check my email.
Oh My.
You should call him, okay?
-What Is wrong?
-I Do not think straight.
What is wrong?
- Your brother is sent.
-What Do you mean? To a school?
No, he did not go to school.
Just call your father.
What do you mean? Where is she?
Right there.
He headed Iraqis.
Sorry dear.
The man who held the knife is a member
Jordan radicals funded Bin Laden.
Trained by Bin Laden,
loyal to bin Laden.
His name was Zarqawi.
The jerk is the prince
Al-Qaeda in the Iraqis.
Troops, AQL, amounted to 5 thousand people.
They are not ordinary mercenary force.
They are well trained, well paid ...
... and this time, they run the operation
biggest offensive since Vietnam.
Zarqawi and his Lieutenant, they
is our top priority.
There is only one way to
find them.
Ie check from door to door,
until we find them ...
... or someone who can
provide their location.
So we need to examine 10
building per hour.
I know it very much,
very aggressive.
Do not rely too much on
air support.
This is a priority target
The highest until today.
I want them dead or captured, understand?
Any question?
If the Marines in haste,
they could be shot.
They can not be training like us.
Most of them
civilians 6 months ago.
Let us train them.
I'll show you how to them.
No, we need you to keep an eye on the situation.
- The enemy already knows we're up there.
- Under very dangerous.
You want to be the savior?
I just wanted to catch them.
Can not see, can not shoot.
They all know your name.
They feel safe when you're up there.
- Do Not.
- That's what they think.
So stay up there, watch them.
You said snipers AQL
never follow the Olympics?
While the Iraqis have not qualified
for three Olympics.
Mustafa instead of Iraqis.
He is from Syria.
Once you get in, I do not
could see nothing.
So only slowly.
Okay.
Log In!
To hell with this.
I will go down to the bottom
with the marines.
You coming?
Do Not.
I want to go home alive.
Not my job knocking on the door.
I do not want to do that.
If I do not see you down there ...
... make sure I will not see you again.
Hey, do you mind if I come with you?
Of course.
You're the legend that, right?
You've killed 24 people?
-I Do not count.
- That was really cool.
There was a nigger in Bravo
the chase.
I know a few things.
There are several things that can
I show you, how?
All Right.
-What Does it mean?
- Break.
Get down on the floor right now!
- Do not!
- Get down!
Why are you here?
You should have an evacuation.
Who are you?
I do not care about this house.
This is a war zone, sir.
Get down.
Fast.
They hide behind.
Still no one else in this house?
He's going to blow us.
Searched his clothes.
- He knows we're talking.
- Who are you talking about?
Who knew we talk?
He cut ...
- Please ...
- Target is secured?
Okay, take him.
Put your hands behind your head.
The Current! Fast!
Take him into another room.
When he spoke, a
he will come to his house.
Who is he? ''
Someone named Butcher.
A son of the Devil.
He was a bouncer?
Zarqawi's number one soldier.
- Zarqawi?
- Zarqawi.
Yes, we want to know the location of Zarqawi.
You know where he is?
Tell us where he is.
How can we meet?
You no information about Zarqawi?
Find Butchers,
you will find Zarqawi.
Okay, how do we find him?
Look at me when you're talking.
Where can we find it?
He asked for money.
- 100 thousand dollars.
- You need 100 thousand dollars?
You do not have any evidence of this guy there.
Hello.
This is the proof.
I want to help, but I need something.
Phone number, address, name.
- Sir, the third team need help.
- Moving On!
Look at me when you're talking.
Hey, look at me.
I need something.
I can help.
Give me a name,
we will take care of it.
I bisajanji you.
Will I guarantee you safety.
Tell us.
-Amir Khalaf Fanus?
- That was the original name of the Butchers.
He was the number two Zarqawi.
He's the one.
Yes, but you do not know his real name,
otherwise you would have written.
There are several pseudonyms.
If your information is correct,
we met the Sheik.
He asked for 100 thousand dollars.
If he can submit Butchers,
he will get it.
This Agent Snead, DIA.
Check the name Amir Khalaf Fanus.
Yes, I'll wait.
If we're going back there,
3 teams could just ...
Can not. Centres need contractors
if we would send money.
Yes, what you got?
Ok.
Let's meet the Sheik.
Who is our target?
Bouncer Zarqawi.
They say she likes to wear
a drill as a weapon.
Prior to joining the Marines
I joined the seminary school.
-I Hampirjadi pastor.
- Why do so?
I like to bet.
I love the game of dice.
Personal cell phone?
You have not heard? I legend.
- Hey, baby.
- You're right, the doctor told the boy.
What?
-little Boy.
- A boy!
Nice One. Congratulations.
Chris?
Take the money. Refuge.
Take the bag!
Chris?
Let's go from here.
Dear?
- I heard one shot.
- From a high angle.
- 280 meters.
-Oh My.
- Did you see it?
- Do Not.
Damn, he took the child from the Sheik.
Ask for help.
We are stuck.
Location, 4,536,237.
I will throw smoke grenades.
Wait.
Forward!
Who will die open mouth.
Come on!
Screw you!
Gosh, messy once.
You're a fool.
What do you think?
You failed to secure the location.
This will stop them all.
Back to headquarters.
- We have to go after them.
- No, the mission was canceled.
-What Do you mean?
- They will be making plans.
We can not let
they run like that.
I'll be home in 3 weeks.
It will be three weeks long.
- You are okay?
- Yes I Do.
It is okay.
I'm here.
- You are okay?
- Yes I Do.
You're the most beautiful woman
I've seen.
There was an alien in my body.
- And there was a strange man in my room.
- Our room.
Your hand feels different.
This is my hand.
- Why am I so nervous ...
-I Also nervous.
- Do Not.
-I Oath.
What if the alien was holding me?
How Do?
Spooky.
You're laughing.
Everything will be alright.
- Promise?
- Yes, of course.
You're very good to me.
Maybe we could get out.
Are you listening?
- Chris?
-What?
What you want to do today?
We can relax here.
Okay, okay.
Let us relax.
-What Are you doing?
- Tease.
You're good at teasing.
I will be there.
All looks good.
-What Do you feel?
-I Am fine.
- Soon will come out.
- I hope so.
-What Are you, Mr. Kyle?
-I Just fine, thank you.
Surely you're still adapting.
Do Not.
It was the first time we left the house.
-I Am glad to be home.
Please use this.
I do not want to be checked.
- Are you a smoker?
- Do Not.
- Do you drink?
- Only when I'm thirsty.
- 170-110.
-Oh My.
- Chris ...
- That's a high figure?
As if you just drank 40 cups of coffee.
I appreciate the thought.
- Thank you.
- You're going to check it?
Yes I Do.
- You're pranking earlier.
-What Should I do? You did not say anything.
- As if all is fine.
- Everything is fine.
No, Chris, your blood pressure 170-110.
I'm driving a car
on the highway in bright daylight.
I am fine. being there
war, people die.
And there's nothing to talk about,
as if nothing ever happened.
We're on the way home.
Life is simple.
There is not even in the news,
nobody cares.
Currently no war and
I go to a mall.
I should be there.
-What Is wrong? You are okay?
- It would come out.
Gosh, okay.
- You're crazy.
- It is okay.
Gosh, dear.
You look beautiful.
Soon born.
Hi There.
Hi, little man.
Our baby cry,
I thought you would calm him down.
I've watched it.
I have to make sure you
did not have a mistress.
Recording enemy sniper victim.
He sold his recording on the streets.
The victim of the American army.
When we are on the phone, what was he?
Right?
Speak Up. You do not protect
with silent.
-I Do not want to talk.
- Lmajinasiku very bad.
- They are barbarians.
- Chris.
- This is not about them.
It's about us.
What?
You've got to get back to us.
Ok?
Welcome back.
Colonel wait.
Back from vacation.
True.
- Hey, wait a minute.
- Okay, hurry up.
Hey.
Brother ...
- You are okay?
- I heard you in action here.
All the talk about you.
That's what they say?
How are you?
You are okay?
You are my hero.
-Come On, Kyle! Colonel wait.
- The legend.
You are okay?
Yes, I would skip tumpanganku.
I'm just tired.
I want to go home.
I am proud of you.
The father was also proud of you.
To hell with this place.
- You said what?
Come on.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you sir.
Gronsky and officers
top was gone.
I've studied them.
I know everything.
This war is influenced by the thoughts of our enemies.
Yes, Sir.
- That was you?
- Yes, that's right, sir.
You're a man most wanted Iraqis.
There are 180 thousand dollar reward
above your head. Congratulations.
Do not tell my wife.
He might fill my head.
Do you want to form a team
to hunt Butchers?
Yes, Sir.
There is intelligence that indicates
area of operation.
I want you to kill him.
Find him.
Yes, Sir.
Okay, let's get him.
Clean up all before going.
- In action together with the legend.
-What?
- The legend.
-will Tell you another time.
- You're great, man.
- Thank you.
What would you say?
Gospels is bulletproof?
- It?
- Yes, I have never seen you open it.
We must honor God, right?
You have a God?
Why not?
When I was a kid there was a fence
electricity near our house.
Children trying to touch
and the most enduring.
War like that.
You must hold on tightly.
You want to get out of the team?
I just wanted to believe what we are doing.
We're chasing bad guys.
Yes, there are bad people everywhere.
You want them to come to
San Diego or New York?
We are not only protecting the sandy soil.
Ok. Let us kill him.
I was in the building next to the East
facing restaurant.
Log In. Come on.
Safe.
- Get down.
- Okay, okay.
Put your hands behind your head.
Target looks.
I watched the window, Chris.
- Create a safe limit.
- Well, let's get ready.
On the corner.
Let's move to another room.
Your wife know? Do you know this man?
She said she did not know.
How are you, son?
Do you know this face?
Are you sure?
Should you tell them
do not go until we go.
Hey, keep an eye window, make sure you
taking pictures of all the incoming and outgoing.
What we can?
16 military agents entered.
- 16?
- Yes, they serve many customers.
Look at this.
- He's still there?
- He had just entered.
- He's in there,
but it is not easy to reach.
-I Do not know about it.
They see the legend entry, he like
celebrities, ask for his autograph?
They're partying?
Hey, I do not promote myself.
True, I did it for you.
- You're not going to be the head
if it were not for us.
- True.
He invites you to
dinner ldul Adha.
He said on this day everything
should sit down and eat with him.
He was really sweet.
Cucumber was put here?
Yes I Do. This chili.
Soaked overnight.
Then just add vodka.
- That's the point.
- Just do it.
Good, the food is delicious.
That's a good question.
All these people.
Oh My.
You will eat with your left hand?
Come On.
I want to wash your hands.
Hey.
He is clean.
Hey!
- Check it.
- Do not go anywhere.
- Hey, what is this?
- Beagles,
Chill Out.
Look at that?
- Did you see?
-What Is wrong?
- Bring the tarp.
-Oh My.
Well, you tell him that
he will go to jail,
in lraq, they know what
that will be done to him,
or he can help us
search for the man in the restaurant.
Tell him, it's his choice.
That's him.
Safe.
Good, let's move it.
Southern team ready.
Right-ready security.
He moves.
15 meters.
10 meters.
5 meters.
He knocked.
Wait.
They open it.
I shoot.
Forward.
Forward!
Beagles, nothing out of the back?
No, he did not move.
- D, put him down.
- Okay.
Put him down.
We find something,
carefully, remain vigilant.
Enemies come!
Back Off!
The outer side of security!
Get down!
That's them!
Butchers stir.
3 Butchers move, I'm chasing.
Butchers shot, to your position.
We've told him, that is her choice.
He chose the wrong side, it's his choice.
Hey, Chris, Clean up all, we
go, things got messed up.
Sir, there are here, we have to make a trail.
Good work, Richie.
- You want more?
- See what this is.
You can be the object was given,
The way it works.
You can not get that one.
This.
- That's great.
-Come On, we're ready.
- You can raise it.
- Troops ready.
That's not possible.
Okay, interesting.
- That's for you.
- Okay.
What? Take from the floor.
Come take.
- Put that it's here.
- Excuse me, Sir.
- See?
- This is it.
Purple.
- You're Chief Chris Kyle?
- Yes, Sir?
My name ments, you saved my life.
- Is It True?
- Yes I Do.
We were stuck in the house, until you come
with force, you are bringing us out.
Marines often save us.
-How Are you? You are okay?
- Okay.
I'm just thankful I'm alive.
- That's not ...
- Oh.
Not easy, well you know.
I was lucky to only lose one leg.
- Your friends are also lost?
- Yes, they also.
But I'm talking about people who
still alive, they managed to come back.
- They can not seem to live a normal life.
- Yes I Do.
Why did not you come to our place?
They will be happy.
They want to know about you.
- Yes, it seems like a good idea.
- Hey, friend.
Can I tell?
Your father ... A hero.
True. He saved my life, and he ...
He could go back to his son.
So, thank you
lend it to us.
- Ok.
-I Will not be here
if not for him.
My family is grateful for your services.
Okay, thanks. Okay.
- Take care of you.
- Nice to see you again.
- Okay.
- Sometime stop by the VA.
Ok. Okay. Take kadalmu.
- Thank you. Have a nice day.
- You are welcome.
- Have a nice day.
- Ok.
- See you.
-Come We find your sister.
Hey, sorry, it's time.
That's my daughter, I think you're
should pay attention to him.
Excuse Me.
Hey! Hey, where are you going?
Hey!
Hey! Please note my son.
Hey! Please note my son now!
I make my own memory.
I can not share it with anyone.
Well, it is.
When did it begin?
Even when you're here,
you're not here.
I see you, I feel you.
But you're not here.
I hate that team.
True.
You're my husband.
You're the father of my children, but
instead they are the reason you get back.
They can not wait,
wealso can not.
If you think this war is not
change you, you're wrong.
You can just walk in circles.
That's true.
This Cadillac 31 we are
follow courier Butcher,
we're on the road Marylin, replace.
Hey, you can ring.
- Where from? From here?
- Yes, it's cheaper here.
You buy it from the collector? how Do
you know there is no blood in the ring?
What do you care? You do a lot of killing
here, you legend.
- Not to ring.
-what Is the problem?
- It's hypocritical.
- Slowly.
- Do not get too close.
- Okay, you tell him.
- You tell him where did you get it?
- Of course not, I would say
I bought elsewhere.
Are you still with us?
Half a block in the back.
We are ready.
You know, D ...
My guess is 20 years away at the reunion.
You will marry a man.
As long as she can cook and clean.
- That's them.
-Oh My.
They got people all over the city.
They are the Al-Qaeda-like everything.
Hey, next time if you can
shoot, not to fail, right?
I'm into the alley to save.
- So, you're going to be my companion?
- Who else?
There is only one companion.
Beacon 1're fired!
-Come On, give me a shot of protection.
- Okay.
Let's move.
Safe.
Come with me.
We saw them. Bacon safe.
Prepare security, Chris.
Well ...
Secure roof.
You're not afraid he would
release after she know?
Do Not.
Prepare security.
- Now I'm a little concerned.
- It should.
You mean she could keep track of diamonds?
I think so.
You are okay?
There were shot, Beagles shot.
Northwest corner, on top of the roof.
Hang in there.
I need a medical today.
Okay, we'll pick you up
and bring you down.
Come on.
Come on, put him into the Humvee.
-Angkat Him.
- Ok.
Fast.
Come on, get in. Hang in there, Beagles.
Hang in there, Beagles.
- Chill Out.
- I am sorry.
What for? Why are you apologizing?
- That was my fault, we go up to the roof.
-I Will die?
No, Beagles. You Frogman.
Frogman not die.
He will put the sand in the wound,
and entered the water, you're fine, Beagles.
Hang in there.
Hey, Chris. Make sure he can ring it, okay?
Sure.
Raise suction.
Blood again.
How much longer?
We need 3 units of blood.
The Current.
- Vacuum.
- Put it here.
Press firmly!
Her blood less quickly.
Did you see the shooter?
No, the distance is 1000 meters more.
No one can shoot that far.
- She will survive?
- He is being treated.
- That's not good.
- He was shot in the vitals.
Fuck!
We have to find that person.
The unit is still looking for that person.
I understand if you do not
would continue and gather.
Up to you.
You're the leader.
Eye to eye.
We will be back.
- Nice One.
- Of course.
Come on.
I am coming along.
Hey!
2 kilometers to the south.
On the left.
Hallway.
Safe hallway.
On the left.
Safe.
Everything is safe.
Mark, there seems to be a rush to go.
- Get down!
- Stay away from windows!
Stay away from windows!
Come on, Mark.
Come on, friends. I got you.
Look at me.
I'm here.
Mark died, bro.
There were shot, I need help immediately.
We have to move it.
Victory, some people after him,
and some people stumble.
Did not expect to find them.
But everyone ...
good people stumble.
My question is ...
When did it disappear victory
and into safety?
Or then it becomes ...
Who spent one I ...
Love in the war.
And I saw ...
Preparing!
Lift arms!
Ready! Aim!
Shoot!
Ready!
Aim! Shoot!
Ready! Aim!
Shoot! Lower arms.
Mark wrote the letter two weeks ago.
He told you?
Chris, I want to know what
you think about the letter.
Eating cold night, and ...
Beagles just been shot,
and we were ambushed.
But, is not that strange.
The letter was killed Mark.
He just ... he died,
and he paid the price.
Signature here.
Hey, friend.
- Chris?
- Yes I Do.
-How Are you?
-I'm Here.
- Damn, you're blind as a bat.
- Yes, the bullet jerk.
They said they would
fix my face.
Fortunately, we let
them to fix it.
Seriously.
- Too fast?
- Too fast.
- Hey, I heard you apply.
- Yes I Do.
Congratulations.
You did not tell him
you buy a diamond that
- In that place, is not it?
- Do Not.
- Do Not?
- Do Not. I bought a new one.
- The smaller, and she likes.
- Nice One.
- Yes I Do.
He will not leave me, bro.
I told him to go, he did not want to.
He wants to be with me.
Why do you say that?
Do not say that, he loves you.
- He was in love with you.
- Are you kidding.
Yes, I'm glad I have it.
-I Know you can handle it.
- Maybe you're right.
They said you were the most lethal sniper
in American military history.
- Is It True?
- That's what I heard.
- You heard them say that?
- Yes I Do.
- You're not going back.
- Yes, we will hunt him down.
-Ayolah, You do not need to do that.
- We have to do it.
You're my brother, and they have to pay
for what they've done to you.
How are you going to do?
There are crazy.
He survived.
He'll be fine.
He did apply.
Do you want to die?
If that's what you want.
What?
Tell me.
Why did you do it? I want to understand.
I did it for you, I
do it to protect you.
- Do Not.
- Yes I Do.
I'm here. Your family here,
your children, no father.
-I Had to serve my country.
- That's nonsense!
- Do Not.
- You do not know when to stop.
You've done your job, you're pretty
sacrifice, let someone else have a go.
- Let someone else go?
- Yes I Do.
-I Can not live.
- You have to find a way.
You should do it.
Ok? I want you to be human again.
I need you here.
They need you here.
If you go again ...
I guess we will not be there
here when you return.
Chris.
We have 3 missions
respectively.
That would be worse.
- It will be chaotic.
- Are you coming?
I think so.
His wife scolded him.
Once again my wife
will kill me.
- True.
- They do not understand.
I went to the hospital
previously, it was bad.
He was already dead, Chris.
He was operated on yesterday,
died on the operating table.
It Taya, leave a message.
It's me, just want
hear your voice.
I think it
are you saying ...
I told you kids
love them.
I love you too.
Put.
Come On.
Listen, they believe this will
can help us win the war.
The problem engineers designed so as not to
can be defeated by a sniper.
In Which?
- Approximately 100 miles.
-There Is something else?
-I Do not know.
- Snipers will kill us.
He was either anyone.
We just have to kill him.
We've blocked 6 blocks from the North region
enemy, you will be in front of the shooter jitunya.
- In the middle of the desert storm?
- Bring your sunglasses.
We must kill the sniper.
Understand?
- Be prepared.
- Yes, Sir.
-Safe.
- Going down. Come on.
Come on.
Safe. The Way.
Everything is safe.
The building is safe.
No one came.
Hold fire.
In the middle of a desert storm.
-Watch Out!
- Take cover!
Shit. The shot of the East.
We are in the wrong position.
Not important. Hold fire.
There are people below us.
There is a target at 19 yards.
I can not see that far.
Hold fire. We could get caught.
He's right, there's no point.
Correction, 21 yards.
More than 1 mile.
Impossible to shoot, Chris.
That's him.
I've got
target, change.
Understandably, the troops will
soon arrived within 20 minutes.
- He oversees our friends.
- Can you confirm?
That's him.
- That's him.
- Your decision, Chris.
The team will arrive within 20 minutes.
Hold fire.
You have to kill him.
This is very important.
I will do.
He screwed us.
- Tango fall.
- We need help.
- Mission accomplished.
- He oversees our people.
- Kill him.
- Yes, now we are stuck.
He would be proud.
You did it, Chris.
Echo 7, there are near you.
White Side, damn.
Yes, let's go.
We will come down from the roof.
Saving your ammunition.
Fast attack!
Fast ride!
Shelter!
Echo 7, no weapons
The Green Side.
We fired, White Side!
We have to move!
Do not stop shooting!
They will come.
- Where Is?
-Arah 3 hours.
Only the remaining 1 clip.
Hang in there!
Anyone have any ammunition?
We can not hold any longer.
We have to move!
- They stuck.
- We're heading down the road.
Right, let's go.
- Call them.
- We need help.
Coordinates 70,837,575.
- That's your position.
-I Know, drop it!
Viper 34, ready to attack.
Viper 34, replace.
30 sec.
Hello?
Dear?
Chris? Love me
can not hear.
I am ready.
I'm ready to go home.
What?
What happened?
I'm ready to go home, dear.
Chris?
Here is the danger.
I can not last long.
- Command pilot shoot.
- Viper 34, gunshot.
Misses.
Shit.
We have to move,
come on, quickly!
We have to move!
Echo 7, where are you?
We attack attack!
Down!
Come on! Fast!
The last person!
Let's get together!
Fast!
- Hurry up!
- Up to the truck!
-Come On, we have to go!
- Let me help you, come on!
The Way!
Where is Chris?
He had been behind us.
Open the door.
Stop the truck!
Chris! Come on!
Come on, quickly!
We will not leave.
Received my hand, come on!
Chris! Come on, quickly!
Come ride!
- Yes I Do?
-I Can message you on the plane?
Yes I Do. I came home early.
Really?
You're in Germany?
Do Not. I'm here.
Near here.
You're home?
What are you doing?
I think it only took
a minute.
Chris, children want to meet.
It's been 9 months.
I'm going home.
You are okay?
Yes I Do.
Unfortunately, go home.
We miss you.
Ok.
Chris? Dear?
I'm going out.
Come on, higher.
See your face, dear.
Nice One.
Look different.
The game Tuesday.
He will be in the team.
That would be great.
Crazy, right?
I was so mad when
see other children.
You was either a coach.
He would lose the tooth,
I was a little worried.
He says only you
which may be pulled.
You want to do it?
Chris?
I can phone
draw from your wife.
She stories about barbecue.
That's a pity.
It seems out of control.
You're worried?
No, sir.
So you do not worry about that happening?
No, sir. I do not
anxious about it.
I want to ask you, Chris.
How long have you
serve your country?
- 4 mission, so ...
- Approximately a thousand days?
Yes, Sir.
You will be surprised if I tell AL
note you kill more than 160?
Ever think of doing things
do not want you doing there?
That's not me.
Like what you?
I'm just protecting my friends.
They are trying to kill our soldiers.
I'm willing to die for
protect them.
The problem I feel sad for
people who could not I save.
I want to be there,
but I'm here, stop.
So you want to save
more people?
Yes, Sir.
You can go from here.
There are many soldiers who
must be saved.
- Want to go strolling?
- Of course.
All Right. I want to show you something.
I still smoke, do not get angry,
because it saved my right hand.
How can?
When exploded, second
there hands on the steering wheel,
before exploding, my right hand
reached for a cigarette and put into my mouth.
When I turned it on ...
explosion occurred. destroy
all over my left hand.
I'm lucky to have this.
My right hand injury,
but still there.
- And you still smoke?
- Yes I Do.
Misses. 3 inches to the right.
Come on, you can do better than that.
3 inches to the right?
That is quite complicated.
Vibration shock you.
Unlike shooting paper.
- You bisajangan confuse me?
- Kenai only target.
- Kena.
- Right in the middle.
Shit, as has
courage back.
Why did you do it?
-I Know you've got a family.
-I Heard you collect shoes.
I see we are the same size.
Really, why did you do it?
We look after each other, right?
Try shooting again.
Come on, you can.
- Kena.
- Nice One.
Shit.
Who's the legend now?
You do not want that title.
Believe.
Help me.
- Once again?
- Yes I Do.
- Take into.
- All Right.
Come here.
Life here is not bad, right?
He smiled.
Looks happy.
Just do a habit.
Do not think of the other.
Who is it?
- Honey! That you?
- Yes dear.
-What?
-I Never mind.
- Honey, I'm sorry. What happened?
- No problem.
You know about it, right?
Yes I Do.
That's what we'll do
for the first time.
All Right.
Remember, you must be calm.
Self confidence.
And do not hesitate.
- All Right.
-There Is a problem?
-I Understand.
- Do you feel good?
Yes I Do.
Hands up, lady.
Raise your hands.
Put it.
Slowly.
- Honey, look at you.
- Look at you.
May I say something?
Tell me to judge.
No, I'm very proud of you.
I'm very proud of you,
you're a great dad.
I am very happy
my husband back.
I know it's hard
for you to return.
Of course.
Tell one thing,
you beg for it?
Yes, ma'am. I beg of them.
- You're like a regular cowboy.
- Yes, that is true.
I do not worry
anything, unfortunately.
I got 4 minutes.
- It is only 4 minutes.
- No, only 2 minutes.
But I want to look at you 2 minutes.
You're going to go there?
You're going to come out?
There marines.
I just want
help my mother.
I can do it.
Just briefly, I immediately returned.
- Make sure you ... what?
-Dad.
I can not play now.
Later when I got home,
You've lv 8, I want to win.
- Do Not.
- At his bear.
- At what?
At bear.
Hell No! You should have roared.
Like what?
Well, do not they, okay?
- Yes I Do.
- Great responsibility, you ready?
See you later dear.
-I Love you.
-I Immediately returned.
How are you? Okay?
His journey is about 2 hours. may Be
we talked for a while there, how?
- Yes I Do.
-Let's Go.
Thank you.
You have eaten?
Want to buy something?
Download applications guess the title of the movie "Quiz Mania Movies"
in google play http://tinyurl.com/no73pwk
www.moviesubtitles.org