♪ Fixed & Synced by bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick ♪
"Golden dreams
and great heartache,"
"churn in the depth of the soul
of this river... called life."
"When great mountains lay
in its path,"
"it cuts deep gorges through
the rock... to keep flowing!.."
"This unstoppable, inexhaustible
river called life..."
"It is called
the river of life."
Lord Shiva!
For all the sins
I have committed,
if death is the only redemption,
then take my life!...
But this boy should live...
He should live for his mother
who is waiting for him...
he should live to ascend
the throne Mahishmati...
Mahendra Baahubali should live!
Dear me!
Hey! What are you
waiting for? Hurry!
Hey! Be careful!
- What happened?
- I am not sure, master.
With all the jewelry on her,
she must have been
a queen or something.
She died with her
hand pointing up!
Master!
What happened?
They must have come
here to kill her.
Looks like she got
the better of them.
Master!
Oh my God! A cave!
We never knew this existed!
Looks like it goes all the way
to the top of the mountain!
If the lady was holding the
baby up, pointing to the top,
Maybe she wanted us
to take it back there!
You are out of your mind?
They sent soldiers
to kill an infant!
What dangers do
you think await him...
- if you send him back there!
- But, Sanga..
This is my baby.
I have no children...
and the river Goddess
has given this boy to me.
If anyone of you object,
I will trample upon your necks.
What are you waiting for?
Close the cave.
Shiva!
What are you doing here,
my dear?
What is up there, mother?
There are ghosts
and demons up there!
They prey on
and eat little kids!
But I want to go up there,
mother!
Don't ever say you want
to go up there! Let us go.
How many times have I told you
not to climb up there?
Why do you keep doing it?
You are my darling, right?
You won't do it again, right?
Looks like he will
make it this time.
No way!
Look at the water mountain!
It goes way up into the clouds...
And how many times has he fallen
from that hundred feet?
He always slips and falls
after the first hundred feet.
Yeah, he slipped and fell
at least a hundred times.
Watch!
He is going to come sliding down again.
Shiva!
Your mother is upto something there!
'Shiva, Shiva, Shiva, Shiva,
Shiva, Shiva, Shiva, Shiva!'
That is fifteen!
Pour another 101 times and
your prayers will be answered!
Sage, if I do this,
will my son listen to me?
Will he stop trying to climb
up that mountain?
Of course!
This is a powerful ritual!
Pour this water over Shiva,
with all your heart,
and He will guide your son
onto the right path.
- Alright! 0! Sage.
- Hail Shiva!
Mother, you are not
getting younger, are you?
It won't help you if you
run around so much!
- Out of my way!
- Mother, please listen to me!
Why should I?
Do you ever listen to me?
Father, can you please
tell her to stop?
- Sanga?
- What?
- Where are the flowers?
- Father! Father!
Let go of me!
Alright! Let me do it on your behalf.
Okay?
No way!
Lord Shiva won't accept it.
The one who took the oath
will have to pour the water!
- Sire, carry on with what you are doing.
- Hail Lord Shiva!
- Mother.
- What is it now?
How about I carry you...
and you can pour the water
over Lord Shiva? Fine?
No way!
Lord Shiva won't accept it.
The one who took the oath
will have to pour the water
and she has to walk up
to pour the water!
Sage, are you and your Shiva
planning to kill my mother?
How should I know what
the Lord has in store?
Lord Shiva!
Sanga!
See what your lad is up to now!
What is it this time?
Shiva, stop!
You will go to hell for this
blasphemy! Shiva, stop!
Shiva.
Shiva, wait".
"The celestial river agitatedly
moving through His matted hair"
"which makes His head shine
with those soft waves."
"And His forehead shining
like a brilliant fire"
"and the crescent of moon which
is an ornament to His head"
"makes my mind love Him
each and every moment."
"Who is he and
where he comes from?"
"He brought with him eternal
light spreading everywhere."
"His strong arms can turn
the tide of history."
"River Bhagirathi, Lord Shiva
head towards you."
"Look at this great irony."
"The consort of the sportive
daughter of the mountain"
"whose mind rejoices
at Her side long glances."
"With the stream of merciful
look which removes hardships"
"“Makes my mind
take pleasure in Him"
"who wears the directions
as apparel."
"With the lustrous gem"
"on the serpent's hood
in His matted locks."
"He, who is with His bride
whose face is decorated"
"by the melting of
red saffron vermillion."
"And who wears on His shoulder
the hide of the elephant"
"which was blind
with ferociousness."
"Makes my mind happy
and contented in Him"
"who is the leader of demons."
Mother!
Not just a thousand
showers for your Lord,
He will bathe all the time now.
Are you happy now?
Yes..
Sage, it played out
just like you predicted!
My son hasn't looked up
at that waterfall since.
Do you ever underestimate
Lord Shiva's power?
But now he sits staring
at the wooden mask
that fell on the Shivalingam
from above.
Now what is with that?
Lord Shiva works
in mysterious ways.
Only He would know.
A small doubt.
Since my son was
the one who made sure
the idol is bathed all the time.
Will his wish of climbing
up the mountain come true
or will Sanga's
wish of him always
staying down here come true?
To hell with your doubts.
My son did what he did for me!
My wish will be fulfilled.
Isn't that right?
Lord Shiva does whatever
He thinks. Hail Lord Shiva!
Hail Lord Shiva!
What did he say?
Shiva!
How long are you going
to sit holding that wooden mask?
There is somebody up there.
Maybe there is, but your mother
is calling out to you.
- Let us go home.
- Go ahead. I will come later.
Let us go, boys.
Who are you?
Why did you come to me?
"My heart is lost."
"Like a drop in the waves."
"l am the one whose
eyes shine amidst the stars"
"l am the one who
sings amidst the waterfalls."
"My voice echoes through
streams, listen to me!"
"The persevering one, your
bravery will take you forward."
"You leap higher and higher,
firm and stable and determined."
"The persevering one, your
bravery will take you forward."
"You leap higher and higher,
firm and stable and determined."
"l breathe for you..."
"and only you."
"Come and let us live together."
"Let me tell you something,
my love."
"l chose you as my soul mate."
"Whether I stumble and fall,
with haste I will come."
"l am but a sudden gust of wind.
I stop for no one."
"l will break free of every
mountain in no time."
"He is strong and without an
equal adversary who can fight."
"His anger will cause
new fears in his foes."
"He is strong and without an
equal adversary who can fight."
"His anger will cause
new fears in his foes."
"You come out of blue
with a gift of love."
"Drop a word and I swear"
"l will give up my life for you."
"Scaling peak impossible, his
blood flows like a rivulet."
"His sturdy body, a weapon.
Hail this hero of the world."
"Destructive in the air and sky
can win with his roar of war."
"A ferocious warrior will become
soft-hearted afterwards."
"Killer of fear.
Ocean of wealth."
"Arduous struggle over,
healing calm sets over him."
"Killer of fear.
Ocean of wealth."
"Arduous struggle over,
healing calm sets over him."
"Killer of fear.
Ocean of wealth."
"Arduous struggle over,
healing calm sets over him."
"The persevering one, your
bravery will take you forward."
"You leap higher and higher,
firm and stable and determined."
"The persevering one, your
bravery will take you forward."
"You leap higher and higher,
firm and stable and determined."
"The persevering one.."
"Hey, warrior. Come closer!"
"Hey, handsome. You are mine."
Hey!
Hey! Stop!
Stop!
Over there!
Kasi!
It is a trap. Kill them!
Dear God!
How come you got this?
One of your men,
sneaked into our kingdom.
He tried to rescue Devasena.
We killed him.
It was tied to his wrist.
I took it from him.
I don't know anything else.
Let me go! Let me..
Bury the dead
and leave no traces.
Dilip too has attained
martyrdom, chief!
Don't let the drop of tear
breach your eyelids.
That monster from the palace
has imprisoned our princess
and has her shackled
right in the town square.
Our Queen Devasena being
treated like cattle in a fair.
Our pride and honor is injured
and we suffer in silence.
It is not time to shed tears.
It is time to breathe fire.
Have you forgotten
your solemn oath?
We will remember it
till our last breath.
To meet our goal
we will clash with thunder"
- We won't lose courage.
Come hell or high water"
- We will be brave!
- Or death that splits us in pieces..
- We won't budge!
We shall rescue Devasena!
If we are to achieve our goal..
"Attachments become
our weakness..."
"and there is no place for
joy or celebrations."
"Our body is for our lost
Motherland, Kuntala Kingdom..."
"and soul exists
only to free Devasena."
My leader...
I heard many good things
about a warrior...
called Kattappa of Mahishmati.
I heard he is a good man.
Couldn't we ask him to help?
Karikala Kattappa Nadaar.
He is indeed a good man.
He can help us if he wants to.
But he won't...
Kattappa is a slave
the throne of Mahishmati.
Kattappa.
A sword trader, Sheik Aslam Khan
from Kabul is here to see you.
The ore is extracted from
the depths of Baghdad mines.
Purified in the furnaces
of the Golan mountains.
Crafted by the best
blacksmiths in Persia.
With this in hand...
even a child can slice
through ten banyan trees.
I call this the Sikander.
The Pride of Swords.
A wonderful sword.
But forgive me, Aslam,
this cannot match our speed.
How insulting!
Spoken words and spilled blood
can never be taken back.
Duel with my sword and
prove the worth of your words.
Does that prove
my point, Kattappa?
I have traveled across the world
China, Persia, Mongolia, Greece.
But never seen
a warrior like you.
It will be an honor
to break bread with you.
- Please come, Kattappa.
- Please forgive me, Aslam.
Slaves here do not
dine with royal guests.
Slave?
You are the head of the armory,
how can you be a slave?
Yes, Aslam. A slave
like you have never seen before.
He forges the weapons for war.
During war, he must protect
the king with his own life.
After the war,
he should still lay by his feet.
Tell me, what will it cost
to buy your freedom?
I will pay 10, even 100 times that
to buy your freedom.
You cannot put a price
on this slave, Aslam.
My ancestors pledged that
everyone born in our clan...
will serve the throne
of Mahishmati for life.
For a pledge that
a long forgotten ancestor made
you still..
People who made the pledge
might be dead
but their word
still lives on, Aslam.
For this life, these bonds
will stay tied to this land.
If loyalty has a face,
it is you, Kattappa.
If you ever need anything...
please don't ever forget that
you have a life-long friend.
- Vaishali.
- Hmm.
- Where are you going?
- I will be right back.
We have a golden opportunity
to fulfill the oath
we have taken.
They are celebrating
Bhallaladeva's birthday
on the next new moon.
The entire kingdom will be busy
with the celebrations.
The opportunity to
free Queen Devasena...
- Give me the opportunity, sir!
- Chief, let me go!
I offer it to Avanthika,
this time.
Avanthika!
What is this, Avanthika?
Where did this come from?
You focused on your beauty
more than your oath!
You cannot put your life at stake
since you love yourself so much.
You are not worthy
of this honor. Leave us.
These tears are not
a reflection of my cowardice
nor do they come from pain.
They are a testament
to my boiling blood.
If you can feel their intensity
then let me go.
You have to leave in two days.
So get ready.
Be careful and get
the job done, Avanthika.
If you get caught because
of your own neglect...
Bhallaladeva will torture you
mercilessly before he kills you.
"Our Mahishmati Kingdom
shall remain unconquerable."
"As long as the sun, moon
and stars are shining there."
"Felicity and glory
reigns supreme here."
"A flourished kingdom,
happy subjects"
"and the home of peace."
"May the glory of Mahishmathi
soar sky high."
"Our flag with the emblem
of the rising sun"
"our golden throne
flanked by to stallions."
Your Majesty,
it is just been two days since
we caught that bull
in the forests.
We haven't broken it yet.
It is quite dangerous...
Minister!
It would take 10 such bulls
to intimidate Bhallaladeva.
Please come.
Stamp it out, Bhalla!
Yes!
Kill him, father.
Did you see, grandfather?
His Majesty overpowered
the bull.
Glory to the king!
That was a great feat.
Bravo, Your Majesty!
Bhallaladeva!
Father!
He did it!
- Have you ever seen a mightier warrior!
- No, Prince!
Your loyalty amuses me,
Kattappa.
I know deep in your heart...
you nurture this
desire to kill me.
Yet you put your life
on the line to save mine.
How do you do it?
How do you manage to do this?
Alright! You deserve it!
Ask for a reward.
Ask for anything!
Your Majesty!
You have been holding Devasena
captive for 25 years.
Please release her.
So be it.
Since I have given my word.
Go and kill Devasena
and release her!
There is no greater liberation
than death! Go and release her!
No?
Then let her suffer.
Not just another 25 years,
but till she dies.
Hey old hag! Get up!
Hey! Get up.
Hey Devasena! I hope there is
nothing lacking in your torture!
You chose him over me.
So where is he now?
Tell me the truth, Devasena.
In all these years...
have you ever heard
anyone even utter his name?
On those long and dark night,
amid the desperate silence...
and in the clunk
of your shackles...
did you ever hear his name?
No.
Mahishmati has forgotten him,
Devasena.
They neither talk
about him anymore...
and nor do they remember him.
There are only two people in
this kingdom that remember him.
You and I.
You remember him as you want
to see him before you die.
And I remember him
as I want to kill him again...
with my bare hands.
But both our wishes
will remain unfulfilled.
Lady Devasena!
At least, accept it now.
You just have to say yes...
and I will break these shackles
and set you free.
Do you want to be a prisoner
for all your life?
No, Kattappa.
My son will come
and he will set me free.
How can your dead child
come back for you?
My son is alive.
He will come looking for me!
You are suffering
in the name of a son...
who is no longer alive, My Lady!
Please get a grip on yourself.
I won't get a chance
like this once again.
The guards on the night shift
will be here any moment.
Please agree!
Please accept it.
I am begging you and you
keep doing these silly things!
Do you think I am picking twigs
like a mad woman, Kattappa?
This is a funeral pyre!
This is for a funeral pyre
to burn to ashes...
the body and the
blood of Bhallaladeva.
My son will come...
he will drag that animal...
and place him on this pyre.
My son will make me
light the pyre...
while Bhalla is still alive.
The death cries of
Bhallaladeva will reverberate...
beyond the walls of Mahishmati.
My son will come!
What happened, Avanthika?
Someone right here tattooed
my hand last night.
He will come back
once he sees me.
Avanthika?
What is on your shoulder?
- Avanthi..
- Go ahead, I will see you later!
Avanthi, listen!
You saw the painting on your shoulder?
Did you like it?
Why that sour face?
Can you smile a little?
Oh My God!
Hey! What is with the arrows?
You want to kill
this hunk of a man!
- Who are you?
- That is better.
My name is Shiva.
I come from village Ambuli.
I climbed this huge
mountain just for you..
What a girl!
See, you should listen.
Now you are in a hole.
Avanthika?
- Now tell me who are you?
- I am telling the truth.
- I climbed up the mountain..
- Shut up.
It is possible only for the
likes of the great Lord Shiva!
That is what I am saying.
I am Shiva!
I will tell you.
I will tell you everything.
- But before that I have to ask you one thing.
- What?
Who are you? Who are you?
You got a sword in your hand.
Not to mention body armour, anger
sparks flying from your eyes.
I am not asking about
this mask of yours!
I want to know the one
that is hidden beyond it.
Shall I tell you?
You are a woman and I am a man.
I have come here to love you.
Now that hurts.
This is mine.
I dropped it near the waterfall.
Did you really scale
the mountains to reach me?
Just for me?
I came all the way just to see
the smile behind the mask.
I still don't see it.
"Birds chirp and ask you
to take me along."
"Let there be thirst for love
and let our love grow",
"Listen to what
my heart echoes."
"Let the time stand still
and while love makes us alive."
"The life I lived all
these years has no value."
"But now I want to live for you."
"l made a pact with my heart."
"l will be born a hundred times
for you."
"Birds chirp and ask you
to take me along."
"Let there be thirst for love
and let our love grow",
"l will write our love saga
on the skies."
"Let us be together for
the rest of our lives."
"Write it with your eyes and
make my heart your canvas."
"Being in love is so lovely."
"The life I lived all
these years has no value."
"But now I want to live for you."
"l made a pact with my heart. I will be
born a hundred times for you."
"Birds chirp and ask you
to take me along."
"l am growing thirsty for love,
let there be love."
"Listen to what
my heart echoes."
"Let the time stand still
and while love makes us alive."
This is something
the world has never seen.
A hundred foot
tall golden statue.
Even the Gods don't
get this honor.
Once this is erected,
your son,
our King Bhallaladeva's prestige...
will live on forever
in the entire world.
- Are all the arrangements done?
- Yes, Your Majesty!
There will be celebrations galore.
The applause and the din
will be unprecedented, My Lord!
Avanthika..
Frisk her!
Attack!
Baahubali..
My Lord! Forgive me, My Lord!
Please don't kill me!
My Lord! Forgive me, my Lord.
Forgive me.
Shiva!
Please forgive me, Shiva.
I didn't know what else to do.
I cannot let go of you
nor can I abandon my duty..
You are mine, Avanthika.
Everything that is yours
is mine.
I also share your obligation.
I don't know who Devasena is.
If your goal is to free her
then I will bring her back!
This is my word.
"The pyre is lit and
I feel choked."
"Nevertheless there is a
yearning in my heart."
"Will there be sunrise again,
ask these shackles of mine?."
"0 Kingdom! See who
comes your way."
Mahishmati, you can breathe now.
My son is back.
Baahubali is back!
When the king's statue
is erected...
everyone must applaud!
When the king's statue
is erected
everyone must applaud!
No worries!
It is a hundred foot statue.
Won't it take a sacrifice
of a hundred heads?
Thank you.
Baahubali..
- Baahubali?
- Baahubali.
- Baahubali!
Baahubali! Baahubali!
- Move it!
- Baahubali! Baahubali!
Baahubali! Baahubali!
Hey!
Who was that?
Baahubali! Baahubali!
Baahubali!
- It is been fifteen days since my son left!
- Hold this.
He hasn't returned yet.
I wonder if he is alright.
Our son carried Lord Shiva's idol
all by himself,
What can happen to him?
If he is alright,
why isn't he back?
Maybe he found his family.
He must have realized
we are his foster parents.
- Will he never come? Will he not call me mother again?
- Sanga.
People, hurry up, will you?
Come on.
Earlier you saw the fire
in my eyes and
trusted me to
carry out the mission.
Once again I request you
to have that belief in me.
I know Shiva will rescue
Queen Devasena. Come with me.
Alright!
"Mahasena!"
Who says that Baahubali,
the one who showed us the
righteous path is no more?
I am nothing, but a living dead.
You are dead and yet you are
alive in people's heart.
Baahubali! Baahubali!
The echo still lingers
in these walls.
It felt like it was his statue
that was being erected!
Did the people express their
bottled-up feelings?
Or did they see someone?
No! Impossible!
Let us question the soldiers on duty...
as to who uttered the name
and why they did so!
Then the truth will come out,
grandfather.
What are you doing here?
I.. - The king has ordered us
to come. Let us go.
Who first uttered the
name of Baahubali in the crowd?
Am I talking to these walls?
Speak! Or I will have
your tongues cut!
- I didn't see who, My Lord!
- Stop it!
Bunch of idiots as you are!
Didn't anyone of you see him?
I saw him, My Lord!
I have seen those eyes before!
- Bhadra! I want him alive.
- Let us go!
Hey, who are you?
He is here! Catch him.
Catch him..
That way..
Sound the alarm!
I have come to rescue you.
Kattappa, a marauder
has entered the palace
and he set fire
to the King's chambers!
You head north.
Kattappa, Chop off his legs and hands
but I want him alive.
- As you say, My Prince!
- I want him alive!
Come on!
The alarm!
Attack!
Get up!
You lousy old hag!
All these years of punishment...
for your infidelity
and still no shame!
The moment you see a man,
you take off with him!
Kattappa! He is going to kill me!
He is going lo kill me!
My Prince!
It is my duty to protect you!
To get to you,
he has to go through me first!
Kattappa!
Devasena!
Attack!
They are going for Devasena.
Stop them.
Hail Mahishmati!
Shiva!
Siddha!
"Mahasena!"
Anila!
Baahubali!
You resurrected our lost hope.
You made a great
warrior out of him
and brought him back to us.
Kingdom of Mahishmati will be
eternally grateful to you.
My mother looks at me
with this sadness and
not the usual affection.
I don't know who they are...
and yet they look at me like
I am their God!
And when I see the wounds
that tester on that lady...
I have never met before,
my blood boils and
my soul hurts! Why?
Who am I?
You are the son of our savior (GOD)
Amarendra Baahubali.
You are the balm
for your mother Devasena
who awaited your return
for 25 years.
You are the fruit of our.
Queen Mother Sivagami's
ultimate sacrifice.
The story you need to know
began 50 years ago, my son.
This kingdom of Mahishmati
was established
by your grandfather
Maharaja Vikramadeva.
Though eider,
Bijjaiadeva was not crowned
because of his conniving nature.
But Bijjaiadeva blamed it only
on his physical disabilities
and it caused
great turmoil in him.
The King died.
He was survived by his subjects
and the queen
who was six months pregnant.
Three months passed by and
Mahishmati continued to mourn.
The King's sister-in-law
and Bijialadeva's wife, Sivagami
took up the reins of the kingdom.
Being an astute woman
she focused on
the welfare of the people
and defense of the kingdom.
She could hear
the howls of the jackals
making their move
towards the throne.
It was a dark new moon night.
The queen was in labor.
We could not save the queen,
My Lady!
It is a boy!
Baahubali!
The empty throne reminds
me of a widow's forehead.
So, I will take the throne and
restore it to its former glory!
Hail him!
You all swore a solemn oath
to be loyal to this throne.
A revolt at a time
when the kingdom mourns
goes against every tenet
of being a Kshatriya, Marthanda!
Being a leader
is the first tenet
of being a Kshatriya, Minister.
Lady Sivagami?
All those who support this
royal family step to one side.
Who will support a woman,
Sivagami?
Kattappa!
They have soiled Mahishmati
with their revolt.
Wash it off with their blood!
How can you stand and watch...
while our people
are being hacked to death?
Move! Kill that
slave and Sivagami!
Kill Kattappa!
You bribed and bought my people!
How conniving!
Not conniving, Marthanda.
It is called the statecraft!
Lady, you are a born
statesman and a warrior
and we had the privilege to witness it.
Please ascend the throne
and rule Mahishmati!
No, Minister.
That is not my place.
- Then whose is it? O! Lady!
- What kind of a question is that, minister?
It belongs to my son,
Bhallaladeva.
Tell him, Sivagami!
Both my sons have
a right to the throne.
The one with more valour,
compassion and wisdom
will be crowned
the king of Mahishmati.
This is my word
and my word is the law!
"You found in her
an ocean of affection."
"May you live long,
my dear Baahubali."
"Ambrosia and venom."
"Mind is where
they both get churned."
"The scion of Mahishmathi"
"the heir to the throne
the only one.. Baahubali."
"He roars like a lion in the
battlefield." - Rest for now.
"He is nothing,
but a thunderstorm."
Kattappa! I am very hungry.
Can I have some?
My Prince!
Why are you standing?
Please sit down.
Now give me some.
My Prince!, your mere
presence here is wrong.
And then to sit with us
to break bread?
I am hungry.
Your lectures won't help me.
There is a spread
of delicacies ready
for you in your royal chambers.
I know. What is wrong
with this food?
Just the aroma is
making my mouth water.
You know what is wrong,
My Prince.
You are royalty
and we are slaves.
Alright! As the Prince
of Mahishmathi, I command you.
Feed me, uncle.
"Now has risen the sword
that will condemn."
"Now flies the arrow
that will pierce."
"His enemies remain astonished."
"They don't know where
to run or hide."
Bhallaladeva!
Great Bhalla!
When I become the King,
you will be my commander!
Both the princes have excelled
in their training as
warriors and scholars.
They stand as equals.
How are you going to decide who
will be crowned, Queen Mother?
God has blessed both my
children with equal strengths.
Now he is testing me
with the difficult decision
I have to make!
Make their next challenges
much more difficult.
Before she could decide
on who will ascend the throne
the Queen Mother was
faced with a new crisis.
It's the form of one
of their trusted Saketa.
Saketa killed the guards
and stole our military secrets.
- Call for the Princes!
- As you wish.
The young Princes searched
for the traitor
in neighboring kingdoms.
Finally they found out
that he was hiding
in a den of thieves
called Singapuram.
It is a lawless place
where bandits
thieves and murderers
gathered and mingled.
Strangers who drew
attention to themselves
were in mortal danger.
- I have never seen you before.
- I just got here.
A hidden dagger! What is it for?
Are you a spy?
If our guards were this good..
We wouldn't have
had the opportunity
to see so many
different Kingdoms.
Swords or smarts?
Whichever is sharper.
Do you have a drink?
Big one?
Much bigger?
Do you have money?
I need something large enough
for all my brothers!
Look what is happening there..
Come on!
Not just booze.
There is a lot more here.
"Intoxication tonight,
your magic gets me high."
"Your love surrounds me,
my love."
"Let your lips find mine."
"Come and steal myself from me."
"You are the charming one."
"Your words are as
intoxicating as a bunch"
"of ripe grapes
soaked in honey."
"You know way to my heart,
you are the key to my soul."
"Let me drink this love potion."
"You are mine, just mine."
"Intoxication tonight,
your magic gets me high."
"Your love surrounds me,
my love."
"Take me in your strong arms,
I want to live."
"You got the magic, no one has."
"You are something
I want to lose myself in."
"l want to be your
and make you mine, too."
"Come and enjoy me."
"You are the charming one."
"Yes, I am."
"Don't shoot me
with love daggers."
"Please listen to me, my love."
"Let me drink this love potion."
"You are mine, just mine."
"Intoxication tonight,
your magic gets me high."
"Your love surrounds me,
my love."
Instead of being
tortured by you, I should..
Bhalla!
Kattappa“.
Who did you sell our secrets to?
Tell me!
Kalakeya!
The Kalakeya's don't believe
in tactical attack.
There is no limit
to their morbidity.
If they barge into the kingdom
they will kill every
innocent child
and violate every woman.
They will destroy
and burn everything.
This talk might scare
some small kingdoms.
We have a standing
army of 25,000 soldiers.
Why should we be scared?
- How big is the Kalakeya army?
- One hundred thousand.
When wild bulls barge into the crops
and lands that the Kalakeya's
plunder, are both left barren.
We have to defend our kingdom
and we have to attack our
enemies at the same time.
What military strategy
should we use to attack?
"The trident strategy".
It is one for the textbooks.
No one has ever used it.
You want to go to war
with something untested?
If no one has used it
the Kalakeya's wouldn't
expect it either.
That is why
we should implement it.
- I second the plan.
- I approve it.
It is the only way
into our kingdom.
Kattappa, how big a force
do you need to stop them?
Five thousand, Your Highness!
I will use armour and spears
to erect a wall of iron.
I will turn it into an
impregnable fortress.
I will command the forces
to the north.
I will take responsibility
for the south.
According to our sources,
the Kalakeya chief
will stand back
and send half his army forward.
Our military formation
and our weapons...
will repel that kind
of attack for three hours.
But we have to kill
the chief during that time.
Their army,
without a chief, will scatter!
In the middle of that battle
both princes with their cavalry
will attack the Chief
from two sides.
It will take them
at least three hours
by the time they launch
a counter attack on us.
That will be enough, mother.
Victory will be ours.
Half that time will be enough
to behead him.
Great! This will also
solve the conundrum
of who should be the king.
Yes! The one who kills
the Kalakeya chief
will ascend the
throne of Mahishmathi!
- My Lord has the perfect solution.
- Yes.
Divide the rest of the army
equally between the Princes!
Bhalla, Baahu.
This is the opportunity to
pay tribute to your motherland!
Accept it.
- Hail Mahishmati!
Your uncle has
treated you unfairly.
He has only given you
tools to breach a fort.
Of what use will those
be in an open battlefield?
The arrow-machines
and the swords' chariot,
all went to Bhallaladeva!
You should have objected, Baahu!
Your son shall ascend
the throne of Mahishmathi.
- You brilliantly hoodwinked Baahubali!
- What hoodwink?
If he can't even demand the
right army, the right weapons
what is he going to do
on the battlefield tomorrow?
I made the strong one
even stronger.
It is not cheating,
it is statecraft!
- Hey! Who is it?
- Forgive me, My Lord!
The younger Prince
asked us to pull out
the tents and bring them to him.
(SANSKRIT CHANTS)
Welcome, Bhallaladeva!
- Invincible!
Welcome, Baahubali!
Baahubali! Baahubali!
Bahu, it is
a time-honored ritual.
If you don't
sacrifice the animal
- the soldiers will read it as a bad omen.
- Yes, My Prince!
If you don't offer the sacrifice
the Goddess will be angry.
Why quench the
Goddess's thirst with
the blood of
this innocent animal
when my own blood
can be offered?
- Hail Mahishmati!
Hail Mahishmathi!
Mahishmathi will be
forgiving and benevolent!
This is your last chance.
Drop your weapons and run
and we will spare your lives.
I heard that you promised
both your sons that
the one who kills me
would be made king.
And if both of them
die at my hands?
I will conquer you
and your kingdom
and then I will have
a son with you.
You can make him the king!
I want him alive.
I want him to be alive
even after his arms and legs
are cut off and he
lies in a pool of blood!
When the vultures pluck out
his eyes and feast on his guts.
He should be alive.
Kattappa! ' My Lady!
Blow the conch
to begin the battle.
It is ready.
Arm the weapon.
Fire!
Baahubali's command!
Get ready!
Arm the weapons.
Attack!
- Well done, Baahubali!
- Well done.
Soldiers. Attack.
Attack!
Hold! Hold strong!
Swords group, step forward!
Trident strategy begins!
Stop-
Bhallaladeva!
My Prince?
- My Prince!
- Army!
Hold your lines!
Hold your lines! Hold them!
Our defenses are in tatters.
We are seeing an enemy
flag on Mahishmati soil...
for the first time!
This is the death of us. Death!
Death! Death!
Death!
Soldiers!
What is death?
To think that the
enemy is stronger
than our resolve, is death!
Cowardice on the battlefield
is death!
The cruel man insulted our
mother and he is still alive.
Instead of presenting his
decapitated head at her feet
we are turning our backs
to him and that is death!
I will ride on to annihilate
that death!
No rogue can ever harm
my mother or my motherland.
I am about to rip them apart
and proclaim my war cry!
Who is with me?
Me!
- Who will die with me?
- Me!
- Who will vanquish that death and live on?
Me!
Hail Mahishmathi!
Semupathy!
I want him alive when
the vultures pluck out his eyes
and feast on his guts.
His limbs are to be cut off
and his blood should flow!
My Son!
Bhallaladeva! Bhallaladeva!
My brave son killed
Kalakeya and won the battle!
To the future king,
Bhallaladeva!
Hail Bhallaladeva!
Bhallaladeva's valour
will be told in Mahishmati
for generations to come!
Tales of his victory will be
etched on shrines and temples.
Today, I proclaim
my son Bhallaladeva
as the commander of the
armed forces of Mahishmathi!
I proclaim Baahubali
as the King of Mahishmathi!
Sivagami,
What sort of a decision is this?
My son, our son,
killed the Kalakeya chief!
You saw it with your own eyes!
He has to be the King! Only he!
The merits of a King
are evaluated not
by the number
of enemies he has killed
but by the number of
his own people he has saved.
During the battle.
Bhallaladeva's focus was
only in vanquishing the enemy.
Baahubali,
while killing the enemy
also managed
to save his subjects.
That is the difference
between a soldier and a king.
If you kill a hundred men you will
be called a great warrior.
But if you save one life,
you will be called God!
So, saving a couple
of common men
is now the
qualification to rule?
Baahubali will be
crowned the King of.
Mahishmati on an auspicious day.
That is my word
and my word is law!
Baahubali! Baahubali!
- Baahubali!
Amarendra Baahubali!
Glory to him!
My Shiva is the son
of such a great king!
We are so glad
to hear about him.
I wish we can
see the great man once!
He is no more.
The savior is no more!
(THAT GOD IS NO MORE!)
You said no enemy
could come near him.
You said the weapons
were afraid to touch him?
How did such
a great warrior die?
More grievous than
the wound of a sword or a spear
is a stab in the back, Mahendra.
Who? Who was it?
That traitor...
was me!
"Golden dreams
and great heartache."
"churn in the depth of the soul
of this river called life."
"When great mountains
lay in its path."
"It cuts deep gorges through
the rock to keep flowing!"
"This unstoppable, inexhaustible
river called life."
"It is called
the river of life."
♪ Hope it helped -> bozxphd ♪