Gentlemen, cock your pistols.
Gentlemen!
Barry's father had been bred, like
many sons of genteel families...
...to the profession of the law.
There is no doubt he would've made
an eminent figure in his profession...
...had he not been killed in a duel...
...which arose over the
purchase of some horses.
Barry's mother, after
her husband's death...
...lived in such a
way as to defy slander.
Many a man who had been
charmed by the spinster...
...renewed his offers to the widow.
But she refused all
proposals of marriage...
...declaring that she
lived only for her son...
...and the memory of her departed saint.
First love! What a
change it makes in a lad.
What a magnificent secret
it is he carries with him!
The tender passion gushes
out of a man's heart.
He loves as a bird sings...
...or a rose blows from nature.
Killarney.
Now, what shall it be?
Turn around and face the wall.
The object of Barry's attention...
...and the cause of
his early troubles...
...was his cousin, Nora Brady by name.
I have hidden my neck ribbon
somewhere on my person.
If you find it, you can have it.
You are free to look anywhere for it.
I will think little of
you if you do not find it.
I cannot find it.
You haven't looked properly.
I'll give you a hint.
I feel the ribbon.
Why are you trembling?
At...
At the pleasure of finding the ribbon.
Liar.
Company, forward march!
Company, eyes left!
About this time the United
Kingdom was greatly excited...
...by the threat...
...of a French invasion.
The noblemen and people of condition...
...loyally raised regiments...
...to resist the invaders.
Their scarlet coats and swaggering
airs filled Barry with envy.
Company, eyes right!
Brady Town sent a company to join...
...the Kilwangan Regiment, of
which John Quin was the Captain.
The whole country was
alive with war's alarms...
...the kingdoms ringing
with military music.
At ready!
Present!
Fire!
Redmond, what is the matter?
Were you obliged to dance
five times with Captain Quin?
I don't care a fig for Captain Quin.
He dances prettily, and is
a pleasant rattle of a man.
He looks well in his regimentals.
He asked me to dance.
How could I refuse him?
But you refused me.
I can dance with you any day.
To dance with my cousin looks as
though I could find no other partner.
Besides, Captain Quin is a man.
You're only a boy and penniless.
If I meet him again, you will
find out who is the best man.
I'll fight him Captain as he is.
Oh, don't be so silly!
I mean it.
But Captain Quin is known
as a valiant soldier.
It is mighty well of
you to fight yokels...
...but to fight an Englishman
is a different matter.
You best have him take you home.
Redmond!
Barry resolved never to see Nora again.
But such resolutions, steadfastly
held for a whole week...
...are abandoned in a
few moments of despair.
No, Nora, no, except for
you and four others...
...I vow before all the gods my heart...
...has never felt the soft flame.
Ah, you men, you men, John...
...your passion's not equal to ours.
We are like some plant I've read of.
We bear but one flower and then we die.
You, you, you mean you...
...never felt an
inclination for another?
Never, my John. How can
you ask such a question?
Oh, darling Norelia!
Nora was chaperoned by her
brothers Mick and Ulick...
...whose interests would be affected...
...by the favorable outcome
of her affair with Quin.
Redmond, how nice to see you.
Redmond!
How could you do this to me?
Redmond, what's the matter?
What are you saying?
I think this might be the moment
to return something to you.
I...
Thank you, Redmond.
I must have forgotten it.
Yes, you did.
Captain Quin, may I introduce
my cousin, Redmond Barry.
Miss Brady, it would appear...
...you both have something
private to discuss.
It would be best for me to withdraw.
Captain Quin, I have nothing
private to discuss with my cousin.
Miss Brady, it appears you
have a great deal to discuss.
Captain Quin, he don't signify
any more than my parrot or lapdog.
Indeed!
Are you in the habit of giving...
...intimate articles of your
clothing to your parrot or lapdog?
Mayn't I give a bit of
ribbon to my own cousin?
You're welcome, miss.
As many yards as you like.
When ladies make presents to gentlemen,
it's time for other gentlemen to retire.
I wish you both a good day.
Jack Quin!
What's the matter?
I'll tell you, sir.
I've had enough of Miss
Brady and your Irish ways.
Ain't used to them.
What is it?
We'll accustom you to Irish
ways, or we'll adopt English ones.
It is not the English way
for ladies to have two lovers.
And so, I'll thank you to
pay me the sum you owe me.
And I resign all claims
to this young lady.
If she fancies schoolboys,
let her take 'em, sir.
You're joking!
Ha. I never was more earnest.
John, wait.
Meddling brat!
Your hand is in everybody's pie!
What business had you to quarrel
with a gentleman of substance?
Redmond, me boy, take a seat.
Mrs. Brady and ladies, if you please.
This sort of toast is drunk
too seldom in my family...
...and you'll please to
receive it with all honors.
Here's to Captain and Mrs.
John Quin and long life to them.
Go on.
Kiss her, Jack, for faith
you've got a treasure.
Come on, Jack.
There's the man!
A long and happy life together.
Thank you.
Redmond!
Here's my toast to
you, Captain John Quin.
Redmond, how dare you
behave like that in my house!
Mrs. Brady, take the children out.
My dear fellow, are you all right?
In heaven's name, what
does all the row mean?
The fact is, sir...
...the young monkey's in love with Nora.
He found her and the
Captain in the garden today.
Now he's for murdering Jack Quin.
Mr. Brady, I've been insulted
grossly in this house.
I'm not satisfied with
these ways of going on.
I'm an Englishman!
And a man of property!
And this impudent young swine...
...should be horsewhipped!
Mr. Quin can have satisfaction
any time he pleases...
...by calling on Redmond
Barry, Esquire of Barryville.
I'll see the boy home.
A pretty day's work, Master Redmond.
Knowing your uncle is
distressed for money...
...trying to break off a match which will
bring £1,500 a year into the family...
Quin has promised to pay off the
£4,000 which is bothering your uncle.
He takes a girl without a penny...
...a girl that's flinging herself at
the head of every man in these parts.
And missing them all!
And you, who ought to be attached
to your uncle as to your father...
I am.
And this is the return
you make for his kindness?
Didn't he harbor you
when your father died?
Hasn't he given you and your
mother a fine house, rent free?
Mark this, and come what will of it...
...I will fight the man who
pretends the hand of Nora Brady.
I'll follow him if it's into
the church and fight him there.
I'll have his blood, or he'll have mine.
Faith, and I believe ye!
I never saw a lad more game in me life.
Give me a kiss, me boy.
You're after me own soul.
As long as I live, you shall
never want a friend or a second.
Will you take my message to
him? And arrange a meeting?
Well, if it must be, it must.
Look here, Redmond, me boy,
this is a silly business.
The girl will marry Quin, mark my words.
And as sure as she
does, you'll forget her.
You're but a boy and Quin is
willing to consider you as such.
Right, Quin?
Oh, mm-hm.
Now, Dublin's a fine place.
If you've a mind to ride there
and see the town for a month...
...here's ten guineas at your service.
Will that satisfy you, Captain Quin?
Yes, if Mr. Barry will
apologize and go to Dublin...
...I will consider the whole
affair honorably settled.
Say you're sorry, Redmond.
You can easily say that.
I'm not sorry.
And I'll not apologize.
And I'd as soon go to Dublin as to hell.
Then there's nothing else for it.
God bless you.
This isn't my pistol.
It's all right, it's one of mine.
Yours will serve, if it's
needed, for the next round.
Good luck, Redmond.
Gentlemen...
...cock your pistols.
...aim your pistols.
One.
Two.
Three.
Is he dead?
Quite dead.
This has been a sad
day's work for our family.
Ye've robbed us of 1,500 a year.
Now you'd better ride off
before the Police are up.
They'd wind of this
before we left Kilwangan.
Come on, Redmond, I'll go home with you.
How different Barry's
fate might have been...
...had he not fallen
in love with Nora...
...and had he not flung the
wine in Captain Quin's face.
But he was destined to be a wanderer.
And the battle with Quin set him
on his travels at an early age...
...as you shall soon see.
The boy must go into hiding
for a short time, anyway.
Dublin's the best place for him.
He can stay there 'til
matters have blown over.
But the child has never
been away from home before.
Wouldn't he be as safe here?
I wish that were true, Aunt Belle.
But the Bailiffs may
be on their way already.
Now, Dublin is five
days' ride away from here.
There's not a soul
who'll know him there.
I don't want to harp
on unpleasant matters...
...but you do know what can
happen to him if he's taken.
I'll be all right.
I'll be all right in Dublin, Mother.
No lad with liberty
for the first time...
...and 20 guineas in his pocket...
...is very sad.
Barry rode towards Dublin
thinking not so much of...
...the kind mother left alone,
and the home behind him...
...but of tomorrow and all
the wonders it would bring.
Excuse me, miss.
Would it be possible to
have a drink of water?
Yes, sir.
Good day to you, young sir.
Good day.
Will you join us in a drink?
No, thank you.
Would you like something to eat?
That's very kind of you,
but I have to be on my way.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Good morning again, young sir.
Don't even think about it.
Get down off that horse.
Raise your hands above
your head, please.
Come forward.
Stop.
How do you do? I'm Captain Feeney.
Captain Feeney!
Captain Feeney, at your service.
The Captain Feeney?
None other.
May I introduce you to my son... Seamus?
How do you do?
To whom have I the honor of speaking?
My name's Redmond Barry.
How do you do, Mr. Barry?
Now we must get onto the more regrettable
stage of our brief acquaintance.
Turn around and keep your hands
high above your head, please.
There must be 20 guineas
in gold here, Father.
You seem to be a very well
set up young gentleman, sir.
Captain Feeney, that's all the
money my mother had in the world.
Mightn't I keep it?
I'm just one step
ahead of the Law myself.
I killed an English Officer in a duel, and
I'm going to Dublin until things cool down.
Mr. Barry...
...in my profession we
hear many such stories.
Yours is the most intriguing
and touching I've heard in weeks.
Nevertheless, I cannot
grant your request.
But, I'll tell you what I will do.
I'll allow you to keep those fine boots,
which normally I would have for myself.
The next town is only five miles away.
And I suggest you now start walking.
Mightn't I keep my horse?
I would like to oblige you...
...but, people like us must be able
to travel faster than our clients.
Good day, young sir.
You can put down your
hands now, Mr. Barry.
Gale's Regiment of Foot, commanded
by Lieutenant General Charles Gale...
...which has distinguished itself
during the recent troubles...
...wants several men to supply
the places of those veterans...
...who have deserved to be
pensioned at one shilling a day.
All clever young fellows
who are free and able...
...and are ambitious of becoming
gentlemen by bearing arms...
...are hereby invited to
meet the Recruiting Officer...
...who promises that they shall
meet with every encouragement...
...that merit and good
behavior can entitle them to.
Those meeting the qualifications
will immediately receive...
...His Majesty's Royal Bounty
of one and a half guineas...
...with complete clothing,
arms and accoutrements.
King George and Old England forever.
Left, left, left, right, left.
For a young man in difficulty...
...who had killed a man in a duel and
was anxious to find refuge from the Law...
...the chance to earn distinction
in the European wars...
...seemed a stroke of good fortune.
And King George needed men too
much to heed from whence they came.
Hey, lad! Lad!
Lad!
Can I have a new beaker?
This one is full of grease.
Covered in grease! Give the gentleman
a towel and a basin of turtle soup.
If you want to vex him,
ask him about his wife...
...the washerwoman, who beats him.
Mr. Toole, is it a towel
of your wife's washing?
They say she wipes your
face often with one.
Ask him why he wouldn't see her
yesterday when she came here.
Mr. Toole, why did you hide when
Mrs. Toole came to visit you?
Afraid of getting your ears boxed?
Gentlemen, you may fight it
out with fists if you choose.
We'll form a square for that purpose.
Gentlemen, step this way, please.
Shake hands.
Take your stance.
No biting, kicking or scratching.
The last man to remain
standing is the winner.
Gentlemen, commence fighting, now!
Barry's training continued at the camp.
Within a month he was transformed
into a proper young soldier.
The Regiment's strength
was steadily increased...
...by the arrival of other troops...
...in preparation for joining
their armies fighting in Germany.
One occasion...
...brought the welcome appearance
of his second in the fatal duel...
...Captain Grogan.
It would have helped if we'd
known what had become of you.
Didn't you think of
writing to your mother?
Of course.
But the shame I felt
of losing her money...
...my father's sword and pistols...
I couldn't tell her.
She wouldn't care about those things.
You are her only concern.
Tonight you must write
her a proper letter.
Tell her that you're safe and well.
I will.
Is Miss Brady well?
There are only six Miss Bradys now.
Has something happened to Nora?
She took on so about your going away...
...that she had to console
herself with a husband.
She is now Mrs. John Quin.
Mrs. John Quin?
Was there another John Quin?
No.
The same, me boy. He
recovered from his wound.
The shot you hit him with could
not hurt him. It was made of tow.
Tow?
The Bradys wouldn't let you kill
1,500 a year out of the family.
The plan of the duel was arranged
in order to get you out of the way.
The cowardly Quin couldn't
be brought to marry...
...from fear of you.
But hit him you certainly did, me lad.
With a fine thick plugget of tow.
He was so frightened, it
took him an hour to come to.
Are you in want of cash?
You may draw on me. For I got a
couple of hundred from your uncle.
While that lasts, you shall never want.
It would require a great
historian to explain the causes...
...of the Seven Years' War in Europe...
...to which Barry's
regiment was now on its way.
Let it suffice to say, that
England and Prussia were allies...
...and at war against...
...France, Sweden, Russia and Austria.
Barry's first taste of battle...
...was only a skirmish against
a rearguard of Frenchmen...
...who occupied an
orchard beside a road...
...down which the English
main force wished to pass.
Though this encounter is not
recorded in any history book...
...it was memorable enough
for those who took part.
I've only a hundred
guineas left to give you...
...for I lost the rest at cards.
Kiss me, me boy, for
we'll never meet again.
It is well to dream of
glorious war in a snug armchair.
It is a different thing
to see it firsthand.
After his friend's death, Barry's
thoughts turned from military glory...
...to those of escaping the Service...
...to which he was tied for six years.
Gentlemen talk of the Age of Chivalry...
...but remember the ploughmen,
poachers and pickpockets they lead.
It is with these sad instruments
great warriors and kings...
...have been doing their
murderous work in the world.
Barry could not have fallen
into worse circumstances...
...than those in which he found himself.
But fate did not intend he should
remain long an English soldier.
An accident occurred...
...which took him out of the
Service in a rather singular manner.
Freddie, I hope you won't
be angry with me, but...
...I've got something to tell you
which you won't be happy about.
Oh? What is it?
First, promise me
you'll keep your temper.
Jonathan, don't be an ass!
You're making a big mystery of it.
What is going on?
I have to go away again.
For about two weeks.
Oh, God, you're not serious?
I am. There's nothing I can do about it.
Where to this time?
To Bremen, carrying important
dispatches to Prince Henry.
But you promised me last
time it would be never again.
I know. And I've kept my
part of the bargain, but...
...Pontersby insists I'm the only one
who can be entrusted with the trip.
Here was the opportunity
to escape from the Army...
...for which he had been searching.
It was only a few miles to the area
occupied by their Prussian allies...
...where this Officer's
uniform and papers...
...should allow him to
travel without suspicion...
...and stay ahead of the
news of his desertion.
Then, we'll have little time together.
Are you cross with me?
Damn you, I can't stay
cross with you for long.
Oh, Jonathan...
...at times like this I realize
how much I care for you...
...and how empty life
would be without you.
Frederick!
Barry was glad to see the
uniforms of the Prussian Infantry.
They showed him that he was out
of English-occupied territory.
His intention was to make for Holland...
...almost the only neutral country
of Europe, in those times...
...and thence to get
a passage home, somehow.
As he rode away...
...Barry felt he was
now in his proper sphere.
And determined never again to
fall from the rank of a gentleman.
Excuse me, miss.
Yes.
Good day.
Do you speak English?
I'm speaking little.
I have not eaten all day, no food.
Is there an inn nearby
where I might have a meal?
No... I don't think so.
There is nothing to
eat before Grünberg.
Do you live near here?
Yes.
Would you... feed me?
I'd be happy to pay you.
I think so.
Is it a boy or girl?
A boy.
What's his name?
Peter.
How old is he?
He's one year old.
Where is Peter's father?
Where he is?
Yes.
In the war.
How long has he been gone?
Sorry... I didn't understand.
What?
Oh! A long time.
Since springtime.
It must be hard for you to be alone.
It is.
It must be dangerous for you in the war.
I'm an Officer and must do my duty.
You are sometimes...
...lonely?
Sometimes.
What did you say your name is?
Lieutenant Fakenham.
No, I mean...
...what is the name before Fakenham?
My first name?
Jonathan.
Jonathan?
Would you like...
...to stay with me?
For a few days, or sometimes?
That would be very nice.
Goodbye, my beautiful Lischen.
Goodbye, Redmond.
I love you.
Look after yourself.
God be with you.
A lady who sets her heart
on a lad in uniform...
...must prepare to change
lovers pretty quickly...
...or her life will be a sad one.
This heart of Lischen's was
like many a neighboring town...
...and had been stormed and occupied
many times before Barry came to invest it.
During five years of war...
...the illustrious Frederick had so
exhausted the males of his kingdom...
...that he had to employ recruiters...
...who would commit any
crime, including kidnapping...
...to keep supplied those brilliant
regiments of his with cannon fodder.
Good evening, sir.
I'm Captain Potzdorf. To whom
have I the honor of speaking?
Good evening. I'm Lieutenant
Fakenham, Gale's Regiment of Foot.
Pleased to meet you.
Can we be of assistance to you?
Thank you, but I am carrying urgent
dispatches and must continue on my way.
And your destination?
Bremen.
Then you're obviously lost, Lieutenant.
Bremen is in the opposite direction.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Wouldn't you know it!
My departure was so hasty that my
orderly forgot to prepare proper maps.
I understand.
Please, do not be
offended, Lieutenant...
...but are you carrying
your identity papers?
Yes, of course.
May I see them?
Of course.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Thank you, Lieutenant, I hope
I haven't inconvenienced you.
Not at all.
Now that we are riding
in the same direction...
...may I offer you a meal
and a bed for the night...
...and a proper map for the journey?
That's kind of you, Captain.
I'd be honored to accept.
Barry was treated with great civility...
...and was asked
questions about England.
He answered as best he
could, inventing many stories.
He described the King and Ministers...
...boasted that the British
Ambassador in Berlin was his uncle...
...and even offered Potzdorf
a letter of introduction.
His host seemed satisfied
with these stories.
But, he led Barry on with a
skillful combination of questions...
...and flattery.
I know so little of your
country of England...
...except that you are the
bravest nation in the world...
...and that we are fortunate
to have such allies.
Lieutenant Fakenham...
...let us drink to the friendship
of our two great nations.
To our two great nations.
Ah.
Aren't you lucky, going
to Bremen tomorrow?
I know one of the loveliest
women in Europe there.
Would you take a letter to her?
Certainly.
By the way, to whom are you
carrying your dispatches?
General Williamson.
General Williamson?
Yes.
General Percival Williamson?
Yes, the same.
Sergeant.
This man is under arrest.
Under arrest? Captain Potzdorf, sir...
...I'm a British Officer.
You're a liar and an imposter.
You're a deserter.
I suspected you this morning. Your
lies and folly have confirmed this.
You pretend to carry dispatches to
a General, dead these ten months.
You say the British
Ambassador in Berlin...
...is your uncle, with the
ridiculous name of O'Grady.
Now, will you join and take
the bounty, or be given up?
I volunteer.
The Prussian Service was
worse than the English.
The life of a Private
Soldier was frightful.
Punishment was incessant. Every
Officer had the right to inflict it.
The gauntlet was a common
penalty for minor offenses.
More serious ones were
punishable by mutilation or death.
At the close of the Seven
Years' War the army...
...renowned for its disciplined valor,
was officered by native Prussians.
But it was mostly composed...
...of men from the lowest
levels of humanity...
...hired or stolen from
every nation in Europe.
Thus, Barry fell into
the worst company...
...and was soon far advanced in the
science of every kind of misconduct.
Help.
Get me out of here.
The Colonel's speech declared
the King's satisfaction...
...with the conduct of the
Regiment at the Battle of Audorf...
...and with Corporal Barry's bravery
in rescuing Captain Potzdorf...
...which was to be rewarded with
the sum of two frederick d'or.
Corporal Barry, eight paces forward...
...march!
Corporal Barry.
You're a gallant soldier,
and evidently of good stock...
...but you're idle and unprincipled.
You're a bad influence on the men.
And for all your bravery, I'm
sure you'll come to no good.
I hope the Colonel is mistaken.
I have fallen into bad company, but
I've only done as other soldiers do.
I've never had a friend
or protector before...
...to show that I was
worthy of better things.
The Colonel may say I'm ruined,
and send me to the Devil.
But, I would go to the
Devil to serve the Regiment.
Corporal Barry, fall in.
The war ended and Barry's regiment
was garrisoned in the Capital.
He had, for some time, ingratiated
himself with Captain Potzdorf...
...whose confidence in him
was about to bring its reward.
Good morning, Redmond.
Good morning, Captain.
I should like you to meet my
uncle, the Minister of Police.
Good morning, Herr Minister.
Redmond...
...I've spoken to the Minister regarding
your services and your fortune is made.
We shall get you out of the Army...
...appoint you to the Police
Bureau, and, in time...
...we'll allow you to
move in a better sphere.
Thank you, Captain.
Your loyalty to me and service
to the Regiment has pleased me.
Now there is another occasion
on which you can assist us.
If you succeed...
...depend on it...
...your reward will be secure.
I'll do my best, sir.
There is a gentleman in Berlin in
the service of the Empress of Austria.
He calls himself the
Chevalier de Balibari.
He appears to be a professional gambler.
He's a libertine:
Fond of women, of good food...
...polished, obliging.
He speaks French and
German indifferently.
But we have reason to fancy
that Monsieur de Balibari...
...is a native of your
country of Ireland.
And that he has come here as a spy.
Your knowledge of English...
...makes you an ideal choice
to go into his service...
...and find out whether
or not he is a spy.
Does this assignment interest you?
Minister, I'm interested in anything
that can be of service to you...
...and Captain Potzdorf.
You will not know a word of English.
If the Chevalier remarks on your
accent, say you are Hungarian.
You served in the war.
You left the Army for medical reasons...
...then served Monsieur de
Quellenberg for two years.
He's now with the Army in Silesia,
but you'll have a certificate from him.
Good morning, Your Honor.
So you are the young man
recommended by Seebach.
Yes, Your Honor, here
are my credentials.
Your name is Lazlo Zilagy?
Yes, Your Honor.
Monsieur de Quellenberg
recommends you highly.
Monsieur is a very good man.
It was imprudent of him...
...but when Barry saw the
Chevalier's splendor...
...and noble manner...
...he felt unable to
keep disguise with him.
Those who have never been exiled...
...know not what it is to hear
a friendly voice in captivity...
...and would not understand the cause...
...of the burst of feeling
now about to take place.
You seem the right one to me.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Are you ill?
Sir...
...I have a confession to make to you.
I'm an Irishman.
My name is Redmond Barry.
I was abducted into the Prussian Army.
Now I've been put into your service...
...by my Captain Potzdorf and his
uncle, the Minister of Police...
...to serve as a watch
upon your... actions...
...and to give information to them.
The Chevalier was much affected...
...at thus finding
one of his countrymen.
For he too was an exile.
And a friendly voice, a look...
...brought the old
country back to his memory.
He is very religious and
attends church regularly.
After Mass he comes home for breakfast.
He then takes an airing in his carriage.
Barry presented his reports
regularly to the Minister.
The details were arranged
beforehand with the Chevalier.
He was instructed to tell the truth...
...as much as his story
would possibly bear.
The information he gave was
very minute and accurate...
...though not very important.
...But who does not acknowledge him.
Wine or punch, Your Honor?
Wine.
It was agreed that Barry should
keep his character of valet.
That, before strangers, he
should not know a word of English.
And that he should keep a lookout
on the trumps when serving the wine.
Having excellent eyesight...
...and a natural aptitude...
...he was able to give his
dear patron much assistance...
...against his opponents
at the green table.
If, for instance, he wiped
the table with a napkin...
...the enemy was strong in Diamonds.
If he adjusted a chair
it meant Ace King.
If he said, "Punch or wine, My Lord?"...
...Hearts were meant, and so forth.
The Prince of Tübingen...
...who had intimate connections
with the Great Frederick...
...was passionately fond of
play as were the gentlemen...
...of almost all the Courts of Europe.
You owe 15,500 frederick d'or.
Chevalier...
...though I cannot say how...
...I believe you have cheated me.
I deny Your Grace's accusation...
...and beg you to say
how you have been cheated.
I don't know.
But I believe I have been.
Your Grace owes me
15,500 frederick d'or...
...which I have honorably won.
Chevalier...
...if you will have your money
now you must fight for it.
If you will be patient...
...maybe I will pay you
something another time.
Your Grace, if I am to be
so tame as to take this...
...then I must give up an
honorable and lucrative occupation.
I have said all there is to be said.
I am at your disposal for
whatever purposes you wish.
Good night.
Was the Prince cheated?
In as far as I am able to
tell, Herr Minister, no.
I believe he won the money fairly.
What are the Chevalier's intentions?
I'm not sure.
The Prince told him that if he wanted
his money he'd have to fight for it.
A meeting with the Prince is impossible.
The Prince has left him no other choice.
Now.
Will you be able to return here
tomorrow without arousing suspicion?
I know they won't allow
a meeting with the Prince.
But if I say that, do you know any
reason why he'll pay me what he owes?
You must tell them I intend
to demand satisfaction.
Don't look so downcast, my boy.
They cannot harm me, the
Austrian Embassy will see to that.
The worst they can do is send me
out of this dreary country of theirs.
If they should, don't worry...
...you shall not be left behind.
Have no fear of that.
The King has determined to send
the Chevalier out of the country.
Has he already demanded satisfaction?
Not yet, but I believe he intends to...
...possibly today.
Then this must be done tomorrow.
All the arrangements are made.
You said he takes a drive
after breakfast every day.
Yes, sir.
Is there any reason he should
do any different tomorrow?
No, sir.
Good.
When the Chevalier comes out to
his carriage in the morning...
...two Officers will meet him
and escort him to the frontier.
His baggage will be sent after him.
Excellent.
At ten o'clock the next morning...
...the Chevalier de Balibari...
...went out for his
regular morning drive.
Where's my servant, Lazlo?
I will let down the steps, Your Honor.
What is this about?
Please get inside.
Am I under arrest?
We're driving to the frontier.
Frontier? But I'm on my way to
the Austrian Ambassador's house.
My orders are to escort
you to the frontier...
...and see you safely across the border.
But, I'm not going to the frontier.
I have very important business at
the Austrian Ambassador's house.
My orders are to take Your Honor to
the frontier by any means necessary.
If you come willingly...
...I'm to give you this purse on
behalf of the Prince of Tübingen...
...containing 2,000 frederick d'or.
All Europe shall hear of this.
And so, without papers or passport...
...and under the eyes of
two Prussian Officers...
...Barry was escorted across the
frontier into Saxony and freedom.
The Chevalier himself had uneventfully
crossed the frontier the night before.
By these wonderful circumstances,
Barry was once more free...
...and began his professional
work as a gamester...
...resolving, thenceforward and
forever, to live the life of a gentleman.
Ahh!
The four wins.
Soon he and the Chevalier were
received in all the Courts of Europe...
...and were speedily...
...in the very best society
where play was patronized...
...and professors of that
science always welcome.
The seven.
Why not the seven?
All... all, yes.
Shh.
CHEVALIER No more bets.
Aww.
Number seven...
...loses.
Place your bets.
Chevalier, will you give me credit
for 5,000 louis d'or, please?
CHEVALIER Of course, Lord Ludd.
Five thousand.
Now, everything on the four.
Yes, I know, everything on the four.
No more bets.
The four loses.
It is not important.
Now, I'm weary.
I would like dinner. Shall we?
Excuse me, Lord Ludd.
If you don't mind.
Not at all.
They always played on credit with
any person of honor or noble lineage.
They never pressed for their winnings...
...or declined to
receive promissory notes.
But woe to the man who did not
pay when the note became due.
Barry was sure to wait
upon him with his bill.
There were few bad debts.
Saluez.
It was Barry's skill with the
sword, and readiness to use it...
...that maintained the reputation
of the firm, so to speak.
En garde!
I will pay you today, sir.
Thus, it will be seen, their life...
...for all its splendor, was not
without danger and difficulty...
...requiring talent and
determination for success.
And required them to live a
wandering and disconnected life.
And, though they were swimming
upon the high tide of fortune...
...and prospering with the cards, they
had little to show for their labor...
...but some fine clothes
and a few trinkets.
Five years in the Army, and
considerable experience of the world...
...had dispelled any romantic
notions regarding love...
...with which Barry commenced life.
And he had it in mind, as many
gentlemen had done before him...
...to marry a woman of
fortune and condition.
And, as such things so often happen...
...these thoughts coincided with
his setting sight upon a lady...
...who will play a considerable
part in the drama of his life.
The Countess of Lyndon...
...Viscountess Bullingdon of England...
...Baroness Castle Lyndon of Ireland.
A woman of vast wealth and great beauty.
She was the wife of
Sir Charles Lyndon...
...Knight of the Bath...
...Minister to George lll at
several of the Courts of Europe.
A cripple, wheeled about in a chair...
...worn out by gout and
a myriad of diseases.
Her Ladyship's Chaplain, Mr. Runt...
...acted as tutor to her son,
the little Viscount Bullingdon...
...a melancholy little boy,
much attached to his mother.
I'm going outside for a breath of air.
Yes, My Lady.
To make a long story short...
...six hours after they met...
Her Ladyship was in love.
And once Barry got into her company...
...he found innumerable occasions
to improve his intimacy...
...and was scarcely out
of Her Ladyship's sight.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Good evening.
Sir Charles.
Good evening, Mr. Barry.
Have you done with my Lady?
Pardon?
Come, sir. I'm a man who would rather
be known as a cuckold than a fool.
I think, Sir Charles, that
you've had too much to drink.
Ha, ha, what?
As it happens, your Chaplain, Mr.
Runt, introduced me to your Lady...
...to advise me on a religious
matter, of which she is an expert.
He wants... to step into my shoes.
He wants to step into my shoes.
Is it not a pleasure for me,
as I am drawing near the goal...
...to find my home such a happy one...
...my wife so fond of me, that she is even
now thinking of appointing a successor?
Isn't it a comfort to see her
like a prudent housewife...
...getting everything
ready for my departure?
I hope you're not thinking
of leaving us, Sir Charles?
Not so soon as you may fancy, perhaps.
I've been given over many
times these four years.
And there was always
a candidate or two...
...waiting to apply for the situation.
I'm sorry for you, Mr. Barry.
It grieves me to keep you
or any gentleman waiting.
Had you not better
arrange with my doctor...
...or have the cook flavor
my omelet with arsenic, eh?
What are the odds, gentlemen, that
I live to see Mr. Barry hang yet?
Sir, let those laugh that win.
Gentlemen.
I'll get a surgeon.
Have some brandy, Sir Charles.
From a report in The
Saint James' Chronicle:
"Died at Spa in Belgium...
"... Sir Charles Reginald Lyndon...
"... Knight of the Bath,
Member of Parliament...
"... and for many years...
"... His Majesty's Representative
at various European Courts.
"He has left behind him a name which
is endeared to all his friends. "
"Dearly beloved...
"... we are gathered together
here in the sight of God...
"... and in the face
of this congregation...
"... to join together this man
and this woman in holy matrimony. "
A year later, on the
fifteenth of June...
...in the year 1773...
...Redmond Barry had the honor to lead
to the altar the Countess of Lyndon.
The ceremony was performed by the
Reverend Runt, Her Ladyship's Chaplain.
"And therefore is not in
any way to be enterprised...
"... nor taken in hand unadvisedly...
"... lightly or wantonly...
"... to satisfy men's
carnal lusts and appetites...
"... like brute beasts
that have no understanding.
"But reverently...
"... discreetly...
"... advisedly...
"... soberly...
"... and in the fear of God.
"Duly considering the causes
for which matrimony was ordained.
"First...
"... it was ordained for the procreation
of children to be brought up...
"... in the fear and nurture of the
Lord, and to the praise of His holy name.
"Secondly...
"... it was ordained for a remedy
against sin, and to avoid fornication...
"... that such persons... "
Barry had now arrived at
the pitch of prosperity...
...and by his own energy had raised
himself to a higher sphere of society...
...having procured His Majesty's
gracious permission to add the name...
...of his lovely Lady to his own.
Thenceforth, Redmond
Barry assumed the style...
...and title of Barry Lyndon.
Redmond, would you mind
not smoking for a while?
Redmond?
Lady Lyndon was soon destined to
occupy a place in Barry's life...
...not very much more important than
the elegant carpets and pictures...
...which would form the pleasant
background of his existence.
My Lord Bullingdon, you
seem particularly glum today.
You should be happy that
your mother has remarried.
Not in this way.
And not in such haste.
And certainly not to this man.
I think you judge your
mother too harshly.
Do you not like your new father?
Not very much.
He seems to me little more
than a common opportunist.
I don't think he loves my mother at all.
And it hurts me to see her
make such a fool of herself.
At the end of a year Her Ladyship
presented Barry with a son.
Bryan Patrick Lyndon, they called him.
None of those ancient
heroes E'er saw a cannon ball
Or knew the force of powder
To slay their foes withal
But our brave boys do know
it And banish all their fears
With a tow, row, row, row,
row To the British Grenadiers
Her Ladyship and Barry lived,
after a while, pretty separate.
She preferred quiet, or to say the
truth, he preferred it for her...
...being a great friend to a modest
and tranquil behavior in woman.
Besides, she was a mother,
and would have great comfort...
...in the dressing, educating and
dandling of their little Bryan.
For whose sake it was
fit, Barry believed...
...that she should give up the
pleasures and frivolities of the world...
...leaving that part of the duty
of every family of distinction...
...to be performed by him.
Lady Lyndon tended to a
melancholy and maudlin temper...
...and, left alone by her husband,
was rarely happy or in good humor.
Now she must add jealousy
to her other complaints...
...and find rivals even among her maids.
Samuel, what would the time be?
Twenty-five minutes
past eleven, My Lady.
Shall we make this
the last game, ladies?
Yes.
Good morning, ladies.
Good morning, sir.
Would you mind excusing us? I'd
like a word alone with Lady Lyndon.
I'm sorry.
This coat is made of
the finest velvet...
...all cunningly worked
with silver thread.
No finer velvet has ever been woven,
and you will see none better anywhere.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
Good morning, dearest.
We're taking the children for a ride
to the village. We'll be back for tea.
Have a nice time. I'll see you then.
Goodbye, little Bryan.
Lord Bullingdon.
Take good care of your mother.
Come now, give your
father a proper kiss.
Lord Bullingdon...
...is that the way to
behave to your father?
Lord Bullingdon, have
you lost your tongue?
My father was Sir Charles Lyndon. I
have not forgotten him, if others have.
Lord Bullingdon, you
have insulted your father!
Madam, you have insulted my father.
Dearest, would you excuse us? We
have something to discuss in private.
Gentlemen.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Lord Bullingdon...
...I have always been willing to
live with you on friendly terms.
But be clear about one thing:
As men serve me, I serve them.
I never laid a cane on the
back of a Lord before...
...but, if you force me to, I shall
speedily become used to the practice.
Do you have anything
to say for yourself?
No.
You may go.
Barry believed, and not without
some reason, that it had been...
...a declaration of war against
him by Bullingdon from the start...
...and that the evil
consequences that ensued...
...were entirely of
Bullingdon's creating.
I shall make you into a
real magician now, Bryan.
I shall show you the
knot that never was.
As Bullingdon grew up to be a man...
...his hatred for Barry
assumed an intensity...
...equaled only by his
increased devotion to his mother.
Very good, Bryan. A little bow.
Put it on the table for me. Thank you.
For Bryan's eighth birthday the local
nobility, gentry and their children...
...came to pay their respects.
The inside and outside are quite empty.
Wave your hand over the
top. Is there anything there?
Yes? Oh!
Wonderful! Wonderful,
colorful silk handkerchiefs!
Take a bow, Bryan, you
did that beautifully.
Very good.
Let's see if you have
something behind your ear.
Yes, you have. Ha, ha.
A little ball. Let's make it vanish.
It's gone.
Here it is, behind my elbow.
Wave your hand over my
green silk handkerchief...
...and see if we can produce a
magic flower. I wonder if we can?
Here it comes.
The colors of the rainbow.
You know all the colors of the
rainbow produce but one color, Bryan.
Nothing in my magic cabinet.
They produce the color... white.
And there is my own...
...beautiful white rabbit.
Bryan, you did that
very well. A little bow.
We crept up on their fort, and
I jumped over the wall first.
My fellows jumped after me.
You should have seen the Frenchmen's
faces when 23 rampaging he-devils...
...sword and pistol, cut and thrust,
came tumbling into their fort.
In three minutes we left as
many Artillerymen's heads...
...as there were cannonballs.
Later we were visited by
our noble Prince Henry.
"Who is the man who has done
this?" I stepped forward.
"How many heads was it
that you cut off?" He says.
"Nineteen," says I,
"besides wounding several. "
Well, I'll be blessed, if
he didn't burst into tears.
"Noble, noble fellow," he said.
"Here is nineteen golden guineas,
one for each head that you cut off. "
What do you think of that?
Were you allowed to keep the heads?
No, they always become
the property of the King.
Will you tell me another story?
I'll tell you one tomorrow.
Will you play cards with me tomorrow?
Of course I will. Now go to sleep.
Will you keep the candles lit?
Bryan, big boys don't
sleep with the candles lit.
I'm afraid of the dark.
My darling, there's
nothing to be afraid of.
But, I like it with the candles lit.
All right, you can sleep
with the candles lit.
Thank you, Papa.
Good night.
Ah, Redmond!
It's a blessing to see my darling boy has
attained a position I knew was his due.
And for which I pinched
myself to educate him.
Little Bryan is a darling boy...
...and you live in great splendor.
Your lady wife knows
she has a treasure...
...she couldn't have had,
had she married a Duke.
But, if she should tire
of my wild Redmond...
...and his old-fashioned Irish ways...
...or if she should die...
...what future would there be
for my son, and my grandson?
You have not a penny of your own...
...and cannot transact any
business without her signature.
Upon her death the entire estate
would go to young Bullingdon...
...who bears you little affection.
You could be penniless tomorrow...
...and darling Bryan at the
mercy of his stepbrother.
Shall I tell you something?
There is only one way for you and
your son to have real security.
You must obtain a title.
I shall not rest until
I see you Lord Lyndon.
You have important friends.
They can tell you how
these things are done.
For money, well-timed
and properly applied...
...can accomplish anything.
And Barry was acquainted with someone...
...who knew how these things were done.
This was the distinguished Barrister
and former Government Minister...
...Lord Hallam...
...whose acquaintance he had made, like
so many others, at the gaming table.
Do you happen to know the
Thirteenth Earl of Wendover?
I don't believe I do.
Well, this nobleman is one of the
Gentlemen of His Majesty's Closet...
...with whom our revered Monarch is
on terms of considerable intimacy.
In my opinion, you would
be wise to fix upon him...
...your chief reliance for the
advancement of your claim to the peerage.
When I take up a person, Mr.
Lyndon, he, or she, is safe.
There is no question about them anymore.
My friends are the best people. I
don't mean they're the most virtuous...
...or, indeed, the least
virtuous, or the cleverest...
...or the stupidest,
richest or best born.
But, the best.
In a word, people about
whom there is no question.
I cannot promise how long it will take.
You can appreciate it
is not an easy matter.
But, any gentleman with an
estate, and 30,000 a year...
...should have a peerage.
And there standing behind
me was a total stranger.
I looked at him, and he said to me:
"Excuse me, sir, could you tell
me, is Lord Wendover alive or dead?"
I was so astonished, I
couldn't think of what to say.
Then I became angry, and
said to him, "He's dead. "
The striving after this peerage was
one of Barry's most unlucky dealings.
He made great sacrifices
to bring it about.
He lavished money here,
and diamonds there.
He bought lands at ten
times their value...
...purchased pictures and articles
of virtue at ruinous prices.
He gave entertainments to
those friends to his claim...
...who, being about the Royal
person, were likely to advance it.
And, I can tell you, bribes were
administered. And in high places, too.
So near the person of His Majesty
that you would be astonished to know...
...what great noblemen
condescended to receive his loans.
This is by Ludovico Cordi...
...a disciple of Alessandro Allori.
It's dated 1605...
...and shows, "The
Adoration of The Magi. "
It's beautiful.
Yes.
I love the use of the
color blue by the artist.
Yes, that is very beautiful.
What is the price of this one?
Well, this is one of my best pictures.
But, if you really like it, I'm
sure we can come to some arrangement.
Count Andrachier.
Mr. Henry Drummond.
Mr. Drummond.
Sir Gilbert Elliot, Your Majesty.
Sir Gilbert.
Lord Wendover, Your Majesty.
I'm glad to see you here
today, Lord Wendover.
What news of Lady Wendover?
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Lady Wendover is much better.
Good! Present my compliments to
her. Say we miss her company here.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
And what of those
excellent boys of yours?
They're well. Charles has gone to sea
under Captain Geary on the Ramillies.
John has gone to Oxford to
learn how to preach and pray.
Good, good!
Your Majesty, may I
present Mr. Barry Lyndon.
Mr. Lyndon. We were very
fond of Sir Charles Lyndon.
And how is Lady Lyndon?
She's very well, Your Majesty.
Mr. Lyndon raised a company of troops
to fight in America against the rebels.
Good, Mr. Lyndon. Raise another
company and go with them, too.
Sir Christopher Neville.
Sir Christopher.
Peregrine Cavendish.
Mr. Peregrine.
Barry was born clever enough
at gaining a fortune...
...but incapable of keeping one.
For the qualities and energies which
lead a man to achieve the first...
...are often the very cause
of his ruin in the latter case.
Now he was burdened with the
harassing cares and responsibilities...
...which are the dismal adjuncts
of great rank and property.
And his life now...
...seemed to consist mostly of drafts of
letters to lawyers and money-brokers...
...and endless correspondence...
...with decorators and cooks.
Gentlemen, I'm going to leave you for
a few minutes. Carry on with your work.
Yes, sir.
Bully.
Mm-hm?
What does...
..."strenuous" mean?
Bryan, I'm trying to work.
But what does it mean?
It means "an effort
requiring strength. "
What does "quadrangle" mean?
A quadrangle is a four-sided
figure like a square or a rectangle.
Now, please be quiet, and
let me get on with my work.
Bryan, please be quiet!
Have you seen my pencil?
No, I haven't.
Bryan, please stop making so much noise.
That's my pencil.
No, it isn't.
It is. It's my pencil!
I've had this all morning.
It's my pencil!
Listen, will you be quiet!
I'll teach you a lesson.
What the devil's going on in here?
I told you never to lay
a hand on this child.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
- Aah!
- Six.
Will that be all, Mr. Redmond Barry?
Yes, that will be all.
Well then, look you now.
From this moment, I will submit to
no further chastisement from you.
I will kill you if you
lay hands on me ever again.
Is that clear to you, sir?
Get out of here!
Don't you think he fits my
shoes very well, Your Ladyship?
Dear child...
...what a pity it is I'm
not dead, for your sake.
The Lyndons would then have
a worthy representative...
...and enjoy all the benefits...
...of the illustrious blood
of the Barrys of Barryville.
Would they not...
...Mr. Redmond Barry?
From the way I love this child...
...you ought to know how I
would've loved his elder brother...
...had he proved worthy
of any mother's affection.
Madam!
I have borne as long as
mortal could endure...
...the ill treatment of the insolent Irish
upstart whom you've taken to your bed.
It is not only his lowly birth and the
brutality of his manners which disgust me.
But the shameful nature of his
conduct toward Your Ladyship...
...his brutal and
ungentlemanlike behavior...
...his open infidelity...
...his shameless robberies and
swindling of my property, and yours.
And as I cannot personally chastise
this low-bred ruffian, and cannot bear...
...to witness his treatment of you...
...and loathe his company
as if it were the plague...
...I have decided to leave
my home and never return.
At least, during his detested life...
...or during my own.
Good day, My Lord.
Good day, Barker.
Will anyone be joining Your Lordship?
No, I shall be alone.
Thank you.
The roast beef's very good, My Lord.
Uh-huh.
Hello, Neville. How are you?
Ah, Barry. Hello.
I see you're alone.
Why don't you join me?
Oh, thank you, Barry,
you're very kind, but...
...I'm expecting someone to join me.
What a shame! Lady Lyndon and I
have missed your company lately.
Please give my respects
to Lady Lyndon...
...and say I've been very busy of late
and not been able to go about much.
I shall.
The eighth of next month we're
having some guests over for cards...
...we'd love to have you
and Lady Wendover join us.
I'll check my diary, but I think
I'm engaged on that evening.
I hope you're not engaged.
We'd love to see you again.
I'll write and say if I'm free or not.
I look forward to hearing from
you. It's nice to see you again.
If he had murdered Lord Bullingdon...
...Barry could scarcely have been received
with more coldness and resentment...
...that now followed
him in town and country.
His friends fell away from him.
A legend arose of his
cruelty to his stepson.
Now all the bills came
down on him together.
All the bills he had been contracting
for the years of his marriage...
...and which the creditors
sent in with a hasty unanimity.
Their amount was frightful.
Barry was now bound up in an
inextricable toil of bills and debts...
...of mortgages and insurances, and
all the evils attendant upon them.
Lady Lyndon's income was
hampered almost irretrievably...
...to satisfy these claims.
Do you think that's good?
Excellent.
Who's this?
It's a peacock on the wall.
What's it say?
I saw this bird yesterday.
Who's that?
Mama in her coach.
Is she going to London?
I don't know.
Parry.
Very good.
Barry had his faults...
...but no man could say of him that
he was not a good and tender father.
He loved his son with
a blind partiality.
He denied him nothing.
It is impossible to convey what
high hopes he had for the boy...
...and how he indulged in a
thousand fond anticipations...
...as to his future success
and figure in the world.
But fate had determined that he should
leave none of his race behind him...
...that he should finish his life...
...poor, lonely...
...and childless.
Papa.
Yes, Bryan?
Will you buy me a horse?
Buy you a horse?
Yes, Papa.
But you already have little Julia.
She's only a pony, I want a real horse.
Then I can ride with you on the hunt.
You think you're big
enough for the hunt?
Oh, yes!
Jonathan Plunkett is only a year older
than I am and he rides with his papa.
I'll have to think about it.
Please, say yes. There's nothing I want
in the whole world more than a horse.
I'll think about it.
Oh, thank you, Papa. Thank you!
How much are you asking for him?
One hundred guineas.
He's a nice little horse, but
I don't think he's worth that.
Seventy-five seems more
like the right price.
I'll accept eighty guineas,
and not a shilling less.
Five guineas should never keep two
gentlemen from their drink. Eighty then.
Done, sir.
Take the horse to Doolan's farm. Tell
him he needs a bit of breaking in.
Say it's for Master Bryan's birthday,
and I want it to be a surprise.
And remember that yourself.
Yes, sir.
Papa.
What is it, lad?
Did you buy the horse?
What horse is that?
The horse you were going
to buy me for my birthday.
I know nothing about any horse.
But one of the stable boys told
Nelly you'd already bought it...
...and it was at Doolan's farm where
Mick the groom was breaking it in.
Is that true?
When is your birthday?
Next Tuesday.
Well, you'll have to wait
till then to find out.
Then, it's true! Oh, thank you, Papa.
Bryan?
Yes, Mama?
Promise me you won't ride that
horse except with your father.
Yes, Mama, I promise.
And I promise you a good flogging...
...if you even go to Doolan's farm
to see him before your birthday.
Yes, Papa.
You understand?
You promise me?
Yes, Papa, I promise.
All right, eat your food.
Come in.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, Reverend.
I'm sorry to trouble you, Mr. Lyndon...
...but I believe Master
Bryan has disobeyed you...
...and stolen away to Doolan's farm.
On going to his room this
morning, I found his bed empty.
One of the cooks saw him
cross the yard at daybreak.
Didn't you see him go?
He must have passed through
my room while I was asleep.
Oh, my God! What has happened here?
I noticed the lad riding
across the field, sir...
...and having trouble with the
horse, which was playing up.
Suddenly the animal plunged and
reared, and the poor lad was thrown.
Oh, Bryan, why did you disobey me?
I'm sorry, Papa.
You won't whip me, will you?
No, my darling.
I won't whip you.
Take my horse and ride like
the Devil for Doctor Broughton.
Tell him whatever he's doing he
must come at once. Understand?
Yes, sir.
The doctors were called.
But what does a doctor avail in a
contest with the grim, invincible enemy?
Such as came could only confirm the
hopelessness of the poor child's case.
He remained with his
parents for two days.
And a sad comfort it was
to know he was in no pain.
Papa.
Am I going to die?
No, my darling, you're not going
to die. You're going to get better.
But I can't feel anything,
except in my hands.
Does that mean I'm already
dead in part of my body?
No, my darling, that's where
you were hurt by the horse.
But you're going to be all right.
Papa, if I die, will I go to heaven?
Of course you will, my darling...
...but you're not going to die.
Mama, give me your hand.
Papa, give me your hand.
Will you both promise me something?
Yes.
Promise me never to quarrel so.
But to love each other.
So that we may meet again, in heaven...
...where Bullingdon said
quarrelsome people will never go.
We promise.
Will you tell me the
story about the fort?
Of course.
We crept up on the fort.
I jumped over the wall first,
and my fellows jumped after me.
And you should have seen the look...
...on the Frenchmen's faces when
23 he-devils, sword and pistol...
...cut and thrust, came
tumbling into the fort.
In three minutes...
...we left...
"'I am the resurrection and
the life,' saith the Lord.
"'He that believeth in
me, though he were dead...
"'... yet shall he live.
"'And whosoever liveth
and believeth in me...
"'... shall never die. '
"I know that my Redeemer liveth...
"... and that He shall stand at
the latter day upon the earth.
"And though after my skin
worms destroy this body...
"... yet in my flesh shall I see God.
"Whom I shall see for myself
and mine eyes shall behold...
"... and not another.
"We brought nothing into this world...
"... and it is certain
we can carry nothing out.
"The Lord gave, and the
Lord hath taken away.
"Blessed is the name of the Lord. "
Barry's grief was inconsolable.
Such solace as he could
find, came only from drink.
His mother was the only person who would
remain faithful to him in his misfortune.
And many a night, when he was
unconscious of her attention...
...saw him carried off to bed.
"O blessed Lord...
"... the Father of mercies
and God of all comforts.
"We beseech Thee, look down in
pity and compassion upon this...
"... Thy afflicted servant.
"Thou writest bitter
things against her...
"... and makest her to possess
her former iniquities. "
Her Ladyship, always
vaporish and nervous...
...plunged into devotion...
...with so much fervor that you would
have imagined her distracted at times.
In the doleful conditions which
now prevailed at Castle Hackton...
...management of the household,
and of the Lyndon estate...
...fell to Mrs. Barry,
whose spirit of order...
...attended to all the details
of a great establishment.
Come in.
You wish to see me, madam?
Yes, Reverend. Please sit down.
I have some matters I would
like to discuss later, Graham...
...but just now would
you go to Her Ladyship...
...and have her sign these papers.
Yes, madam.
Reverend Runt...
...I need not tell you that the
recent tragedy to this family...
...has made the services of a
tutor no longer required here.
And as we are in considerable
difficulty about money...
...I'm afraid I must ask you,
with the greatest reluctance...
...to resign your post.
Madam, I'm sensible
of your predicament...
...and you need have no concern about
my wages, I can willingly forego them...
...but it is out of the question for me
to leave Her Ladyship in her present state.
I'm sorry to say this to you...
...but I believe you are largely
responsible for her present state of mind.
The sooner you leave,
the better she will be.
Madam, with the greatest respect...
...I take my instructions
only from Her Ladyship.
Reverend Runt...
...Her Ladyship is in no fit mind
to give instructions to anyone.
My son has charged me with managing
the affairs at Castle Hackton...
...until he recovers from his grief and
resumes his interest in worldly matters.
And while I'm in charge...
...you'll take your
instructions from me.
My only concern is for Lady Lyndon.
Madam...
...your only concern is for
Her Ladyship's signature.
You and your son have almost succeeded
in destroying a fine family fortune.
And what little remains for you...
...depends on keeping Her
Ladyship prisoner in her own home.
Reverend Runt...
...this matter bears
no further discussion.
You will pack your bags
and leave by tomorrow.
God, help. Help!
In the midst of these
great perplexities...
...Her Ladyship made an attempt
to kill herself by taking poison.
Though she only made
herself dangerously ill...
...due to the very small
amount which she swallowed...
...this, nevertheless, caused an
intervention from a certain quarter...
...which was long overdue.
Oh, my God!
If my mother had died...
...it would've been as
much my responsibility...
...as if I had poured the
strychnine for her myself.
For to the everlasting
disgrace of my family name...
...I have, by my cowardice
and my weakness...
...allowed the Barrys
to establish a brutal...
...and ignorant tyranny
over our lives...
...which has left my
mother a broken woman...
...and to squander and
ruin a fine family fortune.
My friends profess sympathy,
but behind my back...
...I know I am despised.
And quite justifiably so.
However...
...I know now what I must do.
And what I shall do.
Whatever be the cost.
Good morning, My Lord.
Good morning.
Is Mr. Barry Lyndon here?
Yes, My Lord, he's inside.
Thank you.
Mr. Redmond Barry.
The last occasion on which we met...
...you wantonly caused
me injury and dishonor.
In such a manner, and to such an extent
no gentleman can willingly suffer...
...without demanding satisfaction...
...however much time intervenes.
I have now come to
claim that satisfaction.
Mr. Lyndon...
...these are a matched pair of
pistols, and as you have seen...
...your second has loaded one,
and I have loaded the other.
As they belong to Lord Bullingdon,
you may have whichever one you wish.
Lord Bullingdon.
Now, gentlemen, to determine
who will have first fire...
...I will toss a coin in the air.
As the offended party, it is Lord
Bullingdon's choice to call the toss.
Is that agreeable to both of you?
Yes.
If Lord Bullingdon calls correctly
he will have the first fire.
If incorrectly, Mr. Lyndon
will have the first fire.
Is that clearly understood?
What is your call, Lord Bullingdon?
Heads.
It is heads.
Lord Bullingdon will
have the first fire.
Lord Bullingdon...
...will you take your ground?
One... two... three...
...four... five... six...
...seven... eight... nine... ten.
Mr. Lyndon, will you take your ground?
Mr. Lyndon, are you ready to
receive Lord Bullingdon's fire?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
...cock your pistol...
...and prepare to fire.
Sir Richard, this pistol must be faulty.
I must have another one.
I'm sorry, Lord Bullingdon, but
you must first stand your ground...
...and allow Mr.
Lyndon his turn to fire.
That is correct, Lord Bullingdon.
Your pistol has fired, and
that counts as your shot.
Mr. Lyndon, are the rules
of firing clear to you?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
...are you ready to
receive Mr. Lyndon's fire?
Yes.
Very well, then.
Mr. Lyndon...
...cock your pistol...
...and prepare to fire.
Are you ready, Lord Bullingdon?
Is your pistol cocked, Mr. Lyndon?
Yes.
Then prepare to fire.
One...
...two...
Lord Bullingdon, in view of Mr.
Lyndon having fired into the ground...
...do you now consider that
you have received satisfaction?
I have not received satisfaction.
Mr. Lyndon, are you ready?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
...cock your pistol
and get ready to fire.
One...
...two...
Barry was carried to an inn
nearby and a surgeon was called.
I'm nearly finished.
I'm sorry to have to
tell you this, Mr. Lyndon.
I'm afraid you'll
have to lose the leg...
...most likely below the knee.
Lose the leg?
What for?
The simple answer is to save your life.
The ball has shattered the bone
below the knee and severed the artery.
Unless I amputate, there's no way
that I can repair the artery...
...and stop the hemorrhage.
Graham.
Yes, My Lord?
When we arrive at Castle Hackton,
inform Mrs. Barry of what has happened.
Don't go into any unnecessary detail.
Just tell her where he is and that
he has been wounded in the leg.
She will want to go to him.
See that she is out of the house and on
her way to London as soon as possible.
And in no event...
...is she to be allowed
to see my mother...
...or create any disturbance
at the house before she leaves.
Yes, My Lord.
Ah, Mrs. Barry, how do you do?
How nice to see you, Graham. Come in.
Thank you.
You, uh... You received my note?
Yes, we were expecting you.
Oh, good, I didn't want
to call unannounced.
Mr. Lyndon, how are you feeling?
I'm feeling much better,
thank you, Graham.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you, Mrs. Barry.
Would you like some tea?
Oh, no! No, thank you,
Mrs. Barry. Not just now.
How's the world treating you, Graham?
Oh, not too bad.
And, uh...
Are you comfortable here?
Most comfortable.
Good, good!
Um...
Well, uh...
...shall, uh, ahem...
Shall we get down to the matter at hand?
By all means.
Yes.
Well...
Mr. Lyndon...
...Lord Bullingdon has instructed me...
...to offer you an annuity...
...of 500 guineas a year for life.
Specifically on the condition of your...
...leaving England...
...and to be stopped...
...the instant of your return.
Lord Bullingdon has also
asked me to point out to you...
...that should you
decide to remain here...
...your stay would
infallibly plunge you...
...into jail.
As in view of the present
circumstances there will soon be...
...innumerable writs taken
out against you for...
...debts long-outstanding...
...and your credit is so blown that...
...you could not hope...
...to raise a shilling.
Utterly baffled and beaten...
...what was the lonely and
broken-hearted man to do?
He took the annuity and returned
to Ireland with his mother...
...to complete his recovery.
Sometime later he traveled abroad.
His life there, we have not the
means of following accurately.
He appears to have resumed his
former profession of a gambler...
...without his former success.
He never saw Lady Lyndon again.