(HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAL)
(FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(GASPS)
(CHITTERING)
(CHATTERS)
Hmm?
(CHIRPING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(CLUCKING)
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLES)
(EXCLAIMS)
Boo!
(INDISTINCT ANIMAL SOUNDS)
(BELL CHIMES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Mmm!
(LAUGHS)
Whoo!
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(MACHINE SQUEAKING SOUND)
(HORN BLARING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GASPING)
(BUZZING)
(SCATTERED NOISES)
(FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BELL CHIMING)
- (GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CHIMING CONTINUES)
(PANTING)
(BOTH CONVERSING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GRUNTS)
(PLAYING FLUTE)
(HEARTBEAT)
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(METAL SCRAPING)
(WHEELS SQUEAKING)
(GASPING)
(SIGHS)
(FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHIRPING)
Boo!
(LAUGHS)
(CREAKING)
(GRUNTING)
Huh?
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(FLUTE MUSIC PLAYS)
- MOM: Menino!
- (GASPS)
(MOM CONTINUES SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
- (CLANKS)
- (GASPS)
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MOM SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SIGHS)
(STUTTERING)
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCRAPING)
(BOTH CONVERSING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GASPING)
(STRAINING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(THUNDER CRACKLING)
(COUGHS)
(BLOWING)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFS)
(GARGLES)
(STOMACH GRUMBLES)
(BURPS)
(GROANS)
(COUGHS)
(DOG BARKING)
(CHUCKLING)
(SNIFFS)
(GRUNTING)
(WHEELS SQUEAKING)
(BARKS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(JOVIAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BARKS)
(BOTH GASP)
(LAUGHING)
(DOG BARKING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHS)
(SIGHS)
- (DOG BARKING)
- (GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(PLAYING FLUTE)
(PEOPLE SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
(BIRD SCREECHING)
(PANTS)
(SCREECHES LOUDLY)
(RUMBLING)
(TRUCK HONKS)
(HONKING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BARKS)
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
(BARKING)
(SIGHS)
(GROANS)
(WHIMPERS)
(SHOUTS ANGRILY)
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHS)
(GROWLS)
(CART WHEELS SQUEAKING)
(CHIRPING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(BARKS)
(MUFFLED BARKING)
(MENINO SCREAMS)
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GATE CREAKING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(CLATTERS)
(PANTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
(WHIRRS)
(GRUNTS)
(SQUEAKING)
(ENGINE TURNS OFF)
(GASPS)
Huh?
(ALARM BLARING)
(GROANS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCATTERED HONKING)
(BEEPING)
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(BUS ENGINE REVVING)
(APPROACHING FOOTSTEPS)
(WOMEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(MEN CHANTING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
(SIGHS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(TV PLAYING)
Mmm! Mmm!
(SNORING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(CLOSES DOOR)
(STUTTERING)
(VEHICLES HONKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(GASPS)
(OBJECTS CLATTER)
(PLAYING FLUTE)
(BLOWING)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHS)
(PLAYING MUSIC USING INSTRUMENTS)
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT OVER PA)
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SLURPING)
(CHICKEN CLUCKING)
(CHIRPING)
(SHIP HORN BLARES)
(MACHINES WHIRRING)
(HORN BLARES)
(RUMBLING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(HORN BLARES)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(COMMENTATOR SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE OVER TV)
(CROWD CHEERING OVER TV)
(FIRECRACKERS BURSTING)
(PEOPLE SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SCREECHING)
(BUZZING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(CHAIR SQUEAKING)
(SQUEAKING)
(GASPS)
(BUZZING)
(MACHINERY SQUEAKING)
(LAUGHING)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
- (GATE CREAKS OPEN)
- (GASPS)
Hmm?
(TRUCK SIREN WAILING)
(MAN SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(LOUD WHIRRING)
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(GASPS)
Oh!
(ALARM BLARING)
(BUS ENGINE STARTS)
(TRUCK HONKING)
(VEHICLES HONKING)
(CROWD SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
(TRAIN HORN BLARES)
(GASPS)
(HORN BLARING)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
(BICYCLE BELL RINGING)
(RINGING BICYCLE BELL)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(GASPING)
(SIGHS)
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
(SCREECHING)
(CROWD SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(GROWLS)
(SCREECHES)
(SCREECHES LOUDLY)
(SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
(MAN SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE OVER TV)
(WOMAN SPEAKING OVER TV)
(SQUEAKING)
(LAUGHING)
(PEOPLE GRUNTING LOUDLY)
(RUMBLING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(PANTING)
(BELL CHIMING)
(CHIMING CONTINUES)
(SIGHING DEEPLY)
(WINDOW CREAKING)
(MOM VOICEOVER IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(CONTINUES SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES)
(PANTING)
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(WINDOW CREAKING)
(KIDS PLAYING MUSIC USING INSTRUMENTS)
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(FLUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)