After all... I'm stupid.
After all, yes, I must. I must!
- Michel! Take me with you!
- What time is it?
- 10:50.
- No.
I'm on my way, hey-hey!
Buenas noches,
mi amor...
If he thinks he's gonna pass me
in that crappy thing!
Pa... Pa... Patricia!
Patricia!
I pick up the cash,
I ask Patricia, yes or no, and then...
Buenas noches, mi amor!
Milano, Genova, Roma!
The countryside's nice.
I really like France.
If you don't like the sea,
if you don't like the mountains,
if you don't like the city,
then get stuffed!
Little girls trying to hitch a ride!
I'll charge a kiss per kilometer.
The short one's not bad.
Nice thighs.
But the other one...
Shit, they're too ugly.
The sun is beautiful.
Women are such cowards
behind the wheel. Overtake him!
Oh, there's roadwork’s.
Never use the brakes.
As old Bugatti said:
"Cars are made to run, not to stop."
Shit! Cops!
The wire's come off!
This could get me nabbed!
Don't move, or I'll waste you.
- Miss Franchini's room?
- She isn't here. She's out.
Girls never have any cash!
Espresso.
- How much is ham and eggs?
- 1.80.
- Right. I'll have some.
- OK.
Just going for a paper.
- Oh, wow, Michel!
- Can I come in?
- How are you, sweetheart?
- No jacket?
I left it in my Alfa Romeo.
- Want breakfast at the Royal?
- I must be at the TV station by 9:10.
It's torn. Listen to this.
- What have you been up to?
- Nothing, I've been travelling.
What's new around here?
- You don't go out?
- To the discotheque sometimes.
- Still making films?
- No. You need to sleep around.
Do you recollect Enrico?
"Remember" or "recall",
not "recollect".
I work with him at the station.
I'm a script-girl.
When I was broke in December,
I was assistant on a film at Cinecittà!
You?
Ever been a gigolo?
I was just asking.
I wouldn't mind.
Call me back in a few minutes.
Is Gaby back from Spain?
He's bought the Pergola.
Great. It was stupid
to paint it all black.
- What's it say there?
- "Why?"
Never finished it.
I smoke Luckies now.
- Can you lend me 5000 francs till noon?
- I might have known.
- You're a creep, Michel.
- I'll pay you back.
I don't have that much.
- Here's 500 if you want.
- No, keep it.
- So, no breakfast at the Royal?
- I'm really late.
Okay, then.
- Is Mr Tolmachov here?
- He's here, but he's not here.
- Seen Patricia?
- Yes, over there.
Come with me to Rome?
It's crazy, I wanted to see
if I'd be glad to see you again.
Have you been in Monte Carlo?
No, Marseilles. I was in Monte Carlo
before that to see a guy.
- I called on Monday, from Marseilles.
- I was out of town.
- I'll take one.
- That's kind.
- You said you hated Paris.
- No, I said I've got enemies here.
- So you're in danger?
- Yes, I am. Will you come to Rome?
To do what?
- No, I've things to do here.
- You going up or down the Champs?
- What's the "Champs"?
- The Champs Elysées.
I'm going to Avenue George V.
Go on, walk with me.
Just to the corner.
Here, no horoscope! It's the future.
I want to know the future.
- Don't you?
- Sure.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing, just looking at you.
- You angry I left without a goodbye?
- No, I was furious because I was sad.
It's nice to wake up next to a girl.
Are you staying in town?
I have to see a man who owes me money.
- Then I have to see you.
- You don't have to.
- There are prettier girls than me.
- No.
I slept with two girls since you.
It was a washout.
- What's "washout"?
- They were pretty, but it was no fun.
So will you come to Rome?
I'm fed up with France.
I have to enroll at the Sorbonne
so my parents will send money.
- We only had 3 nights together!
- No, 5.
- Why don't you wear a bra?
- Don't be rude!
- What time is it? See you later?
- Not later. Tonight. Okay?
- Yes. Where?
- Round here.
LIVE DANGEROUSLY UNTIL THE END!
- Sir? You've nothing against youth?
- I have. I like old people.
POLICEMAN'S KILLER IDENTIFIED
- Is Mr Tolmachov here?
- At the airline desk.
Hi, amigo.
- You came by at ten?
- Yeah, for my money.
I got bored down south.
I came up to see a girl.
- I'm rusting away here.
- Better rusted than busted.
Over here.
Do you have the envelope I gave you?
- Idiot! Why did he cross it?
- Just sign it over to someone else.
Not to me.
I blew my last penny on the races.
- And your pal, Bob Montagné?
- He's in prison.
- There's Berruti, but I don't trust him.
- I thought he was your pal.
- Is he back?
- Yes, I saw him last night.
- What was his number again?
- Elysée 99-84.
- Can I call from here?
- Go ahead.
- Who's the girl you came for?
- A New Yorker.
She's amusing. I like her.
Elysée 99-84?
I'd like to speak to Antonio.
I see. No, I'll call back.
He's out. I'll ask around.
- Bye, sonny.
- Ciao, amigo.
- Inter-Americana Agency?
- Yes, that's us.
- Do customers have mail sent here?
- Yes.
- Know a certain Michel Poiccard?
- No.
Also goes by the name Laszlo Kovacs?
Ask that gentleman.
He'll help you.
If it isn't Tolmachov!
Hello, Inspector.
- In the travel business now?
- As you can see.
Remember how you grassed
on your friend Bob?
- What of it?
- Well, you're going to do it again.
Michel Poiccard, 1 metre 79,
brown hair, former Air France steward.
- He has his mail sent here.
- Yes, I know him.
- He been around lately?
- No.
Miss!
Nobody been to see
Mr Tolmachov recently?
- Just 5 minutes ago, quite a tall man.
- Bloody hell!
Accessory to murder. Think about it!
THE HARDER THEY FALL
Bogey...
I saw a man die.
An accident.
- Take me out to dinner?
- Evidently.
Let me make another call first.
Wait for me?
- Call from the restaurant.
- No. I'll just be a second.
The French always say one second
when they mean 5 minutes.
- Where we going?
- Anywhere. To Saint Michel.
Sleep with me tonight?
- Don't you like it with me?
- Sure, I do.
I just read something in the paper.
About a bus conductor.
He stole 5 million to seduce a girl.
Impersonated a rich impresario.
He took her down to the Riviera.
They blew the lot in 3 days.
The guy didn't chicken out.
He told her:
"It's stolen money, I'm a bad guy,
but I like you."
It's great she stuck by him.
She said: "I like you, too."
They came back to Paris,
and were caught burgling villas.
She was the look-out.
- Excuse me, got a light?
- Go buy yourself some matches!
- I forgot! I have an appointment.
- Who with?
A journalist on the Champs Elysees.
It's a press conference.
- Where? Now?
- You can really get on my nerves.
- So you're leaving me?
- But I'll see you tomorrow.
Not tomorrow, tonight, Patricia.
- I told you I can't.
- Why are you so cruel?
- Any taxis around?
- My car's near the Opera. Want a lift?
- What happened to the Ford?
- It's in the garage.
- Let me stay with you.
- I've got a headache anyway.
- We won't make love.
- That's not it, Michel!
- Why are you so sad?
- Because I am.
That's silly.
Why are you sad?
- Should I use "vous" or "tu"?
- Either. But I can't do without you.
- Yes, you can.
- Maybe. But I don't want to.
Look at that great Talbot. A 2.5 litre.
- You're a kid...
- What?
- Oh, I don't know.
- I forbid you to meet this guy.
Alas, alas, alas!
I love a girl who has a nice neck,
nice breasts,
a nice voice, nice wrists,
a nice forehead, nice knees.
But she's such a coward!
- It's there. Stop.
- I'll park.
Get lost then!
I never want to see you again.
Get lost!
Get lost, you creep!
- I'd be sad if that happened to you.
- We'll see.
What's wrong?
If I could dig a hole
and hide in it, I would.
You should be like an elephant.
When they're sad, they vanish.
Let me tell you a story.
It'll take your mind off things.
I've known a girl 2 years.
And now, I suddenly think:
I'll ask her to sleep with me.
It had never occurred to me.
We met for lunch. I wanted to say:
"We're friends, let's sleep together."
I don't know why,
but it completely slipped my mind!
Later I sent her a telegram,
saying I'd forgotten to say
we should sleep together.
3 hours later I get
a message back, saying:
"What an amazing coincidence!
I was going to suggest the same thing!"
- Is this the late edition?
- Yes, sir.
- My key isn't here?
- You must've left it in the door.
Oh, no!
- What are you doing here?
- The Claridge was fully booked.
So I came here.
I took the key downstairs.
- There are other hotels.
- I always stay at the Claridge.
You're crazy!
- Don't sulk!
- I can never be alone...
It doesn't suit you.
- What's "sulk"?
- This.
It suits me fine.
You're even crazier than me.
What a pain. I always fall for girls
who aren't for me.
Did you notice
I followed you last night?
- What's wrong?
- Leave me alone. I'm thinking.
What about?
The thing is, I don't even know.
- Well, I do.
- No, nobody does.
You're thinking about last night.
Last night I was furious,
but now I couldn't care less.
I'm not thinking about anything.
I'd like to think about something,
but I can't seem to.
Well, I'm tired, very tired,
and I'm going back to sleep.
- Why are you looking at me?
- Because I am.
- You should've stayed last night.
- I couldn't.
You should've told the chap
you couldn't see him.
I had to. He's getting me articles
to write. It's really important for me.
What's important
is going to Rome with me.
Maybe, I don't know.
- Did you sleep with him?
- No.
- I bet you did.
- No. He's really sweet.
He said one day we'd sleep together,
but not now.
- But he doesn't even know me.
- Not you. Him and me.
- We had a drink in Montparnasse.
- I was there, too. At what time?
I don't know. We didn't stay long.
Why did you come here, Michel?
- I want to sleep with you again.
- That's hardly a reason.
- Sure it is. It means I love you.
- But I don't know yet if I love you.
- When will you know?
- Soon.
- In a month, in a year?
- Soon means soon.
A woman never wants to do
in eight seconds
what she'll want to do
eight days later.
Eight seconds or eight days,
it's all the same.
- Why not eight centuries?
- No, eight days is good.
A woman's all half-measures.
It gets me down.
Why won't you sleep with me again?
Because I'm trying to find out
what it is that I like about you.
- I want us to be like Romeo and Juliet.
- Just like a girl!
You said last night you couldn't
live without me, but you can.
Romeo couldn't live without Juliet,
but you can.
No, I can't live without you.
Just like a man!
Give me a smile.
Right. I'll count to 8.
If by 8 you haven't smiled,
I'll strangle you.
Two.
Three.
Four, five, six.
Seven.
Seven and a half.
Seven and three quarters.
You're such a coward
I bet you're gonna smile.
Enough games for today.
- Too bad you're a coward.
- Why do you say that?
- You get on my nerves.
- And you get on mine.
- I'm not a coward.
- How do you know I'm scared?
If a girl says she's not scared,
then can't even light her cigarette,
it means she's scared of something.
I don't know of what, but she's scared.
- Have one.
- None of those Chesterfields.
Hand me my jacket.
- In this one?
- Give it here!
- This is your passport?
- My brother's. Mine's in the car.
- But it says Kovacs here.
- He's not my real brother.
My mum was divorced
by the time he was born.
See? I'm not scared.
- I never said you were.
- You bet, pet.
But you wish you had said it.
And now you're angry.
I'm not talking to you anymore.
Do you ever think about death?
I do, all the time.
- What?
- Say something nice.
- Like what?
- I don't know.
Then neither do I.
- I like your ashtray.
- It's Swiss.
My granddad had a Rolls-Royce.
Great car!
Never had to raise the bonnet
in 15 years!
Seen my new poster?
Come here!
Come here, for Christ's sake!
It won't do here. Where can I put it?
Why did you slap me
when I looked at your legs?
It wasn't my legs.
It's exactly the same thing.
The French always say things
are the same when they're not at all.
- I've thought of something nice.
- What?
I want to sleep with you again
because you're beautiful.
I'm not.
- Then because you're ugly.
- Is it the same?
Yeah, baby, it's the same.
- You're a liar, Michel.
- No, lying's stupid.
It's like at poker...
It's better to tell the truth.
The others think you're bluffing,
and that's how you win.
What is it?
I'll stare at you
until you stop staring at me.
I'm going to put my poster
in the bathroom.
- Can I phone?
- Yes.
- It's not bad here.
- Just fine.
- Do you like this poster?
- It's not bad.
- Renoir's a really great painter.
- I said, not bad!
Think she's prettier than me?
When you're scared or surprised,
or both at once...
...there's a funny glint in your eyes.
I want to sleep with you again,
because of that glint.
Mind if I piss in the sink?
- Guess what I'm going to say.
- No idea.
I'm pregnant, Michel.
You heard me.
- Whose is it? Mine?
- I think so.
- Seen a doctor?
- Yesterday.
I have to go back Thursday for tests.
You should've been more careful!
Get me Elysée 99-84.
99-84.
Is Antonio there?
You don't know if he's coming back?
I'll call back.
Michel Poiccard.
Elysée 25-32.
I'm calling
the man who owes me money.
Mr Tolmachov, please.
Hey, sonny.
I can't find Berruti.
I wandered
around Montparnasse all night.
The police?
Thanks. Ciao, sonny.
Shit!
- What?
- I slipped.
Heard the one
about the condemned man?
As he's climbing the scaffold,
he slips and says, "that figures!"
- You look like a Martian up close.
- Because my head's in the clouds.
- Some idea, having a kid!
- But it's not sure.
I wanted to see what you'd say.
- Take your clothes off.
- What's the point?
You Americans are so stupid.
You adore La Fayette
and Maurice Chevalier.
And they're the stupidest Frenchmen!
I'm making another call.
Belle Epine 35-26.
Patricia, come here!
Hello, Mr Mansard?
Will he be in this afternoon?
Tell him I'll come by.
I'm a friend of Tony's. From Marseilles.
Laszlo Kovacs. I've got an American.
- An American?
- Laszlo Kovacs.
Not you. An American car.
I can't find the man
who owes me money. What a pain!
- Do you prefer records or the radio?
- Quiet, I'm thinking!
- I know them all so well.
- How old are you?
- I'll put the radio on. I'm 20.
- You don't look it.
- Why don't you like music?
- It depends. I do.
Come on, Patricia, come to Italy.
What's the point of studying
at the Sorbonne?
You never took any exams.
Sure, the baccalaureate.
But I packed it in.
- What's "packed it in"?
- I did other things.
- I sold cars.
- Here?
No.
In New York,
did you sleep with a lot of men?
Not so many.
How many?
- How about you?
- Me?
Not so many either.
You know where I'd like to live?
Mexico. I hear it's really lovely.
When I was a kid my dad would say:
We'll go next Saturday.
But he'd always forget.
No, Mexico doesn't grab me.
I bet it's not all that great.
People are such liars.
It's like Stockholm. Everyone says...
"Swedish girls are terrific.
I had 3 a day. Go there."
I went there. It's not true.
Swedish girls don't act
the way they do here.
Most of them are dogs
like Parisian girls.
No, Swedish girls are very pretty.
It's a myth.
One or two maybe, like in Paris
or London, but not all of them.
The cities where the girls are pretty,
not gorgeous, but like you, charming,
girls who rate 15 out of 20,
because they have something...
Aren't Rome or Paris or Rio
but Lausanne and Geneva.
- Now you tell me something nice.
- I don't know what, either.
Would you let another man caress you?
You know, you said I'm scared.
It's true, I'm scared.
Because I want you to love me.
But at the same time,
I want you to stop loving me.
I'm very independent, you know.
I love you.
But not the way you think.
- How then?
- Not the way you think.
But you don't know what I think.
You don't know.
- Yes, I do.
- No, it's impossible.
I want to know
what's behind your face.
I've looked at it for 10 minutes,
and I still know nothing.
I'm not sad. I'm scared.
Sweet, gentle Patricia.
OK, then, cruel, stupid,
heartless, pathetic...
...cowardly, despicable.
- Yes.
You don't even how to apply
your lipstick. Now you're hideous.
Say what you like, I don't care.
I'll put all this in my book.
- What book?
- I'm writing a novel.
- You?
- Why not me? What are you doing?
- Taking off your top.
- Not now.
You're a bloody pain! What is all this?
You know William Faulkner?
- Who's he? Someone you slept with?
- No way, Jose!
To hell with him, then!
Take off your top.
He's one of my favourites.
Have you read Wild Palms?
- Take off your top, I said.
- The last sentence is beautiful.
"Between grief and nothing,
I will take grief."
- Which would you choose?
- Let me see your toes.
Toes are important in a woman.
Don't laugh.
- Which would you choose?
- Grief's stupid.
I'd choose nothing.
It's not better,
but grief's a compromise.
I want all or nothing.
And now I know.
Now I do.
Why are you shutting your eyes?
I'm shutting my eyes tight
so everything goes black.
But I can't do it.
It's never entirely black.
Your smile, seen in profile,
it's the nicest thing about you.
- That's you.
- That's me!
We look each other in the eyes,
and it means nothing.
Patricia Franchini.
I hate that name.
I'd like to be called Ingrid.
Kneel for me.
What's wrong?
- I'm looking at you.
- The French are stupid, too.
- I want you to stay with me.
- OK.
We interrupt our programming
in order to synchronize our networks.
Funny, I can see
my reflection in your eyes.
A real Franco-American reconciliation.
We're hiding like happy elephants.
- Women's hips move me somehow.
- It's hot under here.
If it was another man caressing you,
would you mind?
Our musical program is about to start.
There!
You know Dylan Thomas'
Portrait of the Artist as a Young Dog?
Sunday morning is most satisfying
to have a really long lie-in.
I'm getting dressed.
- What time is it?
- Noon.
Was it good?
- Let's stay in bed.
- Nope, I've got to buy a dress.
- Have you got your car?
- Yeah.
Good morning, Michel.
Elysée 99-84.
Hello.
Good morning.
Has Antonio been back?
Oh, no. This is unbelievable!
You don't know where he is?
No, never mind.
Michel Poiccard again.
Want me to wear a bra?
Which do you like best:
My eyes, my mouth or my shoulders?
If you had to choose.
- There was no press conference.
- No, it's at Orly in a little while.
I'm not much of a looker,
but I'm quite a boxer!
Going to your press conference?
- I have to drop by the office first.
- I'll come with you.
Eisenhower, with General de Gaulle,
will lay a wreath
on the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier.
- Were you in the army?
- Yes.
- What did you do?
- I did in the sentries.
- "Did in"?
- I laid them out flat like this.
- I'm exhausted. I'm gonna die.
- You're crazy.
Yeah, totally barmy.
- What's "barmy"?
- I am.
- Your car's not here?
- Yes... No... Yes.
It's at the garage.
Great, a Ford!
- What floor?
- Fifth.
I got the wrong floor.
- Scared of getting old? I am.
- You're stupid!
I told you,
the worst flaw is cowardice.
- Will you buy me a Dior dress?
- No way!
There are nicer dresses
at the supermarket.
You make calls at Dior.
It's the only place
where you can phone for free.
France Soir! France Soir!
- Give me one!
- Here you go.
Thank you.
- I'll take one, please.
- Yes, sir.
POLICE KILLER STILL AT LARGE
- How long will it last?
- Half an hour or so.
I'll go and see my guy, then.
Why did you call your novel "Candida"?
I'm sure that the French
will give my book
a cool reception
because of their prudishness.
Mr Parvulesco!
Can one still believe
in love in our time?
Of course, especially in our time.
What about Rilke's saying:
"Modern life increasingly separates
men and women?"
Rilke was a great poet,
he was probably right.
Move back a bit!
Typical Pathé-Journal!
Do French and American women
differ in their romantic attitudes?
French women
are totally unlike Americans.
American women dominate men.
French women don't yet.
What's your greatest ambition?
Who are more moral:
Unfaithful women or deserting males?
Unfaithful women.
Are women more sentimental than men?
Feelings are a luxury
few women can afford.
Do you think there is a difference
between eroticism and love?
No, not really.
I don't think so, because...
Eroticism is a form of love,
and vice versa.
Does the soul exist in modern society?
Do women have a role to play
in modern society?
If she's charming and wears
a striped dress and dark glasses.
Casanova said that there's no woman
who can't be seduced with gratitude.
Cocteau will answer that.
How many men can a woman love
in a lifetime? Physically, I mean.
More than that!
- Miss, you're in the shot.
- Two things matter in life.
For men, it's women,
and for women, money.
If you see a pretty girl
with a rich chap,
you know she's nice
and he's a bastard.
- Do you like Brahms?
- Like everyone, no.
- And Chopin?
- A creep!
What's your greatest ambition?
To become immortal and then die.
Are you Claudius Mansard?
Yes, Mr Kovacs.
I called this morning.
I was told you'd be here.
- Tony sent me.
- Yes, Mr Kovacs.
- Didn't we meet in Nice?
- No, Mr Kovacs.
- Did they call?
- They said it'd be an Oldsmobile.
It fell through at the last minute.
- And so?
- So, it's this.
- 800,000.
- OK.
- I'll have the money next week.
- You bastard!
And you, Mr Kovacs?
Who are you?
- So what?
- You don't get the money now.
Tough. Is it 3 o'clock yet?
Can I use the phone?
- Is Antonio there?
- He just left.
He said to meet him at the Escale at 4.
OK, thanks.
Don't bother. I carry my cash on me.
- Lend me 10,000.
- No.
5000?
2500?
She's not running?
Hey, you!
You remove the distributor cap?
- You owe me a phone call!
- For a taxi!
Step on it! Never mind
the pedestrians! Just hurry!
Step on it!
The Thunderbird's left wing torn off!
Me, not a scratch!
That's where I was born.
Look at the eyesore they built opposite!
Houses like that get me down.
They ruin the whole block.
I have a feeling for beauty, Beauty.
Go through Châtelet!
If we're late it's your fault.
Overtake that Peugeot!
Don't brake for a 4CV!
You're being overtaken by a scooter!
Take the next left!
- Wait. I'll be back.
- Yes, sir.
He left 5 minutes ago.
The friend who owes you money?
Antonio Berruti, yeah,
and it's your fault.
Now it's double or quits.
I'll tell you later.
Overtake that 2CV.
- Where you going?
- To the New York Herald.
- Why bother writing?
- To have money and not rely on men.
Paris girls look like tarts
in those short dresses.
Makes me want to run up behind them
and do like this.
- We'll be right back.
- Not paying the fare?
- Where are we going?
- To the Champs Elysees, on foot.
I hate taxi-drivers who are afraid
their car will get scratched.
The Gestapo put up a wall here
so nobody could escape them.
I've been thinking about that girl.
The one with that chap on the Riviera.
You said you admired her.
Yeah, an ordinary girl. That's rare.
- Come with me to the paper?
- No, I've a call to make.
I'm going to see my tailor.
I'll pick you up later.
You're late. They're waiting.
- Miss Patricia Franchini?
- Over there.
You speak French?
Do you know this man?
No.
Careful, little girl,
don't mess with the Paris police.
- Yes, it's Michel.
- Poiccard?
I didn't recognise him.
It's an old photo.
You were seen with him this morning
just outside.
He was driving
a Ford Thunderbird, 3382 GM 75.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Watch it,
watch what you say, little girl!
I've seen him five or six times.
I found him nice. I don't know
where he lives or what he does.
Known him long?
I met him 3 weeks ago in Nice.
I was on holiday.
He came to Paris to see someone
who owes him money.
- Who?
- I don't know. Some Italian.
- Think you'll see him again?
- Maybe.
Sometimes he calls me
and asks me out. Like this morning.
- Got a work permit?
- Yes.
You don't want any passport problems?
So if you see him, here's my number.
Danton 01-00.
President Eisenhower
is waving his arms.
Was that what you meant
by double or quits?
- More or less.
- Let's go see a western.
Yeah, better wait till dark.
Beware, Jessica. On the kiss's
beveled edge time is a void
Avoid, avoid memory's broken pledge.
You're wrong. Your tale is noble
and tragic as the mask of a tyrant.
No drama so perilous or magnetic.
No detail can make our love pathetic.
Hi, cutie!
- What's it say?
- I'm reading it.
The cops are stupid to be after me.
I'm one of the few who like them.
Patricia, let me caress you.
- Say something!
- Well!
- So you're married.
- Show me.
That was ages ago.
She was crazy. She dumped me.
- Or I dumped her. I can't remember.
- I really like you, Michel.
What's it like, to ride in a stolen car?
- And killing a policeman?
- I was scared!
- How did they know I knew you?
- Someone must've seen us together.
That's very bad.
Grassing people up.
No, it's normal. Grasses grass,
burglars burgle,
murderers murder, lovers love.
Look, isn't the Concorde gorgeous!
Yes, mysterious, with all the lights.
I was a fool to keep this car.
Gotta switch.
- What?
- Switch cars.
- Let's steal the Cadillac.
- Sure.
Cadillac Eldorado.
You drive, I hide.
They leave the keys in the car here.
- What do I tell the man?
- Say goodnight... in English.
He won't say a thing.
The French are chickens.
- "Chickens"?
- Scared stiff.
- Are you scared?
- It's too late to be scared.
Goodnight Madam.
ARREST IMMINENT
I really must find Antonio.
Once you look for someone,
you never find him.
Who was that?
- Step on it, poppet.
- What's "poppet"?
- Seen Antonio?
- I'll tell you if I can kiss her.
It's not up to me,
it's up to her.
He's with Zumbart in Montparnasse.
Carl!
- How's things?
- Antonio's not with you?
There he is.
- Who's that?
- Antonio?
Patricia Franchini, Carl Zumbart.
Let's see those socks.
Silk socks with a tweed jacket!
- I like silk.
- Not with tweed!
- Hi, amigo.
- Hi, sonny.
- You wanted to see me?
- I'm in shit, deep shit.
Shit. Got a minute?
It's that man.
- What do I say?
- Anything you want.
- What will they do?
- Take photos of her kissing the man.
Blackmail, probably.
- Right.
- I'll be right back.
- Who's the chick?
- I'm in love with her.
1.3 million, is OK.
- What's your bank?
- The B.N.C.I.
- What shall we do?
- I don't know.
- Where can I reach you tomorrow?
- The hotels are crawling with tourists.
- My friend in Montmartre has a big flat.
- Not Montmartre.
- Why not?
- Too many enemies in Montmartre.
- Try Zumbart's Swedish girl.
- Rue Campagne Première?
- Call me there tomorrow.
- Bye, amigo.
- Antonio said we could stay the night.
- Sit down. I'll be right with you.
OK. Smile.
Smile!
- You could pose. It pays good.
- You have to sleep around.
I was just thinking... I can't decide.
Decide what?
I don't know.
Otherwise I wouldn't hesitate.
- You dumped your journalist?
- Yes.
- Why did you say hello?
- To be sure I didn't love him anymore.
You make life difficult.
That's it.
Drop me on the Champs Elysees?
Bye.
- What record is it?
- Mozart's clarinet concerto.
- Do you mind?
- No, I like that one.
- I thought you didn't like music.
- This one's OK.
My dad played clarinet.
He was brilliant on the clarinet.
Want to turn in? Sleeping's so sad.
- We're forced to apart.
- To be apart.
They say "sleep together",
but it's not true.
What is it?
Nothing.
Patricia, come here.
Go buy the newspaper
and a bottle of milk.
- What time is it?
- Five.
Engaged all the time.
- Michel... Nothing.
- The newspaper!
I'm looking at you.
It's your lucky day. Take a ticket.
- A whisky.
- Don't have any.
Danton 01-00?
Inspector Vital, please.
Hello? Patricia Franchini.
I've just seen the man
you're looking for.
He's at 11, rue Première Campagne.
Yes. 11, rue Campagne Première.
Hello?
- Thirsty?
- No.
Antonio's on his way. He just called.
We're on our way to Italy, baby!
- I can't go.
- Sure you can, I'm taking you.
Berruti's lending me his sports car.
An Amedeo Gordini model.
Michel, I called the police.
- I said you were here.
- Are you mad?
No, I'm fine.
No, I'm not.
I don't want to go with you.
I knew it.
I just talked about myself,
and you, yourself.
You should've talked about me,
and me, about you.
I don't want to be in love with you.
That's why I called the police.
I stayed with you
to see if I was in love with you.
Or if I wasn't in love with you.
And since I'm being cruel to you,
it proves I'm not in love with you.
Say that again!
And since I'm being cruel to you,
it proves I'm not in love with you.
They say there's no happy love.
If I loved you... It's too complicated!
On the contrary,
there's no unhappy love.
- I want people to leave me alone.
- I'm independent.
- Maybe you love me.
- You think you are. You're not.
- That's why I gave you away.
- I'm better than you are.
Now you have no choice but to go.
You're out of your mind!
That's a pathetic way to reason!
You're like those women
who sleep with everyone,
except the one man who loves them,
saying it's because they sleep
with everyone.
Why don't you go?
I've slept with lots of boys.
Don't count on me.
- Just go. Why wait?
- I'm staying.
I'm in bad shape.
Anyway I want to go to jail.
- You're mad!
- Yes.
Nobody will talk to me.
I can look at the walls.
Oh, shit! Berruti!
Hey, amigo! I'll just park.
Cops are coming.
The American girl grassed on me.
- Get in! You fool! Get in!
- No, I'm staying.
I've had enough. I'm tired.
I want to sleep.
- You're crazy! Get in!
- Stuff the police. I'll save my neck.
I shouldn't be thinking of her
but I can't help it.
- Want my automatic?
- No.
- Don't be stupid!
- Get out of here!
I am a real creep.
- What did he say?
- He said: "You're a real creep."
What's a "creep"?