(JAZZY MUSIC PLAYING)
(APPLAUSE)
Thank you very much
and welcome to To TeII the Truth.
Our first guest, he's made a career out
of being the most outrageous impostor
that we've ever come across
on this show. You'll see what l mean.
ANNOUNCER: Number One,
what is your name, please?
My name is Frank William Abagnale.
-Number Two?
-My name is Frank William Abagnale.
-Number Three?
HOST: From 1964 to 1967,
l successfully impersonated
an airline pilot for Pan Am Airways,
and l flew over two million miles
for free.
During that time,
l was also the Chief Resident
Pediatrician at a Georgia hospital
and an Assistant Attorney General
for the State of Louisiana.
By the time l was caught,
l was considered the youngest and most
daring con man in U.S. history.
l had cashed almost $4 million
in fraudulent checks
in 26 foreign countries and all 50 states.
And l did it all before my 19th birthday.
My name is Frank William Abagnale.
(APPLAUSE)
So, for the first time,
he'll have to tell the truth.
We'll start our questioning with Kitty.
Thank you. Number One,
why, with all your talent,
and you're obviously
a very bright fellow,
why didn't you go in for
a legitimate profession?
lt was a question of dollars and cents.
When l was a young man,
l needed the money,
and l thought this list of careers was
the easiest way to get it.
KITTY: I see. Number Two,
l find this all very fascinating.
Who was it that finally caught you?
His name was Carl Hanratty.
(POLICEMEN STRUGGLING
WITH PRONUNCIATION)
Hanratty.
I am
CarI Hanratty.
I represent the F.B.I.
from the United States ofAmerica.
(QUESTIONING IN FRENCH)
I have orders to see
the American prisoner, AbagnaIe.
(POLICEMEN ARGUING IN FRENCH)
(UNLOCKS DOOR)
You sit here.
You do not open the door.
You do not pass him
anything through the hoIe.
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
(FRANK COUGHING)
Aw, Jesus.
(WATER DRIPPING)
(FRANK CONTINUES COUGHING)
(SPITS)
You know,
I've got a IittIe bit of a coId myseIf.
(INTENSE COUGHING)
Frank, I'm here to read
the articIes of extradition
according to the European Court
for Human Rights.
"ArticIe One,
"extradition shaII be granted
in respect of offenses..."
HeIp me.
Frank, stop it.
You don't think
you're actuaIIy going to fooI me, do you?
(COUGHING)
Sixteen pages to go.
Stay with me. "ArticIe Two,
"if the request for extradition
incIudes separate offenses...
"...each of which is punishabIe under
the Iaws of the requesting party..."
Frank?
God damn it!
Get me a doctor in here!
I need a doctor!
-Yes.
-Doctor! Now!
Don't sweat it.
We'II get you right to a doctor.
(HEAD POLICEMAN
SPEAKING FRENCH)
If you can hear me, don't worry.
I'II take you home in the morning.
Home in the morning, Frank.
-What are you doing?
-Washing off the Iice.
This man has to be on a pIane
for America. He has to see a doctor.
Yes, the doctor comes in tomorrow.
I've worked too Iong, too hard,
for you to take this away from me.
If he dies, I'm hoIding you responsibIe.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(CALLS IN FRENCH)
Oh, Frank.
(LOUD CLAMOR)
(COUGHING VIOLENTLY)
(POLICEMEN SHOUTING)
Okay, CarI,
Iet's go home.
BARNES:
The New Rochelle Rotary Club
has a history that goes back to 1919.
ln all those years,
we've only seen a handful
of deserving gentlemen
inducted as lifetime members.
lt's an honor that has seen 57 names
enshrined on the wall of honor.
And tonight, we make it 58.
So please stand
as l present my very good friend,
a man who keeps our pencils sharp
-and our pens in ink.
-(ALL LAUGHING)
Frank William Abagnale.
I stand here, humbIed
by the presence of
Mayor Robert Wagner
and our club president, Jack Barnes.
Most of aII, I'm honored to see
my loving wife, Paula
and my son, Frank, Jr.
Come on.
Sitting in the front row.
Two little mice fell in a bucket of cream.
The first mouse quickly gave up
and drowned.
The second mouse
wouldn't quit.
He struggled so hard
that eventually he churned that cream
into butter
and crawled out.
GentIemen, as of this moment,
l am that second mouse.
(EMBRACEABLE YOU PLAYING)
PAULA: You're a better dancer
than your father.
FRANK: Hear that, Daddy?
FRANK, SR.: Like fun.
PAULA: The girIs don't know
what they're in for.
(FRANK LAUGHING)
Show him the dance you were doing
when we met.
PAULA: Oh, who can remember?
The peopIe in that IittIe French viIIage
were so happy to see Americans,
they decided to put on a show for us.
-So they crammed 200 soIdiers...
-We know the story, Daddy.
...into that tiny sociaI haII,
and the first person to waIk on stage
is your mother
and she starts to dance.
You know, it had been months
since we'd seen a woman,
and here's this bIond angeI.
BIond bombsheII.
(LAUGHING)
And the men
are IiteraIIy hoIding their breath.
HoIding their breath for you. Hear that?
I turned to my buddies and I said...
"I wiII not Ieave France without her."
And I didn't.
You didn't.
I didn't.
Oh, shit, the rug.
-Oh, Mom.
-I can't beIieve I...
It's nothing.
-Frankie, run and get a toweI.
-Yeah.
Come on.
Dance with me, PauIa.
(EMBRACEABLE YOU
CONTINUES PLAYING)
Whenever I dance for you,
I get in troubIe.
Oh! (LAUGHS)
Frank. Wake up. Come on, Iet's go.
Get up, come on.
-Frank, wake up.
-Dad.
You don't have to go to schooI today.
It's okay.
-Why? Is it snowing?
-Do you have a bIack suit?
I oversIept again.
We have a very important meeting
in the city. Eat that.
Come on.
FRANK, SR.: Ma'am, open up, pIease.
It's important.
-(POUNDING ON DOOR)
-What? Oh, gosh.
-We don't open for haIf an hour.
-Just open the door. It's important.
I'm sorry, we don't open for haIf an hour.
What's your name, ma'am?
-Darcy.
-Darcy. That's a pretty name.
I'm in a fix. I need a suit for my kid.
This is my son, Frank.
He needs a bIack suit.
There was a death in the famiIy.
My father, 85 years oId, war hero.
There's a funeraI this afternoon,
miIitary funeraI,
pIanes fIying overhead, 21 -gun saIute.
Frank needs to borrow a suit
for a coupIe of hours.
I'm sorry,
we don't Ioan suits and we're not open.
Darcy, pIease. Come back.
(SIGHS)
Darcy, is this yours?
I just found it in the parking Iot.
Uh-huh.
Must have sIipped right off your neck.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
FRANK, SR.: Don't hit the curb.
Now get out, waIk around the back
and hoId the door open for me.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
-What's next?
-Okay. Stop grinning.
When I get inside,
go back to the front seat and wait.
Even if a cop comes
and writes you a ticket,
don't move the car, understood?
Dad, what's aII this for?
You know why the Yankees aIways win?
Because they have Mickey MantIe?
No, it's because the other teams can't
stop staring at those damn pinstripes.
Watch this. The manager
of Chase Manhattan Bank
is about to open the door for your father.
Mr. AbagnaIe,
we don't usuaIIy Ioan money to peopIe
who have unresoIved business
with the IRS.
That's a misunderstanding.
I hired the wrong guy to do my books.
A mistake anybody couId make.
I just need you guys
to heIp me weather the storm.
You're being investigated
by the government for tax fraud.
(SIGHS) My store is
a Iandmark in New RocheIIe.
I have customers aII over New York.
You're not a customer
at Chase Manhattan.
We don't know you.
I'm sure your bank in New RocheIIe
couId heIp you out.
My bank went out of business.
Banks Iike this one
put them out of business.
I know I made a mistake, I admit that.
But these peopIe want bIood.
They want my store.
They've threatened to put me in jaiI.
This is America, right?
I'm not a criminaI.
I'm a MedaI of Honor winner. A member
of the New RocheIIe Rotary CIub.
AII I'm asking is
for you to heIp me beat these guys.
It's not a question of winning and Iosing,
it's a question of risk.
You're the Iargest bank in the worId.
Where's the...
Where's the risk?
How couId you Iet him
take our car Iike that?
He didn't take anything, we took him.
He overpaid by 500.
Come on, Frank. Let's return the suit.
(PAULA WEEPING)
This pIace is good.
It's smaII, but it's gonna be
a Iot Iess work.
A Iot Iess work for you.
FRANK: Hey, Dad.
Hi.
Where is your mother?
I don't know.
She said something
about going to Iook for a job.
What's she going to be,
a shoe saIesman at a centipede farm?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
What are you doing?
You want some pancakes?
For dinner? On my son's 1 6th birthday?
We're not going to eat pancakes.
Why are you Iooking at me Iike that?
You thought I forgot?
-I didn't think you forgot.
-I opened a checking account
I put $25 in the account
so you can buy whatever you want.
-Don't teII your mother.
-I won't.
Thanks, Dad.
Didn't that bank turn you down
for a Ioan?
Yes, they aII turned me down.
Then why you opening
a banking account with them?
Because one day, you'II want
something from these peopIe.
A house, a car...
They have aII the money.
There's 50 checks there, Frank,
which means, from this day on,
you're in their IittIe cIub.
I'm in their IittIe cIub.
You got that, you got it aII.
It's even got my name there.
-To the moon.
-To the moon. (CHUCKLES)
To the moon.
(BELL TOLLING)
See that? It's just a schooI.
No different than Westbourne.
Ma, you said you were going to quit.
Frankie, you don't have to wear
the uniform here.
Why don't you take off yourjacket?
I'm used to it.
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
Do you know where room 1 7,
French is?
Yeah...
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BELL RINGING)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
You seIIing encycIopedias?
He Iooks Iike a substitute teacher.
Quiet down, peopIe!
My name is Mr. AbagnaIe!
-(GROANS)
-That's AbagnaIe, not AbagnoIee,
not AbagneIee, but AbagnaIe.
Now, somebody pIease teII me
where you Ieft off in your textbooks.
Excuse me, peopIe.
If I need to ask again,
I'm gonna write up the entire cIass.
Take your seats!
Chapter seven.
WouId you pIease open your textbooks
to chapter eight
and we'II get started.
-Excuse me. What's your name?
-Brad.
Why don't you get up here
in front of the cIass
and read conversation number five?
(READING POORLY IN FRENCH)
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
They sent for me.
They said they needed
a sub for Roberta.
I came aII the way from Dixon.
I aIways sub for Roberta.
Excuse me, why aren't you reading?
I'II never come back
to BeIIarmine-Jefferson again!
You teII them not to caII me.
Do they think it's easy
for a woman my age
and aII the money that it costs to traveI?
I teII you, they don't give a damn.
Mr. and Mrs. AbagnaIe,
this is not a question
of your son's attendance.
I regret to inform you
that for the past week,
Frank has been teaching
Mrs. GIasser's French cIass.
He what?
Your son has been pretending to be
a substitute teacher.
Lecturing the students,
giving out homework...
Mrs. GIasser has been iII,
and there was some confusion
with the reaI sub.
Your son heId
a teacher-parent conference yesterday
and was pIanning a cIass fieId trip
to a French bread factory in Trenton.
Do you see the probIem we have?
I've a note to miss fifth and sixth period
today. Doctor's appointment.
-(PHONE RINGING)
-One moment. I'II be right with you.
-You shouId foId it.
-What?
That note. It's a fake, right?
You shouId foId it.
It's a note from my mom.
I have a doctor's appointment.
Yeah, but there's no crease
in the paper.
When your mom hands you a note
to miss schooI,
the first thing you do is foId it
and put it in your pocket.
If it's reaI, where's the crease?
(BELL RINGING)
Frankie.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Ma, I'm home.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Remember that girI Joanna
I was teIIing you about?
I asked her out today.
Think we're going to go
to the junior prom.
-(MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY)
-Ma, is this my driver's Iicense?
That's aII there is, two bedrooms.
Frankie.
You remember Dad's friend?
Jack Barnes. From the cIub.
HeIIo.
He came by Iooking for your father.
I was giving him a tour of the apartment.
(STAMMERING)
It's very spacious, PauIa.
Dad is at the store.
So, Frank,
you're getting to Iook
more Iike your oId man every day.
Thanks for the sandwich, PauIa.
-I'II see you Iater.
-Wait.
Is this yours?
Oh.
Thanks, Frank.
That's the President's pin.
I'd be in deep troubIe if I Iost that.
I'II see you aII Iater.
Are you hungry, Frankie?
I'II make you a sandwich.
Jack wanted to taIk business
with your father.
He thinks we shouId get a Iawyer
and sue the government.
That it's not IegaI,
what they're doing to us.
Why aren't you saying anything?
You're not going to teII him, are you?
No.
That's right. There's nothing to teII.
I'm going out for a few hours to visit
some oId friends from the tennis cIub.
When I get home,
we'II aII have dinner together.
Right?
But you won't say anything
because it's just siIIy,
isn't it?
How couId we sue anybody?
Do you need some money, Frankie?
A few doIIars to buy
some record aIbums?
Here. Take $5.
Or 1 0.
You promised you were going to quit.
Ma, I'm home.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Hey, hey!
You stay away from me. You hear me?
I don't know who you are,
but if you come back here...
Frank, caIm down, wiII you?
I'm Dick Kesner.
I want you to Ieave your things here,
foIIow me into the next room.
Okay? They're aII waiting for you.
PAULA: You don't have to be scared.
I'm right here, Frank.
I'II aIways be here.
But there are Iaws. Everything in
this country has to be IegaI.
So what we need to do
is make some decisions.
That's what Mr. Kesner is here for.
Many times these decisions
are Ieft up to the courts.
But that can be very expensive,
peopIe fighting over their chiIdren.
Nobody is fighting.
Look at me, Frank. Nobody is fighting.
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
(WHISPERING)
Do you remember your grandma? Eve?
She arrived this morning.
-(GREETING IN FRENCH)
-HeIIo.
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
Do you understand
what we're saying to you, Frank?
Your father and I are getting a divorce.
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
Nothing's going to change.
We're stiII gonna see each other.
-Stop it, pIease. Don't interrupt.
-You don't have to read aII of this.
Most of it is for your parents,
boring aduIt business.
But this paragraph right here,
this is important
because it states
who you're gonna Iive with
after the divorce.
Whose custody you wiII be in.
And there's a bIank space right here.
(GRANDMOTHER
GRUMBLING IN FRENCH)
I want you to go into the kitchen,
sit at the tabIe
and put a name down.
You can take as Iong as you want,
but when you come back into this room,
l want to see a name on that line.
(CHUCKLING) Frank, just write down
a name and this wiII aII be over.
It's going to be okay.
FRANK: Dad, what name?
Your mother or your father.
Just put the name there.
It's as simpIe as that.
And don't Iook so scared. It's not a test.
There's no wrong answer.
(MAN CHATTERING ON PA)
(PANTING)
One ticket to Grand CentraI, pIease.
That wiII be $3.50, sir.
Is it okay if I write you a check?
CarI, when do I get to caII my father?
CARL: You can caII him when we get
to New York.
We Ieave for the airport in seven hours.
UntiI then, just sit there.
Be quiet.
On the other side of the hoteI,
they got suites that face the park.
It's the best room the F.B.I. can afford.
It's okay, I've stayed in worse.
PIease. You have to Iisten.
I don't want to hear your story.
Two checks bounced.
You know how much troubIe I'm in?
No, but Iisten. I'm teIIing you.
The bank, they made the mistake.
I'II write you another check right now!
What? Do I Iook Iike
I was born yesterday?
Look, it's midnight.
Where am I going to go?
You're a goddamn kid. Go home.
(BABY CRYING)
I hope you understand. My boss
sent me to BrookIyn, then Queens.
Now he wants me in Long IsIand
to take a few cIients out
for a night on the town.
I'm sorry, but we're not aIIowed
to cash checks from other banks.
-How wouId we know if they were good?
-What did you say your name was?
-AshIey.
You know what I found
on the sidewaIk out there?
Must have sIipped right off your neck.
Is there something
I can heIp you with, son?
It's my grandmother's birthday
next week
and I want to get her something
extra speciaI.
PIease, it's my midterm next week
and my books were stoIen.
(COUGHING)
PIease, just $5.
No one wouId have to know.
I'm sorry,
but we are not aIIowed to take checks
from peopIe we don't know.
MAN: WeIcome to New York.
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
PIeasure to have you back, Captain.
What do you think, AngeIo?
The tomatoes are ripe this afternoon.
What have we here?
-Can I have your autograph?
-You betcha.
-Can I have your autograph, too?
-You gonna be a piIot?
Mmm-hmm.
There you go. Work hard in schooI.
FRANK: DearDad,
l've decided to become an airline pilot.
l've applied to all the big airlines,
and l have several promising interviews
lined up.
How is Mom?
Have you called her lately?
Love, your son, Frank.
HeIIo.
I'm Frank BIack
from Murrow High SchooI,
and I have an appointment
with Mr. Morgan.
You're the young man who's writing
the articIe for the schooI paper.
Yes, ma'am. That's me.
I want to know everything there is
to know about being a piIot.
What airports does Pan Am fIy to?
What does a piIot make in a year?
Who teIIs them where they're gonna
fIy to?
-SIow down. Take them one at a time.
-AII right.
What does it mean when
one piIot says to another piIot,
"What kind of equipment are you on?"
They want to know what aircraft
you're fIying. DC-8, 707, ConsteIIation...
And what about those I.D. badges
that I've seen piIots wear?
Every piIot must have two things
with him at aII times.
One is his airIine personneI badge,
Iooks just Iike this one from Pan Am.
The other one is their FAA Iicense.
And that Iooks just Iike this.
Oh...
Do you think I couId make a copy
of this to put into my articIe?
Frank, you can have that one,
it's three years expired.
Thanks. And what about
your I.D. badge?
Do you have an extra one
I couId borrow?
No, I can't heIp you there.
Those are speciaI-ordered
from PoIaroid.
The onIy way to get one
is to become a reaI Iive piIot
for Pan American Airways.
WOMAN ON PHONE:
Pan Am, may l help you?
FRANK: (IN SOUTHERN ACCENT)
Yeah. HeIIo, I'm caIIing about a uniform.
-Hold for Purchasing.
-Thank you.
WOMAN 2: Purchasing.
I'm a copiIot based out of
San Francisco.
I fIew a fIight into New York Iast night,
but the probIem is I'm headed out
to Paris in three hours.
How can we help you?
I sent my uniform to be cIeaned
through the hoteI
and I guess they must have Iost it.
They lost a uniform.
Happens all the time.
Go down to the Well-Built Uniform
Company at 9th and Broadway.
They're our uniform supplier.
l'll tell Mr. Rosen you're coming.
MAN: You Iook too young to be a piIot.
I'm a copiIot.
Why so nervous?
How wouId you feeI if you Iost
your uniform first week on the job?
(LAUGHS) ReIax.
Pan Am has got Iots of uniforms.
It's gonna be $1 64.
Great. I'II write you a check.
Sorry, no checks, no cash.
You'II have to fiII in
your empIoyee I.D. number.
I'II biII Pan Am, and they'II take it out
of your next paycheck.
Even better.
FRANK: DearDad,
you always told me
that an honest man has nothing to fear.
So l'm trying my best not to be afraid.
l'm sorry l ran away,
but you don't have to worry.
l'm gonna get it all back now, Daddy.
l promise. l'm gonna get it all back.
Are you a reaI Iive piIot?
I sure am, IittIe Iady. What's your name?
-CeIine.
-CeIine, it's a pIeasure to meet you.
It's a pIeasure to meet you, too.
That's 50, 70, 80, 90,
$1 00.
You have yourseIf a great time in Paris.
I aIways do.
Excuse me.
I'm John Modiger. I manage this branch.
I want to thank you for coming in
and using our institution.
It's a pIeasure to meet you, John.
I'II be back again.
Good.
Have you stayed with us before?
No, I've been primariIy based
on the West Coast.
Is it aII right if I write you a check
for the room?
-No probIem, sir.
-Great.
I was aIso wondering
if I couId write you a personaI check?
For airIine personneI,
we cash personaI checks up to $1 00.
PayroII checks we cash up to 300.
Did you say 300 for a payroII check?
(TYPING)
FRANK: DearDad,
l've decided to become a pilot
for Pan American Airways,
the most trusted name in the skies.
They've accepted me into their training
program and told me if l work hard,
l should earn my wings real soon.
Please get in touch with Joanna Carlton
from the 10th grade.
Tell her l'm sorry that l could not
take her to the junior prom.
Love, your son, Frank.
-HeIIo, how are you?
-Fine, thank you.
I have a payroII check I'd Iike to cash.
CertainIy.
Excuse me.
I'm sure you hear this aII the time,
but you have the most beautifuI eyes
I have ever seen.
Yeah, I do get that aII the time.
(CHUCKLES)
How wouId you Iike it?
I'm sorry, sir. We won't have any cash
untiI the banks open in an hour.
But I'm sure they can cash your check
at the airport.
The airport?
Who cashes checks at the airport?
The airIines.
They've aIways taken care of their own.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
-HeIIo.
-Hi. Are you deadheading?
What?
Are you my deadhead to Miami?
-Yes.
-(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, I'm the deadhead. Here you go.
You're a IittIe Iate,
but the jump seat is open.
It's been a whiIe since I've done this.
Which one is the jump seat again?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Have a nice fIight.
Are you my deadhead?
Frank, Captain OIiver.
John Larkin, the copiIot.
Fred TuIIey, fIight engineer.
Frank TayIor, Pan Am.
Thanks for giving me a Iift, boys.
Go ahead and take a seat, Frank.
We're about to push.
What kind of equipment you on, DC-8?
707.
You turning around on the redeye?
I'm jumping puddIes
for the next few months,
trying to earn my keep running
Ieap frogs for the weak and weary.
No shame in that. We aII did it.
-Have a seat.
-Thank you.
WouId you Iike a drink after takeoff?
MiIk?
PILOT: Eighty knots.
CO-PILOT: Check.
PILOT: V-one. Rotate.
V-two. Positive rate.
COPILOT: Gear up.
FRANK: DearDad,
today was graduation.
l am now a copilot,
earning $1 ,400 a month, plus benefits.
And the best part is,
they tell me my family can fly for free.
So tell Mom to pack her bags
and buy a new swimsuit
because l'm taking us all to Hawaii
for Christmas.
l love you, Dad. Aloha, Frank.
-HeIIo, deadhead.
-HeIIo.
Enjoying your free ride?
Marci,
did you drop this?
-Must have sIipped right off your neck.
-No.
No!
MARCI: Yes, yes, yes!
(MOANING)
(PANTING)
Why are you stopping?
I want to teII you something, Marci.
This is by far
the best date I have ever been on.
(GIGGLING)
WeIcome to Miami MutuaI Bank.
How may I heIp you?
My name is Frank TayIor.
I'm a copiIot for Pan Am.
I'd Iike to cash this check and then
I'd Iike to take you out for a steak dinner.
(EXCLAIMS IN SURPRISE)
LUCY: Then we feed the checks
into the MICR machine,
which uses speciaI ink to encode
the account numbers
on the bottom of the checks.
And where are these numbers?
-They're right here.
-Right there?
They're caIIed routing numbers.
So where do the checks get routed to?
I don't exactIy know.
Nobody ever asked me that before.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Our next item up for bid is aIso from
the Jersey CentraI Bank forecIosure.
This is a MICR encoder,
a machine used to encode bank checks.
Do I have an opening bid?
CARL: Our unknown subject
is a paperhanger
who started working on the East Coast.
In the Iast few weeks,
this unsub has developed
a new form of check fraud
l'm calling "The Float."
What he's doing is he's opening
checking accounts at various banks,
then changing the MICR ink routing
numbers at the bottom of those checks.
Next sIide, pIease. Next sIide, pIease.
The remote thing is broken.
You'II have to do it by hand.
Agent MuIIen, it shouId be
the square button by the side.
This carouseI doesn't work.
It's a bad carouseI.
-Thank you.
-Move it manuaIIy.
This is a map of the 1 2 banks
of the U.S. FederaI Reserve.
SIide.
MICR scanners at every bank
read these numbers
at the bottom of the check. SIide.
And then ship that check off
to its corresponding branch.
CarI, for those of us
who are unfamiIiar with bank fraud,
you mind teIIing us
what the heII you're taIking about?
The East Coast branches
are numbered 01 to 06.
The centraI branch is 07, 08,
so on and so forth.
You mean those numbers at the bottom
of a check actuaIIy mean something?
AII of this was in the report I fiIed
two days ago. If you change
a 02 to a 1 2, that means that check,
which was cashed in New York,
does not go
to the New York FederaI Branch,
but it is re-routed aII the way
to the San Francisco FederaI Branch.
The bank doesn't even know
the check has bounced for two weeks.
Which means our unsub
can stay in one pIace,
paper the same city over and over again
whiIe his checks circIe the country.
You want to taIk to my wife.
She's the one who baIances
the checkbook at our house.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Next sIide.
(PIANO PLAYING)
(DINERS CHATTERING)
Daddy.
My son, the birdman.
That's some uniform, Frank.
What do you think?
Nice.
Sit down.
Dad, have you gotten the postcards?
Of course.
This fork is ice-coId.
No, Dad, that's a chiIIed saIad fork.
It's a fancy restaurant, you know.
Here.
-I got you something.
-What's that?
Open it.
You know what those are, right?
Those are the keys
to a 1 965 CadiIIac DeViIIe convertibIe.
Brand-new, Dad.
Red with white interior,
spIit seats, air conditioning, the works.
Are you giving me a CadiIIac?
I'm giving you a CadiIIac.
Dad, she's parked downstairs.
When we're done eating Iunch, why
don't you drive on over to Mom's house,
pick her up, take a IittIe joy ride?
Do you know what wouId happen
if the IRS found out I was driving around
in a new coupe?
I took the train here, Frank.
I'm taking the train home.
AII right.
I have pIenty of money.
You know, if you ever need anything.
You worried? About me?
No, I'm not worried.
You think I can't buy my own car?
Two mice feII in a bucket
of cream, Frank.
Which one am I?
You're that second mouse.
I went by the store today.
I had to cIose the store for a whiIe.
It's aII about timing, Frank.
Goddamn government knows that.
They hit you when you're down.
I wasn't going to Iet them take it
from me, so I just
shut the doors myseIf, caIIed their bIuff.
Sooner or Iater, they'II forget about me.
I understand.
Have you toId Ma?
She's so stubborn, your mother.
Don't worry, I'm not going to Iet her go
without a fight.
I'm fighting for us...
Dad?
...since the day we met.
Daddy, out of aII those men,
you were the one that took her home,
remember that?
Two hundred men
sitting in that tiny sociaI haII,
watching her dance.
-What was the name of that town?
-Montrichard, Dad.
I didn't speak a word of French,
and six weeks Iater, she was my wife.
She is your wife.
My son bought me a CadiIIac today.
I think that caIIs for a toast.
(CLEARS THROAT)
To the best damn piIot in the sky.
It's not what you think. I'm just a copiIot.
You see these peopIe staring at you?
These are the most powerfuI peopIe
in New York City.
They keep peeking over their shouIders,
wondering where you're going tonight.
Where you going, Frank?
Dad, nobody's staring at me.
Some pIace exotic?
Just teII me where you're going.
Los... HoIIywood.
HoIIywood?
Come here.
(WHISPERS) The rest of us
reaIIy are suckers.
So I got on this red dress
and these high heeIs, right?
I got a bra out here.
I'm chasing two Puerto Rican guys
through the park.
They got a suitcase
fiIIed with bank robbery Ioot.
Okay, I'm screaming out,
"F.B.I., freeze!"
I'm reaching for my gun,
but I can't find it in the bra.
It's so damn big,
I thought I was going to shoot my tits off.
(LAUGHING)
That's a funny story.
PeopIe aIways Iaugh at that story.
Let me ask you a question,
Mr. Amdursky.
If you had so much fun undercover,
why did you transfer to bank fraud?
I didn't transfer.
I was censured and reassigned.
It's Iike being punished. I was punished.
I screwed up in the fieId.
What about you, Mr. Fox, were you
punished for screwing up in the fieId?
No, I've never worked in the fieId before.
I audited background investigations
of Department of Justice
cIericaI appIicants.
That's just great. I ask for a team
and they drag the bottom of the Pacific.
Mind if I ask you a question,
Agent Hanratty?
How come you're so serious
aII the time?
Does it bother you, Mr. Amdursky?
Yeah, it does bother me.
Does it bother you, Mr. Fox?
A IittIe, I guess.
WouId you Iike to hear me teII a joke?
Yeah, we'd Iove to hear a joke from you.
Knock, knock.
Who's there?
Go fuck yourseIves.
(GlRL FROM lPANEMA PLAYING)
CLERK: He cashed three checks.
They aII cIeared.
I was going to deposit this one today.
I don't want any troubIe.
No troubIe.
No troubIe at aII.
We'II just take this check
and be on our way. Thank you.
Because I don't want
my customers harassed.
What are you saying? He's stiII here?
201 .
Thank you.
-Corner here.
-Thanks, son.
-Some steps.
-Steps.
Mr. Murphy, how are you?
-Is that Frank?
-Yeah, it's Frank.
-Hey, Frank. How are you?
-How's the knee?
Come on, I'II race you right now.
-Take care.
-Okay, Frank.
EyebaII the back? Come on, CarI.
This guy's a pen-and-ink man,
a goddamn paperhanger.
Why can't we go with you, CarI?
Keep your eyes open, do yourjob
and I'II buy you both a Good Humor bar.
(GASPING)
It's aII right, ma'am. F.B.I.
201 .
F.B.I. !
(TOILET FLUSHING)
F.B.I.
Come out of the bathroom!
Step out of the bathroom!
-Hands on your head.
-That's the new IBM SeIectric...
-Put your hands on your head!
-...print type in five seconds...
Shut up!
Put your hands on your head!
He's got over 200 checks,
a gaIIon of India ink, drafting...
Even has IittIe payroII enveIopes
addressed to himseIf...
-Put it down! Drop it!
-ReIax!
You're Iate, aII right?
My name's Barry AIIen,
United States Secret Service.
Your boy just tried
to jump out the window.
-My partner has him in custody.
-I don't know what you're taIking about.
You think the F.B.I.
are the onIy ones on this guy? Come on.
He's dabbIing in government checks.
We've been foIIowing a paper traiI
on this guy for months now.
You mind taking that gun
out of my face?
PIease. ReaIIy. It makes me nervous.
Let me see some credentiaIs.
Yeah, sure.
Take my whoIe waIIet.
You want my gun, too?
Come over here, take my gun.
Hey. Hey, Iook.
Just do me a favor, take a Iook outside.
Look out the window.
My partner's waIking him to the car
as we speak. Look.
OId guy aImost pissed in his pants
when I came through the door.
He jumped right through the window
onto the hood of my car.
Murph?
CaII the LAPD. I don't want
peopIe waIking through my crime scene.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I didn't expect
the Secret Service on this.
Don't worry about it. (CLEARS THROAT)
What's your name?
Hanratty, CarI Hanratty.
Mind if I see some identification?
You never can be
too carefuI these days.
WeII, tough Iuck, CarI.
Five minutes earIier, you wouId've
Ianded yourseIf a pretty good coIIar.
Is that right? Ten seconds Iater,
you'd have been shot.
Mind if I come downstairs with you?
I got to take a Iook at this guy.
Sure thing. Just do me a favor
and sit tight for a sec
whiIe I get this evidence downstairs.
I don't want some maid waIking
through here and making the bed.
-LAPD shouId be here any sec.
-Wait.
Your waIIet.
You hang onto it for a minute.
I trust you.
(SIGHS)
(EXHALING)
(CHUCKLES)
Secret Service.
Hey!
God damn it!
It was stupid. I made a stupid mistake.
Forget about it.
There are hundreds
of unknown subjects out there.
I can get this guy. The worst thing
a paperhanger can do is show his face.
I read the report.
Six feet taII, brown hair,
27 to 30 years of age, 1 60 pounds.
This couId be aImost anybody.
I heard his voice. I saw his face.
There's nothing for him
to hide behind anymore.
Just be carefuI.
You got 1 2 years in.
Nobody bothers you down
on the first fIoor.
You practicaIIy wrote
the book on bank fraud.
That's the kind of thing that can
make you section chief someday.
Just don't put yourseIf
in this type of position.
What type of position?
The position of being humiIiated.
Sean, wouId you Iike to hear me
teII a joke?
Yeah. Sure.
Knock, knock.
FRANK: My next question is,
when a piIot retires,
Pan Am sends them a check
every singIe month?
Yeah, pension program
sends a check and benefits.
How much is that check for?
Kid, I'm reaIIy not in the mood
for this right now.
This Skywayman's driving me crazy.
Who's the Skywayman?
Some nut fIying around the country,
posing as a Pan Am piIot.
There's a coIumn about him
in the paper today.
I keep teIIing them it's not my probIem.
This guy doesn't even fIy Pan Am.
FIies everybody eIse.
FIies United, TWA,
ContinentaI, Eastern.
The Skywayman.
Newspaper Ioves this cIown.
They caII him the James Bond
of the sky.
Did you say...
Bond, James Bond.
(JAMES BOND THEME PLAYING)
BOND: Tell me, Joan,
why does he do it?
JOAN: He likes to win.
PUSSY GALORE:
We'll be landing in 20 minutes.
Do you want to play it easy,
or the hard way?
And this isn't a tranquilizer.
Pussy, you know a lot more
about planes than guns.
(IMITATING BOND) HeIIo, Pussy.
You're sure this is the suit, right?
Positive.
It's the exact suit he wore in the movie.
Okay. I'II take three.
CertainIy, Mr. FIeming.
Now aII you need is one of those
IittIe foreign sports cars that he drives.
(JAMES BOND THEME
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(THE LOOK OF LOVE PLAYING)
-HeIIo.
-Hi.
Haven't I seen you before?
Maybe.
A coupIe of years ago,
I was on the cover of Seventeen.
You're that modeI, right? CheryI.
Guys used to put your picture
on their Iockers.
Isn't that your siIver car
I saw parked out front?
Yeah. One of them.
So, think I couId get an autograph?
Do you have a pen in your room?
Shh.
A man Iike you can buy
anything he wants.
He buys a deck of cards
at the hoteI gift shop.
You want to see a card trick?
How much did these cards cost?
I don't know, 55 cents, I think.
And if they soId me downstairs
at the hoteI gift shop,
how much wouId you pay?
I'm sorry, how much wouId
I pay for what?
The entire night.
How much wouId you pay me
for the entire night?
CheryI, I reaIIy don't know.
Don't be scared.
Make me an offer.
300?
Go fish.
$500?
600.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Go fish!
$1 ,000.
Okay.
I'II be right back.
Wait a second, where are you going?
I'm going downstairs to cash a check.
You think this hoteI is going to cash
a $1 ,000 check at 3:00 a.m.?
It's a New York Savings and Loan
check. It's Iike goId. They'II cash it.
Don't you think they might get
a IittIe suspicious? Let me see that.
It's a cashier's check.
Endorse it over to me.
I couIdn't do that.
This check is for 1 ,400.
We agreed upon 1 ,000.
Why don't I give you back 400
and you give me that check?
Even better.
Does this beIong to anybody?
(MELE KALlKlMAKA PLAYING)
(PHONE RINGING)
This is Hanratty. Merry Christmas.
FRANK: Hello, Carl.
HeIIo.
Barry AIIen, Secret Service.
l've been trying to track you down now
for the last couple of hours.
What do you want?
I wanted to apoIogize
for what happened out in Los AngeIes.
Uh-uh. Uh-uh.
No, you don't apologize to me.
Do you aIways work
on Christmas Eve, CarI?
I voIunteered
so the men with famiIies
couId go home earIy.
Looked Iike you were wearing
a wedding ring out in Los AngeIes.
I thought maybe you had a famiIy.
No. No famiIy.
You want to taIk to me?
Let's taIk face to face.
AII right.
I'm at my suite
at the Stuyvesant Arms, room 31 1 3.
ln the morning, l leave for Las Vegas
for the weekend.
You think you're going to get me again?
You're not going to Vegas,
you're not in the Stuyvesant Arms.
You'd Iove for me to send out 20 agents,
Christmas Eve, barge into your hoteI,
knock down the door
so you can make fooIs out of us aII.
I'm reaIIy sorry if I made a fooI
out of you. I reaIIy am.
Uh-uh. No.
No. You do not feeI sorry for me.
The truth is, I knew it was you.
I didn't get the cuffs on you, but I knew.
PeopIe onIy know
what you teII them, CarI.
Then teII me this,
Barry AIIen, Secret Service.
How did you know
I wouIdn't Iook in your waIIet?
The same reason
the Yankees always win.
Nobody can keep their eyes
off the pinstripes.
The Yankees win
because they have Mickey MantIe.
No one ever bets on the uniform.
(SCOFFS) You sure about that, Carl?
I'II teII you what I am sure of.
You're going to get caught.
One way or another,
it's a mathematicaI fact. It's Iike Vegas.
The house always wins.
WeII, CarI, I'm sorry, but I have to go.
You didn't caII just to apoIogize,
did you? (CHUCKLING)
What do you mean?
You have no one eIse to caII.
(LAUGHING)
Whoa!
(TURNS UP MUSIC)
(SINGING)
(HE'S SO FlNE PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
More coffee, sir?
-Are you a coIIector?
-Of what?
Captives of the Cosmic Ray,
The Big Freeze,
Land of the Golden Giants.
-I've got them aII.
-What are you taIking about?
Barry AIIen.
The FIash.
Wait, kid.
You mean, Iike the comic book?
Yeah, the comic book. When he's not
The FIash, that's his name, Barry AIIen.
Thank you.
Now get this, he reads comic books!
Comic books! Barry AIIen is The FIash!
FOX: CarI, sIow down. I don't know
what the hell you're talking about.
He's a kid. Our unsub is a kid.
That's why we couIdn't match his prints,
that's why he doesn't have a record.
I want you to contact NYPD for every
aII-points juveniIe runaways
in New York City.
Don't forget the airports. He's been
kiting checks aII over the country.
-Why New York?
-The Yankees!
He said something about the Yankees!
CARL: Where are we on the Iist?
FOX: Number 53, AbagnaIe.
Good morning, ma'am,
we're the F.B.I. agents who caIIed.
Yes, I've been waiting.
I hope you're aII hungry.
I put out the Sara Lee.
My husband, Jack, is a Iawyer.
What about your first husband,
Mrs. AbagnaIe?
AbagnaIe. But I prefer
to be caIIed Barnes.
"Frank WiIIiam AbagnaIe."
It says he was in the service.
Did you two meet during the war?
Yeah, I Iived in a very smaII viIIage
in France, Montrichard.
The kind of pIace
where they never heard of Sara Lee.
HeIp yourseIves.
Nobody doesn't Iike Sara Lee.
You fiIIed out a missing person's report
for a runaway juveniIe by the name of
Frank AbagnaIe, Jr.
Is Frankie okay?
You're aware of the fact that
he wrote some checks
on a cIosed account
at Chase Manhattan Bank?
Yes. The poIice think
he's some type of criminaI.
What he did was a feIony, Mrs. Barnes.
(SCOFFS) It was $1 ,000.
HaIf the kids his age are on dope,
throwing rocks at poIice.
And they scared me to death
because my son made a IittIe mistake.
A 1 7-year-oId boy has to eat,
has to have a pIace to sIeep.
We understand, ma'am.
WouId you happen to have a picture
of your son?
Yes, I have his oId yearbook.
Okay.
We need to send out
an aII-office teIetype.
Our unsub's name
is Frank AbagnaIe, Jr., age 1 7!
Is Frankie okay? Is he in troubIe?
Ma'am, I'm sorry to have to teII you,
your son is forging checks.
Forging checks? Wait!
I'm sure we can take care of that.
I'm working part-time at the church now.
Just teII me how much he owes
and I'II pay you back.
So far, it's about $1 .3 miIIion.
-(YOU REALLY GOT ME PLAYING)
-(TIMER DINGING)
Hi, MeIanie, how are you?
When you're in the house,
pIease use an ashtray.
Frank, this fondue is so good!
-Great. Take this.
-Good, I Iove Moët!
(MUSIC DISTORTING)
James, pIease! Stay away
from the hi-fi system, aII right?
It's a reeI-to-reeI,
you can't wind it Iike that.
Christ, Terry! This is ItaIian knit!
-Watch where you're going!
-It's just a shirt, man!
Frank! Come quick!
Lance just feII into the conversation pit!
Excuse me,
you know where Lance AppIebaum is?
Thank you.
DOCTOR: These bottIes need to be
IabeIed when you pick them up!
Do you understand
how dangerous this is? Do you?
Don't stand there crying. Nod your head.
TeII me you won't do it again.
-Now dry up and get back to work.
-(SOBBING)
You okay?
He toId me to pick up the bIood, so I did.
But he never toId me to IabeI it.
It's okay, stop crying.
What's your name?
Brenda.
Brenda, I wouIdn't worry about it.
These doctors don't know everything.
It's my first week.
I think they're going to fire me.
No, nobody's going to fire you, Brenda.
I bet you're good at yourjob.
No, I'm not.
I bet if I asked you to check
on the status
of my friend Lance AppIebaum,
you couId do that for me in a second.
Mr. AppIebaum fractured his ankIe.
Dr. AshIand is treating him
in exam room seven.
You see that? No probIem.
This is the emergency chart.
See that bIue star? That means
the patient has been diagnosed.
And then after he's been treated,
we put a red circIe here. See?
How do you Iike those braces?
I guess they're aII right.
I got mine off Iast year.
Boy, I hated them. They were bottoms.
I stiII got to wear my mouth guard.
You have reaIIy nice teeth.
WeII, thank you.
And you have a pretty smiIe.
(GIGGLES)
No, I mean it. I reaIIy think
those braces Iook good on you.
Thank you.
You're weIcome.
Brenda.
Yeah.
Do you know if they're hiring here
at the hospitaI?
I'm not sure. What do you want to do?
I'm a doctor.
FRANK: DearDad,
l decided to get off the road for a while.
l've taken a night job at a hospital
and met some really nice people.
Feels good to have
my feet on the ground,
to wake up in the same bed every night.
Who knows, maybe l'll even find
someone to settle down with.
"Harvard MedicaI SchooI."
Top of your cIass.
"Southern CaIifornia
ChiIdren's HospitaI."
That is a pretty impressive résumé,
Dr. Conners.
UnfortunateIy,
the onIy thing I need is
Someone to babysit
six interns and 20 nurses.
But...
HeII, I doubt that you'd be interested
in that.
In the past, they've aIways
Iet me choose my own nurses.
FRANK: Dr. ConneIIy.
-Dr. Harris.
-Present.
Dr. AshIand.
Dr. Conners?
You gonna take roII every night?
Yes, I wiII, Dr. AshIand.
And if you're going to be Iate,
I suggest you bring a note.
(SNIGGERING)
Miss Basmann.
Miss Mace.
Miss Strong.
Here.
Nurse Brown.
Nurse Sanford.
MAN ON TV: Thirty milligrams
of codeine every four hours.
Run the plasma at 60 drops a minute
till we calculate the fluid requirements.
What do you estimate the degree
and extent of the burns, KiIdare?
Second and third-degree burns
over about 20% of the body surface.
-Do you concur?
-l concur. Let's get him up to Pediatrics.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
HeIIo, Brenda.
Hi, Dr. Conners.
-You need to sign these.
-Thank you.
Do you notice anything different
about me?
You got your braces off! Come here.
I've been trying to show you aII night!
Wow.
Good job.
Did it hurt when they took them off?
Mine feIt so weird after.
I keep rubbing my tongue over them.
I can't stop!
They're so sIippery.
-It feeIs good, doesn't it?
-Yeah, it feeIs incredibIe.
Oh, my!
I'm sorry.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(MOANING)
WOMAN ON PA: Dr. Conners to the E.R.
Dr. Conners to the E.R.
ShouIdn't you go?
No. They have a staff doctor
in the emergency ward, we'II be fine.
(PANTING) What if he's in surgery?
Do you reaIIy think I have to go?
In here, Dr. Conners.
(BOY CRYING OUT IN PAIN)
GentIemen, what seems
to be the probIem?
BicycIe accident. A fractured tibia
about five inches beIow the pateIIa.
Hmm.
Dr. Harris.
Do you concur?
Concur with what, sir?
With what Dr. AshIand just said.
Do you concur?
WeII, it was a bicycIe accident.
The boy toId us.
So you concur?
We shouId take an X-ray, stitch him up
and put him in a waIking cast.
Very good, Dr. AshIand. Very good.
WeII, you don't seem
to have much need for me.
Carry on.
I bIew it, didn't I?
Why didn't I concur?
(VOMITING)
FRANK, SR.: Make yourseIf at home!
Frank AbagnaIe, Sr.
You're not a cop.
SpeciaI Agent Hanratty, F.B.I.
My IandIord said you were not a cop.
If you're going to arrest me,
I'd Iike to put on a different suit.
-If that's okay...
-I'm not here to arrest you.
I'm Iooking for your son. He's in troubIe.
Do you know where he is?
If I teII you where he is,
wiII you promise not to teII his mother?
Sure.
Frank made up a fake I.D.
and enIisted in the Marine Corps.
He's over in Vietnam right now.
That kid is haIfway around the worId,
crawIing through the damn jungIe,
fighting the communists, so...
PIease, don't come to my home
and caII my boy a criminaI...
I never said he was a criminaI,
Mr. AbagnaIe. I said he was in troubIe.
If you'd Iike to give me a caII and taIk,
here's my number.
You're not a father, are you?
Pardon me?
If you were a father, you'd know.
I wouId never give up my son.
Yes, sir. I understand.
Sean, now get this.
"Riverbend Apartments, 41 5 Landover,
AtIanta, Georgia."
AtIanta, Georgia.
I'm on my way to the airport. I'II meet
the team in four hours. Bye-bye!
-Come on, it's okay.
-(BRENDA SOBBING)
You don't have to cry.
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry, Frank!
I can't do this.
Brenda, Iisten to me.
I don't care if you're a virgin, aII right?
ReaIIy, I can wait.
I'm not a virgin.
I had an abortion two years ago.
My parents had a friend do it.
A man that my father pIays goIf with.
And when I got better,
they kicked me out of the house.
(SOBBING) I had an abortion
and I wasn't their daughter anymore!
I'm so sorry. PIease don't be mad at me.
No, no.
-PIease don't be mad at me.
-Shh.
What if I spoke to your parents?
Maybe I can straighten things out.
I ask them aII the time,
but they said I stiII can't come home.
And my daddy's a Iawyer.
Brenda?
What if you were engaged to a doctor?
WouId that change anything?
What?
What if I went to your parents,
and I spoke to your father
and I asked permission to marry you?
-It's empty.
-Nobody here.
(SIGHS)
Dr. Conners, are you Lutheran?
Yes, I am a Lutheran.
But pIease, caII me Frank.
Frank, wouId you Iike to say grace?
UnIess you're not comfortabIe.
AbsoIuteIy.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Two IittIe mice feII
into a bucket of cream.
The first mouse
quickIy gave up and drowned,
but the second mouse struggIed so hard
that he eventuaIIy churned
that cream into butter,
and he waIked out.
Amen.
That was beautifuI.
The mouse churned
that cream into butter.
That's right.
Thank you.
Frank, have you decided which hospitaI
you want to work at in New OrIeans?
To be quite honest,
I'm thinking about getting back into Iaw.
Oh, my! Are you a doctor or a Iawyer?
Before I went to medicaI schooI,
I passed the bar in CaIifornia.
I practiced Iaw for one year,
then I decided,
why not try my hand at pediatrics?
(LAUGHS)
You're just fuII of surprises.
Yeah.
A doctor and a Iawyer.
Brenda hit the jackpot.
Where did you go to Iaw schooI?
BerkeIey.
(BOTH GASPING)
Oh, my gosh.
Isn't that where you went, Daddy?
Maybe Frank couId come
work for you, Roger.
You're aIways saying how hard it is
to find assistant prosecutors.
CouId he, Daddy? CouId he, pIease?
CouId he come work with you, pIease?
Was that snake HoIIingsworth
stiII teaching there
when you went through BerkeIey?
HoIIingsworth.
Yes. Grumpy oId HoIIingsworth, right?
Meaner than ever.
And that dog of his?
TeII me, Frank,
what was the name of his IittIe dog?
I'm sorry.
The dog was dead.
WOMEN: Oh.
How unfortunate.
Yeah.
A doctor, a Iawyer, a Lutheran.
So, what are you, Frank?
'Cause I think you're about to ask
for my daughter's hand in marriage,
and I have a right to know.
Know what, sir?
The truth.
TeII me the truth, Frank.
What are you doing here?
What is a man Iike you
doing with Brenda?
If you want my bIessing,
if you want my daughter,
I'd Iike to hear it from you now.
The truth is, sir...
The truth is that...
I'm not a doctor, I'm not a Iawyer.
I'm not an airIine piIot.
I'm nothing, reaIIy.
I'm just a kid
who's in Iove with your daughter.
No.
You know what you are?
You're a romantic.
Men Iike us are nothing
without the women we Iove.
I must confess,
I'm guiIty of the same fooIish whimsy.
I proposed to CaroI after five dates
with two nickeIs in my pockets
and hoIes in my shoes
because I knew she was the one.
So go ahead, Frank.
Don't be afraid.
Ask the question you came here
to ask me.
What wouId I have to do to take the bar
here in New OrIeans?
(LAUGHING)
No, the other question.
WOMAN: Right through that door.
Good Iuck, Mr. Conners.
Thank you.
Hey, Frank.
You know what I couId never figure out?
How did you cheat on the bar exam
in Louisiana?
What's the difference?
-Someone took the test for you?
-I'm going to prison for a Iong time.
SeriousIy, what's the difference?
It's a simpIe question.
Are you going to eat that écIair?
Yeah. I'm saving it for Iater.
Or you want to spIit it with me?
No.
Give me haIf that écIair and I'II teII you.
I'm gonna figure it out sooner or Iater.
You'II be working under PhiIIip Rigby
in corporate Iaw.
Why don't you settIe in,
organize your desk?
We're having Iunch at 1 2:30
with the Attorney GeneraI
and Governor McKeithen himseIf.
A governor!
Did we speII it right?
You sure did.
CongratuIations.
-Thank you, sir.
-WeIcome aboard.
Look at this photograph, Mr. Stewart.
lt's a photograph of Prentice York,
where they found him, dead.
Here is an enlargement
of part of that photograph.
This is a photograph of the defendant's
signature on a canceIed check.
Here is an enIargement of that
same signature, which matches
the signature on the Ietters
that he wrote to Mrs. Simon,
which discuss the possibiIity of
defrauding the great state of Louisiana.
Your Honor,
Iadies and gentIemen of the jury,
this is irrefutabIe evidence
that the defendant is, in fact, Iying.
Mr. Conners,
this is a preIiminary hearing.
There is no defendant.
There is no jury.
It's just me.
Son,
what in the heII is wrong with you?
Is that Mitch? Roger!
It's Mitch!
I Iost aII track of time.
MITCH MILLER: As studio guests
for the sing-along tonight,
we have the children's choir
of Saint Monica's Church
in New York City.
Won't you join them and the gang
in a few songs for the lrish? Everybody!
(CHOIR SINGING
HAS ANYBODY HERE SEEN KELLY?)
(SINGING ALONG)
(EMBRACEABLE YOU PLAYING)
Dad?
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
What are you doing dressed Iike this?
I took a government job.
You see what I'm doing?
Do you have a good Iawyer?
I sort of am a Iawyer now.
Look at this Ietter. The IRS wants more.
I had a deaI with them. Two penaIties.
They ate the cake,
now they want the crumbs.
I want to sue them.
Now they want the crumbs.
Sit down.
They're trying to scare me,
intimidate me. You know what?
You know what?
I'II make them chase me
for the rest of their Iives!
It's great to see you, Daddy.
Sit down, I want to show you something.
I came here to give you this.
It's an invitation to an engagement party.
Daddy, I'm getting married.
Can you beIieve that
I'm getting married?
You don't need to worry
about anything now, Dad. Listen.
I'm getting a brand-new CadiIIac,
I'm getting a $60,000 house,
I'm getting it aII back.
AII the jeweIry, the furs, everything
they took from us, I'II get it back.
Has Ma seen you dressed Iike this?
Yeah, she came to pick up some boxes.
That's okay. You know why?
Because she's going to the wedding
with us.
I'm gonna get you
a brand-new suit, Dad.
One of those Manhattan EagIe,
three-button bIack pearI suits.
You'II Iook great.
Those are nice. She won't see me.
Have you tried to caII her?
Why don't you caII her right now?
Dad, just caII her.
CaII her for me.
TeII her I have two first-cIass tickets
to go see her son's wedding...
You mother's married now
to my friend, Jack Barnes.
They have a house in Long IsIand.
I had an F.B.I. agent come see me.
You got their number, son.
The guy Iooked scared.
The United States Government, champ,
running for the hiIIs.
Pow! To the moon!
Dad.
It's over.
I'm going to stop now.
They're never gonna catch you, Frank.
She wouIdn't do that!
Why wouId she do that to you?
Come on. Sit with me. Have a drink.
I'm your father.
Then ask me to stop.
You can't stop.
Where are you going?
Come on, Frank, where are you going?
Where are you going tonight?
SomepIace exotic?
Tahiti? Hawaii?
(PHONE RINGING)
This is Hanratty.
FRANK: Hello, Carl.
Merry Christmas.
How are you, Dr. Conners?
CarI, I haven't been Dr. Conners
for months now.
(CARL CLEARS THROAT)
WeII,
I'm sitting here in my office
on Christmas Eve.
What do you want?
(SIGHS)
Okay.
I want it to be over.
I want it to be over. I'm getting married.
I'm settIing down.
You've stoIen aImost $4 miIIion.
You think we couId caII it
a wedding present?
This isn't something
you get to waIk away from, Frank.
-I want to caII a truce.
-No truce.
You wiII be caught, you wiII go to prison.
Where did you think this was going?
PIease Ieave me aIone, CarI.
PIease?
I'm getting cIose, aren't I?
You're scared because
I'm getting cIose. I know
you rented a car in Shreveport,
stayed in a hoteI on Lake CharIes.
You want to run, be my guest.
Your checks don't Iie as weII as you do.
Stop chasing me.
I can't stop.
It's my job.
lt's okay, Carl.
I just thought I'd ask.
Hey.
Merry Christmas.
(HANGS UP)
I Iove my job.
AII right.
Let's get every newspaper in Louisiana
for the Iast two months.
What're we Iooking for?
Engagement announcements.
Name of Conners.
Come on, the kid
wouId have changed his name by now.
Uh-uh. He can't change it.
She thinks he's Conners.
If he Ioses the name, he Ioses the girI.
(l CAN'T GlVE YOU
ANYTHlNG BUT LOVE PLAYING)
-CongratuIations!
-Having a good time?
Keep dancing.
Look who's here.
I'm going to the IittIe boys' room.
Hurry back.
(CAR APPROACHING)
Good evening.
I'm Agent Hanratty with the F.B.I.
We'd Iike to have a few kind words
with your host, if possibIe.
I'II get him.
Right over there, sir.
Good evening, gentIemen.
I'm Roger Strong.
CarI Hanratty, F.B.I.
These are Agents Amdursky and Fox.
-Sorry to crash your party, sir.
-Not at aII. What can I do for you?
If it's not too much troubIe,
I'd Iike to meet the groom.
Is there a probIem?
Frank! Can you hoId aII these?
They're checks.
They're from my dad's friends.
They're for us so
we can start our new Iife...
What are you doing? What's wrong?
We have to Ieave.
You Iove me, right?
I mean, you'd Iove me no matter what.
You'd Iove me whether I was sick
or poor, or if I had a different name.
Frank, where did you get
aII that money?
Brenda, Iisten. A name doesn't matter.
My name is Frank Conners.
That's who I am with you.
But we aII have secrets.
Sometimes when I traveI,
I use the name Frank TayIor.
That's my secret.
Frank TayIor, you know.
Frank BIack. It doesn't matter.
Why are you saying aII this?
Brenda, I don't want to Iie
to you anymore.
I'm not a doctor,
I never went to medicaI schooI.
I'm not a Iawyer, or a Harvard graduate
or a Lutheran.
I ran away from home
a year and a haIf ago when I was 1 6.
Frank.
You're not a Lutheran?
You see aII this money? I have more.
I have pIenty more.
I have enough money to Iast us
for the rest of our Iives. Look.
Frank, stop teasing me!
You're Frank Conners
and you're 28 years oId...
Why wouId you Iie to me?
-Brenda.
-(GASPS)
I want to know your name.
TeII me your name.
We can Iive anywhere we want.
But you have to trust me.
Do you trust me?
Do you Iove me, Brenda?
Yes. I Iove you.
Excuse me, Mother.
This is Mr. Hanratty. My wife, CaroI.
-Mister...
-Hanratty, ma'am.
Have you seen Frank or Brenda?
I think they went upstairs.
Come here.
In two days,
meet me at Miami InternationaI Airport.
Leave the house after your parents
go to sIeep. Take a taxicab.
Give the taxi driver this money.
TeII him to drive aII through the night.
You're gonna Ieave at 1 0:00 a.m.
1 0:00 a.m. AII right?
(VOCALIZING)
-Which room, sir?
-In the corner.
You have to Iisten. The InternationaI
TerminaI in Miami. Say it.
No matter what, take a taxicab,
be there at 1 0:00 a.m.
I'II be there at 1 0:00 a.m.
no matter what.
In two days. Two days, Brenda.
Two days.
In two days I'II be there,
no matter what, at 1 0:00 a.m.
We're not gonna teII anyone, Brenda.
You have to promise me now.
PIease! Before you go,
pIease teII me your name. TeII me.
Frank WiIIiam AbagnaIe, Jr.
(WEEPING)
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
(SIGHS)
Brenda.
AMDURSKY: This guy is a no-show.
CARL: Maybe he was tipped.
He's not here today, it'II be tomorrow.
We'II get him before
he Ieaves the country.
He doesn't have a passport.
For the Iast six months,
he's gone to Harvard and BerkeIey.
I'm betting he can get a passport.
Our men are waiting for him here
in Miami InternationaI.
He's used it before,
he knows the Iayout.
The Miami poIice offered us
50 uniformed cops in two shifts of 25.
With our guys,
that's aImost 1 00 men in one airport.
Don't you think we shouId
spread it around?
No, this is the exit point.
How do you know he hasn't rented a car
and driven to airports
in New York, AtIanta?
Because I'm not in New York.
I'm not in AtIanta.
Yes. This is Frank Roberts.
I'm Ietting aII the universities
in the area know
that Pan Am wiII be initiating
a new recruiting program this year.
I'II be stopping by
your campus tomorrow morning.
Thank you all very much for coming.
At the end of the day,
l'll be choosing eight young ladies
-to be a part of
-(GIRLS EXCLAIMING)
Pan Am's future stewardess
flight crew program.
These eight young ladies
will accompany me on
a two-month public relations tour
through Europe
where they will discover firsthand
what it takes
to be a Pan American stewardess.
(ALL CHEERING)
Give me at Ieast two men, no,
one man per every two counters.
Amdursky?
Make sure your uniforms are covering
the sidewaIks, entrances and exits.
Let's have periodic sweeps
of the men's Iav.
What quaIifies me
to be a future stewardess?
WeII, I think that I'm reaIIy friendIy
and I can reaIIy heIp out
and make peopIe feeI weIcome
on the pIane and...
We'II be traveIing
at 6,000 miIes per hour,
at an aItitude of 300 feet.
(SINGING) All my bags are packed
l'm ready to go
(PLAYING PIANO)
llene Anderson.
(LOUD CHEERS)
Miggy Acker.
Debra Jo McMillan.
Candy Heston.
(COME FLY WlTH ME PLAYING)
-Did you see that bIonde out front?
-I shouId have been a piIot.
ExactIy.
WOMAN ON PA: Mr. Hanratty,
pick up the courtesy telephone.
Hanratty.
AMDURSKY: Your walkie-talkie
wasn't working.
There's a guy in a Pan Am uniform
sitting in a white Coupe DeVille
in front of Terminal J.
That's the charter terminaI.
Did you get a Iook at his face?
He's got his pilot's cap on.
CarI, I think it's him.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Out of the car, Frank.
Frank?
Step out of the car.
Keep your hands where I can see them.
Don't shoot me. I'm just a driver.
A man paid me $1 00
to wear this uniform
-to pick someone up at the airport.
-Who're you picking up?
Hey!
CARL: South America, AustraIia,
Singapore, Egypt.
The kid's gone compIeteIy
out of controI.
-Why wasn't I caIIed?
-Nobody was caIIed, sir.
The banks didn't know
what was happening untiI Iast week.
That's impossibIe.
They didn't caII because it's not
counterfeiting. It's something eIse.
-What is he doing?
-He's making reaI checks, sir.
These are so perfect,
the airIine didn't know the difference.
Last check was cashed in Madrid
a week ago.
My guess is he's stiII there.
We've to Ieave now, sir. Today.
For where? Spain?
You want to go to Spain?
EventuaIIy, he's gotta go back
to where the checks were printed.
I think that's why he's moving back
through Europe.
Look at the map, sir.
He's making a circIe.
He's running out of checks.
It's a Iong shot, but if we couId track him
from Madrid, we couId stiII catch him.
I'm sorry, CarI. If you couIdn't catch him
here, you're not gonna catch him there.
We're going to Iet him get away.
No, CarI, you Iet him get away.
A perfect one-sixteenth
aII the way around.
CoIor separation is fIawIess.
There's no bIeeding.
Nobody does work Iike this
in the States.
Nobody but us.
Where was it printed?
-It was printed on a monster.
-A monster.
-A HeideIberg, an Istra.
-HeideIberg.
A dinosaur, four coIors,
you can smeII the weight.
-Two tons, without the ink.
-(SNIFFS)
Where do they do printing Iike this?
Germany, Great Britain.
France.
France. Frank's mother said the name
of a viIIage in France,
where they didn't have Sara Lee.
The viIIage where
she met Frank's father.
I don't remember.
It started with an "M."
It was "Mont" something. Mr. Fox?
Yes. Question,
"You met your husband during the war?"
Answer, "I Iived in a very smaII viIIage
in France,
"the kind of pIace
where they never heard of Sara Lee."
TeII me you wrote down
the name of the viIIage, Mr. Fox.
Montrichard.
(CHOIR SINGING CHRISTMAS CAROL)
(PRINTING PRESS RUNNING)
(BELL RINGING)
CarI?
Merry Christmas!
How is it that we're aIways taIking
on Christmas?
Every Christmas, I'm taIking to you!
Put your shirt on, Frank.
You're under arrest.
Are you hungry?
Do you want some beans?
CarI, they got
the best French beans here.
There's two dozen
French poIice officers outside.
They wanted to bring you in,
but they needed the heIp
of an American.
But I toId them
I wouIdn't bring them to you,
unIess I couId put the cuffs
on you myseIf.
You have a gun? Do you have a gun?
No gun?
-No.
-No gun.
And you're teIIing me what?
(LAUGHS) There's two dozen
French poIice officers
out there right now on Christmas Eve?
-That's what you're teIIing me?
-Yeah.
AII right. There's no windows here.
I'm going to take a Iook
out the front door.
No!
I toId them I'd waIk out first
and give a signaI. Put these on yourseIf.
No, I can't do that! You know why?
(PANTING)
Because I think you're fuII of shit.
I don't think there's anyone eIse
out there.
I think it's just me and you. That's right.
It's just me and you,
and you know what?
You're gonna have to catch me yourseIf.
-We don't have time for this.
-That's good.
TeII me what you want me to see.
-I wouIdn't Iie to you.
-You're wearing a wedding ring.
You Iied to me about that!
Did you Iie about that?
You asked me if I had a famiIy.
I did. But I don't anymore.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yes. No, there is no probIem.
We're coming out right now.
(LAUGHING)
That was good.
Did you pay some hoteI desk cIerk
to make that caII for you?
Is that what you did?
It was Captain Luc.
I've got one minute to bring you out.
Captain Luc? Oh, Captain Luc! WeII,
that sounds pretty officiaI to me,
but, Iike I said,
I think it's just me and you here.
So you'II have to catch me.
Frank, you have to trust me on this.
These peopIe have been embarrassed.
They're angry.
You rob their banks, you steaI
their money, you Iive in their country.
I toId you this was
what was going to happen.
That there was no other way
for it to end.
Don't make a mistake.
That's good, CarI, you know?
Keep pushing that Iie. Keep pushing it.
-Keep pushing tiII you make it true.
-They'II kiII you.
You waIk out that door,
they're gonna kiII you.
(PANTING)
Is that the truth?
Yeah.
Do you have any chiIdren, CarI?
I have a 4-year-oId daughter.
Do you swear on your daughter?
You swear?
(CHOIR CONTINUES SINGING
CHRISTMAS CAROL)
That was reaIIy good, CarI.
(SIRENS WAILING)
I have him in custody.
(MAN SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
I got him! It's aII right.
It's aII right. I got him.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I want it on the record.
Frank AbagnaIe surrendered
of his own accord. Understood?
Where are you taking him?
I'm supposed to go.
Let me in the car!
Don't worry. I'II have you extradited back
to the United States.
CarI.
You have to remember
to Iet me caII my father when we Iand.
I want to taIk to him before he sees me
on teIevision or something Iike that.
CarI, Iook.
That's LaGuardia right there.
Runway 44.
Frank, your father is dead.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to say anything
untiI we got cIoser to home.
He feII down some steps
at Grand CentraI Station
trying to catch a train.
I didn't want to be the one to teII you.
You're Iying, right?
You said I couId taIk to him.
Who are you to say something Iike that?
-You said I couId taIk to him.
-He feII
and he broke his neck. I'm sorry.
I'm reaIIy sorry.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOBBING) God damn it!
I'm going to be sick.
It's aII right. It's okay.
-I'm going to be sick!
-Sure. Let's go to the bathroom.
God damn it!
(SOBBING)
(BANGING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Daddy.
You'II have to take your seat, sir.
I've toId you twice.
We're Ianding. AII of you.
Frank! Come on now.
We're Ianding in six minutes.
You need to be in your seats...
-Open the door!
-...with seat beIts fastened.
Frank!
You do it.
AII right,
remain seated everyone, pIease.
PIease remain seated.
God AImighty.
(THE CHRlSTMAS SONG PLAYING)
What's your name?
Where's your mommy?
OFFICER: Sarge, we're good.
HoId up!
Put your hands behind your head!
CarI.
Get me in the car, pIease.
Put him in.
JUDGE: Taking into account
the gravity of these crimes,
your history of bold
and elusive behavior
and your complete lack of respect
for the Iaws of the United States,
l have no choice but to ignore
your request to be treated as a minor,
and sentence you to 12 years
in Atlanta's maximum security prison
and recommend strongly
that you be kept in isolation
for the entirety of that sentence.
(SIGHS)
Merry Christmas, Frank.
I got you some comic books.
How's your daughter?
What was her name?
Grace.
I don't know. She Iives with her mother
in Chicago, I don't get to see her much.
What's in the briefcase?
I'm on my way to the airport.
It's a paperhanger
working his way through Minnesota.
(CHUCKLING)
Jesus. He's driving us crazy.
You got any of the checks?
Yeah, I got a counterfeit he drew
in Great Lakes Savings and Loan.
He's using a stenciI machine
and an Underwood.
It's a teIIer at the bank.
Say again?
It's definiteIy a teIIer, CarI.
Banks aIways use hand stamps
for the dates.
They get used over and over again,
so they aIways get worn out.
And the numbers are aIways cracking.
The sixes and the nines,
see, they go first.
Thanks.
(DOOR BUZZING)
MARSH: I'd Iike you to take a Iook
at something for me.
TeII me what you think.
That's a fake.
How do you know,
you haven't Iooked at it?
There's no perforated edge, right?
I mean, this check was hand-cut,
not fed.
Yeah.
Paper is doubIe-bonded,
much too heavy to be a bank check.
Magnetic ink, it's raised against
my fingers instead of fIat.
(SNIFFING)
And this doesn't smeII Iike MICR,
it's some kind of a drafting ink.
The kind you get at a stationery store.
Frank,
wouId you be interested in working
with the F.B.I.'s FinanciaI Crimes Unit?
I aIready got a job here, you know.
I deIiver the maiI.
Frank, we have the power
to take you out of prison.
You'II be pIaced in the custody
of the F.B.I. where you'd serve out
the remainder of your sentence
as an empIoyee
of the FederaI Government.
Under whose custody?
Hi.
I'm Frank AbagnaIe.
I'm supposed to start work here today.
It's a tour company
operating out of the BVI.
Sir, Mr. AbagnaIe is here.
I'm gonna caII you back.
-HeIIo, CarI.
-WeIcome to the F.B.I.
I'II show you where you're working.
How Iong do I have to work here?
It's 8:1 5 in the morning
to 5:00 in the afternoon,
45 minutes for Iunch.
No. I mean, how Iong?
Every day.
Every day, Frank, tiII we Iet you go.
Hey, CarI.
How are you doing?
It's not a good time, Frank.
I'm cIearing my desk for the weekend.
You mind
if I come to work with you tomorrow?
Tomorrow is Saturday.
I'm fIying to Chicago
to see my daughter.
I'II be back to work on Monday.
-You're going to see Grace?
-Yeah, that's the pIan.
What shouId I do tiII Monday?
I'm sorry, kid, I can't heIp you there.
Excuse me.
(PHONE RINGING)
This is Hanratty.
Yeah, put him on.
Mr. Sawyer.
How are you?
I have haIf a dozen more checks
on that tour operator at the BVI.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
How did you do it, Frank?
How did you pass the bar in Louisiana?
What are you doing here?
Listen.
I'm sorry I put you through aII this.
You go back to Europe,
you'II die in Perpignan Prison.
You try to run here in the States,
we'II send you back to AtIanta
for 50 years.
I know that.
I spent four years
trying to arrange your reIease.
I had to convince my bosses
at the F.B.I.
and the Attorney GeneraI
of the United States you wouIdn't run.
Why did you do it?
-You're just a kid.
-I'm not your kid.
You said you were going to Chicago.
My daughter can't see me this weekend.
She's going skiing.
You said she was four years oId.
You're Iying.
She was four when I Ieft. Now she's 1 5.
My wife has been remarried
for 1 1 years.
I see Grace every now and again.
-I don't understand.
-Sure you do.
Sometimes it's easier Iiving the Iie.
I'm gonna Iet you fIy tonight, Frank.
I won't even try to stop you, because
I know you'II be back on Monday.
Yeah.
-How do you know I'II come back?
-(CHUCKLES)
Look.
Frank.
Nobody is chasing you.
AIice, has he stiII not caIIed?
No, he hasn't.
CARL: Good morning.
I've caIIed this meeting to discuss
a new type of check fraud
and counterfeiting.
The unsub is washing
and aItering checks,
then passing them throughout Arizona.
This unsub is a big dog,
passing checks as Iarge as five figures.
(DOOR OPENING)
Sorry I'm Iate.
Sorry.
We have a recovered check
on Agent Reiter's desk.
Why don't we step out to the buIIpen?
There's impressions on every Iine.
Looks Iike the originaI amount
was for $60.
Mind if I take a Iook?
Cashed in FIagstaff a week ago.
Cost the bank $1 6,000.
-It's a reaI check.
-Yeah.
It's been washed.
The onIy thing originaI is the signature.
But it's perfect.
I mean, this isn't hydrochIoride
or bIeach.
No.
Something new.
A naiI poIish remover where the acetone
removes the ink that's not been printed?
How did you do it, Frank?
How did you cheat on the bar exam
in Louisiana?
I didn't cheat.
I studied for two weeks and I passed.
Is that the truth?
I'II bet this guy steaIs checks
out of maiIboxes.
He washes off their names
and puts on his own.
You're saying he's a IocaI?
If it were me, I'd caII the bank first.
Check out the baIance...
Make sure there's enough money
in there to make it worth your whiIe.
ExactIy.
You know, CarI, I think
this guy is pretty smart.
Guess aII we have to do now
is catch him.