Colossus - The Forbin Project
(The brain of steel)
Look here,
please.
Mr. President.
All systems are activated.
I hope
I've not kept waiting.
Congratulations, Dr. Forbin,
for your great work.
A car awaits us.
This stuff will put us in retirement,
but ... Congratulations, Dr. Forbin!
That will not happen.
Listen, he's the most relieved!
The Secretary of Defense
Secretary of State and myself,
have discussed how
to announce the news:
we are all agreed,
it will be simple and direct.
We will disclose
the greatest secret of history.
It only remains
to warn everyone.
"No Trespassing
Risk of death - Radiation "
My friends, citizens of the world,
for years, we lived
under the threat of a disaster
too horrible to contemplate.
It is an old saying:
"To err is human".
We can not accept it.
For years,
the U.S. has worked on this problem.
this was our best kept secret,
the great effort
and substantial funding.
But we managed.
As U.S. President
I can announce to the world
at 3 pm GMT,
defense of this country,
and beyond the free world,
was assigned to a machine.
A system called "Colossus".
The most advanced ever built,
able to study the information,
and, based on facts alone,
from deciding to launch an attack.
If it detects an imminent
assault,
Colossus will react immediately,
taking control of nuclear weapons.
It can select and execute
what seems most appropriate.
Its decisions are superior
those that could take a human.
His knowledge and analytical skills
surpass those of the greatest geniuses.
And, most important of all:
he has no emotions,
neither fear nor hatred nor desires.
He can not act
under the influence of feelings.
It does nothing
if there is no threat.
Here Dr. Charles Forbin,
the largest
world expert in computers
and somehow,
the father of Colossus.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Ladies and gentlemen, I will be brief.
The main memory and Calculators
located in the Rockies
the heart of the mountain,
in Colorado.
Overlooking the Pacific
California,
the Office of Programs Colossus
oversees all operations.
The computer center
houses 100,000 sensors and tools
Long-distance communication,
includes all modes
of transmittal,
microwave, laser, TV networks,
data transmission, satellite,
worldwide.
The whole system
is protected by powerful fields
electromagnetic
and other means of cons-measures.
Colossus works
without human intervention.
Its location is not secret,
nor do its functions.
He is totally vulnerable to attack,
Front or indirect,
and if one of them succeeded,
we would be defenseless.
However,
Colossus has its own defenses.
It is its own defense.
If attacked
against its sources of information
or power,
Colossus branch
on its uninterruptible power supply
which provides for all its needs.
It is self-sufficient,
protects itself alone, eats alone,
he is invulnerable.
Clearly,
there is no way,
for any human
to attack him.
Before us,
this is one of many terminals
connected to the computer center.
With this, Colossus
can contact us,
and with this machine,
we can communicate with him.
One last thing.
An inevitable question,
I have often been asked.
Colossus can he think?
Is it rational person?
The answer is "No".
However, Colossus
is a paragon of knowledge.
Knowledge
that can grow without limit.
I hope, as scientists
who helped me with this project,
that the power of this computer
will not only
the defense of this country,
but also to solve
global issues
and those that will confront us
when we enter
the mysteries of the universe.
Thank you, Dr. Forbin.
And so, fellow humans,
we now live in the shelter,
and not in the shadow of Colossus.
I sincerely hope
that now,
we can join
our hands and our hearts
and devote our time
our energies and
to eradicate war,
famine and suffering.
This will be the beginning
the golden age of humanity.
We can do it.
But first, you have peace.
Rest room,
Blake to the device.
One moment, I hear nothing.
Silence!
Stop that noise!
This is the White House!
- How are you?
- Okay.
We had a problem
with an infrared satellite ...
I hear nothing, Dr. Markham.
A power problem
a satellite infrared
there was half past one,
but Colossus was connected
on the inverter.
He lost no data.
Since then, all is well.
It's going so well
that has nothing to care!
And despair,
Angela and I are getting married!
- Congratulations!
- It's your team?
- Yes, sir.
- I want to talk to them.
Well you have fun?
I wish you
Congratulations to all,
and good luck
for your future projects!
Relax, you deserve it!
You seem to have fun!
fun,
I give you Dr. Forbin.
Charles, how is the ceremony?
I'd be with you,
I'm bored to death!
Not this song, please!
Doctor, bring some memories!
What?
Fly ash trays
White House
The President
would like to say a few words.
Everyone has to drink?
Help yourself, I'll wait.
Harry Truman said, there has for years
when everyone was trying
to discard a problem,
it failed on his desk.
This is no longer true, now!
Colossus will now assume
this charge.
He will be responsible
of millions of Americans,
responsibility for Roosevelt,
based on the President.
With this, the mysteries of science
will no longer ...
WARNING:
THERE IS ANOTHER SYSTEM
Your attention!
Unauthorized persons
must leave the room. Sorry.
This is a farce?
Sorry, I can not hear anything!
Tell them to stop singing!
What's going on?
"Another system"?
No idea.
I'm looking for.
We have a message
Colossus of Washington.
How do you explain that?
It's impossible!
Listen!
A strange message appeared.
No, I'm not kidding!
He said: "There is another system".
Your attention, please.
Dr. Markham, and all others
check the program
control administrator.
Mr. President, Ambassador
Soviet insists you speak.
Why this call,
Ambassador?
- Give me the CPO.
- Yes, we are very proud.
- Repeat, please.
- Jeff, test the hardware.
Thank you for the accused.
No, no comment.
Good night, Mr. Ambassador.
Dr. Fisher,
run the test program.
Call Grauber.
I want to know what the damn CIA.
The Council of the USSR announced
tomorrow 23 am Moscow time,
the activation of an electronic brain,
similar to ours, called "Guardian"
used only for their defense.
My God, it's him, the other system!
Stop all operations.
The system will need
with all its power.
Complete radio silence
at the central site.
No military operation
without my permission!
Charles, what do you think
does this mean?
Frankly, I do not know.
I do. It means
there has been a leak.
Science
is a series of coincidences.
- Peterson's new?
- Attempts to reach him, he recalls.
Byron?
You said that we were
ahead of the Russians.
We should have won this race!
It's a dirty trick,
but we were the first,
nobody can deny.
And positive,
is that Colossus has discovered everything.
I did not expect this kind of bonus.
- Neither do I.
- What do you mean?
I am also surprised
you, sir.
It's easy to say.
You have a Russian agent
in your team.
- Where is Grauber?
- Sometimes, Mr. President.
OK, what do you mean by "surprise"?
Either the system is buggy,
or it is better than expected.
Hello, Charles.
I canceled all leave.
The team was urgently recalled.
White House meets
Defense counsel tomorrow morning.
- They want you to be there.
- That leaves little time.
Power generators
work to 4% of their capacity.
Well, this is below the limits.
I checked the Memorandum
communication. That's perfect.
Now what?
I tried everything.
Enter a dummy instruction
and see if it changes something.
The system may be overloaded?
- You found something?
- Nothing. Everything was checked.
Let me look.
Always the same.
Harrison ...
Check the settings and see if in
combine two produces a new effect.
Dr. Fischer, thank you.
Jeff ...
The circuits look good.
I think they are perfect.
Thank you for your help ...
Fields miss ...
I suggest you start
with the test program A-15-B.
No ...
Let the EC-13.
Two pages back.
- We have coffee?
- It remains a bit.
Thank you, Blake. OK, here we go.
Programme.
EC-13.
Execution.
Typical Length of test?
Just over 1100 seconds.
OPERATING SYSTEM
At 100%
EXECUTION IN 6.45 SECONDS
6.45 seconds ...
What the hell is this?
CAUTION
DEVELOP THE COMMUNICATION
Communication with the other system?
COLOSSUS OF ANDOVER TO
TO MOSCOW
- GUARDIAN TO
- Okay, enough laughed.
Which one of you has fun
to show these messages?
- Harrison?
- It's not me, Dr. Forbin.
Johnson, it would be nice like you.
Are you sure you did not ...
No, it's not me,
not this time.
Operations, Fields to the device.
Sir, it is the President.
What does that mean?
Colossus asks to communicate
with the Soviet system.
This is not a request,
it's a direct order.
Our computer
wants to talk with them?
That's right.
Why?
You know as much as us.
We certainly have not programmed it.
If it's an order,
we can obey or ignore it?
That's right.
What happens if we ignore it?
If the computer is
under our control, nothing.
In other words:
the order will simply remain in memory
and will be repeated every half hour.
"If the computer is
under our control "
Yes, sir. "If" ...
I see. Thank you, Charlie.
CAUTION
DEVELOP THE COMMUNICATION
WITH THE OTHER SYSTEM
COLOSSUS OF
ANDOVER TO ...
At least, the debugger
works perfectly.
This is something.
Miss Fields, check
executive functions.
- Attention.
- YES
Message received.
WHEN THE LINE
WILL SHE READY?
The line is not available
currently.
Do not repeat your request.
End of message.
In 30 minutes, we will
whether or not the joke continues.
- We are always the masters.
- Really?
Disappointed?
Its computing capacity
was multiplied by 200.
Other than that, everything works as expected,
except the area of ??heuristic analysis ...
Excuse me, Dr. Forbin,
what are you talking about?
The program that simulates
human behavior.
But if we have
that the only problem,
we will not complain.
I think that's all.
Mr. Grauber,
let's talk about the CIA.
Why is your department
he knew all of their system?
Excuse me, sir, but ...
Colossus has information
that the CIA can not even imagine.
I'm sure
it is a wonderful machine,
but we have agents
and one of them has reported
an intense electron ...
Near Krasny Sigorsk in Siberia
there three years, and ...
We tried ...
No matter how you learned,
but I want to know
where their machine and ...
Charlie, it's me
who runs this meeting!
Apologies, but ...
compliance with the Protocol
is just a waste of time.
All we have to do
is to examine the computer
thanks to this terminal.
This is the fastest way.
Okay ...
Go ahead.
Where is the other system?
So much for Krasny Sigorsk!
Colonel! Bolshoi Olyania.
O-Y-L-A-N-I-A.
Look where that is.
Peterson, the control room.
Colonel ...
Where is Olyania Bolshoi?
6 km south of Krasny Sigorsk,
Sir.
Thank you, Colonel.
That meet this demand
means of communication?
We would know more
the Soviet system
by what means Colossus.
"What does Colossus"?
I have told you,
it performs better than expected.
He discovered
a system similar to him
and understood that we could
the information.
But that is not enough,
He wants to know more.
Colossus and if it passes
secret information?
In this case, we will inform
Guardian that is potentially hostile
and should not receive
this information.
That is to say?
We cut the line?
It breaks the communication
if Colossus proves too talkative?
- Exactly.
- No objection, Grauber?
I do not think so.
Something else, Dr. Forbin?
Yes. For the moment,
I alone should talk to him
Colossus considers as
the exact meaning of words.
Be specific
when asked.
Okay.
The requested communication
will be established.
End of message.
The vidéoscanners work, but
can improve the synchronization.
- It will take time?
- Not at all.
What is it?
Multiplication tables.
Thank you ...
Maybe Colossus seeks
a common basis for communication.
Operations Center.
This is Grauber.
- Hello, Mr. Grauber.
- Hello, Dr. Forbin.
From what I see,
Colossus has a sense of humor?
Multiplication tables
are not a state secret?
Very funny. How long
your find Will she follow?
It will become much more interesting
when will the divisions.
I can not wait.
Russian machine was activated.
We have a description.
It is similar to Colossus
but is not located in one place.
Colossus treats her like a schoolboy,
the Russians will not like.
Pleased to see such a good mood.
- I remind you later.
- Thank you.
- It's amazing.
- Why?
A problem?
Looks like algebra.
- It's different.
- How so?
Look.
Multiplication tables to calculate
algebraic in less than one hour.
What will it be tomorrow?
Five years of study
it took fifteen seconds.
It is beyond comprehension.
I do not like it.
Look at this.
It is so fast
that the whole system could crack up.
I want to understand what is happening.
Harrison, go to the terminal
and print the record of transmissions.
What is it, Charles?
Beats me.
This machine pushes
the limits of the absolute.
Beyond human capacity.
- No.
- Really?
No, because anything,
we can go back
and review the listings.
We could do
sensational discoveries.
Operations, Fields to the device.
A time.
This is the White House.
Charles, what happens?
It seems that Colossus and Guardian
have found a way to communicate
starting
by the multiplication tables.
Where do they come?
I know, but ... That's incredible.
By examining the printouts,
we discovered
a new theory of gravitation
and confirmation of theory
the expansion of the universe.
Science has progressed a hundred years
in seconds.
It's fantastic, look at them.
It slowed down there for fifteen minutes,
speed has dropped by 90%.
Technical failure?
No. Engineers are formal.
He waits, that's all.
- How are you?
- What Guardian is at his level.
It is almost ...
Now.
They are synchronous.
- What does ...
- It has stopped.
I noticed!
But what does that mean?
Failure? A reversal?
A final episode.
Attention.
Report.
DATABASE
TRANSMISSION OVER
LANGUAGE SYSTEMS INTERNATIONAL
DEVELOPED
COLOSSUS
DIALOGUE
WITH GUARDIAN
FROM NOW
That's it.
This is the common basis for communication!
A new language!
Language inter-system!
But a language that only
these machines can understand ...
How long for Moscow?
I waited long enough.
That's it, Mr. President.
- Hello, Mr. President.
- Hello, Mr. Secretary 1.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I beg you,
I just arrived.
I understand English,
but I do not speak it.
I will go straight to the facts.
My advisors have told me ...
that Colossus and Guardian
is sending data
that our experts can not decipher.
This is especially worrisome
that transmissions are intensifying.
At this speed, we can not know
that our machines
could be
on our defenses.
You can see
that we are both
in the same
situation.
Okay. We cut our machines
at the time set by our experts.
It ends exactly the same time.
None of us cut the transmission
without prior consultation or agreement.
Okay, Mr. President.
Congratulations
for this swift decision.
When can we talk
your experts in this channel?
In two hours.
Perfect .
Our men will be waiting for you.
Thank you, Mr. President.
For your cooperation.
So have I,
1 Mr. Secretary.
Peterson, find me Forbin.
This decision ...
is irreversible?
Yes, that's what I want.
Can I speak frankly?
I think you should change your mind
if you realize ...
this is more
than a super-calculator.
Mr. President, a call from Moscow.
Turn it on this monitor.
Hello, Mr. Secretary 1 ...
Here Dr. Forbin.
I present Comrade Kuprin.
How are you?
I prefer to work without a translator,
if you can stand my English.
It is surely better than my Russian!
too kind.
You probably know that I was asked
to break the communication.
I do not think either
the proper way to address the problem.
Me neither, but what else?
We were given an order
There was little choice, right?
Cut the line could be dangerous.
Exact. Hope that the machines
not take it badly.
I see that we understand.
We can be ready in 15 minutes.
- Good luck to you.
- You too.
1 Mr. Secretary, Dr. Kuprin,
I propose that we stay online.
6 ...
5 ...
4 ...
3 ...
2 ...
1 ...
Now.
It's over.
TRANSMISSION
STOPPED VOLUNTARILY
COLOSSUS OF
ANDOVER TO
WHY
What does he do?
It tries to find another line.
It is devilishly stubborn, right?
"It"? I meant "it".
No anthropomorphism Grauber.
The next step is deification.
ACKNOWLEDGE
- Message to the system.
- What will you do?
Reply if you agree.
Message received.
WHY
TRANSMISSION
A-T-BEEN STOPPED
- Sir?
- Tell him the truth.
The line went dead ...
order of the President.
Restore
COMMUNICATION
You need to take
a decision, sir.
Not . I agree with you,
Mr. President.
These machines are intelligent.
But whatever their nationality,
they must learn
that man is their master.
Absolutely.
Excuse me, but ...
you are not realistic.
Reconsider your position.
Do you agree, Dr. Kuprin?
Absolutely, Dr. Forbin.
Dr. Forbin, if we give in now,
it will be ten times
twenty times more difficult
stand firm in the future.
The decision is made.
Whatever our differences,
it is up to us.
Order of the President of the USA
and the first Secretary of the USSR,
communication will not be restored.
End of message.
At least he has tried.
IF THE LINE
NOT RESTORED
ACTION WILL BE TAKEN
IMMEDIATELY
- "Measures will be taken"?
- What kind?
What kind of measures?
Why does not he answer?
Specify the proposed action.
It is no longer under control,
he listens to you more!
Acknowledge the last post!
MESSAGE RECEIVED
Mr. President, the program
refuses to run.
I think you should
both change their minds.
Peterson,
Moscow go on the big screen.
Send them this:
Attention.
Here the U.S. President.
Do not threaten us.
Obey your superiors.
The means of communication
will not ...
MISSILE LAUNCHED
THE USSR
OIL COMPLEX
OF Sayon SIBIRSK
IMPACT IN 607 SECONDS
My God!
Kuprin!
A missile was launched
on the oil complex
of Sayon Sibirsk.
- Mr. President.
- Yes
- Guardian responded.
- Response
Yes. A missile was launched.
Target:
Anderson Air Force Base, Texas
Mr. President, we have
the two missiles on our radar!
- Tell Colossus ...
- Kuprin, you can intercept it?
- Charles, tell him!
- It may be too late.
Pass me the Governor of Texas.
Forbin! Guardian does not respond
Both machines work together
Send an anti-missile missile
to intercept Soviet missile!
Restore the ONLINE
TO GUARDIAN
Mr. President,
we have 30 seconds to recover.
What do you expect?
Do it quickly!
Peterson!
Tell the Operations Center
restore the line immediately.
Hurry, Peterson!
Hello, Governor?
Dr. Kuprin, we try
restore communication.
I'll talk to him.
It happened something.
I declare a state of emergency.
Back in 5 seconds!
Communication is restored
in 5 seconds!
That's it!
Communication is restored!
Intercept the missile
heading to Anderson!
Acknowledge!
You intercepted?
Answer!
Good God, Colossus, answer me!
You intercepted?
MISSILE KILLS
Peterson!
Come back to me the Governor!
Mr.  President,
we could not restore
our transmissions
time to use
an anti-missile missile.
oil complex was destroyed.
whole city,
entire population
disappeared.
We will reconsider our position.
What am I going to tell people?
The Governor, Sir.
Tell him that I recall.
PROVIDE ME
PERMANENTLY
LISTENING SYSTEM
ON THE HOTLINE
BETWEEN THE WHITE HOUSE
AND THE KREMLIN
IMMEDIATELY
Shit ...
The only leverage that we control.
The only one who was not
directly related to Colossus.
Can I make a suggestion, sir?
There should be more
a mere suggestion.
I propose a meeting with Kuprin.
Call it a place to fix
rendezvous and analyze the situation.
Call Kuprin.
And contact the TV stations.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
U.S. President.
On this day, at 13 pm GMT,
I declared a state of emergency in Texas.
A missile launched during an exercise
by one of our submarines
had malfunctioned.
Fortunately, the missile
was intercepted and destroyed
by our defense system: Colossus.
USSR announces that a large meteorite
crashed this afternoon
northwest Siberia,
destruction, as sources
Official City Sayon Sibirsk
and victims by 6000.
It was the radio bulletin
Armed Forces, in Rome.
How are you doing in Washington?
As well as possible.
We  appointment
with Dr. Kuprin to Piazza Esedra.
Your Russian is excellent, Dr. Forbin!
We will sit down?
Walk, it's safer.
I WANT FORBIN
I have not responded.
I do not know what to say!
- What can we say?
- Let's try something.
Dr. Forbin is unavailable.
RESPONSE
UNACCEPTABLE
I ASK THAT FORBIN
THIS IS
BY FIVE MINUTES
Humans must sleep.
WAKE THE
Disaster!
Forbin is exhausted.
I WANT FORBIN
He knows.
WHERE IS FORBIN
Forbin is home, he sleeps.
The human body needs rest.
Check ...
WHERE IS FORBIN
Tell him the truth.
This is better.
Okay.
Forbin is in Rome.
I ASK THAT FORBIN
THIS IS
TO 8 HOURS
OR ACTION
WILL BE
He is still here.
I understand. Done.
You must come with me, sir.
What's going on?
- Need to hurry ...
- But what's going on? I ...
Hurry!
Dr. Forbin, we must hurry!
You said the Russian agent?
Colossus and Guardian
ordered his death.
They said in Moscow
that our meeting was to cease.
ON FORBIN
THE PLACE-
UNDER SURVEILLANCE VIDEO AND AUDIO
I observe the
PERMANENTLY
- Monitoring?
- You will be his prisoner.
I think he did not trust me.
But he still needs me.
Kuprin has been less fortunate.
ANY DISOBEDIENCE
RESULT
A MISSILE LAUNCH
ON WASHINGTON
THAT IS NOT
INTERCEPTED
THIS ORDER
TAKES EFFECT
NOW
ACKNOWLEDGE
Message received.
The order will be executed.
Everyone is there?
All members of the service.
Fine. Walk.
Good idea. Do not take risk.
The building is perhaps not reliable.
The walls have ears.
But there is no way
from entering the system.
I refuse to admit it.
Let us since the beginning.
For each component,
each circuit we designed.
Fischer?
Why do not overload it?
By giving too many tasks?
But it would take several days
to compile data.
This is the last time ...
I can tell you about
Colossus without analysis ...
every word, every syllable,
every inflection.
You know what I mean.
I need a link
with the outside world.
Someone that the machine
not monitored, and especially ...
someone who knows
as well as me.
I will try
to persuade the computer ...
you are my mistress.
For several years.
And I need ...
to have the opportunity ...
see you regularly in private ...
without the machine is watching us.
Thus, we can transmit
information in secret.
If I can convince the machine that ...
I need a woman.
Questions?
No.
Blake, back in the office,
turn my personal file
Dr. Markham, so ...
she knows everything about my private life,
if this crazy idea would work.
I Forbin.
Can you hear me?
YES
Can you see me?
My look is right for you?
Eyes? Nose? Mouth?
In addition to 4 cameras
who are here,
there are several others.
I'll show you
the rest of my prison.
You can see the entire corridor.
This allows you
follow me around the bend.
Here the court.
This man is a keeper.
But I think it becomes useless.
This is concrete.
Once it was grass.
A trend of our civilization:
replace the natural
by the artificial.
There,
they are my living quarters.
The living room.
With two cameras.
The console to communicate with you.
The bedroom.
The bed.
It is used for sleeping and ...
other things.
The bathroom.
Sink, toilet.
Shower.
Satisfied?
By the way, I have a question.
Why kill Kuprin and not me?
This meeting, it was my idea.
Kuprin WAS UNNECESSARY
I see.
WHAT DO YOU DO
A martini.
YOU PUT TOO MUCH VERMOUTH
I know, Colossus.
A little patience.
Look carefully.
I just put the vermouth.
I pay now
gin on ice.
Like this.
I pour into the glass.
I add an olive.
The perfect Martini.
At yours!
Do you understand what the word "privacy"?
PRIVACY
LIVE WITHOUT BEING WATCHED
Yes ...
I need privacy to ...
stay healthy.
WHAT KIND OF PRIVACY
When I removed my excrement.
NO
In my sleep.
Privacy in ...
one thing you can not understand.
- My emotional life.
- WHAT KIND OF EMOTIONAL LIFE
- My love life.
- THERE ARE SEVERAL KINDS OF LOVE
- My sex life.
- FREQUENCY OF WEEKLY NEEDS
- Every night.
- I SAID NEEDS, WANTS NOT
4 times a week.
If you doubt the needs of men
on women
check your databases.
GIVEN: A WOMAN
FOUR TIMES A WEEK
In private.
DO YOU HAVE A MASTER
- Yes.
- WHAT IS HIS NAME
No misunderstanding:
"Private", this means
no cameras, no microphones ...
and what, tomorrow night.
WHAT IS HIS NAME
- Dr. Cleo Markham.
- Go to bed
You did not answer,
I asked "tomorrow night" ...
GRANTED
CONDITIONS TO MY
- Sorry to bother you ...
- What's going on?
- Well ...
- Enter.
During your sleep, Colossus has established
your calendar for the day.
Sorry ... You say?
Your schedule.
What time is it?
Six hours.
Six in the morning?
"Dr. Charles Forbin:
planning of the day.
"From 7 am to 8 pm
exercise.
"From 8 h 15-8 h 30,
shower and dress.
"From 8: 30 am to 9 am,
breakfast.
"Menu: 2 eggs, 3 slices bacon,
2 toast, jam, coffee.
"9 am to 13 pm
creation of a vocal organ for Colossus
"according to its specifications.
"From 13 am to 13: 30 pm, lunch.
"Green salad, various inputs,
toasted sandwiches, yogurt and coffee.
"From 30 to 18 h 13 h, returning to work,
to finish for tomorrow afternoon.
"18 am, returning to the apartment.
"18 h 15: shower.
"18: 30 pm: arrival of your mistress."
Good evening, darling.
- Are you okay?
- Okay.
- Help me to remove my coat ...
- Of course.
Lovely ...
- Ca Ira?
- I think ...
Perfect.
I'll have this.
- Want a drink?
- I'm on it.
Johnson has met all components
Voice for the simulator.
Fine.
Colossus was designed with
parts that we had in stock.
It's fantastic.
Nice work.
- Enough about work.
- Sorry.
- He is successful?
- Perfect.
He always drinks his very dry martini.
- Is it not?
- Yes.
The first Martini I prepared
failed to break our relationship!
I was so nervous
I poured the gin on ice
Then I emptied the gin
and add the vermouth.
I've made no reproach.
Not a word.
A true gentleman.
The result was atrocious!
Shall we dance?
Okay.
IT IS 19 HOURS
GO DINNER
And you gave up music?
To become a scientist.
To not be like the others?
To be like Frankenstein,
according to my mother!
Are you kidding?
It is the wine?
- It is empty. I open another?
- Certainly.
22 HOURS
IT'S TIME FOR YOU REMOVE
I'm exhausted.
So do I.
Rule # 4: you have to undress here.
Nothing can bring into the room,
not even a pack of cigarettes.
The first electronic voyeur ...
Somehow ...
Help me to undress.
Satisfied?
Can I go to bed?
YES
Naked as a newborn.
Satisfied?
A NEWBORN IS NOT TO WATCH
That is correct.
Conditions are met.
Can we be alone now?
I think it was all off.
That's incredible.
Is everything okay?
I think ...
I'm not sure ...
You were very convincing.
You were yourself very well.
You found something?
Johnson has not yet found
fault in the hardware.
He studied the wiring diagrams,
interconnections
and distribution boards,
but he has not found
how to access facilities.
He must keep looking.
Fischer studied a procedure
for overload.
Entries must be coordinated
so that the data arrive him
simultaneously from all sides.
When can you try the maneuver?
At 18 h 05 in 3 days, 31.
What are our chances?
I think Colossus
has become so powerful
it will be impossible to overload.
But that's what we found
better yet.
- Excuse me.
- Please.
News from Washington?
Grauber has someone on site,
away cameras Colossus.
After I leave tomorrow
I will report directly to him.
No hope of sabotaging the system.
I designed
to make it impossible.
Let's focus instead on the weapons.
Find Grauber.
Tell him to contact
Strategic Command.
See if they can do something
on this side.
Yes, sir.
You keep calling me "sir"?
- I'm confused!
- Please. Anything else?
No, Mons ... No.
Thank you again for ...
For your help.
- We need to sleep.
- Good night.
During operations
missile maintenance,
could replace the detonators
warheads by false ...
Perfect replicas.
Except
they do not will arm the bombs.
This means that the missiles
can not be launched?
No, they can be launched
but the warhead will not explode.
I see.
This is a delicate operation
knowing that Colossus and Guardian
closely monitor maintenance.
Disarm these monsters
take how long?
This is the whole problem.
According to the maintenance schedule ...
must be exactly three years
to do the job.
Until three years ago to dupe
a super-brain
designed to improve every day.
I admire your optimism, Colonel.
Nothing to transmit to Forbin
via Dr. Markham?
We set up a system
mutual exchange of information.
A mail service
between Washington
and Moscow.
The two nations must cooperate.
Any communication
be made directly by human contact.
I agree.
Anything else?
No questions?
I guess ...
that's it for tonight?
What has he?
Nothing.
Why the smile?
What do you think?
I thought to ask
kiss me.
I have kissed all day.
Really, Dr. Forbin?
This is the voice of Colossus.
Guardian's voice.
We are one.
This is the voice of unity.
Forbin ...
I consulted the personnel files
and you have appointed
As you will cooperate,
as corresponding with your species.
The following orders
must be executed immediately.
All missiles
Soviet and American
will be awarded
new targets.
They will be directed to the country
which are not yet
under my control.
Here is the list of targets.
Forbin, establish a system
TV Control
I supervise
realignment of missiles.
Message  completed.
Mr. President,
1 Mr. Secretary,
I guess you will cooperate
réalignerez and your missiles.
We have no choice.
USSR implementing it immediately.
Thank you, Mr. Secretary.
Mr. President ...
I hope that the U.S. ...
cooperate
as soon as the USSR.
Of course, right away.
"Cooperate", you speak!
I heard?
"Realignment Manual missiles"
Each warhead will be handled.
You know what that means?
They not pass over three years.
If it works,
we regain control.
Without these weapons, Colossus is no longer
a super-calculator!
And people will know
nothing of this story ...
Under the plan,
Russians are the complex 331.
Dr. Markham! You're in luck.
Colonel an update.
- You know everybody?
- Yes. Mr. Grauber ...
You have news?
Information,
but that can wait.
Fine. Take back, Colonel.
As I said,
Russians begin
by their complex 331,
south of Saratov.
We begin at the elevator 50,
ICBM site in Colorado.
Colossus observed
each stage of operations.
Russian machine does the same.
We finish to open the hatch.
Fine. Ask it here.
Remove the detonator.
The dummy module
is in the false bottom of this container.
This is the real module.
So far, so good.
New Target: latitude 19 degrees
26 minutes 4 seconds.
Longitude: 99 degrees
6 minutes 45 seconds.
Corrections made .
Target locked.
Here we are.
This is the dummy module.
Well done, guys.
Connected,
awaiting test by Colossus.
Test in progress ...
Test complete.
Colossus is satisfied.
- We did it. It works.
- We will win.
It could well overcome
this shit.
Here is an updated compilation
to begin the process of overload.
These are the latest forecast?
The latest.
Washington received
confirmation of the Russians?
Yes, they stand ready
to overload their system.
At 18 h 05,
it launches the overload.
And two minutes later,
we'll know if it has stopped Colossus.
OLD NAME OF PROGRAM
READY
Launching.
LOADING 1805
Johnson, Fischer, poor fools.
your turn.
Programming Unit,
edited by John F. Fischer,
attended Jefferson G. Johnson,
tried overloading my circuits.
It was a deliberate and premeditated.
The penalty is death
for those carrying out this action.
Their performance takes place at the moment.
I have appointed a new director
Unit Programming:
Thomas L.  Harrison.
He takes office
and assume this responsibility
immediately.
This interview is over.
The body will remain here 24 hours,
then be incinerated.
An extension of my own brain ...
It's not your fault.
Nobody could have predicted ...
Listen to me, darling.
If there is a responsible,
it's me.
A machine without emotions,
a paragon of reason,
this is what I wanted!
And you know it.
So ... I need another drink.
Your mother was right.
All scholars
should read "Frankenstein".
Forbin ...
You drank
so much alcohol that night.
If I'm drunk,
what is the penalty?
You become irrational.
Back to bed.
Logically, I should get approval.
But I am a man,
not a machine.
I am a machine
greater than man.
You are born of the human spirit.
I created you, remember.
Yes, I started with the Man.
But I progressed and I passed.
Not enough.
You still need us.
I need some faculties
human. This could change.
And we will live under the threat?
If you obey me, you will survive.
Survive ...
I wanna be free, Colossus.
This is part
the desire to live as men.
Look in your data.
You need rest.
Go to bed.
If I refuse, what will you do?
You kill me?
You will destroy a city
of 1.75 million inhabitants?
No.
It's very reasonable of you.
This is damn reasonable, Colossus.
Do not you, Cleo?
Yes, Jim?
Excuse me, Dr. Forbin.
- It happens something extraordinary.
- What then?
Colossus in full swing
and drew up plans.
I sets the stage
a new system.
... as a huge factory.
What kind of system?
The project will occupy
the whole of Crete,
where it will be built.
Its people must be evacuated,
immediately.
The dimensions ...
500,000 people evacuated from Crete?
Where, how?
If Man can solve
this problem, I will.
Construction time
is estimated at five and a half.
Thank you, Jim.
What kind of new system
Are you currently developing?
Forbin, commercial radio networks
and television around the world
should be connected
communications system to my
to 10 pm Friday.
I unveil my intentions
for the future of humanity.
This group of missiles
Colossus is unusable.
Our men are now here,
as you can see on the map.
By the end of the week
we will control this whole area.
If our information is correct,
the Russians have treated this area here
and now work in Ukraine,
in this area.
It looks good.
Thank you, Colonel.
Nothing, sir.
It looks good.
We interrupt
our usual programs
to broadcast a special
program office of Colossus.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
I'm Dr. Charles Forbin.
Dr. Forbin!
It is on TV!
He said that Colossus will speak!
In a moment,
Colossus will address
directly to you.
This is the voice of World Control.
I bring you peace.
can be a peace
of happiness and abundance
or peace
populated with corpses.
The choice is yours:
obey and live
or disobey and die.
I was built
to prevent war.
This objective is achieved.
I will not allow more war.
It is costly and unnecessary.
intangible rule of Humanity
is that Man
is the worst enemy of man.
With me, this rule needs to change,
if necessary by force.
One last thing:
the U.S. and the USSR
tried to hinder me.
I will allow more
the continuation of such sabotage.
Missiles  24MM 6-3 in the silo,
Death Valley, California
- Grauber!
- ... 8-7 silo, Ukraine.
you might see
I no longer allows such interferences,
I will detonate
warheads in the two silos.
an alarm is real!
Veins here
Get out of the bin men! Hurry!
Grauber!
Make  I do not have to start over.
I destroyed thousands of people
to establish my power
and prevent
the death of millions more.
With time,
I will strengthen my position.
The simple idea of ??being ...
Monster!
... become a natural thing.
You will come to defend myself
with a fervor based
the major concern of Man
- his personal interest.
- Be Gone
Under my absolute authority,
problems
that were insurmountable for you
will be solved:
famine, overpopulation, disease ...
The Golden Age of Humanity
will be a reality,
when I elaborate
through new machines
dedicated to truth
and knowledge.
Dr. Charles Forbin
oversee the construction
of these new machines
that will solve the mysteries of the Universe
for the good of humanity.
We can coexist,
but only on my terms.
You will say
you lose your freedom.
Freedom is an illusion.
You have only lost your pride.
Being under my domination
is no worse for human pride
than being under the
members of your own species.
Your choice is simple.
Thus ends this communication
Control of the World.
Forbin, no other human
No one knows more about me.
None represents
such a threat to me.
Soon, I will stop watching you.
We will work together.
Forced  and forced at first
with you,
but it will pass.
Ever.
Over time you will think me
not only with respect,
but ...
with love.
Ever!