Last Day of School
May 28, 1976 - 1:05 P.M.
I'm headed this way.
Later. - So what did we decide?
- About what?
About tonight?
I'll probably get hung up
with the guys.
Why don't we just meet at the party?
- Okay.
Wouldn't want you waitin' around
for me all night. - Alright. - Cool.
See ya later.
- Bye.
Slater - san!
How's it goin'?
- Fixin' to be a lot better.
What time is your party, man?
- 9:30, man.
I'll be there, man.
See ya later, alligator.
Wait! I gotta cruise by this afternoon
on a little business,
if you know what I'm talkin' about.
- That. - It's what I'm talking about.
I'm fuckin' wasted.
Walkin' down the hall by myself,
smokin' a "J" with 50 elves.
Later.
- Woodward, Bernstein.
That makes you Deep Throat!
Is this a smoked or liquid lunch?
Smoked, right?
Are we gonna play poker tonight?
- Count me out.
I'll probably be going
to Pickford's party.
We should do that. We can play
poker anytime. - Go to a party?
Mike! Cynthia...?
- Don't worry about it.
I don't feel comfortable at those
things. - Pick us up at 8.
I guess we're going to the party.
I gotta tell you
about this dream. - Oh yeah?
But you gotta promise
not to tell anyone. Say "l promise."
I promise
not to tell anyone. - Thank you.
Okay, there I am.
And I'm gettin' it on
with this perfect
female body, but...
What?
- I can't say.
You can't build me up and not deliver!
"Perfect female body." Not bad.
But the head of Abraham Lincoln.
I mean, the hat and the beard...
Oh well, best not think too deeply.
- Best not.
I gotta get some stuff from Mr.
Birchfield. See ya in a few minutes.
"Gilligan's transistor radio."
That was a good one!
What about that one where that sexy
surfer catches that huge wave!
You remember that?
- Oh yeah.
The mosquitoes!
- Pink, let's go!
Come on!
I can't go until Miss Wilk gets here.
So get Benny. - Alright.
What?
- Coach gave me something for you.
They're really doin' this?
- He wants 'em all back today.
Everybody's signing it?
- Just to get him off our backs.
You sign it.
Never think about it again!
You're gonna make
a big deal outta this, aren't you?
You're gettin' air from here.
It's no good. You see this?
It's gotta be tight
to get a good hit.
I ain't believin' that about Bonham's
1 - hour drum solo. - 2 minutes.
You couldn't handle that on acid.
We're gonna go to the bathroom.
Could you let Miss Wilks know?
This is totally amazing!
"l voluntarily agree to not indulge
in any alcohol, drugs or engage
in any other illegal activity that may
jeopardize the years of hard work
we have committed to a championship
season in '76." - Bullshit!
You guys are signing? - Apparently.
- What next? Urine tests?
I didn't know drugs are such a problem
they had resort to neo- McCarthyism!
They're afraid we'll have a good time!
- The "age- suppressing- youth thing".
"Neo- McCarthyism!" I like that!
- That's good, Tony.
You were in class trying to list
all the "Gilligan's lsland" episodes!
What're you talking about, girl?
- You weren't thinking about it, huh?
"Gilligan's lsland?" - It's what 's
called a male pornographic fantasy.
Oh my!
- Think about it!
You're alone on a deserted island
with two readily available women:
one a seductive sex- goddess type,
the other a healthy girl- next- door
type with a nice butt.
So guys have it all...
the Madonna and the whore.
Women get nothing.
We get a geek,
an overweight, middle- aged guy,
some nerdy scientific type.
The professor is sexy.
- Pink!
Come on, man! - We're off
to raise some hell. Look at that!
Hey, you guys!
Wait up! Benny, I have a favor
to ask you. - What do you need?
Take it easy on my brother
this summer. - Mitch Kramer?
Yeah, Mitch Kramer.
I'm gonna give him a beating!
Don't get him more than the others.
He's kinda little. - You got our word.
Little brother'll be okay.
- Thanks. See you guys!
These guys, I don't know...
Just a little bullshit, right?
- Major bullshit. He's a dead man!
Shotgun!
Check it out. I been waitin' 3 years
for this. Those junior high kids
are dead meat.
We're gonna beat 'em!
Okay, you freshman fucks,
listen up!
It's your lucky day.
Usually you spend your freshman summer
getting your asses busted
and running for your lives.
But this year, we feel sorry for you.
So we're gonna take it easy on you
and save us all a lot of time.
So if you meet here
after school today,
you'll only get one lick from each
of us. But you run like cowards,
it's open season all summer.
Oh yeah, Mitch Kramer!
Mitchy!
We're lookin' for you, pal.
Your ass'll be purple...
Have a nice afternoon.
You better get outta town. Spend
the summer with your grandparents.
You are gonna show up
to our game tonight?
I'm pitching. I kinda have to. - How
should we inscribe your tombstone?
How 'bout "Bent over"?
- Right, piss- ant!
Why aren't they after anybody else?
- They are, man. Believe me.
I know, man.
Come on, Mel, hop on.
- Let's go!
Shit!
Hey, Coach.
So tell me,
any of you girls gonna be ready to
play football this fall? - Don't know.
I've been doing so good in English,
I figured I'd be a writer.
You wouldn't know how to write your
name if it wasn't on your locker.
Don't go soft on me this summer,
sitting around the pool all day,
chasing the muff around.
Hell, man! My grandmother's
quicker than you pansies!
'course she's 6'3", 250
and runs a 4.5 40.
- What's the matter, Floyd?
Quarterbacks don't have to do what
coaches say? You give him that pledge?
The pledge, did you give it to him?
- Yeah, it's right here.
If you could get that to us by the end
of the day. You guys see that he does.
Alright, Coach.
- See ya!
Randy Floyd!
You need an attitude adjustment.
Get your priorities straight!
And watch out
with that other crowd.
Don't think I haven't noticed. Hey!
I want that paper
on my desk before you leave here
today, you hear me?
"Attitude adjustment!"
"Priorities!" - Runs with that
bad crowd. Watch yourself.
Well, I got Coach's and everybody's
attitude- adjusted priorities here.
Yeah, that's good.
- Yeah.
You hear O'Bannion flunked?
- What a dumb shit!
You all ready to bust some ass?
What's up, Don, Benny, Melvin? Good
to see ya. - See ya in half an hour.
We gotta take your truck. I'm low
on gas. - My truck?
What're you doing?
Picking up trash?
I was waiting for one of them idiot
coaches to piss me off.
You take the thing too personally.
You gotta... shake it off.
Ever thought why we play football?
How many times you gotten laid
because you're a football player?
I don't know.
A few, probably.
- A few?
I bet we could do just as well
if we were in a band or something.
I gotta put in a final appearance...
- Who you got going in there?
Vicky.
Come on, let's go get naked now!
Come on!
- Mr. Dawson?
Take it somewhere else. Mr. Floyd,
are you gracing us with your presence?
Might as well.
Ginny?
You and I could get together. It'll
be illegal. I'll keep things quiet.
At the party there's gonna be a girl
with knockers this big. - Bullshit!
Promise. Two handfuls.
- No way! - Hey!
Pentico's got his brother's car.
Let's go, man. Cool.
Go talk to him.
- I'm not going alone.
Mr. Payne? Sir?
Every second you let us out early
would increase our chance of survival.
Like our sergeant told us
before one trip into the jungle:
"Men,
50 of you are leaving on a mission.
25 ain't comin' back."
The '68 Democratic Convention
was probably the most bitchin' time
in my life.
One more thing: This summer, with all
the bicentennial 4th of July brouhaha,
you're actually celebrating a bunch of
slave- owning, aristocratic white males
who didn't want to pay their taxes.
Jump in! Come on!
Hurry up, Hirschfelder, or we're
gonna leave your ass. - Let's go!
Oh shit!
Ducks on the pond!
- How're you doin', boys?
Wake up, bitch!
Open! Open!
Hey, open!
What do you think?
- Alright. Let's go.
Hey, you! Come here.
You.
Who are you?
Nobody. I mean,
I wasn't in the truck.
Are you a freshman?
- Yeah.
Are you in or are you out?
- ln. - Let's go.
We really pissed 'em off. Just drop me
off at my house. You still with me?
My house!
They're slowing down.
You get out and get 'em!
Good luck, man. Be there tonight!
Nice try, freshman.
For being brave little kids, I'm only
gonna give you 5 licks.
Grab a pole and let's get going.
I don't think so, creep!
Mom!
Carl, get in the house.
Get in the house!
And you...
Get the hell off my property.
Sorry, ma'am. I was just escorting
your fine son home from school.
There's some ruffians
about and l...
Oh, Mitch and Carl,
we'll be seeing each other again.
I fuckin' saw that, you sack of shit!
You two are dead! Fuckin' dead!
Excuse me. Thank you.
Alright, you little freshman bitches!
Air raid!
That was pathetic!
Let's try it again. That means
get up, you lazy bitches! Get up!
Air raid!
That was horrible, you slut girls,
you freshman sluts! Get up!
Up!
Up! Up!... Air raid!
The entire community seems to be
supporting this, or turn their heads.
They have permission to use the
parking lot. No parents seem to mind.
They're selling concessions.
- I know.
We seniors, we tried. We gave you
a chance, but since you prick teasers
can't follow instructions,
we're gonna have to try something
else, won't we? Seniors?
You love us. Smile!
You love us!
Suffer, sisters!
Eat it! Open wide!
Love it, girls!
Welcome to high school,
honey!
Propose to Mr. Dawson.
Will you marry me?
Don't know. What's in it for me?
Anything you want.
- Anything? - Anything.
Go like this.
Do you spit or swallow?
Whatever you like.
Whatever I like? I'd definitely marry
you. - That's so degrading.
You're an asshole.
- Yes, I am.
That's terrible, man. Horrible.
I feel for you. I did it when I was
a freshman, and you'll do it.
Now fry like bacon,
you little freshmen piggies!
Hi.
- Propose to Tony.
Oh, God.
On your knees!
Will you marry me?
What am I supposed to say?
- I don't know.
What will you do for me?
- Anything you want.
Imagine the possibilities.
Seriously, you can stand up.
What's your name? - Sabrina.
- I'm Tony, Anthony actually.
Sorry.
This is Mike.
We're just discussing the utter
stupidity of these initiation rituals,
wondering why someone like you
would subject yourself to it.
What're we having? Social hour?
I'm a bitch. Back to the pit.
It's almost over.
Am I mistaken, or was there a little
thing going on with that vixen, stud?
You know how it is... - Bet she's
cute once you clean the shit off her.
Okay, it's hot out here,
and I'm sick of looking at you.
So let's get outta here.
What you lookin' at?
Wipe that face off your head, bitch!
Get in the truck.
Maybe if you ever left
the poker table. - What about you?
The point is, that's why
we're going out tonight.
You might experience something more
tangible than an Abe Lincoln dream.
A hairline fracture! What did you do?
- Benny was wearin' their asses out!
Just givin' 'em a little beatin'
they'll never forget.
"Here's to you, Ma!"
That's your fuckin' mother!
Say man, fuck the coaches. Do it
for us. - You pick this thing up?
Yeah. - What're you doin'?
- He ain't doin' shit.
Any more details of my life you can
let me in on, Ben? - Lots!
O'Bannion, what're you doin'?
You didn't hear, did you?
I got a shotgun pulled on my ass.
Seniors are the best!
Hey, Mrs. Pickford.
- You here to see Kevin?
No, actually, we came to see you.
- Bet you're glad school's out.
Got our report cards today. - How did
you do? - Straight A's. - Both of you?
Just kiddin'. - Big trip?
- For the weekend. - Takin' Kev?
No, he's staying here.
- Oh, he is?
Go on in. He's up there somewhere.
Let's get together sometime.
- Yeah, that'd be fun.
What do you do for fun?
- Just hang out with the girls.
Drive around. That kind of stuff.
There's a big party tonight.
Do you wanna come?
- Yeah? Cool.
You think it'd be all right? - Fine.
- Great. Pick you up at 8:30.
See you then.
- Okay, bye.
Sample of the goods.
15 bucks.
Can you spot me ten?
I'll pay you like Tuesday.
Thank you.
Who is it?
- Kevin, you need to come out.
It reeks in here.
Kevin, there's someone out here
who needs to talk to you.
What about?
- Get the door, man! Here.
Slater, lose it!
- Kevin, open the door.
Dad, Mom.
What's up?
- Did you order kegs of beer? - No.
There's a fella on a beer truck
that says you did.
Oh, really? Just a sec.
That guy said I ordered a keg of beer?
- Yeah.
He said it's for the Pickford
residence. - This address? - Yeah.
Funny. Why don't I see what's
going on? - Think you better.
Be right back.
Know anything about a party here?
No, sir.
Hey, man.
Aren't you a bit early?
Yeah, about an hour and a half.
I got a little action happenin'...
- So you got the wrong house.
Yeah, inconvenience for you...
Wrong Mr. Pickford altogether!
These things happen.
Don't worry about it... Ben.
Were you going to have a party here?
- Don't know what that was about.
Start unpacking.
We're not goin' anywhere.
Fucker!
Strike two!
Time!
Kramer, get this kid out,
or we're gonna beat your ass!
Let's go!
- Beat you like a runnin' mule!
Hey, man, forget about those guys.
Just get this last guy out.
Easy for your ass to say!
- There's nothin' you can do.
How'd they know I was gonna be here?
Quit stallin'! - Hope you got more
than a jock strap under there!
Because you're not gonna be able
to sit, don't let it affect you.
Leave through the gate in right field.
That'll draw them out of here.
They're gonna get you anyway.
Yeah, get outta here.
What're you lookin' at?
Keep your head in the game!
Strike three!
Good game...
Good game!
- Way to go.
Come on.
Mitch!
What happened to your buds?
- Let's get this guy!
How's your dad doing?
- He's doing great.
This arm ready to throw 2,000 yards
next fall? - We'll see.
We're dependin' on you boys. Let me
tell you what. You're lookin' good.
13 starters comin' back,
22 lettermen.
Yeah.
You folks take care.
- Good to see you, Randy.
Oh God, you know that hurts!
- What's goin' on here?
Pink, you missed it!
- Where are you headed to now?
The Emporium. Gonna join us?
- Yeah, see you up there.
You sign my paddle later.
Gotta get seconds with him.
- You next, Pink. - Sure.
You already got him.
Fuck it. I'm gonna find your skinny
partner Carl and his mom.
I took it easy on you. You're not
smilin' now, you sack of shit.
Benny, Don!
- Bummer about Pickford's party.
His old man found out.
Total rip- off.
We got a few sixers. You with us?
- Yeah, gotta go home and change.
Catch up with you. - See you later.
Kid, take care of that butt. Hold up!
You need a ride?
Yeah.
I think they left me.
Here you go.
There's always one senior
who has to be the bad ass.
O'Bannion's gonna be the first senior
to take that honor 2 years in a row.
The guy's a dick, right?
Yeah, he's kind of a joke.
He's not a bad guy
to have on your side.
Did you get it bad when you were
a freshman? - Shit, man!
They waited for my ass after baseball.
It was vicious.
It's best to get a lot at once,
'cause after 10 licks, your ass is so
numb, it's best to get it over with.
I had some pretty cool seniors.
They'd take you out, bust the hell
outta you and get you drunk.
Thanks, man.
- Take care.
Since the party's not goin' on,
me and the other guys'll end up
ridin' around. Want us to pick you up?
Think that's a good idea?
- Yeah, sure, man.
The guys who haven't got you yet
will give you a few days to rest.
It'd be pretty cool to show up and
let 'em know it doesn't bother you.
Yeah, okay. Cool. - See ya later?
- Sure. Thanks for the ride.
Hey, man.
Put some ice on it. Won't be anything
a few beers can't take care of.
What did she say? I'm just interested.
What did she call me?
You hang out with her. You know it.
They talk about us. Just tell us.
Nothing. - Nothing? I know
you're lying, you bitch!
You're not gonna get mad. - I'm not.
- I don't care what she thinks.
She called you a bitch and you a slut.
- She called me a slut?
That bitch!
- Everybody calls you a slut!
That bitch! I'm gonna kick her ass.
What a bitch!
You said you weren't gonna get mad.
- I'm not mad.
Look, I got a confession to make.
- What do you mean?
Well, y'know I've been talking about
going to law school, to help people?
I was standing at the post office
and everybody's looking pathetic.
People got drool sorta... This guy's
bending over. You could see the crack.
And I realized
that I don't want to do it.
Sounds good but I don't like the
people I was talking about helping.
I don't like people, period. You guys
are okay, but I'm a misanthrope.
You're not goin' to law school?
What do you wanna do?
I wanna dance!
Alright, let's rock and roll.
Hop in, man.
Whose car?
You know Wooderson?
- How's it goin'?
Pretty good. How's it goin' with you?
Say man, you got a joint?
No, not on me.
It'd be a lot cooler if you did.
You drivin' into Houston to get
those Aerosmith tickets? - Damn right!
Evenin', ladies.
- Nice...
Need me to pick up a couple?
- Yeah, two. - Cool.
You sure I'm okay in here? - If anyone
starts messin' with you, play it cool.
One to go.
Prickford!
"Would- a- been" happenin'!
- Bummer about your party.
What can I say?
Delivery guy bricked.
He said: "Keep your eye on the ball."
How's it goin'? - What's goin' on?
- Nothin'... nothin' at all.
You know Mitch?
- I just heard about you.
What'd you hear?
- Don't know. Are you okay?
Guess I'll see you guys later.
- Okay.
What grade's she in?
- Sophomore.
We gotta hurry though.
Check this out, man. - Donny,
I got a big surprise for you.
Come on, let me make this shot!
Hold onto this! Tight!
Gene! Nice tongue! Who painted 'em?
- Mostly Michelle.
I got an idea.
- What?
A beer bust later! - Pickford's
got a dube about to burn.
You with us?
- Think about it.
You cool, man?
Like how?
He was just askin' if you get high.
- Like smoke pot?
I never have before, but...
Where you goin'?
Hi... No.
Crank it up!
It's the chicks. Shavonne's still
mad at me. Watch me get something
going. Hey, what's goin' on?
What're you up to?
- A little weed...
Maybe a beer bust later on.
- Really? Cool!
See you around.
- Check you later.
Slate, why're you such a dork?
- What? - "Check you later!"
Get off my case, man!
Chicks don't wanna hear that shit.
- They don't wanna hear anything!
The girls in our classes are all
prudes. Worthless little bitches.
The girls ahead of us were wild.
Our class is worthless.
Maybe you've never got past
the sniffin' - butt stage.
It's quality, not quantity.
Wait till I get to college.
- All I'm gonna do is bang, bang...
Hirschfelder, let's go.
- Let's get outta here.
Come on, man!
It's time to leave!
I'll be right back.
You leave, you can't come back.
- Aw, gee. You hear that?
If we leave, we can't come back.
- Oh no!
What should we do?
What the hell? I was gettin' there.
I had my hand up her shirt.
You were gettin' there?
Hear that? He was getting there!
You wouldn't know what to do,
so don't worry about it.
Just 'cause you're striking out!
- That was our last junior high party.
We're in the big time now, where
all the girls will be puttin' out.
Your days of pullin' tongue all night
are over. - Yeah, right!
You didn't know she stuffs her bra?
- Those were socks!
They looked real to me.
Shit!
- Scatter!
Where you runnin' to?
We ain't gonna hurt ya...much.
Hold onto that fence
and just squeal like a pig.
You ready to switch hit?
- Oh yeah. - I'm first.
Bastards!
Hey, you guys.
Take it easy on the kid.
Ladies...
Who is that kid?
Some kid we saw that shouldn't
have been at the rec center.
Can we have some of those beers?
One of these?
- Yeah. - Why?
Just gimme a beer.
- Get outta here!
Catch!
Tubbs, catch! Get outta here.
What're you wastin' a beer on him for?
- What?
Son of a bitch. - Give 'em a beer.
- This fuckin' sucks!
Last fuckin' day of school.
No fuckin' party... nothin'!
Another fuckin' beer!
- Shut up!
Which one of your friends the beer
this time? - Hey, fuck her. I did.
Bite me!
You wish, asshole!
- Fuck you! - Why're guys such pigs?
What?
- Let's get outta here.
We're outta here.
Let me tell ya
what Melba Toast is packin'.
411 positrack out back,
750 double pumper, Edelbroc intakes,
11 to 1 pop- up pistons, Turbo- jet 390
horsepower... some fuckin' muscle!
Man, you got this out of a comic book,
I saw the ad next to the sea monkeys.
See that? That's white lightning!
See the shoes on that thing?
Wow, such an expert.
This is sad.
Let's do something else.
- Like what?
I'm bored.
- Let's split. - Where you wanna go?
Pink, hear anything about a beer bust?
- Talk to this man.
Patience, darling. Patience.
What're you doing here?
- I was just about to ask you.
Heard you got busted.
- Yeah.
Hirschfelder, too.
- Really? - Yeah.
Like how bad?
- Bad.
Was it O'Bannion?
- Yeah. God, I hate that jerk!
I know.
What've you guys been doin'?
Don't know.
Drivin' around mostly.
I didn't know Jodi was your sister.
I hear my name over here? You talkin'
about me? Hey, kiddo.
Heard they got you
pretty bad.
I asked them
to take it easy on you.
God, no wonder!
Where'd they find Hirsch?
- Walkin' outta the rec center...
Face it. You couldn't get away.
- Try and outrun those guys!
I'm gonna laugh my ass off
when it's your turn!
Last year, they caught
10 freshmen at once.
O'Bannion backed over some pizzas
and made 'em eat it. - It's bullshit!
Idiot flunks so he can be a dick
2 years in a row. Is that legal?
Damn you, Carl!
Okay, let me out. Slater,
you fuckin' hippie! Gimme drugs!
Get some from your mother!
We just banged your mother!
- Fuck you!
Those guys! What's goin' on?
Haven't seen you in so long.
What's happenin'?
- Long time, no see.
What've you been up to?
- Same old shit.
Workin' for the city. - Workin' man?
- Thinkin' about goin' back to school.
Back to J.C.?
- Yeah, man.
That's where the girls are.
I'd just as soon keep workin'.
Keep a little change in my pocket.
Rather than listenin' to some dipshit
who doesn't know what he's sayin'.
I know what you're talkin' about.
So you're a freshman?
- Yeah.
How's this year's crop
of freshman chicks lookin'?
You're gonna end up in jail sometime
really soon. - No, man.
That's what I love
about these high school girls:
I get older, they stay
the same age. - Yes, they do.
Yes, they do.
Wanna go for a spin?
Shotgun!
Woods.
- I'm here, man.
You gonna come along?
- Yeah, why not?
You boys have fun.
I'm gonna give you shotgun,
but only 'cause I'm goin' inside.
Keep that in mind.
Whose bowling ball is this?
- It's yours.
What's happenin'? Play a little
foosball? - Yeah. - Alright.
Pull over.
Pull over to the trash can.
Pull over there.
Bowling ball.
Throw the bowling ball.
Think I should?
Throw it!
You're playin' with the big boys now.
Faggot sissy- pussy freshman,
throw it! - Heave it!
Fuck 'em!
- That bowling ball said "Oof!"
to that windshield!
You're nuts, Junior!
We're outta beer.
We gotta make a grab- 'n' - go stop.
I don't have any money. - Who's got
money? - I gave... - Where's yours?
Doesn't matter. Head out that way.
You gonna hoist it? - Yeah.
I need the freshman as a lookout.
I don't wanna get in trouble. Do you,
Pink? - I don't know about this, Don.
Be careful, Junior!
Sunflower seeds.
- Zigzags.
I'm not sure about this.
I'm gonna pay for it.
I'm just messin' around with 'em.
Good.
Run! Go!
Don't try anything, or
I'll shoot the shit outta you!
Give the beer back, man.
- I paid for the beer.
You busted my mailbox.
Look me in the eye, punk!
Don't know what you're talking about,
but... - You busted it!
Tamperin' with mailboxes
is a felony offense.
I done called the police.
You oughta get outta the car.
Just go, man!
Nice and slow...
Fairly uneventful, huh?
Which one of you had the theory
about how President Ford's football
injury is affecting the economy?
- Ford's on the Warren Commission.
He's outta there this fall.
We need alcohol. - That's a thought.
Run out to the Centennial and
pick me up a sixer of this stuff.
Think you can do that?
Thanks.
- Good luck!
If we're gonna drive around,
we should just do somethin'.
You're right, man. I'm gonna get
drunk, maybe get laid
or get in a fight.
- We should be up for anything!
We are, but what?
Don't you ever feel
like everything we do
is just to service the future?
It's like it's all preparation.
But what for?
Death.
- Life of the party!
It's true.
- But y'know, that's valid.
If we're all gonna die, shouldn't we
be enjoying ourselves now?
I'd like to quit thinking the present
is some minor preamble. - Exactly.
Everybody in this car needs
some good old visceral experience.
Remember, eat a green thing every day.
And lots of calcium. It's important
for young mothers to have calcium.
Here you are.
- See you tomorrow.
How are you this evening?
- Pretty good. How's it goin'?
A lot better when I get off.
Yeah, I hear that.
You're 18, right? - Oh, yeah.
Just graduated. - Congratulations.
Off to college in the fall?
I'm still not sure.
I'm workin' now. For the city.
Thinkin' of holdin' on to the job
for a while. It's money in my pocket.
I hear that. Here's some more.
Have a nice night.
- Thanks.
Take it easy.
There you guys are!
What's in the bag?
Sixer. You owe me one, man!
They busted Hirschfelder, too.
- I heard. - You over at the Emporium?
Is that bastard O'Bannion there?
Yes. I hate that jerk.
You guys wanna get him back?
- Yeah.
They really sold it to you?
- Of course. - Cool!
There ya go, buddy.
Paycheck.
- Oh yeah.
Nice shooting.
- Thanks.
What we got here?
I got your change.
- Don't worry. A beer for my partner.
Want a beer?
- Yeah. - Alright.
Guys, party at the moon tower.
You and Benny pick up the first keg.
I'm going to collect for the rest.
Spread the word. At the moon tower!
Good game, man. You too.
Y'all an embarrassment to the sport.
You should be proud I let you play.
You are the worst pool player. Keep
watching. You might learn something.
You got so many balls on the table
I have to get 'em outta the way!
Corner pocket.
God, you are terrible!
Homo, I hope you're ready to taste
the bitter humiliation of defeat.
They're busting Carl Burnett out back.
- What did you say?
He's gettin' busted.
Benny, they got Burnett out back.
- Carl Burnett?
Come on! - Let me finish this game.
You hold him for me!
Hey, man. That Julie chick
loves you. Oh yeah. You want her?
Play it cool. Can't let her know you
like her. She'll dump you like that.
If she asks you to ride with her,
say, "Nah, got my own ride,
but maybe I'll see you later."
Sounds stupid but it works.
We got another one. You wouldn't mind
if I went first, would ya?
Alright? It's a personal thing between
me and this piece of shit.
So... we meet again, huh?
This motherfucker's mom pulled
a shotgun on me this afternoon.
Fuckin' bitch.
Haven't had any licks yet?
- No.
Another cherry, boys.
Get the fuck against the wall!
You have to be the dumbest
freshman cocksucker out tonight!
You knew I was gonna find you!
I dedicate this first lick
to your mother.
Fucker!
Not yet.
It's gettin' warmer.
What the fuck?
Remember me, you pig?
Hurry, man!
It was beautiful! You should've seen
the look on that fuck's face!
You let that little fuck get away!
What's the matter with you? Pitiful!
Fuck!
Freshman shitheads!
What the fuck are you lookin' at?
Kick your fuckin' ass right now!
Pussy!
What're you smilin' at?
Freshman faggot!
Fuck you.
Fuck all of you!
Goddamn it!
I swore I'd never go to a Top Notch.
And I am sorting through jalapeno
burgers and soggy fries. Take 'em.
Oh Christ!
How ya doin'?
Pretty good.
Cool. Heard about the party
being busted? - Oh yeah.
Not to worry. There's a new fiesta
in the making. At the moon tower.
Full kegs, everybody's gonna be there.
You oughta go.
Okay.
- We'll be there.
So ya need a ride?
I got my own car. Thanks.
Ditch the two geeks and get in
with us, but that's all right.
I'll see you there.
I love those redheads, man.
- I know you.
We had geography together.
Oh God!
- What a dick. - That was so creepy!
Why're you smilin'?
- I thought he was cute. - Cute?
When he graduated we were 3.
Cynthia, what're you thinking?
I don't know.
We gonna still go?
- Huh? - Yeah.
You better have your wood screws. I'm
gonna blow your doors off! - Fuck you!
Someone's tokin' some reefer.
Hey, man, slow down. What's up?
- How's it going? - What'd you say?
When?
Just now, when you walked past.
About what?
You said,
"Someone's tokin' some reefer '."
It was just an observation.
Oh, an observation? And who the hell
are you? Isaac fuckin' Newton?
I'm the one smokin' marijuana, fucker!
You got a problem with that?
- No. - Why'd you say that?
Don't let your mouth write a check
your butt can't cash.
So I'm blazin' with my friends, I'm a
fuckin' pothead. What's it to you?
Outta observations? Observe while
I punch your teeth down your throat!
Come on, dude. Relax.
- I'll be watchin' you, Newton!
I only came here to do 2 things:
Kick ass and drink some beer.
Looks like we're almost outta beer.
You okay, man?
Why's it called the moon tower?
They put it up when they were
buildin' the power plant.
Actually, it's a good idea. You got
a full moon out here every day.
But nothing's ever been repaired.
This whole place could fall down.
So you better
watch your step, Junior.
This place used to be off - limits,
'cause some drunk freshman fell off.
He went right down the middle,
smackin' his head on every beam.
Doesn't hurt after the first couple.
Autopsy said he had 1 beer. You?
Four.
- You're dead. You're so dead.
Look at the bloodstains.
- Shut up.
I'm gonna get that guy. - What guy?
- That asshole on the way in. Clint.
That super dominant male greaser.
- I wouldn't suggest that, Mike.
I got it all planned. Most fights
never get past a punch or two.
An instinct not to upset the herd.
I gotta get in one good punch,
play defense and wait.
- What? - What're you talking about?
At first, I was relieved to get out,
but now there's this humiliation
that's gonna be with me forever.
I'm not gonna let this
contribute to me being an ineffectual
nothing the rest of my life.
Look at this fuckin' town!
It's dead!
Imagine how many people
out there now are fuckin'!
Just going at it.
Remember me?
- Sure. Sabrina, right? - Right.
How ya doin'?
- Let's go. - What brings you here?
Just hanging out.
You havin' fun?
- Yeah.
Does your offer still stand?
What am I supposed to say?
Anything you want.
Why'd we even come here?
I always feel out of place.
You're tellin' me!
I'm being stalked by a Nazi.
That reefer I smell on you?
Coach is right. You're runnin' with
that bad crowd. Attitude adjustment!
Am I the only athlete at this party,
you two drunks?
Coach is right. Those guys don't care
if we win or lose.
Check this out. Watch this.
Watch me...
Oh no, it's the cops! Look!
It was so easy!
Oh, shit. He needs another drink.
Hey, Mitch!
How's it goin'?
- Wonderin' if you were around.
Just wanted to talk.
Are you quittin' football?
Or you don't wanna sign the pledge?
That's what it is.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm not into it anymore.
"You're not into any of it"?
The biggest mistake of your life.
No one quits senior year.
Especially if you're starting
quarterback. We got a shot at state.
We'll kick some butt this year.
It's what we've been working for
all our lives.
Me and you wanna be champions!
All I'm sayin' is
if I do play next year, it's gonna be
on my terms, not theirs.
Remember, Pink. It ain't just about
you. It's about us: me, Donny, Mel.
You'll be fuckin' us over!
Or maybe you're just scared.
Have a nice night.
Watch them fly...
... away.
You know what that song's about?
It's about aliens.
We're the aliens. We're the savages.
- That song's about that?
Yeah, that song's about that.
- About aliens?
Yeah! This country was founded by
people who were into aliens.
George Washington was in a cult
that was into aliens. You didn't know?
No...
- They were way into that stuff!
The every- other - decade theory:
The 50s were boring,
the 60s rocked,
and the 70s obviously sucked.
Maybe the 80s will be radical.
We'll be in our 20s,
and it can't get any worse.
Wait a minute! Who put the keg
in the woods? - I don't know.
This is where they told me
it would be. - Oh yeah?
I don't think we need beer anyway.
George toked weed. - Absolutely!
Are you kiddin' me?
He grew fields of that stuff.
- Up in Mount Vernon.
All over the country.
He had people growin' it all over.
The whole country was getting high.
'cause he knew
he was onto something.
He knew it'd be a good cash crop for
the southern states. So he grew it.
Behind every good man, there's a
woman. That was Martha Washington.
She'd have a big bowl
waiting for him when he'd come in.
She was a hip, a hip lady, man.
Wait.
- What? - What're you doin'?
Don't you have a girlfriend?
What girlfriend?
- What's her name?
Simone?
She was real cool, too.
She'd harvest the crops.
She'd put it in bushels and sell it
to make ends meet.
Ever look at a dollar bill?
There's some spooky stuff going on.
It's green, too!
Later.
- See you.
What was that? - What were you doin'?
- What you wish you were doin'.
Look at your boy.
- Look at your boy.
Kramer!
Yeah, you, freshman!
Right here, buddy!
He waves at us.
- What is this wave shit?
Over here.
Now!
Come on.
Shit, I should go.
- I guess you should.
I'll be back.
He's like Casanova. Amazing!
- Look at that shit- eatin' grin.
Not bad for a freshman, but watch out
for them older girls. - Hey,
we wanna know something: Gonna
fuck that, or are you a wimp?
How do you know
I haven't already?
Get outta here.
It's past your bedtime! Run along!
Go get a ride with her.
Say we left.
It will work.
Kramer, show it to her!
Air raid, freshman.
What?
Darla... - This is between
me and her. She better be
on the ground in 5 seconds!
She doesn't have to air raid,
'cause she's with me, okay.
Air raid, or it's your ass!
Don't do it, Sabrina.
Oh, that's it.
Miss Hot Stuff.
I'm going to make the next year
of your life a living hell.
Lick me, all of you!
Good for you.
Don't air raid for that bitch.
It's like that Clint fucker.
Hey, motherfucker!
- Alright, okay, Mike.
Dominant male monkey motherfucker!
Tara. - I never met a "Tara" before.
You're my first.
He did it. I can't believe it!
I fuckin' knew I should've
kicked your ass. Come on!
You guys, that's Mike.
- It's Clint. - That crazy bastard.
You like this, motherfucker?
You're fuckin' dead, faschist!
You're dead!
Hey, little brother.
That a beer?
- Yes, it is.
You had more than one?
- A few. Nobody's counting.
Hey, how ya doin'?
I should get used to you being
at the same social functions as me.
And hanging out
with people I know.
What time are you supposed to be home?
- I don't know. Couple of hours ago.
Bullshit!
That's major bullshit.
Mom barely let me outta the house
when I was your age.
Don't think she's not gonna be
waiting up. I've been through it.
And she's tough. - Just don't ask her
to take it easy on me, please.
What's that supposed to mean?
Take it easy on him?
Let's go smoke that joint.
- He's in for a surprise.
Alright!
Thanks a lot, man.
- No worries. Take care.
I'll pick you up tomorrow at 4.
- Okay.
Aerosmith, 3 weeks, front- row seats.
- Alright. I won't forget.
Who's buying breakfast?
- Not me. - I will, I guess.
You comin' along? - Sure.
- Night, John Boy, Ali.
"Would- a- been!"
- Pink, what's happenin'?
Cynthia, man. I like it, man.
- Red's a good color for you.
My favorite color.
Have you seen Jodi around?
- She left your ass. - Really?
Ya win some, ya lose some.
Slater, you look good.
- What's goin' on? - What's goin' on?
Nothing.
- What time is it?
Let's go smoke a joint on the
50- yard line, to honor Coach Conrad!
We're there.
- Great idea.
Man with the plan!
- Wanna come with me? - Okay.
Joint subcommittee meeting
on the 50- yard line in 15.
Don, y'all ride with me. Let's hit it!
- This is cashed, man!
Cashed! Ride with us, but in the back,
'cause I gotta shotgun you.
Watch the leather.
Don't you quit. You wanna hit him?
- Jesus, you're wearin' Rebel gray.
Now break down!
Break down!
You don't deserve to wear
that Rebel gray!
You won't hit him?
"Only the strong survive!"
That's it! Only the strong survive!
Where's your pitch?
Hit your goddamn pitch!
My grandmother can hit harder!
What the fuck, man?
She's a 8'4", 652 - pound hairy- ass
gorilla and runs a 40 in 10.2.
She's gotten bigger. She was
only 6'2", 195 in my day.
Still drivin' that Mack truck, though.
- Pink, you got my papers?
In my glove compartment.
I got 'em. Hit me on the slant.
Gimme the keys to an inside.
Marijuana on one.
- Reefer on two.
Looks pretty good, huh? - Yeah.
- Could be a little more symmetrical.
Does that hurt? Sorry.
- It's a bruise.
I don't know.
Let me ask you something.
I got some pretty good ones in there.
You wouldn't say I got my ass kicked.
After a couple of years people won't
remember if you won or lost.
You're right, 'cause I read about
a Jackson Pollock
or Ernest Hemingway. You never read
who won or lost a brawl.
Thanks for the ride
and breakfast. - No problem.
Nice to pile on some pancakes
and syrup after a night of beer.
Good night.
Hope you're not grounded
or anything. - Thanks.
"... not to indulge in drugs, alcohol
sex, or any other illegal activity."
Slater, babe.
Found that in your glove compartment.
You're the third person
who's given me this.
What you gonna do?
I don't know.
Probably end up signin'.
It's the same bullshit
they tried to pull in my day.
If it ain't that, it's some other
choice they're gonna make for you.
You gotta do what Randall "Pink" Floyd
wants to do. Let me tell ya this:
The older you get, the more rules they
are gonna try to get you to follow.
You just gotta keep livin', man.
L - I - V - I - N!
If you sign that, you should throw
a little grass in the middle.
Roll it up, sign the joint, man.
Tell 'em! - That's what I'll do.
Assholes. - A bunch of assholes, but
we've had good times here, Pink.
Yeah, I can't believe this.
You act like you're so oppressed.
You guys are kings of the school!
You get away with whatever you want.
If I ever start referring to these as
the best years of my life,
remind me to kill myself.
All I'm sayin' is
I just wanna look back and say:
I did it the best I could
while stuck in this place,
had as much fun as I could
played as hard as I could
while stuck in this place,
dogged as many chicks as I could
while stuck in this place.
Right, Mr. Premature Ejaculation!
That the cops?
- What...?
All of you! Get over here!
Now! - Ditch that pot! Is it illegal
to be on the football field?
Come on, Slater. - What'd we do?
- Got any Visine?
I can't believe this.
If it ain't Richard Wrath!
How ya doin', Dick?
Well, well,
a couple of football players!
Wonder what Coach is gonna think.
Line up.
Wooderson? - Slavey? - Reliving
old glories on the football field?
Get through! You shouldn't be mad that
I got All- District and you didn't.
Get your
scrawny butts over here!
Mornin', Coach!
Why am I gettin' wake- up calls
from the cops?
They just left.
- False alarm. - Come here, Randy.
You been out with those losers?
Hey, Coach Conrad, remember me?
Second- period gym class?
That's the kind of people I mean.
Trouble means nothing to that bunch.
You're the one with something to lose.
You don't even know them.
How can you talk that way?
I'm willing to wipe the slate clean
and forget. I want you to get
your priorities straightened out,
quit hangin' out with hoodlums,
and sign your commitment to your team.
Have you done that yet?
I'm still thinkin'. - No one's paying
you to think about it. Just do it!
You know, Coach?
I gotta get goin'. Me and my loser
friends gotta get Aerosmith tickets.
Top priority of the summer.
Oh, Coach, I forgot.
I might play ball,
but I will never sign that!
Let's rock and roll!
Alright, man. Livin'.
I'm gettin' my third wind.
You gonna come? - Shotgun!
You guys not goin'?
- Can I use your keys?
Time to boogie on outta here.
- Hey.
So that's that?
I never get shotgun!
Hi, Mom.
This is your one
"get- outta- jail- free" card.
Hope you enjoyed it.
- No.
Your sister told me everything, so
I've decide to make this deal.
I'm gonna be open- minded this time.
Next time you come in at sunrise,
we've got problems.
And who is this older girl
who gave you a ride?
She's just like...
Have you been drinking?
No!
Are you drunk?