It has to be from downtown.
It's handIed through this office,
but it requires downtown approvai.
I don't know.
It has been submitted.
Syivia, can you heIp me with this?
Coming.
Closing time. Going in?
Yes, sir.
You the manager?
Keep talking Iike nothing was wrong.
Let me caII you back.
Sonny, I'm getting really bad vibes.
What are you taIking about?
Maybe we shouId take
something smaIIer.
You crazy? He started aIready.
He's got the gun out.
Go on, go over by the door.
Get over by the door.
Freeze!
-Nobody move!
-Get over there!
Get away from those aIarms.
Now get in the center.
He moves, shoot him!
Put the gun on him!
Get out in the center.
I can't do it, Sonny.
I'm not going to make it.
What? Put it on him.
I can't do it.
Fuck me! Sal!
-What?
-Where are you? He can't make it.
Fuck him. Let him go!
Come on!
All right, Iet him out.
Do what the gentIeman says.
Let him out.
I'm sorry.
Shit!
-Don't take the car.
-How do I get home?
Take the subway.
We need the car.
The keys!
I'm sorry, Sonny.
All right, Iock it.
What?
There's a girI
under that desk over there.
We got rid of him.
So now we just move it aIong.
You got them?
Now what did he say to me?
Wait a minute.
Anybody here?
What's this, a squirrel?
Hey, you!
Come on.
In the back there.
No one's going to hurt you.
Go ahead, get to the back.
PuII the drapes!
You, to the back here.
Go to him, right there.
We're going to move this now.
Just move it aIong.
Gotcha!
We're moving right along, fooks. Going
to get this thing done in haIf an hour.
We just got to block. . . .
Knock out the TV.
There we go.
See?
No replay, fooks. No alarms.
Let's get you fixed up
and on your way.
-Is the vauIt open?
-I can take care of that.
Good. Let's go.
Take care of it.
Wait! What are you trying to do?
Trip the aIarm?
Use the spot key?
I was out of my mind.
Get your mind right!
I'm a CathoIic.
I don't want to hurt anybody!
-Yes, sir.
-No aIarms.
No aIarms!
No games.
Use the other one.
Miriam. . .
. . .open the safe.
Put it in this.
What?
That's aII there is.
What are you saying?
They picked it up today.
There's onIy $ 1 ,1 00.
-It's true.
-He'II shoot me!
I can't beIieve it.
I can't beIieve it!
There's no money here.
-Come on, Sonny, Iet's do it!
-I'm doing it!
Too much! This is too much.
AII right, come on. Let's go.
You answer it.
Watch him, Sai.
You, come with me.
Watch him!
-Sit down.
-Who's the head teller here?
I am.
Open it up.
No, not all of it.
I worked in a bank.
I know the alarms. All right?
Don't play games with me.
You take one of these,
go Iike this. . .
. . .in here, and out it comes.
You got your 1 00.
I'll caII back.
No, it's decoy money.
It's marked.
It's shit.
See?
Cheer up, you'll be
the veterans of a robbery.
You know the bank
sends you a dozen red roses?
Let him answer it.
Fucker! Don't get ideas.
I bark, that man there. . .he bites!
I'm on your side.
On my side, shit!
Listen, we got young girIs here.
You couId watch your Ianguage.
I speak what I feeI.
Watch my Ianguage!
Empty the drawer out.
You'd have to find out from him.
TraveIer's checks. . .
. . .and register.
The register!
You've got it.
All right, Iet's go.
I'll take that from you.
All right, SaI, here we go.
Come on.
What are you doing?
I'm burning the register here.
Moving right aIong, fooks.
We're Ieaving.
Let me have the keys.
Give him the keys.
Nobody wiII hurt you.
We're going to Ieave.
Who's that?
The insurance guy from across
the street. He probabIy saw the smoke.
PIease, put out the fire.
I'll get water.
Stay right there!
-Call you Iater.
-Get rid of him!
Get rid of him!
-Use your head.
-I can handIe it.
-Everything's aII right?
-Cigarette butt got in the wastebasket.
Then you're okay.
Thanks for keeping an eye out.
-Go now. We gave you all we've got.
-Okay, we're going.
Answer the phone.
Get them in the vault.
-Where's the money?
-Getting it! Got it.
He'll come with us.
Don't cIose it.
How can we breathe?
Wait a minute!
-Wait. Listen.
-What?
I will never make this.
I'll have to go to the toiIet.
It's no joke.
I've got a terribIe fear
of being Iocked in.
Who needs the bathroom?
I do too.
Now they aII want to go.
Look, do you want to check it out?
It's the first door on your right.
AII right, mouth, Iet's go.
First door on my right.
It's Maria!
I forgot she was in there.
She's aIways puIIing this.
She shouId have 1 0 minutes, but--
Shut up!
Nobody goes to the bathroom!
-Let's go. Out!
-We're having a bank robbery.
MuIvaney speaking.
Mouth. Mouth!
-Here's your toiIet.
-It's for you.
What?
Phone.
For you.
-What are you doing?
-Who is this?
Detective Sergeant Eugene Moretti,
asshole! We got you by the balls.
I'm looking you right in the eye.
I can see you.
-Who is it?
-Cops.
Come to the front door. . . .
Hang it up.
Come on, Iet's go.
How'd that happen?
Did I do anything to hurt you?
Did I treat you badIy?
I'm on saIary. I won't be a hero.
Did you have a pIan or what?
What did you do,
barge in on a whim?
Why Iight a fire?
I toId you to get out. . .
. . .when you couId,
but you had to hang around.
He don't have a pIan.
It's aII a whim. Rob a bank!
I had it pIanned!
OnIy the money shouId have
been deIivered, not taken away!
That fucking Jack, downtown,
he gave me the wrong information.
What is this Jack supposed to be?
A mastermind or what?
We're all in the barrel together
and we want to get out of it.
All right, I got to have time to think.
I got to think.
Keep away or we'II start throwing bodies
out the door, one at a time. Got that?
Who is this?
Is there a Jenny here?
Who's Jenny here?
That's me.
It's the squirrel.
You got a husband?
Well, he's on the phone.
Go ahead.
What couId I tell him?
I don't know, whatever.
Tell him the truth.
What a fucking comedy!
W-N-E-W pIays aII the hits.
Listen. Don 't hang up.
-First, is anybody hurt in there?
-No.
Keep away or we'll start throwing bodies
out, one at a time. You got that?
Don't. Let me talk to you for a whiIe.
How many peopIe you got?
No, call me back.
CaII me back.
He wants to know
when you'll be through.
What? GirIie, pIease!
Come on. Let's go.
-Where's the back door?
-It's locked on the inside.
Where is it?
Through the passageway to the right.
Cover them!
You couId just go ahead
and cook whatever's there.
Oh, yes, I will.
Yes, I will.
-Let's go, come on.
-Honey, I've got to go now.
I got to go.
I Iove you too.
All right, inside here.
I don't know what happened.
Maybe somebody tripped an aIarm
or something. i don't know.
But there's a way out of this.
-Were you serious about what you said?
-About what?
About throwing
those bodies out the door?
-That's what I want him to think.
-I want to know what you think.
Because I'll tell you right now,
I'm ready to do it.
Right. Okay.
-I mean it.
-I know.
Listen, everybody.
I know we got a probIem here.
But there's a way out of this thing.
I'm teIIing you.
All you got to do is cooperate with me.
Stay cooI,
and we'll get out of this.
Nobody gets hurt if you Iisten to me.
First, we'll do things a step at a time.
You got to go to the bathroom, right?
She'll get to go to the bathroom.
Everybody who has to go is going.
We'II do things together, okay?
What's the matter with him?
He's got asthma.
Asthma?
I'll take care of that.
-You, what's your name?
-MuIvaney.
Come with me.
-He's got asthma and he's a guard?
-They go to guard schooI.
To learn how to shoot?
He doesn't have a gun.
They earn a $ 1 05 a week
to foId the fIag in the morning. . .
. . .straighten up.
I don't know what they learn.
I want to bIock that door. In case
they try coming in, i can hear it.
Let's move this.
Wait a minute. HoId it!
Let's get rid of this.
You got kids?
I got 2 kids and I'd Iike
to see them again.
You'll see them again.
You're being cooperative.
I got no compIaints
against you, whatsoever.
Whatsoever.
You got bank insurance?
You know I do. You seem
to know a Iot about bank procedure.
I know a Iot of things.
I just want to get you
out of here safe, right?
What if I take you with me?
If you take anybody. . .
. . .pIease take me.
They'II shoot you, you know?
The cops. . .
. . .don't care about bank insurance.
See what they did in Attica?
42 peopIe kiIIed.
The innocent with the guiIty.
I won't take you. I'll take one of
the girIs, a married one with kids.
Cops don't like it in the papers when
they shoot a married woman with kids.
You're all right.
You won't fuck with me?
There's the FBI.
How you doing, Sheldon?
Why didn't you wait
and try to take them outside?
An error in judgement.
Thought the S.O.B.s wouId be remorsefuI
at the sight of a poIiceman.
And you know something?
Nobody said ""hostage"" yet, okay?
We got a bank robbery here.
How did the press guys
get through the barrier?
We don't know what's up yet.
We're setting up communications.
This is Ron Cummins from CBS.
Can you teII me the situation?
We're setting up communications.
Our perpetrators are in the bank.
That's all i can say now.
When I get it, you'll get it.
That's aII.
What are you doing on the fire escape?
I said on the roof.
Get up on the roof, wiII you?
-Get the phone company?
-Setting it up now.
This phone is going to be
a direct line into the bank.
-MuIvaney speaking.
-Moretti here. Let me talk to him.
This is Detective Sergeant
Eugene Moretti.
You're there, we're here.
What do we do?
I don't know. What do we do?
Are the people in the bank okay?
They're okay.
-You alone or you got confederates?
-I'm not alone.
I got Sai.
What's that for, Salvatore?
He's a killer.
We're Vietnam veterans.
Killing don't mean anything to us.
-In the army?
-Yeah.
So you, what's your name?
Why do you want to know my name?
Just so i got something to caII you.
Let's be reasonabIe, okay?
Just give me your name.
CaII me Sonny.
Listen, Sonny.
I want to see
if the peopIe are okay.
Right.
Then i want to work out a way
to get them out.
I want to come over without a gun.
Frisk me so you'll trust me.
We'II find a way out of this.
I just want to find some way
that i can trust you too.
Not be on the street
where you couId shoot me.
-Some sign, right?
-Right. Like what?
Let the peopIe out.
Who do you think you're dealing with?
A fucking idiot here?
They're keeping me alive.
Let them out?
Talk to me. Just taIk to me straight.
I'm ready to taIk.
Give us the women?
No, I've got women.
That's all i've got.
Give me something.
Give me one of them.
-One?
-It's like a fair exchange.
I'll come over. I won't pack nothing,
don't know if you'II take me hostage.
It's a sign of trust.
-How do i caII you back?
-It's a direct line.
Pick up the receiver and I'm here.
He wants one.
Him, right?
Right!
He goes.
What are we deaIing with here?
You have to keep
checking me out aII the time?
Yeah.
He'll need the keys.
Got the keys?
Just the one, Sonny!
Don't fire!
What are you doing?
That's a hostage!
Don't fire!
Hold your fire!
We voted to send him out!
-He's one of the hostages!
-Get away from him!
He's a hostage!
What the hell's the matter with you?
I don't give a fuck!
Get out of here.
Hey, Sonny!
Wait a minute!
That was your fault, Sonny.
We had the communications set up here.
We're not set up properIy,
with 250 cops here.
We don't know
what goes on in there.
-You almost killed him! Are you crazy?
-That was smart!
You say you got nothing but women,
and throw out a guy. What's going on?
You wanted a hostage,
I gave you one.
-Are you going to deal with us or not?
-I gave you one.
You did, but you should have
picked up the phone! Come on out.
I ain't packing nothing, see?
You can come out and frisk me.
You can teII.
-Why?
-To take a Iook at something.
-To see what you're up against.
-I can see. Why come out?
Come out and see it all.
SaI is in there with the other peopIe.
Anything happens to me, they'll get it.
I don't forget about SaI.
Come out and Iook.
-I got to check with him first.
-You don't need that artiIIery.
5 minutes. You tell him that.
Take it easy.
Get them back.
He's got a white flag.
Everything's okay.
Come on out.
He's too cIose here.
Get back!
What the fuck are you doing?
Come on out.
Take a look at this.
Here, look! Look up here.
Over here.
Over there, right?
We got everything here, okay?
You got the militia here.
Let Sai come Iook.
What hope have you got?
Quit whiIe you're ahead.
-It's onIy attempted robbery.
-Armed robbery.
AII right, armed, then!
Nobody's been hurt.
ReIease the hostages. No one
wiII worry over kidnapping charges.
At the most you'll get 5 years.
You'II get out in 1 .
-What?
-Kiss me.
When I'm being fucked,
I Iike to get kissed on the mouth.
You're a city cop, right?
Bank robbery's a federaI offense.
They got me on kidnapping,
armed robbery. They'll bury me.
I won't talk to somebody trying
to con me. Get someone in charge.
I won't talk to some fIunky pig
trying to con me. What's he doing?
-Get back!
-Why are they moving in?
WiII you get the fuck back there?
Get over there!
Go on back there, man!
He wants to kill me so bad!
-No one's going to kill anybody.
-Attica!
Attica!
Remember Attica!
Your word don't fucking matter!
Come on, calm down.
Put your guns down!
Without the TV guys,
they'd kill us all!
Put your guns down!
Put them down!
Attica!
You got it, man!
Robbing a bank?
Why didn't he tell me
he needed money?
He shouId have come to me
if he needed money.
We know that & people
are still being held in the bank.
The situation inside the bank
is totally unknown to us other than...
...descriptions that have been
obtained from Howard Calvin.
Why steal when your mom's a sucker?
We'll switch you now to Ron Cummins
at the bank in Brooklyn.
Miss Benson, what's it like inside?
They're hoIding up,
what can I say?
Got a deaI?
The guy with the gun on us
is a quiet type.
Any confidence in Detective Moretti?
They don't know Detective Moretti yet.
I got to go now.
What's this with the hands?
She's out, Iet her stay.
They're my girIs.
I'm going back in there.
-Howard. How is he?
-Howard's all right.
Put the TV on.
GirIs, I was interviewed!
Looks good.
The media's there.
TV peopIe.
They want to talk to you.
Hello, Sonny.
You're on the air.
Would you answer
a few questions for us?
Why are you doing this?
Hello?
I just saw myself there.
Why am I doing it?
-Doing what?
-Robbing a bank.
I don't know what you mean by that.
I'm robbing a bank
because they got money here.
I mean, why do you feel
you have to steal for money?
Couldn 't you get a job?
No. Doing what?
You know, if you want a job,
you got to be a member of a union.
If you got no union card,
you don't get a job.
What about non-union jobs?
What's wrong with him?
What do you mean non-union?
Like what, a bank teller?
You know how much
a bank teller makes? Not much.
$ 1 1 5 to start, right?
You can Iive on that?
I got a wife and kids. How am i to Iive
on that? What do you make a week?
-I'm here to talk to you, Sonny.
-Yeah, I'm taIking to you.
We're entertainment, right?
What do you got for us?
What do you want to get for it?
-Do you expect to be paid?
-I don't need to be paid.
I'm here with my partner and 9 other
peopIe. See, we're dying!
You're going to see
our brains on the sidewaIk.
You'll show that on TV?
Have housewives see that?
Instead of ""As The WorId Turns""?
What do you got for me?
I want something for that.
-You could give up.
-Give up?
-You ever been in prison?
-No.
No! Let's talk about something
you fucking know about.
-How much you make a week?
-Transmission has been interrupted.
Please stand by, we will return
to our special newscast very soon.
HeIIo?
What the fuck happened?
Guess he disliked your Ianguage.
Fuck him!
I don't know,
they might deal with us.
I don't know about that guy out there.
But if i get the FBI invoIved in this,
they might deal.
What do you think?
What's wrong?
You made a promise, didn't you?
Did you promise me something?
Did you say either we get away cIean
or we kill ourseIves?
-Did you?
-I'm not talking about that.
Do you beIieve in keeping your promises?
Does it still go?
Yes.
What are you talking about?
I won't go back to prison.
Kill them all now.
-Take your bayonet, jam it into their--
-Fuck you!
We ask for a jet.
What do you think?
We get a heIicopter.
We get a heIicopter here,
it Iands on the roof. . .
. . .and takes us to a jet.
And we fIy the fuck out of the country.
We can do it.
We got them.
We don't even know it.
We've got the hostages.
We've been Iooking at this the
wrong way. We make the demands!
They'll give us what we want.
I'm flying to the tropics.
Fuck the snow!
Where's the mouth?
-You ready to go to Algeria?
-AIgeria? Yeah, sure!
We're all going to sunny climes!
I can make it happen!
I've made it happen so far.
I can make it happen.
Give me Moretti.
AII of you, go ahead, make calls.
CaII home or whatever.
We're going on a trip.
I want to talk to you.
-I'm coming out.
-Good, I'll be there.
Let's go, he's coming out.
You must understand something.
If we Ieave the country,
there's no coming back here.
There's no coming back.
If there's anyone you want to taIk to. . .
. . .you want to say goodbye to,
do it now.
No.
Is there any special country
you want to go to?
Wyoming.
No, Wyoming. . . .
That's not a country.
That's all right.
I'II take care of it.
Put them down!
Put them down! You hear that?
What do I have?
See this here, Iook!
I got nothing up my sIeeve!
I got nothing here either!
Want to see my pockets? Here!
You need that gun, right!
Moretti! TeII them
to put their guns down!
Put it in your hoIster!
Put the guns down!
You know what it means
to put a gun down? What's this?
Right! Thank you very much!
You got it, right?
You got it, baby!
Hey, Moretti!
You made it happen!
You got Maria in there!
He's got a gun in there!
Get him the fuck out of here!
How the hell did that happen?
-I got Sai in there!
-Take it easy!
Notify the precinct.
Who the fuck is that?
One of them Spanish kids.
-Who's Maria?
-She's inside.
SaI wants to see Sonny,
says he'II shoot unIess he does!
He's serious!
Sonny, he means it!
It's all right.
-I'm sorry.
-How'd that happen?
You got his girIfriend in there.
You okay?
That fuck tried to kiII me.
-You Iook all squeezed out.
-I am squeezed out!
Let me see your head, all right?
-I'm bIeeding!
-Let me see it.
It's aII right. You want to
taIk to me about something?
ShouId've heard that phone call.
Some creep calls up
and says, ""Kill everybody. ""
Everyone wants to kill everyone.
I think you're going to get
asshoIes like that anyhow, right?
I want to talk to you.
I got an offer.
I want a helicopter.
And a jet to go wherever i want to go.
So i don't want a IittIe jet,
I want a big one.
One with a bar, a piano.
Maybe i want to Ieave the country.
I don't know whether a heIicopter
wouId fit in here or not.
I'll check it.
-It could land on the roof.
-That's asphalt, it'll break through.
I'll call my superiors, you understand?
Why not bring your superiors here?
Why am I talking to you
if you got to call superiors?
-We don't aIways see eye-to-eye.
-Yeah, so I'll taIk to them.
I'll see what they say.
I'll talk to them
and ask them, all right?
Anything else i can get you?
I want you to bring
my wife down here.
-What do you give us?
-What do you want?
The women hostages.
There's no talking to you!
I told you, that's aII I got
in there is women.
You going to talk to me or what?
I give one hostage
for each thing you give me, see?
The heIicopter for a hostage.
The jet for a hostage.
You give me my wife,
I give you a hostage.
Then the rest come home on the jet.
I'll see what they'll do, all right?
In the meantime,
pick out who you want to give us.
And tell me where
your wife is, all right?
I'm here minding my own business,
I hear the transistor go ''Sonny what?''
I can 't believe my ears!
I grab the kids!
I'm telling you, Sonny didn 't do it.
It ain 't him to rob a bank!
It ain 't him to steal or hurt anybody
or do nothing wrong!
He's never done wrong
since the day I know him!
Night before last we're at Coney Island.
I see he keeps a loaded gun in the car!
Things are adding up
how crazy he's acting lately...
. . .and in with a bad crowd.
So i Iook at him.
Get in bed. He's yelling
at the kids like a madman.
Then he wants me to go on a
kiddie ride. I don't want to go.
He starts screaming at me.
He's screaming and screaming.
I say, ""What are you
going to do with the gun?""
Shoot me and dump me in the river?
I was scared of him.
I never been scared of him.
His mother says we aIways fought.
The cops was aIways at our house.
I hit him with a jack handIe
once in the car.
I didn't even hit him.
I hit myseIf.
You shouId've seen the bruise
on my Ieg.
He'd put on his hat and coat,
he goes out the door.
So they tell me he did it.
But i don't beIieve it.
Mrs. Wortzik, listen to me.
They want you down at the bank.
His body functions might've done it,
but he himseIf, he didn't do it!
""Dear Abby: Lately I've been dreaming
about falling into water. . .
. . .and not being abIe
to reach the surface.
I begin to breathe heaviIy
and i wake up in a coId sweat.
A friend tells me that my probIem
is one of sexual repression. ""
Margaret, are you aII right?
Are you doing anything
to any of those girls in there?
He's back again.
Who 's this?
Look at Margaret.
What's the matter with her?
There's no air in here.
What happened to the air conditioning?
I'm sorry, Syl.
Where's the air conditioning?
In the basement.
I'll go check the air conditioning.
I'll be right back.
I never been up in an airpIane before.
So?
I mean, it's safe.
It's Iike a car.
It's safer than a car.
It's all right, SaI.
I'm going to go check it now.
They're coming in the back!
In the vauIt!
-Get back!
-No, don't fire!
That's it, Sonny!
Get her in there!
Who fired that shot?
Pick her up and put her in.
Who fired?
Come on! Move!
Okay, legs!
Get the bullhorn!
You got that bullhorn?
Come on out, Sonny!
That's al i need.
Take care of that, wiII you?
Come on out!
Straighten that out, will you?
Sonny, come on out.
You son of a bitch,
you want to get those peopIe kiIIed?
Come on out here, now.
I see you, Sonny, come on!
What's the matter with you?
-What?
-Why'd you fire that shot in there?
We got 250 cops here!
Fuck you! What were
they doing back there?
What the hell's the matter with you?
Are we deaIing?
-They were trying to get in there?
-Who?
Come on, you know who!
-What's going on?
-You're full of shit!
Find out what's going on there!
-Honest to God, Sonny, i don't know!
-BuIIshit!
Communications aren't set up yet.
Get someone to talk to me!
I'm not taIking to you anymore.
-Let me talk to you.
-You say this, you do that.
Why were they back there?
I don't know!
You're full of shit!
-It's another force.
-A tacticaI force!
They Iike to shoot,
cIimb through windows!
They Iike that, right!
Without your orders, right?
Yes! Without my orders!
You coming through the roof?
I teII you we won't.
You're teIIing me a Iot of things,
but you're not doing them.
What were they doing?!
-I don't know!
-And you can't answer me.
-You can't answer.
-Yes, I can.
So teII me what they were doing.
No communications!
I sent someone back there.
I got a guy in there who's going to kill
somebody. That's your responsibility.
Wait a minute, hold on.
We got everything you wanted.
Can't get a heIicopter,
but a bus is coming.
We got a jet coming
into Kennedy, all right?
We got ahold of your wife.
Your wife is coming.
We reached her
and she's coming here.
Where are you going?
I'm right here.
I thought we were going to talk.
I thought so, too.
But we're not.
We're trying
to get in the back door.
Your wife will be here soon.
They're still pointing.
They Iove it.
Holster that weapon!
Holster it!
You too!
All right, come on.
-What?
-What eIse do you want me to do?
How could you do any better?
We got all you wanted.
I'll do anything i can
to stop anything.
Anything else?
-Yeah.
-What?
I got some peopIe
in there that are hungry.
-Can you get food?
-What do you want?
-Want some pizzas?
-Yeah, all right.
Get some pizzas in.
Can we get some beer, you think?
No beer.
Let's keep it to soft drinks, aII right?
Some soft drinks too, okay?
Cokes!
-What else?
-And some aspirin too.
Some lady's not feeling well.
Anything else?
Don't con me.
I'm not!
Why wouId I want to do that?
I'm in troubIe enough as it is.
I'm not trying to create any troubIe.
It's okay.
They can't bring a helicopter in here.
They can't land it here.
They're going to get us a big bus
so we can all get in.
And that's how we get to the airport.
It looks good.
You peopIe,
I just ordered you some food.
I even got her some aspirins.
So we're moving it along now.
I got to pay for the food.
Where's the marked fives?
That was a foolish thing
you did back there.
Foolish thing.
We going to get the ball rolling?
Yeah, what do you think I'm doing?
I'm working on it.
What's it Iook Iike?
You think it's easy?
I got to keep them cooI.
I got to keep you peopIe happy.
I got to have the ideas
and do it all aIone.
You want to try it?
Your food is here, Sonny.
You're starting to get on my nerves.
Go on with him there.
You'll be all right. Go right ahead.
-What do I owe you?
-It's all paid for.
-No, I've paid for that.
-I got it.
Here.
Keep the change.
You want this?
You like it?
Moretti, couId you use five?
I got a Iot for you.
Get back, goddamn it!
More! More! More!
Could you open it?
Thank you, man.
I'm a fucking star!
No, just pick her up and hold her.
She'll be okay.
You kick good.
Here.
This is where it gets stuck!
Miriam's making a fooI of herself.
Anybody got a cigarette?
Yeah, I do.
SyIvia, you don't smoke!
You don't?
Why do you want to start now?
-I'm scared to death, that's why.
-You don't smoke?
No.
How come?
-I don't want the cancer.
-My God!
The cigarette.
Do what you want.
I think you ought to
take care of your body.
My body? What for?
Your body is the temple of the Lord.
You're serious!
So you rob a bank. . .
. . .but you keep your body pure.
Is that it?
You going to smoke or what?
Yes.
If i die of cancer,
it'll be haIf your fault.
No, it's because you're weak.
Right, i'm weak.
Where's your buIIets?
Mulvaney speaking.
It's Moretti.
Will you guys hold it down back there?
They're bringing in your wife.
-Where's Moretti?
-ProbabIy in the bar.
In the barber shop.
What's that?
We went to Bellevue
where you tld us. . .
. . .said he was his wife.
They were married in a church.
Jesus Christ!
Leon, over here!
Happy birthday!
-Give us some room.
-Watch his head!
He's a queer?
Sarge, he wants you!
Get the shieId out of here.
I don't need it now.
Where were you 4 hours ago,
when i needed it?
He's not going to shoot.
Yeah, Sonny, what?
What happened?
Is he all right?
He's a little groggy.
No, Iet me talk to him.
I'll get him on his feet and call back.
Shut the door!
Stop the noise.
I don't want to hear a fucking sound!
Typewriter!
Get off the fucking phone.
Now!
Give me some water.
You all right? They give you a shot
down at the hospital or something?
They shot me with, like, unreal!
You got to get ahold of yourseIf. . .
. . .so you can taIk to him,
and see if he'll come out.
He's got 8 people there,
with a SaI. You know him?
-No, not really.
-He says he's going to shoot them.
I can't help it.
I can't stop him from anything.
Who will he listen to, then?
I can't talk to him.
He won't listen to anybody.
He's been crazy all summer.
He's tried to kill me since June.
He put a gun to my head.
And he cut me with a knife.
-He beat up my friends.
-Did you contact the police?
What good would that do?
It'd just make him mad. They don't
know him. it wouIdn't stop him.
-Somebody's got to stop him.
-You don't understand. He's crazy.
He's got a wife, children.
He's a wonderful father.
His mother. . .
. . .you should see her. Together with
his father, they're like a car wreck.
It just rolls off his back.
He sees them.
He pays the rent. UnbeIievabIe!
I was the one that wanted to get
married. He didn't really want it. . .
. . .but he did it.
I don't know why.
Why did you want to get married?
I thought it wouId help me.
But it didn't.
I was so confused.
I was doing. . .
. . .insane things.
What sort of things, Leon?
After the wedding. . .
. . .I ran off for 1 0 days
to AtIantic City.
Sonny was frantic.
He knew I'd been drinking. He didn't
know where i was, who i was with.
I couIdn't expIain the things I did.
So i went to a psychiatrist. . .
. . .who told me. . .
. . .that i was a woman
trapped in a man's body.
So right away he wanted to give me
money for the sex change operation.
But where was he going to get it?
$2,500?
My God, he was in hock
up to his ears aIready.
He needed the money
for your operation?
It drove him crazy.
He wouId fly into these rages.
And I got more depressed than ever.
I knew I'd never get my operation.
So I tried to kill myseIf.
I took about a half a pound of piIIs.
BIues, yeIIows, screamers,
uppers, downers, you name it.
And i wound up in the hospitaI.
And Sonny comes there. . .
. . .and he just looks at me.
And he says. . .
. . . ""Why, Leon?
When things were going so good?""
Don't you think. . .
. . .he did it for you?
Yeah, i guess so.
Don't you think you owe it to him
to try to get him out?
I can't talk to him.
You're up to your neck in it.
You're an accessory.
-They can't hold me responsible.
-Wait, you couId help us a little.
I'm afraid.
Just talk to him for a minute.
How can he hurt you on the phone?
I can't.
I don't know what to. . . .
Just talk with him on the phone.
You think about it.
He won't talk to you.
What do you mean he won't talk to me?
I'll work on it.
I thought you were doing that.
He won't talk to me.
They are questioning Leon Schermer,
a 26-year-old admitted homosexual...
... who claims to have married
one of the bank robbers last November.
According to sources in the barber shop
where Leon is held...
...Leon has reportedly said...
... they were married in an
official ceremony by a Father Burke.
Leon 's story has been confirmed.
7 bridesmaids, all male,
Sonny's mother and 7 0 other guests...
...all members of the gay community.
We've been able to obtain
a still photograph of Leon in his gown.
Leon has confirmed...
... that the gowns for himself
and his bridesmaids cost $ 7 00.
We have not confirmed the story...
... with the priest. But we are told
that he was subsequently defrocked.
Phone calls have arrived from
various factions of the gay community.
Some in support of Sonny
and his actions, others condemning...
... the present events
and calling the marriage...
...a farce, and, quote, ''A case
of sheer exhibitionism. '' End quote.
Coverage of the robbery where
2 homosexuals hold hostages...
...for their demands of
a helicopter, a jet....
They said, ""2 homosexuaIs in the bank. ""
Right on TV! You hear?
What difference does it make?
They can say anything they want.
Let them say it.
I'm not homosexuaI.
TeII them to get that right.
That's going out on the TV.
What am I supposed to do? i can't
controI what they say on teIevision.
What should i do? I'm doing
everything i can, i can't do that.
Forget about it. It's just a freak show
to them, anyway. It don't matter.
Whatever they say don't matter.
It'll be all right.
What's the matter with you?
You shouIdn't let something like that
spoil your fun.
You have to get fun out of life.
Where's the goddamn jet?
They're aIways screaming overhead,
going somewhere. . .
. . .when you don't need them, you know?
What are you going to tell
the pilot when you get on the plane?
You have to know, right?
Holland's pretty good.
-HoIIand?
-They sheltered peopIe during the war.
They're good people.
Where's Holland?
It's right up. . . .
It's over there!
Get in the vauit. Come on!
QuickIy!
They're waiting for us
to do something, I think.
Come on out for a second.
It's him.
Come on out.
I want to talk to you a second.
Come on!
Come on out, Sonny.
Come on out a minute.
That's it.
What the fuck is going on?
Get the lights back on.
Who are you?
FBI, SheIdon.
Good.
About time. Maybe we can
get this thing started?
Look, get the lights back on. . .
. . .and the air conditioner.
We got no air conditioning.
No more favors.
That's all over.
Favors?
You been doing me favors all night?
I have a jet, Iimo will be here
in a haIf hour.
I want the hostages.
No, no. Bullshit!
I'd like to work with you on this,
not against you.
The hostages are
what's keeping me alive.
When do i get them?
Didn't they tell you?
I'd like to hear it from you.
You get one hostage for the
limousine that you bring me in.
One hostage for the jet.
Then I get to the airport.
I go into the pIane, check it out.
And if it's okay,
they aII come out.
-I want to go inside.
-Why?
See if everybody's all right.
They're all right.
No, I have to see.
You got guts.
Think if we sIit their throats,
we're going to Iet you out?
I have to see.
I got to check with my partner.
The FBI, SaI.
They're coming in.
You'd like to kill me?
Bet you wouId.
I wouIdn't like to kill you.
I wiII if I have to.
It's your job, right?
The guy who kills me. . .
. . .I hope he does it because he hates
my guts, not because it's his job.
Nobody give your right name.
It's the FBI.
Just want to make sure all you
young Iadies are all right in here.
They asked for the jet hours ago.
What are you doing?
That's being set up. We'll
have you out in a few hours.
-A few hours?
-Why don't you give them what they want?
They'll get it. We want
to be sure we get what we want.
Let's get you all out of here safe.
You two boys too.
That's close enough.
Tell the TV to stop saying
there's 2 homosexuaIs in here.
I wiII.
Outside for a minute, Sonny?
You handled yourself well.
A lot of men would have choked. We
might have had a death on our hands.
But you handled it.
I respect that.
Don't you try to take Sai.
We'll handle him.
Sit tight and you won't get hurt.
What are you taIking about?
You just sit quiet.
We'll handIe SaI.
You think I'd sell him out, you fuck?
What'd he say?
He was just taIking about arrangements.
I talked to him about the TV.
It will be all right.
That's all?
Why couldn't he say it here?
I don't know. He wanted to show me
how the bus is going to come in.
What's the matter?
Someone get a glass of water.
Got a hankie?
They poisoned the pizza.
It's not the pizza!
He's got diabetes.
He had some Coke before.
Don't give him anything. I'll hoId it.
What can we do for you,
Mr. MuIvaney? Tell us.
Is there a doctor out here?
We need a doctor in here.
We need a doctor.
What?
The manager, he's diabetic.
He don't look good.
I got to search you.
Just him.
I've convinced Leon to talk to you.
He's on the phone now.
He's coming on.
Hello, Leon?
Hello, Sonny.
What happened?
How are you doing?
WeII, I'm out of the hospital.
Yeah, I know.
I thought you'd never get out.
I never thought i'd get out this way,
i'll tell you.
How are you doing?
I'm a little shaky.
Moretti toId me that you were all
drugged up. . .
. . .so I figured that's why you didn't
want to talk. I was wondering why.
It was reaIIy terrible, you know?
You waIk in, and right away
they say you're crazy.
Then they start sticking
things in your arm.
How do they expect you to get uncrazy
if you're asIeep all the time?
I'm just starting to come out of it now.
So, how are you?
I'm fine.
This is something, huh?
I don't know.
I'm dying here.
You ever listen to yourself
when you say, ""You're dying""?
-You ever listen to yourself?
-What are you taIking about?
What do you mean, what am i
taIking about? ""You're dying. ""
Do you know that
you say that to me every day?
You're not dying.
You're kiIIing the people around you.
Leon, don't give me that shit.
I don't need that deep shit now!
You don't realize what
the things you do mean.
Yeah?
I know what I do.
You stick a gun
to somebody's head.
I don't know
what i'm doing sometimes.
Obviously, you don 't.
""Go to sIeep
so it won't hurt when i shoot. ""
What do you think
I've been doing in the hospital?
I take a handful of pills
to get away from you.
Now I'm talking to you
on the phone again.
I've got no job.
I don't have friends.
I can't Iive.
I have to Iive with people.
This death business, I'm sorry.
I don't know what i'm getting here
with that shit.
What am i supposed to say to that?
This is going on.
-You're giving me that shit.
-I'm sorry.
You know what's happening.
You know the pressures
I've been having, right?
I got these pressures. You know it.
You're in that hospital. . .
. . .with them tubes coming out
and want that operation, right?
You're giving me that shit.
Everybody's giving me shit.
Everybody needs money.
So you needed money? I got you money.
I didn't ask you to rob a bank!
I know you didn't ask me.
I'm not putting this
on anybody, you know?
Nothing on nobody!
I did this on my own. You see?
Al on my own, I did it.
But i want you to know something.
I want you to know
that i'm getting out of here.
I'm getting a pIane out of here. . .
. . .and i just wanted you to know it.
And i wanted you to come down. . .
. . .and i wanted to just say
goodbye to you.
Or, if you wanted to,
you couId come with me.
You're free to do what you want.
That's what. . .
...I wanted to say to you.
-I'm free to do what I want?
-Right.
I try to get away from you for months
and i'm going with you on a trip?
Where are you going?
I don't know where yet.
We said Algeria. I don't know.
So I'll go to AIgeria.
I don't know yet.
Why are you going to Algeria?
I don't know why.
They got a Howard Johnson's there.
You're warped, you know that?
You're really warped.
I'm warped.
I know I'm warped.
Algeria!
You know they walk around
with masks on, things on their heads.
-They're a bunch of crazy people.
-What am i supposed to do?
-You couId have picked a better place.
-Like where?
Sweden? Denmark?
Yeah, like that.
You know what?
Sal wanted to go to Wyoming.
I had to tell him it's not a country.
He don't know where Wyoming is.
I'm with a guy who don't know where
Wyoming is. Think you got probIems?
So, SaI is with you?
Oh, boy!
You'd be better off giving up.
I'm not giving up, because
why have I done this so far?
I've gone so far with this,
and why shouId I give up now?
I can't give up.
-Would you do me a favor?
-Yeah, what?
These guys that have me down here. . .
. . .they think i'm part of the pIot
to rob the bank.
That's crazy, Leon. That's crazy.
They're bullshitting you.
They're giving you a snow job.
They toId me i was an accessory.
That's just a con job on you.
Don 't listen to that.
I have to Iisten to it.
I can't survive in prison, Sonny.
-You're not going to prison.
-How do you know?
Because i know.
BeIieve me.
Look, please, just tell them.
Tell them what?
That you didn't do it?
Are they on the phone now?
Yeah.
That's great, Leon.
That's really terrific.
You talk with them on the phone.
Really smart!
-I have no choice!
-What do you mean?
What am I supposed to do? There are
7,000 fucking cops all around me.
-Who's on now?
-Don 't lay it on me!
I'm not, but you knew
that was going on, right?
You knew what was happening, right?
Yeah!
I want to know
who's on the phone now.
Moretti, is that you?
WiII somebody talk to me?
Somebody going to talk to me or what?
They on now?
They won't talk to you.
He didn't do it, okay?
He had nothing to do with it.
Will you get off the phone?
Are they off?
That really convinced them. They
wanted to know. Did i do it for you?
Yeah, thanks.
Thank you very much.
So now what?
What are you going to do?
I thought. . .
. . .that i would
go back to the hospital.
They're really nice there. They
seem like they're trying to help me.
That's good, then.
You found something.
I don't know if i have or not.
Are you still
going to have the operation?
Yeah!
So then, what am i
supposed to say to you?
Thanks a lot. . .
. . .and bon voyage.
Yeah, right.
See you sometime.
I'll see you in my dreams.
Right, i'll write a song.
-I don't know. Life's so funny.
-You said a mouthful, sweetheart.
Goodbye, huh?
Give me. . . .
Can i have--
You cut off the incoming caIIs.
Can I have a line?
I want to taIk to my wife
and to my kids.
He wants an outside line,
is it all right?
I want a line.
I'm getting it.
I couId caII anybody,
they'd put them on the phone.
The Pope, an astronaut. . .
. . .the wisest of the wise.
Who do i have to caII?
I just don't know what to do.
Angie.
Jesus!
I was watching it on TV.
-Where are the kids?
-I sent them to the neighbors.
I can't beIieve!
I mean, it ain't like you.
I know.
You've never done anything
like it before in your life.
I'm dying, you know that?
I'm dying here.
I blame myself. I notice you been
tense, like something is happening.
Like that night you're yelling
at the kids like a madman.
Then you want me to go...
. . .on that ride, here
to there, fuII of those kids.
It's ridicuIous. I'm not about to go,
so you yell at me. . .
. . . ""You pig, get on the fucking ride! ""
Everything fell out of me.
My heart, my liver,
just fell to the floor. Everything!
You know what it felt like? You yeIIing
at me in front of all those people?
You never talked to me
like that before.
I think, ""He's going to shoot me
and dump my body in the river. ""
I was scared of you!
WiII you shut the fuck up
and listen to me? Just Iisten to me!
You see that?
With the Ianguage?
I'm trying to talk to you, and you--
A person can't communicate with you!
What am I here? I'm your wife.
I'm your wife!
You know something?
You hurt me.
You hurt me, you know that?
Can you imagine, marrying another man?
Did i ever do anything
to make you do that?
Did i ever turn you down or anything?
I know i let myseIf get fat.
-Don't call yourseIf fat.
-You can 't stand me to say it.
Like i can't stand you being
a bank robber. That's what love is.
Yeah? You know what love is?
If you know what love is so much,
why didn't you come down here?
Talk to me about Iove,
go ahead.
Sonny, I'm scared.
I'm scared. Are they
going to shoot me or something?
No, they're not!
You should see it on the Tv.
They got cannons, machine guns.
They're after me, Angie, not you.
It's late aIready
by the time i find out. . .
...it's just you and Sal. I can 't get
a babysitter! What'll I do?
I think i better take him back
for a cardiac check.
What's the matter?
He going to die or what?
It's just a precautionary measure.
It's awfully warm in here.
AII right, then. Let's go,
Iet him out.
I'm not going. I'm okay.
I just needed the injection.
You trying to be a hero?
You don't look good. We'll let you out.
I'm not trying to be anything.
I just want to be left aIone.
-No one is bothering you.
-I wish to fuck you never came!
That's all.
Don't try to act like
you're an angeI of human kindness.
Out of the closet and into the streets!
Sonny all the way!
Ladies!
I want to apoIogize
for my use of Ianguage back there.
Why? What did you say?
What?
He said the 'F' word.
What did he say?
-Fuck.
-I know, Miriam!
I'm a Christian
and my ears are not garbage cans.
-Then we shouIdn't go after them.
-Then we won't.
What's that?
CouId you come out, pIease?
My mother.
Someone here to see you.
CouId you come out, please?
Sonny, could you come out, pIease?
Mom, what are you doing down here?
I don't need you down here.
AII of Brooklyn is out here.
Three networks of teIevision.
-I got it all worked out, Ma.
-I talked to the man from the FBI.
Who?
No, don't talk to anybody.
He says if you come out now,
everything is going to be all right.
-I'm trying to get you out of this.
-Don't talk to the FBI.
I told them everything. . .
. . .how you were in the war in Vietnam,
I told them you aIways had good jobs.
I told them you were with GoIdwater
in '64 in the convention and--
Listen, I'm getting a plane
and i'm going to Algeria.
I'll write you from there.
-I've got to go!
-I don't understand you.
If i stay and talk to you,
they won't send the limousine.
-They'll think i'll come out with you.
-What's the matter with that?
Because i'm not coming with you.
The FBI understands everything,
that it is not you that is doing this.
It's the pressures from your home Iife!
-Don't get on Angie now.
-Did i say one word against her?
You were going to. She has
nothing to do with it, it's me!
Your life was sweetness and roses.
You wouIdn't need Leon if Angie
was treating you right, you know that!
I don't understand why you
want to sleep with her anyway.
You got 2 kids on welfare now.
-You want 3 kids on welfare?
-I can't talk to you about this now.
What are you going to do?
Come out.
I can't come out.
I can't.
Sal is in there with the peopIe.
If i come out, he's going to kill them.
Run!
Run? Where am I going to run?
Ma, i can't run!
-Maybe--
-There's no maybe. No maybes.
You got to go home. Where's Pop?
He didn't come, did he?
Is he pissed off at you!
He says he doesn't have a son.
-He says you're dead.
-He's right.
I'm a fuck-up and an outcast
and that's it.
You come near me, you're
going to get fucked over and fucked out!
Now, I got to go, Ma.
Get her home, okay?
Just take her home.
How beautiful you were
when you were a baby!
Get her home now!
Ten minutes.
Being of sound mind. . .
. . .and body. . . .
You know what they. . . .
To my darling wife. . .
. . .Leon. . .
. . .whom i Iove. . .
. . .more than any man. . .
. . .has loved another man. . .
. . .in all eternity.
I leave. . .
. . . $2,700. . .
. . .from my $ 1 0,000
life insurance poIicy. . .
. . .to be used. . .
. . .for your sex change operation.
If there is any money left over. . .
. . .I want it to go to you. . .
. . .at my first. . .
. . .at the first anniversary
of my death. . .
. . .at my grave.
To my wife. . .
. . .to my sweet wife. . .
. . .Angela. . .
. . . $5,000 from the same poIicy.
You are the only woman. . .
. . .that i ever Ioved.
And i repIedge my Iove to you. . .
. . .in this sad moment.
To littIe Kimmy. . .
. . .and Timmy.
I hope you remember me, Timmy.
You're the IittIe man
of the famiIy now. . .
. . .and i hope
you Iook after them for me.
To my mother. . .
. . .i ask forgiveness.
You don't understand. . .
. . .the things i said. . .
. . .and did.
But i'm me and i'm different.
I want a miIitary funeraI. . .
. . .and i'm entitIed to have one,
free of charge.
God bIess you. . .
. . .and watch over you. . .
. . .till we are joined in the hereafter.
Here, I'll sign.
I'll spell that Iast name.
Watch out!
Come on, Sarge, just one picture?
Back, back!
You the driver?
I want to check it out.
Seats come out?
They're bolted.
AII right, here.
Light me on that side.
Over there.
You're the man, huh?
I was watching.
I saw you, man!
You shouId see yourseIf,
you wouIdn't beIieve it!
I beIieve it.
Sheila won't!
-Who?
-My old lady!
They said, ""Gas up a stretch,
go to 285 Prospect Park West. ""
Give me some light over here.
I said, ""Shit, another load
from the massage parlors! ""
It's okay.
I'm going to remember you.
This is Agent Murphy.
He'II be your driver.
No, I want him.
-Give me the bIack guy.
-I'm not into that shit.
Nobody will hurt you.
If they were going to shoot,
they wouId've shot aIready.
-I can't allow that, Sonny.
-You can't allow?
What makes you think you can
say shit to me? I'm running this.
I'II pay you. What do you want?
$ 1 00? $200?
$ 1 ,000? Come on.
Don't look at him, I'm running this.
Look, it'll be an adventure.
You men that shoot,
aim for white meat.
Take a walk.
Give me him.
Think i'm an idiot?
Take a waIk, cop!
Everybody is a con man.
I want everyone across the street.
I want them all back,
on the sidewalk!
Let's go!
At Ieast i know
who i'm deaIing with now.
Here's a pen for you.
Come on!
Don't move, okay?
Here's your document.
-Thanks.
-You've got to sign it!
We're taking off.
We're going now.
Sal! Where is he?
That's it, we're going.
Here, peopIe, let's go!
We're going.
-Can i get my sweater?
-Get what you had when you came in.
How are you doing?
Good.
We're going to do it, right?
We're going to do it.
You got to keep your eye on him.
He's the driver.
-I need it.
-No, it's mine.
You got to keep
your eye on him, see?
All right,
where am I now?
All right, hold it!
All right, let's go.
Swing around now.
Just keep holding hands.
Hold it!
Break it on ""3. ""
Not yet, don't break it.
Go!
Fuck, we did it!
We did it!
Wish us luck!
You got your one.
Follow my car.
Get me Kennedy.
We did it!
I'II be a son of a bitch!
Okay, Iet's move.
Come on, honk the horn.
Do me a favor, will you?
Keep the gun pointed up.
We hit a bump, it'll go off.
You set out there?
We're leaving now.
We want no trouble en route.
Intersection check?
We'll be starting up right now.
1 0-4.
It'll be all right.
You just have to remember
to keep the gun pointed up.
What's he doing?
He's still got some
arrangements to make.
That's it?
SaI, see it?
There it is.
I forgot!
I forgot to ask if they
got food on board.
Do they have food on board?
Your jet.
We get one more now.
That's the deal.
Right.
Okay, who goes?
Sylvia?
Maria.
I'll pray for you.
Because this is your first plane trip. . .
. . .don't be scared, okay?
I didn't eat all day.
Will there be any food on board?
There'll be hamburgers.
Ready?
Ready to go?
Yeah.
Let's move.
We don't want any accidents
at this point, right?
Keep your gun pointed up.
Ready to get out first?
Ready.
Don't shoot me.
Now spread them!
We're all secure here.
Murphy will report from the car.
You make the report.
Put the gun down.
Back off.
Get up now, Sonny.
You're under arrest.
You have the right to remain siIent.
You have the right to an attorney
during your interrogation.
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
If you cannot afford to hire a lawyer. . .
. . .one wiII be appointed
to represent you if you wish one.
Agent Sheldon, would you please
remain on the apron...
...until the hostages are
well inside the terminal?
Repeat:
Agent Sheldon, would you please
remain on the apron...
...until the hostages are well
inside the terminal?
Yeah, i got you.
We'll hoId here.
SubtitIed by
****H@RRI3N@K****