I'm gone to the market, Idella.
Pepsodent's new improved formula
cleans teeth whiter than ever.
Are you all right, Miss Daisy?
That's good!
You two get back to work.
- Mama!
- No!
It's a miracle you're not laying at
Emory Hospital or the funeral parlor.
Cucumbers are pretty this summer.
You didn't even break your glasses.
It was the car's fault!
- You had the car in the wrong gear.
- I did not!
Idella, want a pickle with lunch?
Not me.
I'm putting up a jar for
you to take home to William.
You backed the car into
the Pollack's yard.
You should have let me keep my Lasalle.
It wouldn't have behaved this way.
Mama, cars don't behave.
They are behaved upon.
You demolished that
Chrysler by yourself.
Think what you want.
I know the truth.
The truth is you just cost
the insurance company $2,700.
You are a terrible risk.
Nobody will issue you a policy now.
You're just saying that to be hateful.
Okay. Yes, I am!
I am making it all up.
Look out on the driveway!
Every insurance company in
America is out there...
...waving their pens
to get you to sign up.
If you're going to stand in my pantry
and lie like a rug, go somewhere else.
I better get back to the office.
Florine will have a fit if I don't
get home on time tonight.
You all must have plans tonight.
The Ansleys' dinner party.
This is her idea of heaven on earth.
What?
Socializing with Episcopalians.
You are a doodle, Mama!
I'll stop by tomorrow evening.
How do you know I'll be here?
I'm not dependent on you for company.
Fine, I'll call first.
But you know, we have got some
real serious talking to do.
No!
I need you now. I have to be at
the beauty shop in half an hour.
No, I most certainly did not know you
had to call a minimum of 2 hours ahead.
Why call yourself a taxicab company
if you can't provide taxicabs?
Why don't you call your son?
He'd send someone to carry you.
That won't be necessary.
I'll cancel the appointment
and fix my own hair.
Sometimes I think you ain't
got the sense God gave a lemon.
Two dots. I want that!
And a five bamboo.
Well, this is not my day for mah-jongg.
Nine bam!
Thank you all for coming here again.
I am a real pariah without my car.
Oh, nonsense!
When do you get the new one?
I don't know! Boolie's
being real pokey about it.
I'll come after you for temple tomorrow.
That's sweet of you, honey.
Mama, you there?
It's just us!
Why didn't you call?
We can't stay.
So I gather.
The Millers are giving a hay ride.
I had these made.
Doesn't your baby look cute?
Well, it's not exactly
the word I'd pick.
New Graham Greene?
I been wanting to read that.
Sorry, but it's due back
at the library tomorrow.
- Want me to return it for you?
- No, thank you.
I'll go to the library on the streetcar.
Damn it, Mama! Quit being so stubborn.
You know perfectly well...
Go on! Don't keep the horses waiting.
Bye!
Is that door making contact?
Oscar?
I'm here.
- Are you all right?
- No, sir, I'm stuck.
I know. Fiddle with the lever.
It fiddled out. I done all I know how.
Call Bell Elevator.
I already did. They're
backed up until around 1:00.
Did you tell them it's an emergency!
You don't have to holler, Mr. Werthan.
I did not break the elevator.
Got that stuff for Davis & Paxon?
Wrapped and ready to go!
I promised it for today.
Call Bell again.
I hear you.
Look up where the gate is supposed
to close. See a do-hickey?
Wait a minute.
Right here!
Reach up and mash it
up until it catches.
I done it. Now what?
Operate the lever.
Do you work here?
No, sir. This here Hoke.
Hoke Colburn, sir.
How'd you know about the elevator?
I used to drive for a dairy, sir.
Their elevator was
worse than this one.
Hoke the one I told you about.
Of course.
Excuse me, sir.
Y'all people's Jewish, ain't you?
Yeah, we are. Why?
I'd rather work for Jews.
I know folks say they stingy and cheap.
But don't say none of that around me!
Good to know you feel that way.
What was your last job?
I worked for Judge Harold
Stone, a Jewish gentleman.
You worked for Judge Stone?
Seven years. I'd still be
there if he didn't up and die.
Mrs. Stone asked me to move
to Savannah with her.
Of course, my wife was dead by then.
But I said, "No, thank you, ma'am."
I didn't want to be too
far from my grandbabies.
Judge Stone was my father's friend.
You don't say?
Sit.
Later, Miss McClatchey.
Oscar said you needed somebody
to drive for your family.
Will I be taking your
children to school...
...and your wife to the beauty parlor?
I don't have any children.
What I need...
You're still a young man.
Don't worry too much.
Thank you. I won't.
Hoke, I need somebody
to drive my mother around.
Yes. Well, if you don't
mind my asking, sir...
...why ain't she hiring for herself?
It's a difficult situation.
She done gone around the bend a little.
That will happen as they get on.
No, she's all there!
Too much there is the problem!
I want you to understand something.
My mother is a little high strung.
The fact is, you would
be working for me.
She can say anything she likes...
...but she can't fire you. Understand?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, I sure do.
Don't worry, Mr. Werthan.
I'll hold on no matter
which way she run me.
I was a little boy back on the farm
above Macon where I come from.
I wrestled hogs to the
ground during killing time.
Well, sir, there ain't a
hog got away from me yet!
How are you, Idella?
Living.
- Where's the new vacuum cleaner?
- In the closet.
She won't touch it.
It gives me a shock
every time I'm near it.
It works for me.
Good! Then you clean and I'll
go down and run your office.
Where's Mama?
Up yonder.
I guess you know who this is.
I'll be right back.
I wouldn't be in your shoes...
...if the sweet Lord Jesus came
down and asked me Himself.
Good morning, Mama.
Just come down and say hello.
You listen here.
Unless they rewrote the Constitution
and didn't tell me, I still have rights!
Of course.
What I do not want, and absolutely
will not have, is...
...some chauffeur sitting in my kitchen,
gobbling my food, using my phone.
I hate that in my house.
You have Idella.
Idella's different!
She's been coming to me for years.
We stay out of each other's way.
Even so, there are chips
in my wedding china.
You think Idella has a vendetta
against your wedding china?
Don't be sassy.
When we couldn't afford them,
we did for ourselves.
That's still the best way.
"Them?" "Afford them?"
You sound like Governor Talmadge.
What a thing to say!
I'm not prejudiced!
Aren't you ashamed?!
You might as well make the best of it.
I knew a Miss Idella once.
Back down in Macon.
You don't say?
She sang!
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about this
woman had some lungs!
She'd be a whole church
choir by herself!
I declare!
Fat, too!
She was as big as that stove!
Don't talk to Idella!
She has work to do.
What are you doing?
Dusting the bulbs, Miss Daisy.
That's the silliest thing I ever saw.
Who cares if lamp bulbs are dusty?
Get down from there!
Put that ladder away
before somebody trips.
I'm gone, Miss Daisy.
All right, Idella. See you tomorrow.
- I'm going too, Miss Daisy.
- Good.
Good morning, Miss Daisy.
Thought I'd see after your zinnias.
Leave me flower bed alone.
You got a nice piece of ground behind
the garage that ain't doing nothing.
I could put in tomatoes...
If I want a vegetable garden,
I'll plant it myself.
What are you doing?
I just love a house with
pictures, Miss Daisy.
It do make a home.
I don't want you nosing
through my things.
Good morning, Miss Daisy.
It was right cold in the night.
I wouldn't know. I was asleep.
Idella says we're
running short on coffee...
...and Dutch cleanser.
We are?
Yes, ma'am.
We're low on silver polish, too.
I know.
I'm fixing to go to the
Piggly Wiggly on the trolley.
On the trolley!
Why don't you let me carry you?
No, thank you.
Ain't that why Mr. Werthan hired me?
That's his problem.
All right. But I'm going to
find something to do here.
You leave my things alone!
I'm gone to the market, Idella.
Miss Daisy, it's a shame.
You have this fine Hudson
automobile out there in the garage.
It hasn't moved an inch from
when Mr. Werthan drove it here.
That insurance company gave you
a brand new car for nothing.
That's your opinion.
My other opinion is that a fine rich,
Jewish lady like yourself...
...has no business dragging herself
onto a trolley carrying grocery bags.
I'll carry them for you.
I don't need you!
I don't want you!
And don't say I'm rich!
- I won't say it no more.
- Is that what you and Idella talk about?
I hate being discussed behind
my back in my own house!
I was born on Forsyth Street.
Believe me. I know
the value of a penny!
My brother brought
home a white cat once.
We couldn't keep it because
we couldn't afford to feed it!
My sister saved up money...
...so I could become a teacher!
We had nothing!
But you're doing all right now!
What are you doing?!
I'm trying to drive you to the store!
Where are you off to this
morning, Miss Werthan?
Just a little shopping.
Go away! I've ridden the trolley
with the groceries plenty of times!
But I can't keep taking
Mr. Werthan's money for doing nothing.
How much he pay you?
Miss Daisy, that's between him and me.
Anything over $7 a week
is highway robbery!
You sure are right about that!
Especially since I don't do nothing...
...but sit on a stool all day.
All right!
Piggly Wiggly.
Then home. Nowhere else.
Oh, I just love the smell of a new car.
Don't you, Miss Daisy?
I am nobody's fool, Hoke.
I know!
My husband taught me to run a car.
I remember everything he said.
So don't think even for a second you...
Wait. You're speeding.
I can see it!
We only going 19 miles an hour.
I like to go under the speed limit.
But the speed limit is 35 here.
The slower you go the more gas you save.
My husband taught me that!
Ain't hardly moving.
Might as well walk...
...to Piggly Wiggly.
Is this your car?
No.
Do you pay for the gas?
- No.
- All right, then!
My son thinks I'm losing my abilities...
...but I am still in control
of what goes on in my car!
Where are you going?
To the store, like you said.
Why didn't you turn on Highland?
Piggly Wiggly ain't on Highland.
I know where it is!
Now take Highland Avenue.
- That's 3 blocks out of the way.
- Go back this minute!
- I can't turn now.
- I've been driving to Piggly Wiggly...
...since it opened for business.
This isn't the way!
Go back this minute!
Miss Daisy, look. Yonder
is the Piggly Wiggly. See?
Get ready to turn.
Look out. There's a little girl
behind that car.
Yes, I see her.
Pull in right here.
Wait.
Give me the keys.
Stay right here by the car.
And don't tell everyone my business.
Mr. Werthan?
Yes, sir, it's me! Guess where I'm at.
I just drove your mama to the store!
You know, she flapped around some,
but she's all right. She's in the store.
Oh, Lord, she just looked
out the window and seen me.
She'll probably throw a fit right
there at the check-out counter.
Yes, sir. You are right about that.
It only took me 6 days.
Same time it took the
Lord to make the world.
Yes, sir. All right. 'Bye.
Hey Oscar, Junior. How you
old boys doing today?
How the lady been treating you?
I'll tell you one thing;
She knows how to throw a fit.
What's so funny?
Nothing, Miss Daisy.
We just carrying on.
Oscar and Junior been doing cleaning
here for 15 years. Never carried on before!
Leave them alone.
Put your coat on.
We're late.
Idella, I'm gone now.
I'm right behind her.
Hear, oh Israel, the Lord
our God, the Lord is one.
Such a nice man. And such a good,
short sermon, wasn't it?
I can get it myself!
Hurry out of here!
Is something wrong, Miss Daisy?
Something I done?
Yes.
I haven't done anything.
You parked the car right in front of the
temple, like I was the Queen of Romania.
Everybody saw you!
I said to wait for me in back.
Yes, Ma'am, but I was just trying to...
There were two chauffeurs
right behind me.
You made me look like a fool.
A g.d. fool!
Oh, Miss Daisy, Lord
knows you ain't no fool!
Slow down!
Miriam and Beulah, I could see what
they were thinking when we came out.
What's that?
That I was pretending to be rich!
- You is rich.
- No, I'm not!
Nobody can say I put on airs.
On Forsyth Street we made many
meals of grits and gravy.
I have done without plenty of times.
Miss Daisy, if I was to ever
get my hands on what you got...
...shoot, I'd shake it around
for everyone in the world to see.
That's vulgar! Don't talk to me!
Never understand some white folks.
What was that?! I heard that!
Now, Miss Daisy...
you needs a chauffeur...
...and Lord knows I need a job.
So why don't we just leave it at that?
Good morning, Mama.
What's the matter?
No, I don't always think
something's wrong when you call.
Just when you call so early.
What?!
All right. I'll be there
as soon as I can.
I better get on over there.
'Bye.
Come on.
It's not healthy to rush like this.
I eat too much, anyway.
Besides, it sounds like she needs me.
When doesn't it?
Give Mother Werthan my love.
Coffee, Katie Bell!
I didn't expect to
find you in one piece.
I wanted you to be here
when he comes.
I wanted you to hear it
for yourself.
What is going on?
He's stealing from me.
Hoke? Are you sure?
I don't make empty accusations.
I have proof!
This! I found it hidden in the
garbage under some coffee grounds.
- He stole a can of salmon?
- Here it is!
I knew there was something funny.
They all take things, you know.
So I counted.
The silverware first.
Then the linen napkins.
And then I went into the pantry.
And the first thing that
caught my eye was a hole...
...behind the lima beans.
And I knew right away.
There are only 8 cans of salmon.
I had 9!
3 for $1 on sale.
Very clever, Mama.
I missed my breakfast and
I'm late to a meeting...
...for a 33c can of salmon?
You want 33c? Here's $1!
Here's $10! Buy yourself
a pantry full of salmon!
Why, Boolie, the idea!
Waving money at me like that!
I don't want money.
I want my things!
- One can of salmon?
- Well, it was mine!
I leave him plenty of food every day.
I tell him exactly what it is.
Like children. If they want
something, they just take it!
He'll never admit this.
"No," he'll say, "I don't
know nothing about that!"
I don't like it! I don't
like living with no privacy.
Go ahead, defend him.
You always do!
I give up! You want to drive again,
arrange your own insurance.
Take the trolley.
Buy yourself a taxicab!
Anything you want!
Just leave me out of it!
Why, Boolie!
What's he doing here
this time of morning?
Can't be good, I promise you that!
I think it's fixing to
clear up out there!
Excuse me, Mr. Werthan.
Y'all busy?
We have to have a little talk, Hoke.
All right, just let me
get out of my coat.
Yesterday, while you were out,
I ate a can of your salmon.
Now I know you said to eat
the leftover pork chops.
Well, they were kind of stiff.
So, I stopped by the Piggly
Wiggly and got you another can.
Do you want me to put it on the shelf?
Yes, thank you, Hoke.
Be right with you, Mr. Werthan.
Well, I got to get dressed now.
Good-bye, son.
You know, Miss Daisy,
I was just thinking.
We been out to this cemetery
3 times this month already.
It ain't even the 20th yet.
It's good to come in nice weather.
Yes, ma'am. You sure
right about that. Sure is.
Mr. Sig's grave is mighty well tended.
I think you're the best widow
in the State of Georgia.
Boolie's always pestering me to have
the staff here tend to this plot.
"Perpetual care," they call it.
Well, don't you do it!
It's right to have member of
the family looking after you.
I'll never have that! Boolie will have
me in perpetual care before I'm cold.
Miss Daisy, you ought to
go on away from here!
Put that azalea on Leo Bauer's grave.
Leo Bauer. Is that Miss
Rose Bauer's husband?
She asked me to bring it out here.
Where is his grave at, Miss Daisy?
I'm not exactly sure. I know
it's two rows over that way.
You'll see the headstone, "Bauer."
What's wrong?
Nothing wrong.
Nothing the matter at all.
Now, you say...
I told you it's two rows over that way.
It says "Bauer" on the headstone.
What that look like?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about I can't read, ma'am.
What?!
I can't read, Miss Daisy.
You look at the paper all the time.
Well, that's just it. I just be looking!
I try to dope out what's going on...
...from the pictures.
You know your letters?
Yes, ma'am. I know my ABC's.
I just can't read.
Stop saying that!
You're making me mad!
If you know letters, then you can read.
You just don't know you can read.
I taught some of the stupidest
children God ever put on this earth.
And they all could read enough
to find a name on a tombstone.
The name is "Bauer."
"Bauer!" What does that "buh"
letter sound like?
- B?
- Of course!
"Er." That is the last part. "Bauer!"
What letter sounds like "er"?
R!
- So the first letter is...
- B!
And the last letter?
R!
B-R. Brr.
It even sounds like Bauer, doesn't it?
It sure do, Miss Daisy! It sure do!
- That it?
- That's it.
- What about the middle?
- Not right now.
This will be enough for you to find it.
B at the beginning.
R at the end.
B... R.
That's it.
That's all right!
I sure do appreciate this!
Don't be ridiculous!
Let's get all this back in the car.
I'm burning up.
Of course I told you!
How can I be expected to buy it
if you don't write it down?!
I'm sorry, Miss Florine.
I need you.
I'll be right there.
Do you have any idea what it takes
to give a Christmas reception?
It takes an eye for detail.
I told you a million times,
Katie Bell, write it down!
More I cannot do!
We are out of coconut.
I'm sure we can manage.
- I told her.
- You didn't write it down!
I don't need to stand and
listen to excuses on Christmas.
You figure out how to serve ambrosia to
50 people without coconut. I give up!
Don't worry, Katie Bell.
It's not quite the end of the world.
Everybody's giving the Georgia
Power Company a merry Christmas.
Bet Miss Florine beat them all,
especially with the new house.
Absurd!
If I had a nose like Florine, I wouldn't
say, "Merry Christmas" to anybody.
I enjoy Christmas at their house.
No wonder. You're the
only Christian in the place.
They got that new cook.
Florine never could keep help.
Of course, it's none of my affair.
Too much running around.
The Garden Club this...
...the Junior League that.
As if they'd give her the time of day.
She'd die before she'd fix a glass of
iced tea for the Temple Sisterhood.
I hope she doesn't take it into
her head to sing this year.
Lord have mercy!
Look what Miss Florine done.
If her grandfather, old man
Frietag, could see this.
What is it you say?
I bet he'd jump out of his
grave and snatch her baldheaded.
Jump up and snatch her baldheaded.
Oh, Miss Daisy, you
go on away from here.
Wait a minute.
This isn't a Christmas present.
You know I don't give
Christmas presents.
I happened to run
across it this morning.
Well, go on, open it.
Look at that.
Ain't nobody never gave
me no book before.
"Zaner Method Writing."
I always taught out of these.
I saved a few.
It's faded, but it works.
If you practice, you'll write nicely.
But you have to practice.
I taught Mayor Hartsfield
out of the same book.
I sure do thank you.
It's not a Christmas present.
Jews have no business
giving Christmas presents.
You don't have to go yapping
about this to Boolie or Florine.
This is between you and me.
Merry Christmas, Mother Werthan.
I hope I don't spit up.
Merry Christmas, Mama. Hoke.
She fought me on this one.
But it is time for a trade.
I'll bet you'll miss the old one.
No, sir, I don't expect
I'll miss it that much.
Come on, you're the only one
who's driven it all this time.
Won't you be a little
sorry to see it go?
It ain't going nowhere.
I done bought it.
You didn't.
I sure did. Already made the
deal with Mr. Red Mitchell.
How much?
That is for him and me to know.
Hey, Boolie!
Got a gem here.
Got that paper, Hoke?
I got it right here.
Be right there.
Why didn't you buy it from Mama?
Would have saved money.
No, sir. Your mama is in my
business enough as it is.
I ain't studying about making
monthly payments to her.
She is mine the regular way.
The Hudson's a good car.
Nobody knows that better than you.
Best that ever come off the line.
And this here new one, if Miss
Daisy don't take to it...
...l'll let her ride in this one.
Mighty nice of you.
We do what we can.
It is three after seven.
Yes, Ma'am. You said we were
leaving at fifteen to eight.
At the latest, I said.
What business you got dragging this
mess out of the house by yourself?
Who was here to help me?
Lord have mercy!
It don't take more than 5
minutes to load this car.
You're fixing to break your arms and
your legs before we even leave the manor.
You're taking on too much.
I hate doing things at the last minute.
What you talking about?
Been ready to go for a week and a half.
- Give me that package.
- No, don't touch that.
It sure is pretty.
Is that Mr. Walter's present?
Yes. It's fragile.
I'll put it on the seat.
You nearly missed us.
You were leaving at quarter of.
- She's taking on.
- Be still!
Florine bought this for Uncle Walter.
Mama, it's not a snake!
I think it's notepaper.
How appropriate.
Uncle Walter can't see.
Maybe it's soap.
How nice that you take an interest
in your uncle's 90th birthday.
Don't start up with me, mama...
...I can't go
to Mobile with you.
I have to go to New York
for a convention.
The convention starts Monday.
And I know what else I know.
Leave Florine out of this.
She ordered those tickets 8 months ago.
I'm sure "My Fair Lady" is more
important than your relatives.
Those Christians will be impressed.
I can't talk to you
when you're like this.
- We're expected in Mobile for supper.
- You'll be there.
- How will you stand her all day?
- They'll fix crab. All that trouble.
She's just worked up.
Here's $50 in case you have trouble.
Don't show it to Mama!
- Have you got a map?
- She's got it in the back seat.
It's 7:16!
You should have a job on the
radio announcing the time.
- I want to miss rush hour.
- You will.
Congratulate Uncle Walter for me
and kiss everybody in Mobile.
The air conditioning...
...did you check it, like I said?
I got the air conditioning checked.
I don't know why.
You never let me turn it on!
Hush up!
Good luck!
Good God!
Turn left.
No, right! Turn right!
Did I ever tell you about the
first time I left Georgia?
When was that?
A few minutes back!
Go on!
My daughter...
...is married to a Pullman porter.
She is always on the go.
New York, Detroit, St. Lois.
I say, "That's all well
and good, Tommie Lee...
...but I don't feel the need for it."
So here it is.
The first time.
And I might tell you, Miss Daisy...
...Alabama is not
looking like much so far!
Idella sure does stuff eggs good!
You stuff yourself good.
I was thinking about the
first time I went to Mobile.
It was Walter's wedding: 1888.
1888! You were nothing
but a little bitty thing.
I was 12.
We went on the train.
Oh, I was so excited.
I'd never been in a wedding party.
I had never seen the ocean.
Papa said it was the Gulf of Mexico, not
the ocean, but it was all the same to me.
I asked Papa if it was all right
for me to dip my hand in the water.
And he laughed because I was so timid.
And then I tasted the
salt water on my fingers.
Isn't that a silly thing to remember?
No sillier than most of
what folks remember.
Boy!
What are you doing with this car?
This is my car, officer.
Can I see your registration,
please, and your license, boy.
What's this name? Wertheran?
Werthan.
Never heard that one.
What is it?
It is of German derivation.
German derivation.
Thank you, ma'am.
An old nigger and an old Jew woman
riding down the road together.
Now that is one sorry sight.
Oh, my God!
The sign says Phenix City 30 miles.
We're not supposed to go to
Phenix City! Oh, my God!
Maybe you read it wrong.
I didn't. Stop the car. Stop the car!
Lord have mercy.
Here. You took the
wrong turn at Opelika.
You took it with me, Miss Daisy.
And you got the map.
I was getting the lunch!
Go on back. My God!
It aint' more than 30
minutes since we turned.
They fixed crab for me.
Minnie always fixes crab.
They go to so much trouble.
It's all ruined by now.
We going to have to pull over.
What's wrong with the car?
There ain't nothing wrong with the car.
I got to be excused.
I got to go make water.
You should have thought of
that at the service station.
You know colored can't use the toilet
at any service station, Miss Daisy.
There's no time to stop.
We'll be in Mobile soon. You can wait.
No, ma'am.
- I told you to wait!
- I heard what you said.
How do you think I feel having to
ask you can I go make water...
...like I am some child.
I'd be ashamed.
I ain't no child, Miss Daisy.
And I ain't just a back of the neck you
look at while you go where you got to go.
I am a man. I'm near 70 years old.
And I know when my bladder's full.
Now I'm going to get out of this car...
...and go over there
and do what I got to do.
And I'm taking the key with me, too.
Now that's all there is to it!
Hoke!
Hoke?
You all right, Miss Daisy?
Of course I am.
Is that you, Slick? It's Boolie.
How you doing?
Congratulations on your dad's big day.
Thank you, Boolie. Thank you.
Aunt Daisy!
It's Boolie on the phone.
Hey, son!
Uncle Walter appreciates your call.
I don't think he can come to the phone.
Fine. How's Hoke?
What do you mean?
How should he be?
Happy birthday, Uncle Walter.
I got to hang up now, Boolie.
Yeah, I'll tell him.
For he's a jolly good fellow.
Which nobody can deny!
Morning, Miss McClatchey.
Well, good morning to you.
Can I see him?
It's Mr. Sinclair Harris, sir.
My cousin Sinclair?
His wife... The one that talk funny.
She's from Canton, Ohio.
She's trying to hire me.
- What?!
- Yes, sir. She said:
"How they treating you
down there, Hoke?"
You know how she sound,
like her nose stuffed up.
So I said, "Fine, Mrs. Harris,
just fine, thank you."
She said, "Well, you looking for
a change, you know who to call."
I'll be damned!
I thought you ought to know about it.
I'll be goddamned.
Ain't she a mess?
Said, "Name your own salary."
I see. And did you?
Did I what?
- Name your own salary?
- Go away. What you think I am?
I ain't studying working for
no trashy something like her.
But she got you thinking, didn't she?
Well, sir, you might say that.
Name your salary.
That's exactly what she said.
Well, how does $65 a week sound?
Sounds pretty good, sir.
Course, $75 sounds better.
It sure does!
Beginning this week.
That's mighty nice of you.
I sure appreciate this. Thank you.
You ever have folks fighting over you?
No.
It sure feels good.
One dot.
Nine dot.
Two dot.
Mah jongg.
You are the luckiest thing, Beulah!
Excuse me.
I don't know how you can look at that.
See it a few times, you get in it.
Both your brains are
fixing to evaporate.
You can bring the cake now, Hoke.
Don't make a mess with those peas.
Do I ever?
Lord have mercy, look at that.
Ain't she got a lot of hair?
How she get it so shiny?
Washes it in mayonnaise.
- Go on away from here, Idella!
- Yes, she did.
I read it in Life magazine.
Don't seem human, does it?
He will tear you to shreds!
I am not going into that court.
And I'm not giving in!
You are at the end of your rope.
You murdered Carlson.
You have to pay!
Either choose the easy way out,
or you go into the courtroom...
...and let them carve you
into pathetic little bits.
You have a minute to make up your mind.
What happened? She up to
something, ain't she?
- You fixing to ruin it.
- What are you talking about?
You got the chicken too close
together and the fire is too high.
Mind your business.
It's your chicken.
Thank you, Hoke.
Now you enjoy it.
Amen.
Who is it?
Morning, Miss Daisy.
What in the world...?
I learned how to drive on ice when
I delivered milk for the dairy.
Ain't nothing to it.
Other folks are banging into each
other like they're in the funny papers.
I figured your stove was out, so
I stopped by the Krispy Kreme.
I know you got to have
coffee in the morning.
How sweet of you, Hoke.
We ain't had any good coffee
around here since Idella passed.
I can fix her biscuits.
We both can make her fried chicken.
But nobody can make Idella's coffee.
Ain't that the truth?
Idella was lucky.
I expect she was.
Where are you going?
I'm just going to take these things off.
I don't know what you can do here
today, except keep me company.
Then I'll see if I can make us a fire.
Eat anything you want
out of the ice box.
It will all spoil, anyway.
And wipe up what you
tracked onto my floor.
What do you think I am, a mess?
Mama, I'll be right out...
...when I can get down my own driveway.
Stay home, Boolie.
Hoke is here with me.
How'd he manage that?
He's very handy. I'm fine.
I don't need a thing in the world.
Hello? I have the wrong number.
Mama's saying loving things about Hoke.
I didn't say I love him.
I said he was handy.
Honestly! Are you trying to irritate
me in the middle of an ice storm?
Thank you, Wellborn.
Thank you all.
I am deeply grateful to be
chosen 1966 Man of the Year...
...by the Atlanta Business Council.
An honor I've seen bestowed
on mighty fine fellows.
And one I never expected
would come to me.
I'm afraid that my loss up here...
...and my gain down here...
...have given me an air of
competence that I don't possess.
I will tell you that I wish my father
and grandfather could see this.
About 72 years ago, they leased
an old mill up on Decatur Road...
...with I believe 25 looms in operation.
They managed to grow with Atlanta.
And Werthan Industries believes that
what we want is what Atlanta wants.
And this award proves
that we were right.
I thank you.
Well?
What is it? What took you so long?
I couldn't help it.
There's a big mess up yonder.
What's the matter? I might as
well not go to temple at all!
No, ma'am, you ain't going to get to
the temple this morning, Miss Daisy.
Why not? What's the matter with you?
Somebody has bombed the temple.
What? Bombed the temple?
That's how come
we stuck here so long.
I don't believe it!
That's what the policeman just said.
Oh, my God. Was anybody there?
Were people hurt?
I don't know. He didn't say.
Who would do such a thing?
You know good as me, Miss Daisy.
It always be the same ones.
I remember one time back
down there in Macon.
Lord, I couldn't've been more than
10 or 11 years old, I reckon.
I had this friend named Porter.
One day there his daddy
was hanging from a tree.
Now just the day before, we'd
all been pitching horseshoes.
Laughing and carrying on and
talking about how me and Porter...
...was going to have strong
right arms, just like him.
Lord, there he was.
Hanging up yonder in the tree.
Had his hand tied behind him.
Flies was all over him.
I tell you, I threw up
where I was standing.
You go on and cry.
I'm not crying.
Why did you tell me that story?
Lord, I don't know, Miss Daisy.
That mess back there
put me in mind of it.
Ridiculous! The temple
has nothing to do with it!
Yes, ma'am, if you say so.
We don't know. Maybe that
policeman wasn't telling the truth.
Why would he go and lie
about a thing like that?
You never get things right!
Miss Daisy, somebody done bombed
that temple and you know it!
I don't want to hear anymore about it!
- You the boss.
- Don't talk to me!
- Where are you?
- Up here!
Hello, Mama. How are you feeling?
Not a good question to
ask somebody nearly 90!
Well, you look fine.
It's my ageless appeal!
Miss McClatchey gave me your message.
Florine is invited, too.
Thank you.
I guess Hoke should drive us.
There'll be a crowd.
Mama, we have to talk about this.
About what?
About the feasibility of all this.
I believe Martin Luther King has
done some mighty fine things.
If you don't want to go,
why don't you just say so?
I want to go! You know
how I feel about him.
Of course, but Florine...
Florine has nothing to do with it.
I still have to do business here.
I see. Werthan Bag will go out of
business if you attend the King dinner.
Not exactly. But a lot of men I do
business with would not like it!
They might...
...snicker a little.
Call me Martin Luther
Werthan behind my back.
Maybe I wouldn't hear
about meetings at the Club.
Old Jack Raphael at Ideal Mills, he's a
New York Jew instead of a Georgia Jew.
All the really smart ones come
from New York, don't they?
Some might throw their business to Jack
instead of old Martin Luther Werthan.
I don't know.
Maybe it wouldn't happen.
And sometimes that's
the way things work.
Anyway, if we don't use those
seats, somebody else will.
If we do not use those seats?
I'm not supposed to go, either?
You can do whatever you want.
Thanks for your permission.
Can I ask you something?
When did you get so fired up about
Martin Luther King?
Why, Boolie!
I've never been prejudiced
in my life and you know it.
Then ask Hoke to go with you.
Don't be ridiculous. He wouldn't go.
Ask him and see.
All right!
Boolie said the silliest
thing the other day.
What did he say?
He was talking about Martin Luther Ling.
I guess you know him, don't you?
King? No, ma'am.
I don't know him.
I was sure you did.
But you've heard him preach?
Yes, Ma'am, same way you have.
On the TV.
I think he's wonderful.
- What you getting at?
- It's so silly.
Boolie says you wanted to go with me
to this dinner. Did you tell him that?
No, I didn't.
I didn't think so. What'd be the point?
You can hear him whenever you want.
I think it's wonderful the
way things are changing.
Now what you think
I am, Miss Daisy?
What do you mean?
The invitation to this dinner...
...came in the mail a month ago.
Now, if did be you wanted
me to go with you...
...how come you wait 'till we in the
car on the way before you asked me?
What? All I said was Boolie
said you wanted to go.
Next time you want me to go
somewhere ask me regular.
You don't have to carry on so much.
Let's just leave it alone.
Honestly!
Talk about things changing.
They ain't changed all that much.
I'll help you.
Thank you, Hoke, I can help myself.
...can see that the South
has marvelous possibilities.
Yet in spite of these assets...
...segregation has placed the South...
...socially, educationally, and
economically behind the rest of the nation.
Yet there are in the white South
millions of people of good will...
...whose voices are yet unheard...
...whose course is yet unclear...
...and whose courageous
acts are yet unseen.
These millions are called upon...
...to gird their courage,
to speak out...
...to offer leadership that is needed.
History will have to record...
...that the greatest tragedy of
this period of social transition...
...was not the vitriolic words and the
violent actions of the bad people...
...but the appalling silence and
indifference of the good people.
And our generation
will have to repent...
...not only for the words and acts
of the children of darkness...
...but also for the fears and
apathy of the children of light.
Morning, Miss Daisy.
Miss Daisy?
Hoke, is that Hoke?
It's me. You all right?
Hoke, what did I do with my papers?
My papers! I had them all
corrected last night...
...and I put them where I wouldn't
forget them on my way to school.
What did you do with them?
What are you talking about?
The children will be disappointed if
I don't give them their homework.
I always give it back the next day.
That's why they like me.
You talking out your head.
Why aren't you helping me?
What'll I do?
Find those papers. I told you.
It's all right if you moved them.
I won't be mad.
But I've got to get to school.
I'll be late.
Who will take care of my class?
They'll be all alone. Oh, God!
I do everything wrong!
Now set down in here. You're
going to fall and hurt yourself.
I'm so sorry. It's all my fault.
I didn't do right.
It's so awful!
Ain't nothing awful except
the way you carrying on.
It's all my fault.
I can't find the papers.
The children are waiting.
There ain't nobody waiting on you.
You ain't a teacher.
It doesn't make any difference.
Now listen, there ain't
nothing wrong with you!
You don't know.
This Hoke here.
What can I do for you?
It's your mama.
What's wrong?
She's taking on something awful.
Why's today different
from any other day?
No, sir. It's not the same.
I'll be right there.
Miss Daisy, now there ain't
nothing wrong with you!
Your mind done took a turn this morning.
You'll snap back if you let yourself.
I can't! I can't!
You're a lucky old woman.
No! It's all a mess now, and
I can't do anything about it.
Now look at you. You rich,
you well for your time.
You got folks who care
what happens to you.
I am being trouble. I don't
want to be trouble to anybody.
You want something to cry about,
I'll run you to the state home...
...let you see what's laying out there.
I bet there ain't one of them
carrying on the way you doing.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Those poor children.
You keep this up and Mr. Werthan's
going to call that doctor on you.
Just as sure as you born, that doctor is
going to have you out in that asylum.
Now is that the way you want it to be?
Do you still have that Hudson?
You talking about from
when I first come here?
No, Miss Daisy.
That thing been in the junkyard now...
more than 15 years.
I'm driving your next to last car now.
1965 Cadillac.
It's running fine as wine, too.
You ought not to be driving
anything the way you see.
Now, how you know how I can see
'less'n you can look out my eyes.
You're my best friend.
- Go on now, Miss Daisy.
- No, really.
You are.
Well, Hoke, good to see you!
- You didn't drive yourself here?
- No, sir. I don't drive now.
My granddaughter drove me.
My Lord, is she old enough to drive?
Michelle is nigh on 37 years old now.
She's teaching biology at
yonder Spelman College.
I never knew that.
Seems mighty funny to sell the
house while Mama's still alive.
Yes, sir, I imagine it do.
But she hasn't been inside
the door for two years.
I know.
I suppose you don't see her very much.
No, sir, I don't.
It's hard, not driving, Mr. Werthan.
There's no bus that goes out yonder.
Course, I take a taxicab
as often as I can.
I' m sure she appreciates it.
Some days she's better than others.
But then, who ain't?
Happy Thanksgiving, Mama!
Look who I brought!
Morning, Miss Daisy.
You been keeping yourself busy?
She certainly has.
She goes to jewelry making...
How many times a week?
She makes all kinds of things.
Pins, bracelets...
She's a regular Tiffany's.
Isn't that something!
Are you all right, Mama?
Hoke, I thought of you the other day.
- I saw an Avondale milk truck.
- Is that right?
A big monster of a thing.
Must've had about 16 wheels.
Go on away from here.
I wondered how you'd have
liked driving that around.
Hoke came to see me, not you.
This is one of her good days.
Mama, Florine said to wish you a happy
Thanksgiving. She's in Washington.
She's a Republican National
Committeewoman now.
Good God!
Go charm the nurses!
She wants you all to herself.
You are a doodle, Mama.
Boolie paying you still?
Every week.
How much?
Now that's between him and me.
Highway robbery!
It sure is.
How are you?
I'm doing the best I can.
Me, too.
Well, that's about all
there is to it then.
Look it here.
You didn't eat your Thanksgiving pie.
Go on now.
Here, let me help you.
Is it good?
Here comes some more.