Legend has it that it was written
by the Dark Ones.
'Necronomicon Ex Mortes'.
Roughly translated
'Book of the Dead'.
The book served as a passageway
to the evil worlds beyond.
It was written long ago,
when the seas ran red with blood.
This blood was used to ink the book.
In the year 1300 A. D.
The book disappeared.
EVIL DEAD I I
So, what's this place like?
It's a little rundown, but...
It's right up in the mountains.
Are you sure it's converted?
I think so.
What do you think, kid?
I love it, Ash.
I feel funny about being here.
What if the owners come home?
We'll tell them the car broke down.
With your car, they'd believe it.
What about some champagne, baby?
After all, I'm a man and you're
a woman. At least, the last time.
There's a tape recorder here.
See what's on it.
This is Professor Raymond Knowby
log entry number two.
I believe I made a significant find
in the castle of Kandar.
Having journeyed there with my wife
my daughter and Prof. Gatly,
it was in the rear chamber that we
stumbled upon something remarkable.
'Naturum de Monto'
the Book of the Dead.
We brought the book here
where I could study it undisturbed.
Here I began the translations. The
book speaks of a spiritual presence.
A thing of evil that
roams the forests.
Through recitation of the book
this spirit is given license
to possess the living.
Here are the pronunciations
of those passages.
Kanda. Estrata. Amantos...
Linda?
Linda...
They're gone.
The sun's driven them away.
For now...
Better pull out of here
before nightfall.
Join us!
Oh, my God!
I gotta get a grip on myself here.
Thank you.
Annie!
How did the expedition go?
Great. I found the pages
of the Book of the Dead.
What condition are they in?
Take a look.
They haven't aged in 3000 years. When
do we begin translations?
Tonight. Is it all set with my father?
I haven't spoken with him in a week.
There's no phone in the cabin.
It'll take an hour to get there.
You hinted that your father was
onto something with his translation.
What has he found?
Probably nothing.
Butjust possibly
the doorway to another world.
You tricked me.
Yeah, just...
Hello, lover.
Work shed.
Even now we have
your darling Linda's soul,
she suffers in torment.
You're going down.
Chainsaw.
Please, Ash.
Please, don't hurt me.
You swore that we'd always
be together. I love you.
Yes! Your love was a lie.
And now she burns in hell.
I'm fine...
I'm fine.
I don't think so. We just cut up
our girlfriend with a chainsaw.
Does that sound fine?
You bastards!
You dirty bastards!
Give me back my hand.
Give me back my hand!
Ex cuse me.
Ex cuse me...
Is this the road to the Knowby cabin?
That's right. And you ain't going.
And why not?
There must be another way in.
A road or something.
Sure ain't no road.
Why the hell
do you want to go there?
None of your business.
I just remembered...
There is a trail.
You could follow Bobby Joe and me.
Sounds all right.
But it'll cost you.
How much?
45... A hundred bucks.
Tell you what: You take my bags
and you got a deal.
Sure!
That's right.
Who's laughing now?
Jesus Christ. I thought she was
talking about them little bags.
Here's your new home.
You son of a...
Gotcha, didn't I, you little sucker?
I'll blow your butts to Kingdom Come!
See if we don't...
Hit him!
You dirty bastard.
You gonna be all right, honey?
I don't know. I think so.
Sit still for a minute.
You know this son of a bitch?
We thought our father would be here.
Where are my parents?
What the hell did you do to them?
Annie, come here! Come here!
Let's throw him in there.
Crazy buck's gone blood simple.
I am...
I made a mistake.
Wait, wait. No!
Damn right, you son of a bitch!
I hope you rot down there.
Oh, shit!
Everything's gonna be fine.
I'm gonna go fetch the sheriff
and bring him...
I checked all the rooms.
Your folks aren't here.
But these are my father's things.
It's been a few hours since I
translated the demon passages
from the Book of the Dead.
This is my father's voice.
I fear that my wife has become host
to a Kandarian demon.
May God forgive me
for what I have unleashed.
Last night
Henrietta tried to kill me.
It's October 1 st, 4:33 p.m.
Henrietta is dead.
I couldn't dismember her corpse.
I dragged her downstairs
and I buried her.
I buried her in the cellar.
God help me,
I buried her in the earthen floor
of the fruit cellar.
What the hell was that?
Somebody's with him.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Someone's in my fruit cellar.
Someone with a fresh soul.
Let me out!
There's something down here!
It's a trick.
Let him out!
Move it!
Open up.
Come to me.
Help!
Come to sweet Henrietta.
Help me, please!
I'll swallow your soul!
There's something out there.
That witch in the cellar
is only part of it.
It lives out in those woods.
In the dark...
Something...
Something that's come back
from the dead.
Jake, let's get out of here!
We're going, baby...
Nobody goes until daylight!
You listen to me...
Hush, little baby
don't say a word
Momma's gonna buy you
a mocking bird
If that mocking bird don't sing
Momma will buy you a diamond ring
If that diamond ring turns brass
Momma's gonna buy you
a looking glass
Remember that song, Annie?
I used to sing it to you.
Mother?
Unlock these chains. Quickly.
No.
You were born September 2nd, 1962.
I remember it well
because it was snowing.
So strange it would be snowing
in September.
That thing in the cellar
is not my mother.
We are the things that were
and shall be again.
Spirits of the Book.
We want what is yours: Life.
Dead by dawn.
Dead by dawn...
Let me out!
Where are you going?
Help us, you fucking coward!
Set me free.
We live! We live still!
That's funny.
What?
That trail we came in here on.
Itjust ain't there no more.
Like the witches swallowed her up.
It's so quiet.
What the hell was that?
Maybe something trying
to force its way into our world.
It's in there.
We'll all go in together.
Hell, no! You're the curious one.
I'll go with you.
Shit! I told you
there weren't nothin' in here.
Holy mother of mercy.
Father?
There is a dark spirit here
that wants to destroy you.
Your salvation lies there.
The pages of the Book...
Recite the passages...
Dispel the evil.
Save my soul...
And your own...
You're holding my hand too tight.
Baby, I ain't holding your hand.
Where's Bobby Joe?
Hey...
Where the hell is she?
We gotta go out and find her.
In those woods, forget about her.
What's wrong?
Like something just walked
over my grave.
That picture, what is that?
In 1300 A. D., they called this man
the 'Hero from the Sky'.
He was prophesied to destroy evil.
He didn't do a very good job.
Can you find it?
Here it is. Two passages.
Recitation of this first passage
will make this dark spirit
manifest itself in the flesh.
Why the hell would we want that?
The second passage...
...creates a rift in time and space.
The physical manifestation
can be forced back into the rift.
That's the best translation I can...
That's right...
I'm running the show now.
We're gonna look for Bobby Joe
and then we're getting out of here!
No, you idiot! It will kill us all.
She's dead. Don't you understand?
With these pages,
at least we have a chance.
Bunch of mumbo jumbo bullshit!
These pages don't mean squat!
Besides, now you ain't got no choice.
Now move!
Move!
I said 'move'!
You stupid fool!
I'll blow your fucking head off!
No trail.
Where to now?
Bobby Joe!
You'll get us all killed!
Leave him alone!
Get out of here!
Bobby Joe?
Where are you, girl?
You're ours!
No.
I'm sorry.
Get me in the other room. Get the axe.
We'll kill him when he comes back.
But first
pull this damn thing out of me!
I can't breathe. Hurry.
I'm trying. I'm trying!
Shut up! Shut up!
Check out... beside the window.
Check the windows
he's probably...
Help me!
Oh, God!
No, wait!
Listen to me!
I'm all right now.
That thing is gone.
Dammit! I said I was all right!
Are you listening?
Do you hear what I'm saying?
I'm all right!
I'm all right.
Okay, maybe you are.
But for how long?
If we're gonna beat this thing
we need those pages.
Then let's head into that cellar
and carve ourselves a witch.
Groovy.
Those pages are down there somewhere.
The pages, quick!
Nosferatos, Kalamimnon, Kanda!
Let's go.
Swallow your soul
I'll swallow your soul.
Hush little baby
don't say a word
Momma's gonna buy you a...
a mocking bird
I'll swallow your soul
I'll swallow your soul...
Swallow this.
I only completed
the first passages!
That was to make the evil
a thing of the flesh.
You didn't finish it?
There's still the second passage...
The one to send the evil back.
Start reciting it! Now!
Don't look, Annie!
Finish the passages! Get rid of it!
Kanda! Amandat!
Nosferatos! Amantos! Akadiv!
We've won!
Victory is ours!
Kanda...
You did it, kid. By God...
For God's sake...
How do you stop it?
Slay the beast.
'Tis a deadite.
Run for the castle!
Hail he who has come from the skies
to deliver us from the deadites!