BEIJING, CHINA
Who are you?
We're with the opera troupe.
Oh, I didn't recognize you!
I'm a great fan of you both.
Is that so?
It's been over twenty years since
you performed together, hasn't it?
Twenty-one.
Twenty-two.
Yes, twenty-two years.
And it's been ten
since we last saw each other.
Eleven. Eleven years.
That's right, eleven years. Yes.
It's due to the Gang of Four
and the Cultural Revolution.
Isn't everything?
Things are better now.
That's for sure.
Everything's fine now.
Please, wait here a moment.
I'll go turn on the lights.
Sorry to trouble you.
FAREWELL, MY CONCUBINE
1 92 4
BEIJING THE WARLORD ERA
Hey, Yanhong, is that you?
It's been ages.
I've really missed you.
Whore!
Ladies and gentlemen,
enjoy the show!
Laizi is trying
to run away again.
Brat! See how far you get!
Quick, go catch him!
Gentlemen, please be patient.
Sirs, do forgive us.
Trash! How dare you
show yourselves around here?
Fuck you all!
Don't anyone move.
You'll get your money's worth!
Just as sure as my name
is Shitou...
I'll give you something
to look at.
What are you screaming for?
I haven't even said hello yet!
You're a disgrace. You couldn't
even play a monkey right.
What are you going to do
with your life?
Thought you'd get away
with that brick act, didn't you?
It's garbage.
Bring your knives
for sharpening!
Sharpen your knives!
This child isn't fated
to be an actor.
Not with that extra finger.
Think of it.
He'd scare off the audience!
Sharpen your knives!
I can afford to raise him...
but he's getting too big
to keep at the brothel.
Help me. Please take him.
If only you take him,
you can do anything you like.
Don't look down on us.
Don't be foolish.
Prostitutes and actors
are equally despised by society.
But I have no place for him.
What can I do?
Ma, my hand is freezing.
It feels like ice.
Ma!
Get away from us,
you son of a whore!
It's from the whorehouse!
Drop it on the floor!
It's freezing!
Are you bullying him?
Come over here.
Sleep with me!
You're really something!
Laizi, go snuggle up
with the Little Monk.
Catch!
It's so cold outside...
the piss froze
on the tip of my dick.
I nearly turned a somersault!
If you belong to the human race,
you go to the opera.
If you don't go to the opera,
you're not a human being.
Pigs and dogs
don't listen to opera.
And are they human?
They're beasts!
And where there's opera,
there's work for us actors!
Stop squealing!
I'm not!
Straighten that back!
If you think
you're above everyone else...
you'll learn the hard way.
This is just the beginning.
Wait till you see what's in store.
Don't worry, Douzi.
We're already halfway through.
Just keep at it.
Shitou, are you helping
someone cheat?
But, Master, I was looking up.
I didn't notice what was on the floor.
Bullshit! Get me my sword.
And hurry up!
Master!
Get up!
Don't you have something to say?
Yes. '' Forming cliques is prohibited
and will be punished.''
I'm not fucking scared
of anything.
From the time opera began...
it's never enjoyed such
popularity as it does today!
You're lucky to be part of it!
We are!
'' Heaven's will,
not a lack of material skill...
has doomed
my kingdom of Chu.''
I've been practicing kung fu
to keep myself warm.
It's cool outside, quite cool.
But I've become a man of fire.
Get away from me.
I am so strong
I can uproot the mountains
My courage is renowned
I've fallen on bad times
Yet even my horse
Won't run away to save itself
''These are our rules.
We must learn them well.
From ancient times,
man has needed a skill.
Having chosen this one,
devote ourselves we will.
In youthful striving lies
the foundation for future fame.''
Now go off and practice!
Let's hear '' Fleeing by Night.''
''I look back at the Celestial Court
and hurry onwards in flight...
heedless of... heedless of...''
Heedless of what?
'' Heedless of loyalty
and filial piety.''
''I am so strong,
I can uproot the mountains.
My courage is renowned.
I've fallen on bad times,
yet even my horse...
won't run away to save itself.
If it won't run away,
what can I do?
And my beloved concubine,
what shall I do about her?''
Excellent,
not a word out of place.
Give me your hand.
This is so you'll remember
to do as well the next time.
''At sixteen I am a nun.
My hair is shorn at youth's prime.''
Go on.
''I am by nature a boy--''
Huh?
You are by nature a girl!
Can't you see you're wrong?!
I'll punish you, Laizi!
You still can't get it right,
can you?
Don't hit me!
I won't do it again!
Sing '' Dreaming of the World
Outside the Nunnery.''
''I am-I am by nature--''
Spit it out!
''I am by nature a boy--''
Is a nun a male or a female?
A-a boy--
You really are in character.
You can't even tell male from female.
''I-I-I am by nature a boy--''
You've forgotten everything
the master has taught you!
Do it again, and I'll beat you
within an inch of your life.
Wrong! Wrong!
You'd better remember this.
If by chance
I'm beaten to death tomorrow...
I want you to have...
the three copper coins
hidden under my mattress.
Careful!
If your hand doesn't heal properly,
your acting career's finished.
Douzi, in a few days, you'll be
initiated into the troupe.
Just pretend you're a girl,
and don't mess up the lyrics again.
Laizi, have you ever eaten
sweet pea cakes?
What's the big deal
about sweet pea cakes?
Have you ever had millet rolls?
'' Basin cakes''?
They're about as fucking special
as dog farts.
So what do you like?
There's nothing yummier
than a stick of candied crab apples.
If I make it big, I'll eat candied
crab apples every day for dinner.
Candied crab apples for sale!
Don't look at us like that.
We're not sticks of candied crab apple.
Laizi, you're drooling!
What the hell are you doing?
Get back here.
Wow, so many big kites!
Come back!
Douzi!
Run for it!
Hold it right there!
Douzi!
Don't forget the money
under my mattress.
You're worthless.
Get out of my sight!
Where'd you get that?
I bought it
with your three copper coins.
Forget Shitou.
I'm spending your money now.
Ten apples on each stick.
I'll give you two. How about it?
What's wrong with you?
I have to pee real bad.
Not in the middle of the street.
Come on!
It's Manager Wang!
The stars have arrived!
Here, come this way.
My dear sir, this is like
a visit from Heaven!
All you need to do is sneeze
and you get a standing ovation.
We've put you
to so much trouble.
We'll be lucky if no one
is trampled to death in there!
BEIJING OPERA
'' FAREWELL, MY CONCUBINE''
I'll sit on your shoulders
for a while, then you sit on mine.
The king! It's the King of Chu!
What does it take
to become a star?
How many beatings?
When will I ever enjoy
such fame?
Hey! You're pissing all over me!
What the hell are you doing?
I knew you'd go back.
You couldn't live
without Shitou!
We're going to get a taste of the sword.
But I'm not afraid.
For me, it's like having
an itch scratched.
I've eaten my candied crab apple.
I'm a fucking star already.
Who the hell do I have
to be afraid of?
You little runts,
you've come back after all.
Good! I deserve it!
Why the hell did you
let them go?
I've had it with you!
Skipping class and running away
must be punished!
Master, I'll never do it again.
Please let me go!
I wouldn't dare do it again,
Master. I was wrong.
Who told you to let them go?
I'll kill you!
Master, it was I who ran away.
He had nothing to do with it.
Beat me instead!
Didn't you think you'd get yours?
I'll kill you!
Douzi, speak! Say something!
Beg for mercy!
Say he's beaten you well!
I'll kill you!
Running away?!
Speak!
Let's just disband the troupe!
You're killing Douzi!
I won't let you do this!
Master Guan!
Something terrible has happened!
Laizi, he--
The opera
'' Farewell, My Concubine''...
tells the story of the struggle
between the Chu and Han kings.
What sort of man
was the King of Chu?
A peerless
and invincible hero...
a bold and resourceful general
capable of defeating vast armies.
But fate wasn't on his side.
At Gaixia he was outwitted...
by the Han king.
As they prepared for battle,
Han's troops sang victory songs...
which carried on the wind
and echoed through the valley.
Fearing the rest of their land
was already conquered...
the Chu warriors fled
in a great panic.
Even the king was weeping.
No matter how resourceful
you are...
you can't fight fate.
The king had once been
all-powerful, but in the end...
all he had left was one woman
and one horse.
He tried to get his steed
to run away, but it wouldn't go.
He wanted his concubine to flee,
but she stayed too.
For the very last time,
Concubine poured wine for her king...
and danced for him
with a sword...
then cut her throat with it,
faithful to the king unto death.
There's a lesson in this story
for all of us...
that each person is responsible
for his or her own fate.
I am so strong
I can uproot the mountains
My courage is renowned
I've fallen on bad times
Yet even my horse
Won't run away to save itself
If it won't run away
What can I do
Old Man Zhang has commissioned you
to hire an opera troupe.
You're like a fairy godmother
to us.
With your patronage, the children
will have new clothes to wear.
Clothes are not a problem.
Good opera, however,
is not so simple.
When he was a palace eunuch...
Old Man Zhang attended operas
with the Empress Dowager herself.
So you can't put anything
over on him. Not that anyone would try.
You realize that if the performance
doesn't make the grade...
I could lose a lot of respect.
But that's nothing.
He could have you locked up!
I understand.
This kid's got something.
How many years
has he been in training?
Douzi, come here
and pay your respects.
He's got
a nice little figure too.
Can you sing any
old-style operas?
Yes, two.
'' Dreaming of the World
Outside the Nunnery''...
is the hardest female role.
Let's hear a bit of it.
''At sixteen I am a nun...
my hair shorn at youth's prime.
Yet I am by nature a boy,
not a girl.
Why--''
Mister Na, I am terribly sorry!
He's usually very good.
Master Guan,
I'll see you some other time.
You screwed up bad!
I'll teach you a lesson.
Open your mouth. Open it!
You've screwed it up
for all of us!
I'll teach you
to keep getting that line wrong!
Come here!
''I am by nature a girl,
not a boy.''
''At sixteen I am a nun...
my hair shorn at youth's prime.
Yet I am by nature a girl,
not a boy.
Why must I wear
these sexless robes?
I see the joyful couples pass...
in their splendid brocades.
Despite myself,
desire burns in my heart...
and I rend my Buddhist gown.''
For year upon year
'' FAREWELL, MY CONCUBINE''
All over the land
I've followed my king
On his military campaigns
Enduring the wind
And frost and hard toil
I hate only the lawless tyrant
Who has plunged our people
Into an abyss of misery
This little boy...
Master Guan...
Mister Zhang, may you live
as long as South Mountain.
This... little boy--
The people have suffered
Untold hardship and pain
The king has returned
to the camp
Your Highness
I've caused you so much grief
This is a token...
of the old man's appreciation
for the two young actors.
Yes, sir!
The Chu king would have won
with this sword!
If I were emperor,
then you'd be queen of the palace.
I want you to have
a sword like this.
Careful, my little man!
That's a real blade!
No need to run!
What's wrong?
The sweat stings
the scratch over my eye.
Aren't the two kids
going in together?
No. It's an old rule
around here.
Master Guan, I'm sorry
if you don't understand.
The concubine has to die
one way or the other.
Isn't it so?
Master?
Douzi!
What year is this?
This is... this is 1932.
Wrong!
This is still the Ching dynasty!
Come over here.
I... I want to find Shitou.
I need to pee.
Pee into this.
Just pee into this.
Don't waste it. Pee into this.
Come to me!
Douzi!
What's happened to you?
Say something!
Have you gone dumb?
Speak to me!
Douzi.
Fate has determined
each of our lots.
Leave him to his destiny.
All right, look at the camera!
Gentlemen, you have done
grandly for yourselves.
You look so dignified,
absolutely striking...
in any style of clothing.
That's it!
Oppose Japan's invasion
of North China!
Damn! It's those students again.
1 937
ON THE EVE OF WAR WITH JAPAN
Down with Japanese imperialism!
Aren't those the two actors
in the photograph?
You're playing into the hands
of theJapanese!
How can you put on makeup
and sing opera at a time like this?
Have you no feeling
for your country?
Take a good look.
We're Chinese too,
Chinese to the core!
Look at us, goddamn it!
That's right, that's right,
we're all Chinese here!
Chinese mustn't fight
among themselves!
We've all descended
from the same ancestors!
And don't you forget it!
Who the hell
do they think they are?
Why don't they go out
and fight the Japanese soldiers?
Would they dare do that?
Those students!
They are only trying
to find a way...
to kill their spare time!
The one who was yelling the loudest
would make a good actor.
Remember the first time we performed
'' Farewell, My Concubine''?
Only you remember
that kind of thing.
Master Duan!
How could you forget?
It was Mister Zhang's birthday party.
I am the one who introduced you to him.
Where you two became stars!
Dieyi! It has become
a coffin shop now!
I went there yesterday.
I know you've been looking
for the sword, but it's long gone.
SHITOU AND DOUZI,
NOW FAMOUS ACTORS...
HAVE TAKEN THE STAGE NAMES
DUAN XIAOLOU AND CHENG DI EYI.
Cheng Dieyi! Cheng Dieyi!
Candied crab apples for sale!
There's a sea of awestruck people
in there...
craning their necks
to catch a glimpse of their idols.
Master Yuan has come especially
to see you perform tonight.
It's a great honor for us.
There'll be a slight delay!
Mister Duan...
the orchestra's been warming up
for ages. Please hurry!
I know. Let me first practice
a few scales.
That way they know
they're getting their money's worth.
Master Yuan!
Year after year
all over the land
I've followed my king
On his military campaigns
Enduring wind
And frost and hard toil
You be the judge.
Has he not blurred
the distinction between theater and...
male and female?
I hate only the lawless tyrant
Who plunged our people
Into an abyss of misery
Your Highness
I've caused you
So much grief
So, Master Yuan has come
to see us tonight.
I know. I sang so loudly,
I drowned out the horns.
But I wanted him to know
that even without his patronage...
we'd still be the talk of the town
here in Beijing.
You shouldn't exert yourself
like that.
Don't worry.
At key moments...
I squeezed my waist
with my hands...
so I wouldn't run out of breath.
Here?
No.
Stop it!
Master Yuan!
It's an honor.
Your reputation turns out to be
well-deserved.
You're very kind.
Please accept a small,
rather slapdash token of my esteem.
I don't believe
the Empress Dowager herself...
ever bestowed such a gift
upon her favorite actors.
If so, I never heard of it!
Master Yuan, how can our Dieyi
be worthy of your favor?
'' Farewell, My Concubine''
has a long history.
It evolved from the old-style opera
''Story of the Precious One.''
Many famous actors
have fallen down in this role.
Your evocation of Concubine Yu
lifts it into a higher realm.
Impressive.
For a moment or two...
this Yuan fellow
was so entranced...
he believed Concubine Yu
had actually come back to life!
Master Duan...
when the king returns to camp
and meets Concubine Yu...
custom has it--
Yes, Master Yuan?
Custom has it he takes seven steps.
You take but five.
If the King of Chu fails to bear himself
with majestic dignity...
he's little better than a gangster
putting on airs!
Master Yuan, you are a master
of the theater arts.
You are an expert in all the varieties
and facets of opera.
Could we doubt your word?
Indeed, we are presumptuous
to parade our meager talents...
in the theaters of Beijing.
Please give us the benefit
of your advice and criticism.
If it's not beneath you,
I'd like to invite you...
to my humble home for some wine.
There is still so much
to be said about this opera.
I'm terribly sorry, Master Yuan.
I've another
drinking engagement...
with a courtesan.
You have other
refined entertainments planned.
Excellent.
And Mister Cheng?
Ah, then we shall exchange
poetic thoughts some other day.
Excuse me.
Master Yuan,
thank you for coming.
Dieyi! I am leaving too.
Girls! Come entertain our guest.
Mister Duan, this way please.
We haven't seen you for a while,
Mister Duan. We've missed you.
I'd like to see Miss Juxian.
Ah, how shall I put it?
You should have said something...
earlier.
She's not here at the moment.
She was asked out to dinner.
What can be done?
How about this?
We'll find you
a good substitute.
Caifeng, come keep Mister Duan
company.
I'll take my leave.
Tell me the truth.
Where is Juxian really?
Upstairs or down?
The phoenix roosts
on the highest branches, of course!
But she's pretty high-class.
You reckon she'll go for you?
You bet!
I specialize in high-class.
Oh, Miss Juxian--
Bastards!
Okay, we're bastards!
Go ahead then.
What are you waiting for?
I'll bet those guys
make mincemeat out of you!
I'm really angry now!
We like it when you're angry!
Cut it out or I'll jump!
Jump! I'll follow on your heels.
Such a death would be ecstasy.
I'd be a very happy ghost.
If you die, we'll all die
and be the planks in your coffin.
Xiaolou!
These guys are revolting!
They were forcing me
to drink wine from their mouths.
Come on, assholes. Jump!
This lady has done it.
Now it's your turn!
Bastards!
Pack of fucking sissies!
All right, if we have
to go down, let's go!
Oh, it's Mister Duan!
Listen, we're all here
to have a good time...
and spend lots of money.
So let's not pick fights
with each other.
Keep out of it, and get lost.
Don't get upset.
Scared?
Juxian, this is really
all your fault.
Didn't you tell these gentlemen
today's a special day?
That we decided to announce
our engagement today?
That's right!
Today is the lady's happy day.
Aren't you going
to offer congratulations?
Drink a toast to me!
Think you can fool us
with this little act?
Gentlemen, on this,
my happiest day...
allow me to drink
to all of you!
And now,
something to sober you up.
Wish us well.
I heard you got into a fight
at the House of Blossoms.
You know the old story...
about Pan Jinlian's husband
meeting the man who screwed her?
Did he have any choice
but to fight?
Does this mean there's
a Pan Jinlian in your life?
What are you saying?
What do you want to hear?
I was just fooling around.
You know, damsel in distress
and all that.
Come with me sometime.
You'll see what it's like.
I'm sorry. I really am!
I wasn't thinking. I really put
my foot in it this time.
I'm a damn fool.
Have you forgotten
the secret of our success?
Don't you remember
our teacher's words?
Which words were they?
''Stick together
until the day you die.''
I want you to be with me.
I mean...
I want to be with you
the rest of my life.
We've come this far together,
haven't we?
It's not enough.
I'm talking about a lifetime.
One year, one month, one day,
even one second less...
makes it less than a lifetime!
Dieyi, you really are obsessed.
Your obsession with the stage
carries over into your everyday life.
But how are we going
to get through the days...
and make it in the real world
among ordinary people?
Give me a hand with my makeup,
will you?
So you want to become
a rich man's wife!
Go live out
this goddamn fantasy, then.
Don't think that
when you walk out this door...
you'll become a lady of virtue!
You think the wolves and tigers
won't recognize your scent anymore?
I'm so scared!
Let me tell you something.
Once a whore, always a whore.
Just remember that.
This is your fate!
Fine. See you around.
Master Yuan has presented you
with a pennant.
It reads,
''The Beauty of the Age.''
What are you doing here?
What is it, Juxian?
Come on in!
No, you come out!
What are you doing barefoot
on such a cold day?
What's happened?
I was kicked out.
The House of Blossoms
won't keep an engaged woman.
Come. Let me introduce you.
This is Miss Juxian.
This is my stage brother, Dieyi.
You may have seen him
as Concubine Yu.
Xiaolou speaks of you so often,
I feel like we're old friends.
Miss Juxian.
Excuse me, I must be going.
Xiaolou, that day
at the House of Blossoms...
if you hadn't caught me,
I'd be six feet under by now.
Remember, it was you
who proposed to me.
I'm used to hardship.
If you take me in...
I'll wait on you hand and foot.
If you tire of me,
I'll kill myself.
No big deal, really.
What a dragon lady!
Incredible!
This is a major production.
When's the performance of...
''Candlelit Night
in the Bridal Chamber''?
Tonight.
Hold on.
I want a formal
engagement ceremony...
to which the entire company
is invited.
I want to enter your home
as a proper bride.
You don't think I plan
to cut corners, do you?
The formal engagement ceremony
will be tonight.
Gentlemen, we request
the pleasure of your company.
Miss Juxian...
where did you study opera?
Me, study opera?
What makes you think I studied opera?
Just the way you're overplaying
your part.
Dieyi, she's going to be
your sister-in-law.
Be nice.
Also, at the engagement party
tonight...
I'd like you to be best man.
I haven't learned the opera
''Gangster King and His Whore.''
Our teacher never taught us
that one.
What are you talking about?
Dieyi, Xiaolou has only
the nicest things to say about you..
both in public and in private.
Don't leave!
Where are you going?
None of your business.
Xiaolou!
Please don't go!
Master Yuan wants us
to visit him tonight.
He wants to become our patron.
Who does he think he is?
No one tells me what to do.
I'm just a fake king.
You really are Concubine Yu.
Let him patronize you
if you like.
Xiaolou!
This feather headpiece
is rare and precious.
The feathers are collected
from the tails of live peacocks.
That's the secret...
to keeping the feathers
soft and colorful.
I'll be waiting for you.
In this world, there is foulness
in both men and women.
Only the bodhisattva embodies
both male and female essences.
Such ecstasy!
This sword has a history.
It once belonged
to the eunuch Zhang.
When Zhang went bankrupt,
I went to great trouble to acquire it.
I can see from this...
you're old acquaintances.
Amazing. One searches
far and wide for something...
only to stumble upon it
by chance.
Like it?
I--
Let's not have any vulgar talk
of money between us.
A precious sword is the classic gift
for one's most intimate friend.
Mister Cheng...
will you be
my most intimate friend?
The soldiers of Han
Have invaded
The songs of Chu
Can be heard on all sides
Since the good king
Has lost his fighting spirit
Why should his humble concubine
Value her life
Don't!
It's a real sword!
''A smile ushers in the spring.
A tear does darken
all the world.
How truly does this befit you.
Only you are possessed
of such charm.''
Where are you going?
He's crazy.
Ah, Mister Cheng.
I knew you'd come.
We saved a seat
at the head table for you.
Xiaolou! Xiaolou!
Well, if it isn't Dieyi!
It's a good thing you showed up.
Otherwise--
Have a look at this.
What a sword!
But we're not on stage.
What would I want with a sword?
Dieyi, you've come so late.
I ought to punish you
by making you drink this.
Yes, drink up!
My gratitude, Miss Juxian.
Dieyi? Mister Cheng!
Xiaolou...
from now on, we'll no longer
perform together.
Mister Cheng, you can't do this!
This isn't-The fans won't--
This is terrible!
Japanese troops
have entered the city!
Dieyi. Where is Dieyi?
BEIJING OPERA
''THE DRUNKEN CONCUBINE''
Dieyi said it looks better
if the eyebrow is very high.
Please! Your troops are
upsetting the performance.
Look at this, Mister Duan.
I won't stand for it! Tell him
to take it off immediately.
Xiaolou!
What's the fuss?
It's only a costume.
If it was the shroud
from your grandma's coffin...
you'd still have
to give it to me.
Understand me, lowlife?
Tell the Japanese
I'll be there right away.
Hold on a moment.
It's not some private party.
They're blackmailing you to sing
for them.
On the other hand,
you're the only one...
who can save Xiaolou.
On the other hand,
if anything happened to you...
this theater of mine would--
All right, go then.
Miss Juxian, what are you doing?
Mister Cheng isn't at home!
Where's Dieyi? Dieyi?
Hurry! I've heard the Japanese
feed prisoners to their dogs!
And you know Xiaolou's temper.
If you delay, he might not have
a life to save!
Dieyi!
But you allowed them
to take him away in the first place.
What are you saying?
Xiaolou has looked after you
since you were small.
Glad you realize that.
Mister Na, would you mind
leaving the room for a moment?
I have something to say to Dieyi
in private.
Everyone says Miss Juxian
is quite clever...
and her timing in this case
certainly proves it.
We're all trying to help Xiaolou.
Talk it over.
How about a clear answer?
Are you going or not?
Say something!
I know what's on your mind.
I have a proposal.
If you can get Xiaolou
out of there in one piece...
I'll go back
to the House of Blossoms.
I'll keep away from both of you.
How's that?
At the House of Blossoms,
you don't have to worry about much.
Life is a lot simpler there.
Just remember, you said it,
not me.
I give my word.
KUEN-STYLE OPERA
'' PEONY PAVILION''
The flowers have blossomed
Their season is past
All has fallen
Into ruin and decay
Xiaolou!
My brother!
Xiaolou, are you all right?
Did you sing for theJapanese?
There's one called Aoki.
He genuinely likes opera.
Xiaolou!
All right. Come here!
Let me have another drink!
Okay. I'll drink one for you.
Come on!
I think this opera,
'' Farewell, My Concubine''...
has turned into...
'' Farewell, My King.''
The king's really irrelevant.
Drink this and your voice
will pierce the heavens...
yet be tender and more fluid
than water.
Don't move!
Forget the opera.
Let's just live a quiet life.
We'll have
a fat little baby boy.
Then I'll have everything
I want. That's enough.
No more opera.
Let's go! Let's go!
See you around, Xiaolou!
Wait! You forgot something.
Don't think he's stupid!
Give him back the money!
We need the money!
Get lost!
Some friends they are!
They only wanted
to take advantage of us.
Get a job? I am an actor.
What else do you want me to do!
You are the one who doesn't want me
to sing opera anymore. Now what?
Get a job? That's easy for you to say.
I know nothing but opera.
Happy now?
You're not mad at me, are you?
Here, take this.
Are you finished?
All right. I knew
I shouldn't have said that.
But your friends really leave me
no choice.
They are a bad influence!
Master Kwang wants you
to work for him.
I am not going.
How could I face my master?
Watch out, here I come.
Sir, they're here!
Who?
Dieyi and Xiaolou.
They came as soon as they heard
you wanted to see them.
Oh, this really is something!
Master!
The two famous actors are here!
We are unworthy of you.
You are so kind to come by.
I'm deeply honored.
Please, have a seat.
Let this decrepit old man
pay his respects.
Master, we wouldn't presume.
Wouldn't presume!
What wouldn't you presume?!
Cheng Dieyi...
Xiaolou helped make you
what you are today.
Now he's not singing anymore.
It's time for you
to give him a hand.
Come on!
Do it!
Little Douzi!
Little Shitou!
There's been a lot of water
under the bridge...
since you were children.
Now...
you're great actors,
but you're arrogant.
But have you forgotten?
Don't you have the heart
for it anymore?
Did I tell you to spoil
and indulge him?
Did I tell you
to cover up for him?
Did I tell you to sit by
while he wastes his talents?
Master!
It's my fault. I'm a failure.
Punish me!
Listen to me, grandpa.
Can you guess
what I have to say?
Xiaolou belongs to me
these days.
If you want to hit him,
you've got to notify me first.
Juxian!
It's that girl from the
House of Blossoms, isn't it?
Today, you are
our number one guest.
Make yourself comfortable.
Have a drink and a look around.
Please.
Did I teach you to indulge
yourself and go whoring?
Did I teach you
to pawn your costumes?
To desecrate the opera?
Good! I deserve it!
Hold on!
If he's desecrating the opera,
you ought to punish him.
But don't you think
his stage brother...
has a part in it as well?
Juxian!
I'm from the House of Blossoms.
This is none of my business...
but as their teacher...
shouldn't you listen
to both sides of the story?
Shut up! This is between us men!
Keep out of it!
Duan Xiaolou...
you really are a tender soul!
Hit me again!
If you don't shut up, I'll kill you.
Don't!
Go ahead.
You'll take two lives at once.
The Duan family line
will stop with you!
Who told you to stand up?
Shitou,
are you paying attention?
You're going to be a father.
If you keep wasting your time
and lose your skills...
how are you going to afford
a celebration for the baby?
Kneel closer to one another!
Closer!
Get to work!
Straighten up!
Stretch those legs! Stretch!
Wait a minute!
You're practicing
'' Fleeing by Night,'' aren't you?
You're playing Lin Chong.
Who's this Lin Chong?
He's head of the palace guard,
not some sneaky little thief.
Take this.
Attention, everyone!
This is what a great hero
is like.
''A man doesn't
lightly shed his tears...
unless his heart has broken.''
Don't! Master told me to kneel
for seven days as punishment.
The troupe has disbanded.
What's the point
of this idiotic kneeling?
Master said that only you
can make yourself a great actor.
Everyone else has left.
You ought to go home too.
I was found on the street as a baby.
I've got no other home.
Do you know who found you?
No! They said if I knew, I'd get
a swelled head and wouldn't work hard.
Do you still want to sing opera?
Yes, even if I have to beg
to support myself!.
What's your name?
Xiao Si.
1 945
THE JAPANESE SURRENDER...
AS CHIANG KAI-SHEK'S
NATIONALIST ARMY RETAKES BEIJING.
I hear the talk of the soldiers
Xiao Si, go tell the manager
to avoid trouble.
And it is all about running away
What's this?
Why aren't you singing?
Don't make trouble!
Don't go, Xiaolou.
It's not worth it!
Soldiers! Gentlemen!
Waving flashlights is not
acceptable behavior in the theater.
Even the Japanese
didn't do this sort of thing.
Everyone's here for the opera.
Please return to your seats.
Well put.
Back to your seats, everyone!
But can we let him get away
with speaking up for the Japanese?
No!
Get him!
Fuck your mother!
Xiaolou!
Leave him alone!
Juxian!
Hurry!
I'm here, Juxian.
Get her a stool. Hurry!
We have to get her
to a hospital.
Save her first
and worry about the baby later.
Let us through!
There was only
a minor disturbance.
Is such a show of force
really necessary?
You can fine us.
Why do you need
to arrest anyone?
The theater's been trashed,
people beaten...
and you still want
to arrest him?
Why?
What for?
Cheng Dieyi betrayed the country
to the Japanese.
Move it!
How can you say that about him?
Teacher, teacher!
Mister Duan!
Mister Duan, I'm afraid
she's lost the baby.
Xiaolou, I'm so sorry.
Go help Dieyi
if he's more important to you.
I don't know whether Dieyi
goes looking for trouble...
or if it's trouble
that comes looking for him.
But sooner or later,
they always meet.
Whenever you're with him,
my heart's in my throat.
Now that I've lost our child,
you're all I have left.
I don't care if I have to beg
with you on the streets.
All I ask...
is peace of mind.
If you help him now,
we'll no longer owe him anything.
Don't perform with him anymore.
Promise me this.
Put it in writing.
Master Yuan...
Dieyi's life is in your hands.
Count this.
If it's not enough--
If only you'll save Dieyi...
we'll give all our earnings
for the next three years.
You think I need your money
to keep my birds from starving?
And this gentleman is...?
Don't you recognize Xiaolou?
He plays the king
to Dieyi's concubine.
Then it should be he
who saves Concubine Yu!
My dear man, that's only a play!
All Beijing knows that Master Yu
is the true king of the theater!
It's true.
Speaking of theater, I'd like to
ask Mister Duan something.
When the king returns
to see Concubine Yu...
how many steps should he take?
Seven.
Show me.
Come on, show me!
Master Yuan.
Is this the honorable home
of Mister Yuan?
When a man called Cheng Dieyi
was arrested, he said...
the owner of this sword
would be able to rescue him.
Have a look.
Do you recognize it?
From your expression, I see I've come
to the right place.
Good. I'll put the sword here.
I'm so relieved
to have found its owner.
But sometimes one's hopes
are misplaced.
Master Yuan,
you mustn't blame Dieyi.
I see.
He didn't say I...
I put him up to it, did he?
If you were involved...
he wouldn't be in trouble,
would he?
True!
Oh, dear!
There's a roomful of reporters
waiting at home.
Xiaolou, Mister Na, let's go.
Wait a moment! Let's talk.
Master Yuan asked me
to talk to you.
Tomorrow in court...
say the Japanese
put a gun to your head.
Say they tortured you.
Master Yuan has made arrangements
for everything else.
This is from Xiaolou.
Dieyi, don't be angry with us.
The death of Xiaolou's child...
was karmic retribution
for your partnership.
After you get out of here,
just go your own way.
Cheng Dieyi betrayed the country
by performing for theJapanese.
You encouraged the enemy
and disgraced your people.
Aoki continued to resist
even after Japan officially surrendered.
That's why we shot him
when we found him.
We've collected these pictures
as evidence...
and they confirm the defendant
sang for the Japanese.
We call on the witnesses Yuan Shiqing,
Duan Xiaolou and Na Kun.
The government has always
been good to me.
I wouldn't dare
deceive the court.
Nor would I betray the laws
of Heaven or my own conscience.
Cheng Dieyi was taken away
in handcuffs by the Japanese.
They put a gun
to the back of his neck.
Duan Xiaolou!
Uh, it's true.
The Japanese beat up
my stage brother.
Exactly as Master Yuan
has just described.
Na Kun!
He--
The prosecutor claims Cheng
performed obscene material.
That is ridiculous!
Cheng performed highlights
from '' Peony Pavilion'' that night.
Anyone with any common sense
knows that...
'' Peony Pavilion'' is
the quintessential Chinese opera.
How can that be obscene
to the prosecutor's eye?
How dare they insult
our tradition and culture like this!
Who's disparaging
Chinese tradition...
and disrespecting its culture?
We ask the accused, Cheng Dieyi:
Have the witnesses
told the truth?
The court wishes to hear...
what the accused has to say.
Cheng Dieyi!
I sang for the Japanese.
I hate the Japanese too.
But they didn't lay a hand
on me.
Cheng Dieyi...
you have the right and duty
to clear your name.
Reconsider carefully
and tell us again what happened.
If Aoki had lived...
he'd have taken
the Beijing Opera to Japan.
Why don't you just kill me?
Master Yuan, Master Yuan!
How did you people get in here?
Please, Master Yuan,
don't leave.
What does it matter?
He's as good as dead.
Master Yuan, you can't go.
If you go, he's finished for sure.
The court has made its decision.
The case of the traitor
Cheng Dieyi is suspended.
The accused is released
under bond.
Court dismissed!
What's going on?
Dieyi, are you playing with me,
goddamn it?
Good-bye, Mister Cheng.
This way, Mister Cheng.
NATIONALIST HEADQUARTERS
The commander has arrived.
Attention!
KUEN-STYLE OPERA
'' PEONY PAVILION''
Chunxiang!
Miss!
How can one know
spring's color...
unless one visits the garden?
'' Ma, did you get my last letter?
Everything's fine here.
Don't worry about me.
My stage brother Xiaolou
looks after me with great kindness.
We rehearse by day
and perform at night...
just like before.
-The world's not what it used to be,
but all we ask is a peaceful life.
We sing and get paid for it.
What more could you want?''
Lucky, the cat, wants you
to blow more opium smoke at her.
See that?
It sure makes her come to life!
Dieyi, should I mail this to...?
The usual address.
Done!
All you classic consumptive heroines
burn your letters.
Have you seen this?
Do you want it?
If you don't, I'll tear it up.
I'll do it!
Xiao Si!
I gave Master Duan the sword
returned to you by Master Yuan.
The river's course is twisted,
but in the end it flows to the sea.
But what gulf still lies
between our concubine and our king?
Talk to each other already.
The Han king
is about to enter the city!
1948 THE EVE OF
THE NATIONALIST EVACUATION
TO TAIWAN
THE COMMUNISTS HAVE
SURROUNDED THE CITY.
For better or worse, we Manchus
ruled for three centuries.
The Republic's only just begun,
and already it's being overthrown.
But even the Communists
have to have opera.
The empire may change hands,
but rest assured...
you'll still get top billing
at the celebrations for the new regime.
We're just waiting to see
what their money looks like.
Well, do you still want to fight
their ragtag troops?
Of course I'll fight them...
if they don't behave themselves.
If you had Master Yuan's class,
you'd prosper...
no matter who was in power.
It's not the same for us!
Do you recognize me?
Cigarettes! Buy one!
Mister Zhang, don't you know us?
Buy a pack!
1949 THE COMMUNIST PEOPLE'S
LIBERATION ARMY ENTERS BEIJING.
Xiao Si...
have them sing whatever
the crowd wants to hear.
Just avoid a scene.
Honorable guests...
I'm very sorry.
Today my fellow actor is--
Mister Cheng, if you can't take it,
have another smoke.
Xiao Si, go call Mister Duan.
Down with the counter-revolutionary
Yuan Shiqing!
Yuan Shiqing is an enemy
of the People and he must die!
We must raise our level of vigil
and see what has been going on!
Yuan Shiqing
has always opposed...
the Communist Party
and the People.
He has harmed his community
and is guilty of monstrous crimes.
Only execution can satisfy
the People's anger!
Down with the counter-revolutionary
Yuan Shiqing!
Down with the tyrant
of the opera world, Yuan Shiqing!
Death to Yuan Shiqing!
Execute Yuan Shiqing!
Take him away!
Only execution can satisfy
the People's anger?
Just like that?
They're going to kill
Master Yuan?
Keep your voice down.
Let me go! Release me!
Fuck you!
Stop carrying on!
Are you listening?
You'll get over it with time.
Good, calm down.
Everything will be okay.
Fuck you!
Cut it out or I'll hit you!
How is he?
We may need to wean him
from the opium slowly.
Keep an eye on him.
Don't let him hurt himself.
Don't go, Xiaolou.
If he really wants to overcome
his addiction...
he's going to have to go through hell!
This is just the start.
My hand is freezing!
It feels like ice.
My hand is freezing.
It's okay.
Everything's all right.
The sky of the liberated areas
is clear and blue.
The people of the liberated
areas are all very happy.
Mrs. Duan!
Where were you?
A meeting.
A meeting?
Xiaolou,
the whole troupe's come.
Come on in. Quick!
Ah, a costume change!
Thank you all for coming to see me.
I'm fine now.
Sounds easy now.
You didn't see him suffer!
Dieyi, get out of bed.
All of Beijing is waiting
with bated breath...
for the next appearance
of the King and his Concubine!
It'll be the goddamn golden hit
of a golden era.
You've asked me to say a few words.
I'm not sure how to put it.
I think these modern operas
are interesting...
but the costumes
aren't very attractive.
The backdrops are too realistic.
Nothing pleases the eye.
Yet Beijing Opera puts
great value on ambiance.
Song recital, movement and acrobatics
are part of this ambiance.
But if you're wearing outfits
like these...
and standing in front of those
backdrops, it just doesn't work.
I fear that this will be
the end of opera as we know it.
What do all of you think?
Are you saying that modern operas
aren't Beijing Operas?
What is Beijing Opera after all?
You can put it succinctly.
'' No sound is but a song,
no movement is but a dance.''
It must have beauty.
For instance--
Teacher, I don't get it.
Practice. When you've sweated
enough to fill buckets, you'll get it.
I still don't understand.
Xiao Si!
I just don't get it.
Why is it Beijing Opera when ancient
heroes and beauties take the stage...
but not when
the laboring masses do?
You're talking apples
and oranges. Upstart!
What kind of attitude is that?
I'd like to hear
from Teacher Duan.
Xiaolou!
It's going to rain.
I've brought your umbrella.
Catch!
Yes, yes, run along home now.
Theoretical questions
give me a headache.
I say if it uses the traditional forms,
then it's Beijing Opera.
Am I right?
I'd like to say something.
I've been part of the New Society
since giving my theater to the state.
Comrade Cheng,
I believe you're wrong.
Modern opera is a new venture.
It deserves our support.
If opera relied on being a smart-ass,
you'd graduate with honors.
Opera requires practice,
skill and talent.
There are no shortcuts!
By forcing me to kneel,
you're breaking the law.
And if I don't punish you,
you'll always be third-rate.
You want to be a great actor?
Dream on!
And when did you ever
seriously want me to succeed?
All you've ever wanted
was a coolie, a stagehand...
a follower, a bit player!
How dare you! You're speaking
absolute rubbish!
Kneel down!
You won't live to see the day!
Xiao Si!
Go, then!
Be a bit player your whole life!
Mister Cheng...
I can hardly believe this.
It's like something
out of the Old Society!
If I continue to get bit parts,
I'll be unworthy of your patronage.
So, you know?
Uh, I just learned myself.
That's not true, Teacher Duan.
You were there
at the meeting last night.
Xiao Si! You said you'd notify Dieyi
that you were replacing him.
I had second thoughts.
I decided you should tell him.
Don't you agree?
If you couldn't tell him,
who could?
Take it off!.
Don't. Don't be like that!
I won't fucking sing anymore!
Let whoever wants to perform
do so.
Xiaolou, you mustn't go.
Comrade Duan...
that audience is made up
of the laboring masses.
You decide whether you'll sing
for them or not.
Xiaolou, the concubine is on stage.
You'd better hurry.
Xiaolou... Mister Duan!
I've followed my king
On his military campaigns
Enduring the wind and frost
And hard toil year after year
I hate only the lawless tyrant
Who has plunged our people
Into an abyss of misery
The people have suffered
Untold hardship and pain
The king has returned to camp!
I'm here.
Your Highness.
I've caused you so much grief.
Thank you very much,
Miss Juxian.
Dieyi!
Dieyi, open the door! Open up!
Won't you accept my apology?
That little snake you rescued...
has turned into
a veritable dragon!
You have to go along with it!
What else can you do?
No matter what, as you told me,
you have to keep on singing!
Come on out...
and see what's playing in
the theater of life these days.
Douzi, listen
to your stage brother.
Go with the times! I'll still be
the king and you my concubine!
Why does the concubine
have to die?
Dieyi, why are you
so impossible?
That's the play,
for heaven's sake!
1966 THE EVE OF
THE CULTURAL REVOLUTION
Central People's Radio
will now broadcast...
the decision of the Chinese Communist
Party Central Committee...
regarding the Great Proletarian
Cultural Revolution...
passed on August 8, 1966.
This new stage
in socialist revolution...
is an event that will touch...
the very soul of the People!
A good Communist
must be brave...
speak righteously
and fight for the revolution.
The greatest virtue
for a revolutionary soldier...
is to overthrow
the reactionary powers.
This is the foundation
of our revolutionary struggle.
If a soldier does not do this,
he is not a true revolutionary.
Those who oppose
the revolution...
will be sent to reform school
to adjust their attitudes.
There they will find their
anti revolutionary stance will diminish.
There are those who repeatedly
complain...
that revolution
is not appropriate...
that it's too violent...
that it's too aggressive...
that it's too abrupt
for the people.
All of that is ridiculous.
How can you drink
at a time like this?
I feel like it.
Anyway, jade cups were part
of the ''Old Society.''
We can't keep them, so we might
as well use them one last time.
Come on!
It still won't break!
I'm so afraid!
I dreamed I was on top of a tall
building alone amongst the clouds.
I wanted to jump.
Jump! I'd catch you.
You weren't there.
Xiaolou, you wouldn't leave me,
would you?
Where did this sword come from?
Cheng Dieyi gave it to me.
How many times
did he give it to you?
Twice.
When was the second time?
Shortly before
the liberation of Beijing.
Where?
On... on the street
in front of the theater.
What did you say to each other?
It was quite chaotic.
I don't remember.
Think about it.
We didn't say anything!
Keep thinking.
If we did, I can't recall.
Something about what you'd do
to the Communists?
No! Certainly not!
I'd stake my life on it.
But what if we've got a witness?
Who? Bring out the bastard!
Na Kun!
What did I say?
I'll give you a hint.
Something about ragtag troops.
Na Kun! This is pure slander!
You reactionary old theater boss!
You only want to protect yourself!.
You said you'd take on
their ragtag troops.
No! I never said that!
What I meant was--
What I said was--
No, I said nothing at all!
Mr. Na, help me. Mr. Na!
Duan Xiaolou...
you've been smashing bricks
since you were a boy, haven't you?
Do one for us.
Do it!
Come on!
Duan Xiaolou,
aren't you the '' King''?
No, I'm not.
But you've always been
the '' King,'' haven't you?
That's just an opera.
It's not real life.
Did you go to brothels
in the Old Society?
Yes.
Don't you think that's shameful?
When you married Juxian,
what was she?
A prostitute.
Good.
Now tell us what we need to know
about Cheng Dieyi.
Of course, you don't have
to tell us anything.
You saw what happened
to Yuan Shiqing.
Make your own decision.
Sweep away all Cow Demons
and Snake Spirits!
If the enemy doesn't surrender,
we will destroy him!
Uncover the Black Gangs!
Cut off the Black Hands!
Seize the Black Hands that have
infiltrated the cultural world!
Revolution is no crime.
Rebellion is justified!
Sweep away all Cow Demons
and Snake Spirits!
Xiaolou!
Duan Xiaolou
is the reactionary king!
isn't telling the truth!
Duan Xiaolou and Cheng Dieyi
are anti-Party elements!
Down with Duan Xiaolou!
Down with Cheng Dieyi!
Talk! Talk!
Obliterate all class enemies!
Talk!
All right, I'll tell you.
He's totally mad about opera.
He's obsessed!
Who? Make yourself clear.
Come on!
Cheng Dieyi!
All he cares about is opera.
No matter who was in the audience,
which class they belonged to...
he'd still give it his all.
Stop avoiding the real issues.
You're not being straight
with us!
If you don't give in,
we will annihilate you.
At the start
of the War of Resistance...
he sang for the Japanese.
He was a... a... a traitor!
Down with Cheng Dieyi!
He sang for wounded
Nationalist soldiers...
for reactionary theater bosses.
He sang for capitalists,
landlords, the idle rich...
their wives and daughters.
He sang for hooligans,
for soldiers and policemen.
He sang for the tyrant
of the opera world, Yuan Shiqing!
Down with Cheng Dieyi!
What else? Tell us.
Talk!
He smoked opium
like there was no tomorrow.
He smoked away the blood and sweat
of the laboring masses.
Keep going. Get to the point.
Speak!
Go on!
Down with Cheng Dieyi!
Talk!
Xiaolou!
In order to get
on Yuan Shiqing's good side--
He-Did you or did you not?
He became Yuan Shiqing's-his--
Xiaolou!
Didn't you? Didn't you?
You were-were-his--
Sweep away all Cow Demons
and Snake Spirits!
Scholars and beauties,
kings and ministers.
Cow Demons and Snake Spirits.
You've all betrayed me!
Betrayed me!
I've got something
to unmask as well!
I want to unmask the ugliness
behind the glamorous facade.
Xiaolou, you've no conscience.
You are as greedy as a wolf,
as cruel as a wild dog.
You're a shell of a man.
From the moment you got involved
with this woman...
I knew you were finished.
Everything was finished.
You think disaster just falls
from the sky?
No.
We have come step by step
towards this fate.
It's retribution.
I'm despicable, and I have been so
for a long time.
But now even the King of Chu
is on his knees begging for mercy!
Can Beijing Opera survive
this indignity?
It's doomed, is it not?
This is what's called
retribution!
Karmic retribution!
And I have something else
to unmask.
See that woman?
Who is she? I'll tell you.
Slut!
Top whore at the House of Blossoms!
Pan Jinlian!
Fight against her!
Fight against her to the death!
Duan Xiaolou, is it true
she was a prostitute?
Well, was she?
Tell us!
Yes.
Do you love her?
Do you?
No.
No, I don't love her!
Is this the truth?
Really! I really don't love her.
I'll never have anything to do
with her again.
Nothing at all.
Leniency to those who confess,
severity to those who resist!
Obliterate all class enemies!
Juxian! Juxian!
Listen to Grandma
talk of revolution
a tale of heroism and tragedy
I was a child
of the rain and wind
''THE CULTURAL REVOLUTION
IS A POWERFUL WEAPON...
IN THE HANDS OF
THE PEOPLE'S CONGRESS.''
ELEVEN YEARS LATER
My king, quickly give me
your precious sword.
No, you mustn't take your life!
My king, quickly give me
your precious sword.
No, you must not do this!
It's no good.
I'm old. I can't do it anymore.
At sixteen I am a nun.
My hair shorn at youth's prime.
I am by nature a boy.
Not a girl.
Wrong! You've done it again!
I am by nature a boy...
not a girl.
Come on, let's try it again.
My king, quickly give me
your precious sword.
No, you mustn't take your life!
My king, quickly give me
your precious sword.
No, you must not do this!
Give me your sword.
No, never!
My king, the soldiers of Han...
they've entered the city!
Where?
Dieyi!
Douzi?