(PEOPLE VOCALIZING RHYTHMICALLY)
(MORE VOICES JOIN IN
VOCALIZATION)
(FOOTSTEPS)
ALL: Born of cold and winter air
And mountain rain combining
This icy force both foul and fair
Has a frozen heart worth mining
So out through the heart
Cold and clear
Strike for love and strike for fear
See the beauty sharp and sheer
Split the ice apart
And break the frozen heart
Hup, ho
Watch your step
Let it go
Hup, ho
Watch your step
Let it go
Beautiful
Powerful
Dangerous
Cold
Ice has a magic
Can't be controlled
Stronger than one
Stronger than ten
Stronger than a hundred men!
(ALL GRUNT)
(GRUNTS) Oh!
(CHUCKLES)
Born of cold
And winter air
And mountain rain combining
This icy force both foul and fair
Has a frozen heart worth mining
Cut through the heart
Cold and clear
Strike for love and strike for fear
There's beauty and there's danger here
Split the ice apart
Beware the frozen heart
(GRUNTS)
KRISTOFF: Come on, Sven.
Elsa. Psst!
Elsa!
(GRUNTS)
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up!
Anna, go back to sleep.
(SIGHS) I just can't.
The sky is awake, so I'm awake.
So, we have to play.
Go play by yourself.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
Do you want to build a snowman?
Come on, come on, come on!
(SHUSHING)
(BOTH GIGGLING)
ANNA: Do the magic!
Do the magic!
Oh...
- Ready?
- Uh-huh. (CHUCKLES)
This is amazing!
(ANNA SCREAMING EXCITEDLY)
Watch this!
(GIGGLING)
Hi, I'm Olaf,
and I like warm hugs.
I love you, Olaf!
(GIGGLES)
ANNA: Olaf...
(GIGGLING)
Tickle bumps!
Oh!
Hang on!
Catch me!
Gotcha!
Again!
Wait!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Slow down!
(GRUNTS)
Whoo!
Anna!
(GRUNTS)
(ELSA GASPS)
Anna!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Mama! Papa!
(SOBBING) No, no...
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
(GASPS) Elsa, what have you done?
This is getting out of hand.
It was an accident. I'm sorry, Anna!
- Oh. She's ice cold.
- I know where we have to go.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Ice?
Faster, Sven.
(PANTING)
(WHISPERS) Sven!
(SVEN PANTING)
Please! Help! It's my daughter.
(GASPS)
It's the king.
(ALL MURMURING)
- Trolls? (GASPS)
- Shush!
I'm trying to listen.
Cuties. I'm going to keep you.
Your Majesty.
Born with the powers, or cursed?
(STAMMERING) Born.
And they're getting stronger.
Here, here.
You are lucky it wasn't her heart.
The heart is not so easily changed.
But the head can be persuaded.
Do what you must.
I recommend we remove all magic.
Even memories of magic, to be safe.
But don't worry. I'll leave the fun.
(SIGHS)
She will be okay.
But she won't remember I have powers?
It's for the best.
Listen to me, Elsa.
Your power will only grow.
There is beauty in it...
But also great danger.
(GASPS)
You must learn to control it.
Fear will be your enemy.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
KING: No!
We'll protect her.
She can learn to control it. I'm sure.
Until then...
We'll look the gates.
We'll reduce the staff.
We will limit her contact with people,
and keep her powers
hidden from everyone.
Including Anna.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Ah.
(GIGGLING)
Elsa?
(KNOCKS RHYTHMICALLY)
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Come on, let's go and play
I never see you anymore
Come out the door
It's like you've gone away
We used to be best buddies
And now we're not
I wish you would tell me why
Do you wanna build a snowman?
(MUFFLED) It doesn't
have to be a snowman
ELSA: Go away, Anna.
Okay, bye
(GASPS)
KING: The gloves will help.
See? Conceal it.
Don't feel it.
BOTH: Don't let it show.
(GIGGLES)
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Or ride our bike around the halls?
(CLATTERS)
I think some company is overdue
I've started talking
To the pictures on the walls
Hang in there, Joan.
It gets a little lonely
All these empty rooms
Just watching the hours tick by
(MIMICKING TICKING)
I'm scared.
It's getting stronger!
Getting upset only makes it worse.
Calm down.
No! Don't touch me!
Please, I don't want to hurt you.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
See you in two weeks!
Do you have to go?
You'll be fine, Elsa.
Your Highness.
Elsa?
Please
I know you're in there
People are asking where you've been
They say "Have courage"
And I'm trying to
I'm right out here for you
Just let me in
We only have each other
It's just you and me
What are we gonna do?
Do you wanna build a snowman?
(SOBBING)
CAPTAIN: All ashore!
Welcome to Arendelle!
(MAN THANKING IN FRENCH)
Watch your step, please.
The gates will be opening soon.
Why do I have to wear this?
Because the queen has come of age.
It's Coronation Day!
That's not my fault.
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(CHUCKLES) What do you want, Sven?
"Give me a snack."
What's the magic word?
"Please."
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. Share.
I can't believe they're
finally opening up the gates!
And for a whole day!
(GIGGLES) Faster, Percy!
(SIGHS) Arendelle, our most
mysterious trade partner.
Open those gates so I may unlock
your secrets and exploit your riches.
Did I say that out loud?
Oh! Me sore eyes can't wait
to see the queen and the princess.
I bet they are absolutely lovely.
I bet they are beautiful.
(SNORING)
KAI: Princess Anna?
- Princess Anna?
- Huh? (CLEARS THROAT) Yeah?
Oh. Sorry to wake you, ma'am.
No, no, no, you didn't.
(YAWNS)
I've been up for hours.
(SNORING)
(GASPS) Who is it?
(STAMMERS) Still me, ma'am.
The gates will open soon.
Time to get ready.
Of course.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ready for what?
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
My sister's corneration.
(GASPS) It's Coronation Day!
(CHUCKLES)
It's Coronation Day!
(EXCLAIMS)
The window is open!
So's that door!
I didn't know they did that anymore
Who knew we owned
8,000 salad plates?
For years I've roamed these empty halls
Why have a ballroom with no balls?
Finally
They're opening up the gates!
There'll be actual, real, live people
It'll be totally strange
But wow!
Am I so ready for this change!
'Cause for the first time in forever
There'll be music
There'll be light
For the first time
In forever
I'll be dancing through the night
Don't know if I'm elated or gassy
But I'm somewhere in that zone
'Cause for the first time in forever
I won't be alone
I can't wait to meet everyone!
(GASPS)
What if I meet The One?
Tonight
Imagine me gown and all
Fetchingly draped against the wall
The picture of sophisticated grace
I suddenly see him standing there
A beautiful stranger
Tall and fair
I wanna stuff some chocolate
in my face!
But then we laugh and talk all evening
Which is totally bizarre
Nothing like the life
I've led so far
For the first time in forever
There'll be magic
There'll be fun
For the first time in forever
I could be noticed by someone
And I know it is totally crazy
To dream I'd find romance
But for the first time in forever
At least I've got a chance!
(INHALES)
Don't let them in
Don't let them see
Be the good girl
You always have to be
Conceal
Don't feel
Put on a show
Make one wrong move
And everyone will know
But it's only for today
It's only for today
It's agony to wait
Tell the guards to open up
The gate
ANNA: The gate
For the first time in forever
Don't let them in
Don't let them see
I'm getting what I'm dreaming of
Be the good girl
You always have to be
A chance to change
My lonely world
ELSA: Conceal
A chance to find true love
Conceal, don't feel
Don't let them know
I know it all ends tomorrow
So it has to be today!
'Cause for the first time in forever
For the first time
In forever
Nothing's in my way!
(EXCLAIMING)
(YELPS)
Hey!
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
Hey.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Uh...
(STUTTERS) No, no, I'm okay.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
I just wasn't looking where I was going.
But I'm great, actually.
Oh... Thank goodness.
Oh! Uh...
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
- "Princess"? My Lady.
- Oh! (SNORTS)
- Whoa.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
(CHUCKLES) Um...
Whew.
Hi. Again.
(BOTH YELP) Oh, boy!
This is awkward.
Not "You're awkward,"
but just because we're...
I'm awkward, you're gorgeous.
Wait, what?
I'd like to formally apologize
for hitting the princess
of Arendelle with my horse.
- And for every moment after.
- No! No, no. It's fine.
I'm not that princess.
I mean, if you had hit my sister Elsa,
it would be... Yeesh!
(CHUCKLES)
Because, you know...
Hello.
(NEIGHS)
But, lucky you,
it's just me.
(CHUCKLES)
"Just" you?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(BELLS CHIMING)
(SIGHS)
The bells. The coronation.
(STUTTERS) I better go.
I have to go. I better go. Uh...
Bye!
(BOARDS CREAKING)
Oh, no. Oh!
(SPLASHING)
(SPUTTERS)
(ALL VOCALIZING IN HARMONY)
(MAN SNORING)
(BISHOP CLEARS THROAT)
Your Majesty, the gloves.
(BREATH ES DEEPLY)
(CHANTING PRAYER)
(GASPS)
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
ALL: Queen Elsa of Arendelle!
(ALL CHEERING)
(PLAYING LIVELY MUSIC)
(GUESTS LAUGHING AND CHATTING)
(MUSIC CEASES)
(APPLAUSE)
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
(PANTING)
(GIGGLES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Oh. Here? Are you sure?
Because I don't think I'm supposed to...
Oh. Okay.
(ANNA CLEARS THROAT)
Hi.
"Hi" me? Oh...
Um... Hi.
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
(CHUCKLES) You look beautiful-ler.
I mean, not "fuller." You don't look fuller.
But more beautiful.
(CHUCKLES) Thank you.
So...
This is what a party looks like.
It's warmer than I thought.
What is that amazing smell?
(BOTH SNIFFING)
BOTH: Chocolate.
(CHUCKLING)
KAI: Your Majesty.
- The Duke of Weaseltown.
- "Weselton"!
Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.
As your closest partner in trade
it seems only fitting that I offer you
your first dance as queen.
One-two, and jump.
(GASPS)
(BOTH SNICKERING)
(CLEARS THROAT) Uh...
- Thank you. Only, I don't dance.
- Oh...
But my sister does.
- What?
- Oh! Lucky you.
Oh, I don't think...
DUKE: If you swoon, let me know.
I'll catch you.
Sorry.
Like an agile peacock.
(WARBLING)
Ow! Ow.
Speaking of, so great
to have the gates open.
Why did they shut them
in the first place?
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
- No.
All right. Hang on!
(GASPS)
They don't call me
the "Little Dipper" for nothing!
Oh-ho!
Like a chicken with the face
of a monkey, I fly.
DUKE: Let me know when you're ready
for another round, Milady.
(PANTING)
(CHUCKLES) Well, he was sprightly.
(GROANS) Especially
for a man in heels.
Are you okay?
(CHUCKLES)
I've never been better. This is so nice.
I wish it could be like this all the time.
Me, too.
But it can't.
- Why not?
- It just can't.
(SIGHS)
Excuse me for a minute.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(SNIFFLING)
MAN: I'd be honored.
(EXCLAIMING)
(GASPS)
Glad I caught you.
Hans.
(CHUCKLES) Oop.
(SOFT ORCHESTRAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
I often had a whole parlor
to myself to slide!
- Oh!
- Oops!
Sorry.
(CHUCKLES)
- Your physique helps, I'm sure, too.
- (CHUCKLES) Ah.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
What's this?
Uh, I was born with it.
Although, I dreamed
I was kissed by a troll.
I like it.
Yeah, the whole thing.
(CHUCKLES)
You got it.
Okay, wait, wait.
So, you have how many brothers?
Twelve older brothers.
Three of them pretended I was invisible,
- literally, for two years.
- That's horrible.
It's what brothers do.
And sisters.
Elsa and I were really close
when we were little.
But then, one day, she just shut me out,
and I never knew why.
I would never shut you out.
(GASPS)
Okay, can I just say something crazy?
I love crazy.
All my life has been
A series of doors in my face
And then suddenly
I bump into you
I was thinking the same thing,
because, like...
I've been searching my whole life
To find my own place
And maybe it's the party talking
Or the chocolate fondue
But with you
- But with you I found my place
- I see your face
BOTH: And it's nothing like
I've ever known before
Love is an open
Door!
- Door
BOTH: Love is an open door
- With you
(BOTH SNICKER)
(EXCLAIMS)
(BOTH GRUNT)
- I mean, it's crazy
- What?
- We finish each other's
- Sandwiches
That's what I was gonna say!
I've never met someone
BOTH: Who thinks so much like me
Jinx! Jinx again!
Our mental synchronization
Can have but one explanation
- You
- And I
- Were
- Just
BOTH: Meant to be
- Say goodbye
BOTH: To the pain of the past
We don't have to feel it anymore
Love is an open door
Love is an open
- Door
BOTH: Life can be so much more
- With you
BOTH: Love is an open
- Door
Can I say something crazy?
(GIGGLES)
Will you marry me?
(GASPS)
Can I say something even crazier?
Yes!
ANNA: Coming through.
HANS: Excuse me. Oh...
ANNA: Pardon. Sorry.
WOMAN: Oh!
Can we just get around you there?
Thank you. Oh! There she is.
Elsa!
I mean, Queen. Me again. Um...
May I present Prince Hans
of the Southern Isles.
Your Majesty.
BOTH: We would like...
Uh, your blessing...
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
BOTH: Of our marriage.
- Marriage?
- Yes! (SQUEALS)
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Well, we haven't worked out
all the details ourselves.
We'll need a few days
to plan the ceremony.
Of course, we'll have soup, roast and ice
cream. And then... (GASPS)
Wait. Would we live here?
- Here?
- Absolutely!
- Anna!
- Oh!
We can invite all 12 of your
brothers to stay with us.
What? No, no, no.
- Of course we have the room.
- Wait, slow down.
No one's brothers are staying here.
No one is getting married.
Wait, what?
May I talk to you, please? Alone.
No. Whatever you have to say,
you can say to both of us.
Fine.
You can't marry a man you just met.
You can if it's true love.
Anna, what do you know
about true love?
More than you.
All you know is how to shut people out.
You asked for my blessing,
but my answer is no.
Now, excuse me.
Your Majesty, if I may ease your...
No, you may not.
(STUTTERS) And I think you should go.
The party is over. Close the gates.
KAI: - Yes, Your Majesty.
- What?
Elsa, no, no! Wait.
(GASPS)
Give me my glove!
Elsa, please, please.
I can't live like this anymore!
Then leave.
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
- What did I ever do to you?
- Enough, Anna.
No, why? Why do you shut me out?
Why do you shut the world out?
What are you so afraid of?
I said, enough!
(GUESTS SHRIEKING)
(GUESTS MUTTERING NERVOUSLY)
Sorcery.
I knew there was something
dubious going on here.
Elsa.
(SIGHS)
WOMAN: There she is!
(ALL CHEERING)
(ELSA BREATHING HEAVILY)
MAN 1: Yes! It is her!
Queen Elsa.
MAN 2: Our beautiful queen!
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
No.
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GASP)
(ALL GASP IN AWE)
There she is! Stop her!
Please, just stay away from me.
Stay away.
Monster. Monster!
(BABY CRYING)
(SHUDDERS)
(ALL MURMURING FEARFULLY)
Elsa!
(PANTING)
ANNA: Elsa!
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
Wait, please!
Elsa, stop!
Anna!
No.
The fjord.
- Snow!
- Snow?
Yes, snow.
- Are you all right?
- No.
Did you know?
No.
Look, it's snowing. It's snowing!
The queen has cursed this land!
She must be stopped!
You have to go after her.
Wait, no!
You! Is there sorcery in you, too?
Are you a monster, too?
No, no. I'm completely ordinary.
That's right, she is.
In the best way.
And my sister is not a monster.
She nearly killed me!
- You slipped on ice.
- Her ice.
It was an accident. She was scared.
She didn't mean it.
She didn't mean any of this.
Tonight was my fault. I pushed her.
So, I'm the one
- that needs to go after her.
- What?
- Bring me my horse, please.
- Anna, no.
It's too dangerous.
(SCOFFS) Elsa is not dangerous.
I'll bring her back,
and I'll make this right.
I'm coming with you.
No, I need you here
to take care of Arendelle.
On my honor.
(GRUNTS)
I leave Prince Hans in charge.
Are you sure you can trust her?
I don't want you getting hurt.
She's my sister.
She would never hurt me.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(CROWD MUTTERING)
The snow glows white
On the mountain tonight
Not a footprint to be seen
A kingdom of isolation
And it looks like
I'm the queen
The wind is howling
Like this swirling storm inside
Couldn't keep it in
Heaven knows I tried
Don't let them in
Don't let them see
Be the good girl
You always have to be
Conceal, don't feel
Don't let them know
Well, now they know
Let it go!
Can't hold me back anymore
Turn away and slam the door
I don't care
What they're going to say
Let the storm rage on
The cold never bothered me anyway
It's funny how some distance
Makes everything seem small
And the fears that once controlled me
Can't get to me at all
It's time to see what I can do
To test the limits and break through
No right, no wrong
No rules for me
I'm free!
Let it go!
I am one with the wind and sky
You'll never see me cry
Here I stand
And here I'll stay
Let the storm rage on
My power flurries through the air
Into the ground
My soul is spiraling in frozen fractals
All around
And one thought crystallizes
Like an icy blast
I'm never going back
The past is in the past
Let it go!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
That perfect girl is gone
Here I stand
In the light of day
Let the storm rage on!
The cold never bothered me anyway
ANNA: Elsa!
Elsa!
Elsa, it's me, Anna,
your sister who didn't mean
to make you freeze the summer.
I'm sorry.
(SHIVERING) It's all my fault.
Of course, none of it
would have happened
if she had just told me her secret.
(CHUCKLES) She's a stinker.
(GASPS) Whoa!
(SPUTTERS)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Oh, no. No, no, no! Come back!
No, no, no!
(SHIVERING) Okay.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
Snow. It had to be snow.
She couldn't have had tropical magic
that covered the fjords
in white sand and warm...
Fire! (CHUCKLES)
(SHRIEKING)
(GRUNTS)
(SHIVERING)
Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold.
(CONTINUES SHIVERING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(READING)
Ooh. "And sauna"!
(GASPS)
(WIND HOWLING)
(SHIVERS)
- Yoo-hoo.
- Hmm?
Big summer blowout.
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
and a sun balm
of my own invention, yah?
Oh. Great.
For now, um, how about boots?
Winter boots and dresses?
That would be in our winter department.
Oh. Um...
I was just wondering.
Has another young woman...
The queen perhaps, I don't know,
passed through here?
The only one crazy enough
to be out in this storm
is you, dear.
(DOOR OPENS)
(PANTING)
You and this fellow.
Yoo-hoo.
Big summer blowout.
(ANNA HUMMING NONCHALANTLY)
KRISTOFF: Carrots.
Huh?
Behind you.
Oh! Right. Excuse me.
Oh. A real howler in July, yes?
Wherever could it be coming from?
KRISTOFF: The North Mountain.
North Mountain.
That Will be 40.
Forty? No, 10.
Oh, dear, that's no good.
See, this is from our winter stock,
where supply and demand
have a big problem.
You want to talk about
a supply and demand problem?
I sell ice for a living.
Ooh. That's a rough business
to be in right now.
(CHUCKLES) I mean, that is really...
(CLEARS THROAT) That's unfortunate.
Still 40.
But I will throw in
a visit to Oaken's sauna.
Yoo-hoo. Hi, family.
ALL: Yoo-hoo!
Ten is all I got. Help me out.
Okay. Ten will get you this and no more.
Okay, just tell me one thing.
What was happening
on the North Mountain?
Did it seem magical?
(EXHALES) Yes!
Now, back up while I deal
with this crook, here.
(GULPS)
What did you call me?
KRISTOFF: Okay, okay. I'm out.
Whoa! (GRUNTS)
Bye-bye.
(SPUTTERS)
No, Sven, I didn't get your carrots.
But I did find us a place to sleep.
And it's free.
(SNORTS)
I'm sorry about this violence.
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
so we have good feelings.
Just the outfit and the boots, yah?
Uh...
(TUNE BEING PICKED ON LUTE)
Reindeers are better than people
Sven, don't you think that's true?
"Yeah, people will beat you
And curse you and cheat you"
"Every one of them's bad, except you"
Aw. Thanks, buddy.
But people smell better than reindeers
Sven, don't you think I'm right?
"That's once again true
For all, except you"
You got me
Let's call it a night
"Good night"
Don't let the frostbite
Bite
Nice duet.
(GASPS)
(SIGHS) It's just you.
What do you want?
I want you to take me up
the North Mountain.
I don't take people places.
Let me rephrase that.
(GROANS) Hey.
Take me up the North Mountain.
Please.
(SNIFFING)
Look, I know how to stop this winter.
(SIGHS)
We leave at dawn.
And you forgot the carrots for Sven.
(GRUNTS) Oops, sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I didn't...
(CLEARS THROAT)
We leave now. Right now.
Whew!
(URGING SVEN)
(ANNA SHRIEKS)
(ANNA CHUCKLES BREATHLESSLY)
Hang on! We like to go fast.
- I like fast.
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Get your feet down.
This is fresh lacquer.
Seriously, were you raised in a barn?
(SPITS) Ugh!
- No, I was raised in a castle.
- Hmm.
KRISTOFF: So, uh, tell me,
what made the queen go all ice-crazy?
Oh. Well...
It was all my fault.
I got engaged, but then she freaked out,
because I'd only just met him,
you know, that day.
And she said she wouldn't
bless the marriage, and...
Wait. You got engaged
to someone you just met that day?
Yeah.
Anyway, I got mad, and so she got mad,
and then she tried to walk away,
and I grabbed her glove...
Hang on!
You mean to tell me you got engaged
to someone you just met that day?
Yes. Pay attention.
But the thing is,
she wore the gloves all the time,
so I just thought,
maybe she has a thing about dirt.
Didn't your parents ever
warn you about strangers?
Yes, they did.
But Hans is not a stranger.
Oh, yeah? What's his last name?
(SCOFFS) "Of the Southern Isles."
- What's his favorite food?
- Sandwiches.
- Best friend's name?
- Probably John.
- Eye color?
- Dreamy.
- Foot size?
- Foot size doesn't matter.
Have you had a meal with him yet?
What if you hate the way he eats?
What if you hate
the way he picks his nose?
Picks his nose?
And eats it.
Excuse me, sir. He is a prince.
- All men do it.
- Ew.
Look, it doesn't matter. It's true love.
It doesn't sound like true love.
(SCOFFS) Are you some
sort of love expert?
No. But, uh, I have friends who are.
You have friends
who are love experts? I'm not buying it.
- Stop talking.
- No, no, no. No, no.
- I'd like to meet these...
- No, I mean it.
(GRUNTS)
(SHUSHES)
(LOW GROWLING)
Sven, go.
Go!
- What are they?
- Wolves.
Wolves?
- What do we do?
- I got this.
You just...
Don't fall off, and don't get eaten.
But I want to help!
- No.
- Why not?
Because I don't trust your judgment.
Excuse me?
Who marries a man she just met?
It's true love!
Whoa!
(GRUNTS)
Whoa. Whoa!
Christopher!
It's "Kristoff"!
Ow! (YELPS)
(KRISTOFF GRUNTING)
Duck!
(SCREAMS)
(SNARLING)
You almost set me on fire!
But I didn't.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SVEN GROANS)
(BOTH GASP)
Get ready to jump, Sven!
You don't tell him what to do.
- Hey!
- I do!
Jump, Sven!
(GRUNTS)
(KRISTOFF YELLING)
(GROWLING)
(BARKING)
Phew!
(WHIMPERS)
But I just paid it off.
Uh-oh. No. No.
No!
Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
ANNA: Grab on!
Pull, Sven. Pull!
(KRISTOFF GRUNTING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(SLED THUDS) Whoa.
(KRISTOFF GROANS)
I'll replace your sled,
and everything in it.
And I understand
if you don't want to help me anymore.
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
Of course I don't want to help
her anymore. In fact,
this whole thing has ruined me
for helping anyone ever again.
ANNA: It's this way?
"She'll die on her own."
- I can live with that.
ANNA: - Here we go.
"But you won't get
your new sled if she's dead."
ANNA: I think, actually, it's up.
Sometimes, I really don't like you.
(PANTING)
Hold up! We're coming.
You are?
I mean, sure. I'll let you tag along.
(CHUCKLES)
(GROANS)
(BOTH PANTING)
(ANNA GASPS)
Arendelle.
It's completely frozen.
(SIGHS)
But it will be fine. Elsa will thaw it.
Will she?
Yeah. Now, come on.
This way to the North Mountain?
(CHUCKLES)
More like this way.
(GASPS)
(ICE TINKLING)
(GRUNTING EXCITEDLY)
I never knew winter
could be so beautiful.
OLAF: Yeah.
It really is beautiful, isn't it?
But it's so white.
You know, how about a little color?
I'm thinking maybe some
crimson, chartreuse.
How about yellow?
No, not yellow. Yellow and snow?
(SHUDDERS) No go.
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH GASP)
Am I right?
(SHRIEKS)
- Hi.
- You're creepy.
OLAF: - Whoa!
- I don't want it.
- Back at you.
OLAF: - Please don't drop me.
- No.
- Come on, it's just a head.
OLAF: All right. We got off to a bad start.
Ew, ew, ew, the body!
(GROANS)
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
Why are you hanging off
the earth like a bat?
All right, wait one second.
Oh. Uh...
Oh!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Now, I'm perfect.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, almost.
It was like my whole life
got turned upside down.
(GRUNTS)
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry!
- Head rush!
- I was just... Are you okay?
Are you kidding me? I am wonderful!
I've always wanted a nose.
(IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE) So cute.
It's like a little baby unicorn.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) But... Hey! Whoa!
(GASPS) Oh.
I love it even more.
(EXHALES) All right,
let's start this thing over.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Olaf.
And I like warm hugs.
Olaf?
That's right. Olaf.
And you are?
Oh. Um...
I'm Anna.
And who's the funky-looking
donkey over there?
- That's Sven.
- Uh-huh.
And who's the reindeer?
Sven.
Oh, the... Oh. Okay.
That makes things easier for me.
(SQUEALS) Aw, look at him
trying to kiss my nose.
- I like you, too.
- Olaf.
- Did Elsa build you?
- Yeah. Why?
Do you know where she is?
- Fascinating.
- Yeah. Why?
Do you think you could
show us the way?
Yeah. Why?
How does this work? Ow!
Stop it, Sven. I'm trying to focus, here.
- Yeah. Why?
- I'll tell you why.
We need Elsa to bring back summer.
- Summer?
- Mmm-hmm.
Oh. I don't know why,
but I've always loved
the idea of summer.
And sun, and all things hot.
Really?
I'm guessing you
don't have much experience with heat.
Nope.
But sometimes I like to close my eyes,
and imagine what it would be
like when summer does come.
(SIGHING CONTENTEDLY)
Bees will buzz
Kids will blow dandelion fuzz
And I'll be doing
Whatever snow does in summer
A drink in my hand
My snow up against the burning sand
Probably getting gorgeously tanned
In summer
I'll finally see a summer breeze
Blow away a winter storm
And find out what happens
to solid water
When it gets warm
And I can't wait to see
What my buddies all think of me
Just imagine how much cooler I'll be
In summer!
(VOCALIZING)
The hot and the cold
are both so intense
Put them together
It just makes sense
(SCATTING)
Winter's a good time
To stay in and cuddle
But put me in summer and I'll be a...
Happy snowman!
When life gets rough
I like to hold on to my dream
Relaxing in the summer sun
Just letting off steam
Oh, the sky
Will be blue
And you guys will be there, too
When I finally do
What frozen things do
In summer!
- I'm gonna tell him.
- Don't you dare.
In summer!
So, come on! Elsa's this way.
Let's go bring back summer!
I'm coming!
(OLAF LAUGHING)
Somebody's gotta tell him.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
No, no. You've got the bark facing down.
The bark needs to be face-up.
- Bark down is drier.
MAN 1: - Bark up!
MAN 2: - Bark down!
BOY: - Papa!
Cloak? Does anyone need a cloak?
Arendelle is indebted to you,
Your Highness.
The castle is open.
There is soup and hot glogg
in the great hall.
Here, pass these out.
Prince Hans!
Are we expected
to just sit here and freeze
while you give away all
of Arendelle's tradable goods?
Princess Anna has given her orders.
And that's another thing!
Has it dawned on you
that your princess may be conspiring
with a wicked Sorceress
to destroy us all?
Do not question the princess.
She left me in charge
and I will not hesitate
to protect Arendelle from treason.
(STAMMERING) Treason?
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(ALL GASP)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(PEOPLE PANICKING)
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa, boy. Easy.
Easy.
MAN: It's Princess Anna's horse.
WOMAN 1: So, where is the princess?
WOMAN 2: Where could she be?
WOMAN 3: Where is she?
Princess Anna is in trouble.
I need volunteers to go
with me to find her.
- I'll go.
- I volunteer.
I volunteer two men, My Lord.
Be prepared for anything.
And should you encounter the queen,
you are to put an end to this winter.
- Do you understand?
- Hmm.
So, how exactly
are you planning to stop this weather?
Oh. I am gonna talk to my sister.
That's your plan?
My ice business is riding on
you talking to your sister?
Yep.
(GRUNTS)
So, you're not at all afraid of her?
- Why would I be?
- Yeah.
I bet she's the nicest,
gentlest, warmest person ever.
Oh. Look at that.
I've been impaled.
(CHUCKLING)
What now?
KRISTOFF: Mmm...
It's too steep.
I've only got one rope and you don't
know how to climb mountains.
ANNA: Says who?
(GRUNTS)
Hmm?
What are you doing?
I'm going to see my sister.
You're gonna kill yourself.
(GRUNTS)
I wouldn't put my foot there.
- You're distracting me.
- Or there.
How do you know
Elsa even wants to see you?
ANNA: All right. I'm just blocking you out
because I gotta concentrate, here.
(GRUNTING)
You know, most people who disappear
into the mountains want to be alone.
Nobody wants to be alone.
Except maybe you.
I'm not alone. I have friends, remember?
ANNA: You mean, the love experts?
Yes, the love experts.
(GRUNTS) Ah...
Please tell me I'm almost there.
Does the air seem a bit thin
to you up here?
(ANNA PANTING)
(CHUCKLES)
Hang on.
OLAF: Hey, Sven?
Not sure if this is gonna
solve the problem,
but I found a staircase that leads exactly
where you wanted to go.
Ha-ha! Thank goodness. Catch!
(BOTH GRUNT)
Thanks.
That was like a crazy trust exercise.
(OLAF CHUCKLING)
BOTH: Whoa.
Now, that's ice.
I might cry.
Go ahead. I won't judge.
(GRUNTS)
All right, take it easy, boy. Come here.
I got you.
(GRUNTS)
Okay. You stay right here, buddy.
(WHISTLES)
Flawless.
Knock.
Just knock.
Why isn't she knocking?
Do you think she knows how to knock?
(GASPS)
(EXHALES) Huh. It opened.
That's a first.
Oh. You should probably wait out here.
- What?
- The last time I introduced her to a guy,
she froze everything.
But, but... Oh, come on!
It's a palace made of ice. Ice is my life!
Bye, Sven.
You, too, Olaf.
- Me?
- Just give us a minute.
Okay.
(SOFTLY) One, two,
- three...
BOTH: - Four...
Whoa.
Elsa?
It's me, Anna.
(EXCLAIMS)
ELSA: Anna.
(GASPS)
Whoa. Elsa, you look different.
It's a good different.
And this place...
It's amazing.
Thank you.
I never knew what I was capable of.
I'm so sorry about what happened.
If I'd have known...
No, no, no. It's okay.
You don't have to apologize,
but you should probably go.
Please.
But I just got here.
You belong down in Arendelle.
So do you.
No, Anna, I belong here.
Alone.
Where I can be who I am
without hurting anybody.
Actually, about that...
OLAF: - Sixty!
- Wait. What is that?
Hi! I'm Olaf and I like warm hugs!
Olaf?
Yeah. You built me.
Remember that?
And you're alive?
(STAMMERS) Um... I think so.
He's just like the one we built as kids.
Yeah.
Elsa, we were so close.
We can be like that again.
YOUNG ANNA: Catch me!
YOUNG ELSA: Slow down!
(GRUNTS)
Anna!
(GASPS) No.
We can't. Goodbye, Anna.
Elsa, wait.
No, I'm just trying to protect you.
You don't have to protect me.
I'm not afraid.
Please don't shut me out again.
Please don't slam the door
You don't have to keep
Your distance anymore
'Cause for the first time in forever
I finally understand
For the first time in forever
We can fix this hand in hand
We can head down
this mountain together.
You don't have to live in fear
'Cause for the first time in forever
I Will be right here
Anna.
Please go back home
Your life awaits
Go enjoy the sun
And open up the gates
- Yeah, but...
- I know.
You mean well
But leave me be
Yes, I'm alone
But I'm alone and free
Just stay away
And you'll be safe from me
Actually, we're not
What do you mean, you're not?
I get the feeling you don't know
What do I not know?
Arendelle's in deep, deep, deep
Deep snow
What?
You kind of set off
an eternal winter everywhere.
Everywhere?
Well, it's okay, you can just unfreeze it.
No, I can't. I don't know how.
Sure you can. I know you can.
- 'Cause for the first time in forever
- Oh, I'm such a fool! I can't be free!
You don't have to be afraid
No escape from the storm inside of me
We can work this out together
I can't control the curse!
We'll reverse the storm you've made
Anna, please you'll only make it worse!
Don't panic
There's so much fear!
We'll make the sun shine bright
You're not safe here!
We can face this thing together
No!
We can change this winter weather
And everything will be all right
I can't!
(GASPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
KRISTOFF: Anna!
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I'm fine.
Who's this?
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just...
You have to go.
No, I know we can
figure this out together.
How?
What power do you have
to stop this winter?
To stop me?
- Anna, I think we should go.
- No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
Yes, you are.
(LOW GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
ANNA: Stop! Put us down!
Go away.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SHUDDERING)
(BOTH YELP)
Heads up!
Watch out for my butt!
(BOTH GASP)
It is not nice to throw people!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, feisty-pants.
Okay, relax.
- Just calm down! Calm down!
- Okay! All right!
- I'm okay.
- Just let the snowman be.
- I'm calm.
- Great.
(GRUNTS)
Oh! Come on!
(ROARING)
Oh. Look, see?
Now, you made him mad.
I'll distract him. You guys go.
No, no! Not you guys!
(MUFFLED) This just got
a whole lot harder.
(ANNA SHRIEKS)
(GROWLS)
KRISTOFF: Look out!
(ANNA SCREAMING)
(ROARS)
(ANNA GASPS)
(BOTH PANTING)
KRISTOFF: Run! Run!
KRISTOFF: What are you doing?
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
I got him! (LAUGHS)
KRISTOFF: Whoa! Stop!
ANNA: It's a 100-foot drop.
KRISTOFF: It's 200.
Ow!
- What's that for?
- I'm digging a snow anchor.
Okay. What if we fall?
There's 20 feet of fresh
powder down there.
It'll be like landing on a pillow.
Hopefully.
(GASPS)
(ROARING)
Okay, Anna. On three.
ANNA: Okay.
KRISTOFF: One...
You tell me when. I'm ready to go.
- Two...
- I was born ready! Yes!
Calm down.
(GRUNTS)
ANNA: Tree!
What the... Whoa!
(BOTH GRUNT)
KRISTOFF: That happened.
(PANTING) Man, am I out of shape.
(GASPS)
There we go. Hey, Anna!
Sven! Where did you guys go?
We totally lost Marshmallow back there.
Hey! We were just talking about you.
All good things, all good things.
No!
(GRUNTING)
This is not making much
of a difference, is it?
(SHRIEKS)
Olaf!
(GRUNTS) Hang in there, guys!
Go. Go faster!
(BOTH STRUGGLING)
- Wait, what?
KRISTOFF: - Hey!
(MARSHMALLOW GROWLING)
(BOTH EXCLAIM) Ow!
Kristoff!
(ANNA GASPING)
Don't come back!
We won't.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
Hey, you were right. Just like a pillow.
(CHUCKLES)
(OLAF PANTING) Olaf!
I can't feel my legs! I can't feel my legs!
(COUGHING)
- Those are my legs.
- Ooh!
Hey, do me a favor, grab my butt.
Oh. That feels better.
Hey, Sven! He found us.
Who's my cute little reindeer?
Don't talk to him like that.
(CHUCKLING)
You're tickling me.
Here.
Whoa!
Are you okay?
Thank you.
- How's your head?
- Ah! Ooh!
(STAMMERING)
It's fine. Uh...
Uh, I'm good. I've got a thick skull.
I don't have a skull.
Or bones.
So, uh... So, now what?
Now what? (CHUCKLES)
Now what?
Oh...
What am I gonna do?
She threw me out.
I can't go back to Arendelle
with the weather like this.
- And then there's your ice business.
- Hey, hey. Don't worry about my ice business.
- Worry about your hair!
- What?
I just fell off a cliff.
You should see your hair.
No, yours is turning white.
White? It's... What?
It's because she struck you, isn't it?
Does it look bad?
- No.
- You hesitated.
No, I didn't.
Anna, you need help, okay? Come on.
Okay! Where are we going?
To see my friends.
The love experts?
- Love experts?
- Uh-huh.
And don't worry,
they'll be able to fix this.
How do you know?
Because I've seen them do it before.
I like to consider myself a love expert.
(SVEN GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Get it together.
Control it.
Don't feel. Don't feel.
Don't feel.
Don't feel! (GASPS)
(ICE CRACKLING)
Look, Sven, the sky is awake.
(SHIVERING)
- Are you cold?
- A little.
(CLEARS THROAT) Uh...
Wait. Come here.
Huh?
Ooh.
(SIGHS)
So, uh, about my friends. Well...
(CHUCKLES)
I say "friends"...
They're more like family.
Anyway, when I was a kid,
it was just me and Sven.
Until they, you know, kinda took us in.
- They did?
- Yeah.
I don't want to scare you.
They can be a little
inappropriate and loud.
(CHUCKLES) Very loud.
They are also stubborn at times,
and a little overbearing.
And heavy. Really, really, heavy.
(STAMMERS) But you'll get it.
They mean well.
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
Okay, then.
(OLAF GRUNTS) Meet my family.
Hey, guys.
They're rocks.
KRISTOFF: You are
a sight for sore eyes.
(WHISPERS) He's crazy.
Rocko's looking sharp, as usual.
Clay, whoa... I don't even recognize you.
You lost so much weight.
(WHISPERS) I'll distract
him while you run.
(IN LOUD VOICE) Hi, Sven's family!
It's nice to meet you.
(WHISPERS) Because I love you,
Anna, I insist you run.
(IN LOUD VOICE) I understand
you're love experts. Ooh!
(WHISPERS) Why aren't you running?
Uh...
Okay. Well, I'm gonna go.
OLAF: - Go.
- No, no, no. Anna, wait.
(GASPS)
Kristoff! (GASPING)
KRISTOFF: Whoa! (CHUCKLING)
Hey!
Kristoff's home!
(ALL CLAMORING EXCITEDLY)
TROLL 1: - Kristoff's here!
- Kristoff's home!
- Wait, "Kristoff"?
- Uh-huh.
Ah, let me look at you.
Take off your clothes, I wash them.
No! No, I'm going to keep my clothes on.
Look, it's great to see you all,
but where's Granpabbie?
TROLL KID: He's napping.
But look, I grew a mushroom.
- I...
- I earned my fire crystal.
I passed a kidney stone.
Kristoff, pick me up.
(GRUNTS) You're getting big.
Good for you.
Trolls. They're trolls!
He's brought a girl!
ALL: (CHEERING) A girl!
- Whoa!
TROLL 2: - Is that a real girl?
TROLL 3: She's like a little cupcake.
What's going on?
I've learned to just roll with it.
Let me see. Bright eyes, working nose,
strong teeth!
(CHUCKLES)
Yes, yes. She'll do nicely for our Kristoff.
Wait, wait, wait. Oh, um, no.
- No. (CHUCKLES)
- You've got the wrong idea.
No. That's not why I brought her here.
Right. We're not... I'm not...
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
What's the issue, dear?
Why are you holding back
from such a man?
Is it the clumpy way he walks?
- What?
- Or the grumpy way he talks?
- Oh, no.
- Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped
Weirdness of his feet?
KRISTOFF: Hey!
And though we know he washes well
He always ends up sort of smelly
But you'll never meet a fella
BOTH: Who's as sensitive and sweet
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
That's nice, but...
BOTH: So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
- So, he's got a few flaws
TROLL 1: Like his peculiar brain, dear
TROLL 2: His thing with the reindeer
BOTH: That's a little outside
of nature's laws
This is not about me!
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
But this we're certain of
You can fix this fixer-upper up
- With a little bit of love
- Um...
Can we please
just stop talking about this?
We've got a real, actual problem, here.
I'll say. So, tell me, dear...
Is it the way that he runs scared?
Or that he's socially impaired?
Or that he only likes
To tinkle in the woods?
I did not need to know that.
Are you holding back your fondness
Due to his unmanly blondness?
(CHUCKLES)
Or the way he covers up
That he's the honest goods?
He's just a bit of a fixer-upper
He's got a couple of bugs
- No, I don't!
- His isolation is confirmation
- Of his desperation for healing hugs
- Aw.
So, he's a bit of a fixer-upper
But we know what to do
The way to fix up this fixer-upper
Is to fix him up with you
BOTH: Whoa!
Stop it, stop it, stop it! Enough!
She is engaged to someone else, okay?
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
That's a minor thing
Her quote "engagement"
Is a flex arrangement
And by the way, I don't see no ring
So, she's a bit of a fixer-upper
- Hey! Whoa, watch it!
- Her brain's a bit betwixt
Get the fiancé out of the way
And the whole thing will be fixed
(ALL VOCALIZING)
We're not saying you can change him
'Cause people don't really change
We're only saying that love's a force
That's powerful and strange
People make bad choices
If they're mad or scared or stressed
But throw a little love their way
Throw a little love their way
And you'll bring out their best
True love brings out the best
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
That's what it's all about
- Father!
- Sister!
- Brother!
- We need each other to raise us up
And round us out
Everyone's a bit of a fixer-upper
But when push comes to shove
The only fixer-upper fixer
That can fix a fixer-upper is...
True, true
True
Love!
Love, love, love
Love
True love
True
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff
to be your trollfully wedded...
- Wait, what?
- You're getting married.
Love!
(HYPERVENTILATING)
Anna?
She's as cold as ice.
There is strange magic here.
- Granpabbie.
- Come, come. Bring her here to me.
Anna, your life is in danger.
There is ice in your heart
put there by your sister.
If not removed,
to solid ice will you freeze, forever.
- What? No.
- But you can remove it, right?
I cannot.
I'm sorry, Kristoff.
If it was her head, that would be easy.
But only an act of true love
can thaw a frozen heart.
An act of true love?
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
(GASPING)
TROLL 1: Something's wrong.
TROLL 2: Are you all right?
Anna, we've got to get you back to Hans.
Hans.
Pull us out, Sven.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Olaf, come on!
I'm coming!
(TROLL KIDS GIGGLING)
Let's go kiss Hans!
Who is this Hans?
(SOLDIERS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
We are here to find Princess Anna.
Be on guard,
but no harm is to come to the queen.
Do you understand?
SOLDIER 1: Yes, Your Grace.
(SOLDIERS AGREEING)
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
(ALL CLAMORING)
(ROARS)
The queen.
(GRUNTS)
DUKE'S THUG 2: Go, go! Come on!
(GASPING)
DUKE'S THUG 2: There!
DUKE'S THUG 1: Up there!
Come on!
DUKE'S THUG 2: We got her.
No. Please.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
DUKE'S THUG 2: Go around. Toss it.
Stay away!
DUKE'S THUG 1: Look out!
DUKE'S THUG 2: Fire! Fire!
Get her!
(MARSHMALLOW GROWLS)
Ah!
(YELLS)
Come on!
(ROARING)
(GRUNTING)
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
SOLDIER: Grab his arm.
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
DUKE'S THUG 2: Aim...
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
SOLDIER 1: This way, this way!
SOLDIER 2: Whoa!
Queen Elsa!
Don't be the monster they fear you are.
(PANTING)
(ICE TINKLING)
(GASPS)
(YELLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(CHAINS RATTLING)
Oh, no. What have... What have I done?
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
(GASPS)
Why did you bring me here?
I couldn't just let them kill you.
But I'm a danger to Arendelle. Get Anna.
Anna has not returned.
(GASPS)
If you would just stop the winter.
Bring back summer, please.
Don't you see?
I can't.
(SIGHS)
You have to tell them to let me go.
I will do what I can.
(DOOR LOCKS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHIMPERING)
(KRISTOFF PANTING)
(ANNA EXHALES SHARPLY)
Just hang in there.
Come on, buddy, faster!
(VOCALIZING)
Oh, boy!
Whoa! I'll meet you guys at the castle!
KRISTOFF: Stay out of sight, Olaf.
OLAF: I will!
Hello!
(WOMAN SCREAMS) It's alive!
It's Princess Anna!
(KRISTOFF PANTING)
(ANNA SHIVERING)
(GROANS)
(SHIVERING) Are you gonna be okay?
Don't worry about me.
(DOOR OPENS)
WOMAN: Anna!
- You had us worried sick.
- My Lady.
Get her warm.
And find Prince Hans, immediately.
We will. Thank you.
Make sure she's safe.
WOMAN: Oh, you poor girl,
you're freezing.
Oh, let's get you inside now
and get you warm.
(WHIMPERS)
(SVEN WHINING)
I'm going back out
to look for Princess Anna.
You cannot risk going out there again.
If anything happens to her...
If anything happens to the princess,
you are all Arendelle has left.
(SIGHS)
KAI: He's in here.
Prince Hans.
Anna.
You're so cold.
- Hans, you have to kiss me.
- What?
- Now! Now!
- Slow down.
We'll give you two some privacy.
What happened out there?
Elsa struck me with her powers.
You said she would never hurt you.
I was wrong.
(GROANS) Anna.
(SHIVERING)
She froze my heart,
and only an act of true love can save me.
A true love's kiss.
Oh, Anna.
If only there was
someone out there who loved you.
What?
You said you did.
As thirteenth in line in my own
kingdom, I didn't stand a chance.
I knew I would have to marry
into the throne somewhere.
What... What are you talking about?
As heir, Elsa was preferable, of course.
But no one was getting
anywhere with her.
- But you...
- Hans!
You were so desperate for love, you
were willing to marry me just like that.
I figured after we married,
I would have to stage
a little accident for Elsa.
Hans!
(GASPS) No. Stop.
But then, she doomed herself,
and you were dumb enough
to go after her.
Please.
(CHUCKLES)
All that's left now is to kill Elsa,
and bring back summer.
You're no match for Elsa.
No, you're no match for Elsa.
I, on the other hand,
am the hero who is going to save
Arendelle from destruction.
You won't get away with this.
Oh...
I already have.
(DOOR LOCKS)
(WHIMPERING)
Please, somebody, help.
(SHIVERING CONTINUES)
Please. Please.
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
DUKE: It's getting colder by the minute.
If we don't do something soon,
we'll all freeze to death.
Prince Hans.
Princess Anna is...
Dead.
What?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What happened to her?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
She was killed.
By Queen Elsa.
ALL: (GASP) No!
Her own sister.
At least we got to say our marriage vows
before she died in my arms.
There can be no doubt now.
Queen Elsa is a monster,
and we are all in grave danger.
Prince Hans,
Arendelle looks to you.
With a heavy heart,
I charge Queen Elsa
of Arendelle with treason.
And sentence her to death.
(SIGHS)
(STRAINING)
GUARD 1: Hurry up!
GUARD 2: She's dangerous.
- Move quickly.
GUARD 3: - Careful.
(STRAINING)
- It won't open!
GUARD 1: - It's frozen shut.
GUARD 2: Put your back into it!
GUARD 4: Come on! Push!
(ALL GRUNT)
(GROWLS)
(WHINES)
(SNORTING)
What is it, buddy?
Hey, watch it.
What's wrong with you?
(GRUNTING)
I don't understand you
when you talk like that.
(YELPS) Stop it! Put me down!
(SNORTS)
No, Sven!
We're not going back.
(WHINES)
She's with her true love.
(SIGHS)
(WHOOSHING)
What the...
Anna!
(PANTING)
(KRISTOFF GRUNTS)
Come on! Come on, boy.
(SHIVERING)
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
(WEAKLY) Help.
(GIGGLING)
(GASPS) Anna!
Oh, no.
(SHRIEKS)
(CONTINUES SHIVERING)
Olaf?
(GASPS)
Olaf. Get away from there.
Wow!
So, this is heat.
I love it.
Ooh! But don't touch it.
(ANNA GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
So, where's Hans?
What happened to your kiss?
I was wrong about him.
It wasn't true love.
But we ran all the way here.
Please, Olaf, you can't stay here.
You'll melt.
I am not leaving here until
we find some other act
of true love to save you.
Do you happen to have any ideas?
I don't even know what love is.
That's okay, I do.
Love is
putting someone else's
needs before yours.
Like, you know, how Kristoff brought you
back here to Hans and left you forever.
(GASPS) Kristoff loves me?
Wow, you really
don't know anything about love, do you?
Olaf, you're melting.
Some people are worth melting for.
(MUMBLES)
Just maybe not right this second.
(YELLS)
Don't worry, I've got it.
(PANTING)
We're gonna get through... Oh, wait.
Hang on, I'm getting something.
(GASPS) It's Kristoff and Sven!
They're coming back this way.
They... They are?
Wow! He's really moving fast.
I guess I was wrong.
I guess Kristoff doesn't
love you enough to leave you behind.
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
No, no, no! You need to
stay by the fire and keep warm.
I need to get to Kristoff.
Why?
(GASPING) Oh, I know why!
There's your act of true love right there!
Riding across the fjords
like a valiant, pungent reindeer king!
Come on!
(BOTH GASP)
OLAF: Look out!
(GROANS) Oh!
(OLAF PANTING)
(BOTH GASP)
Uh... Back this way.
(YELPS) We're trapped.
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERING)
(PANTING)
(SIGHS) Oh...
(SQUEALS)
Whoa! (GIGGLES)
Slide, Anna!
(ANNA BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BOTH SHRIEK)
(OLAF VOCALIZING)
(GROANS)
We made it!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Come on, buddy, faster.
(ANNA GROANING)
Kristoff!
(OLAF PANTING)
Keep going!
Kristoff!
Come on!
(SHIVERING)
(WHIMPERING)
No.
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
Whoa!
(YELLS) Whoa!
Sven... Sven!
(GRUNTING)
Good boy.
(SHIVERING)
(GASPING)
(WEAKLY) Kristoff.
- Kristoff...
- Anna...
Anna!
(GASPING)
Elsa! You can't run from this!
Just take care of my sister.
Your sister?
She returned from the mountain
weak and cold.
She said that you froze her heart.
No.
I tried to save her, but it was too late.
Her skin was ice. Her hair turned white.
Your sister is dead.
Because of you.
No.
(WHIMPERING)
(SOBBING)
(ALL GASP)
(SHIVERING)
(GASPS)
Kristoff.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Anna!
(SWORD UNSHEATHING)
Elsa?
(GRUNTS)
No!
(EXHALES)
(GASPS) Anna!
Oh. Anna!
No, no!
Please, no.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOBBING)
Anna?
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
(GASPS) Anna?
(SIGHS)
Oh, Elsa.
You sacrificed yourself for me?
I love you.
(GASPS) "An act of true love
will thaw a frozen heart."
"Love will thaw."
Love. Of course.
Elsa?
Love!
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE MURMURING IN AWE)
I knew you could do it.
Hands down,
this is the best day of my life.
And, quite possibly, the last.
Oh, Olaf! Hang on, little guy.
Oh, oh, oh!
(GASPS)
My own personal flurry!
(GIGGLES)
(CHUCKLES)
(HANS GROANS)
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Anna?
But she froze your heart.
The only frozen heart
around here is yours.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(ALL CHEERING)
Wonderful!
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN JOY)
(BOTH SIGH)
(GRUNTS)
(CHUCKLES)
SAILOR: Setting course, sir.
(GROANS)
I will return this scoundrel to his country.
We shall see what his 12 big
brothers think of his behavior.
Arendelle thanks you, milord.
This is unacceptable.
I am a victim of fear.
I've been traumatized.
Ah! My neck hurts.
Is there a doctor that I could see?
(STAMMERS)
- And I demand to see the queen!
- Oh. I have a message from the queen.
"Arendelle will henceforth and forever"
"no longer do business
of any sort with Weaseltown."
"Weselton."
- It's Weselton!
SOLDIER: - Let's go.
Come on, come on, come on!
(STAMMERING)
Okay, okay, here I come.
(GRUNTS) Pole!
Whoops! Sorry.
Okay, okay.
Here we are. Oh!
(SQUEALS EXCITEDLY)
(GASPS)
ANNA: I owe you a sled.
- Are you serious?
- Yes!
And it's the latest model.
No, I can't accept this.
You have to. No returns.
No exchanges. Queen's orders.
She's named you the Official
Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
- What? That's not a thing.
- Oh, sure it is.
And it even has a cup holder.
Do you like it?
Like it? I love it!
Whoa.
(KRISTOFF CHUCKLES)
I could kiss you!
I could. I mean, I'd like to. I'd...
(STAMMERS) May I? We me.
I mean, may we?
Wait, what?
We may.
Mmm.
Summer!
(GIGGLING)
(GASPS) Ooh...
Hello.
(CHUCKLES)
(SNIFFS)
(EXHALES)
(GASPING)
(SNEEZING)
(GASPS)
(SLURPS)
(SQUEALS)
(WHIMPERS)
(BELLOWS)
(CHUCKLING)
Are you ready?
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL GASP)
KID: Ice!
(ALL MUTTERING EXCITEDLY)
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(APPLAUDING)
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Ooh! Whoo-hoo...
Swing me.
(CHUCKLES)
Ooh...
(WHIMPERS)
I like the open gates.
We are never closing them again.
(ANNA GASPS)
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful,
but you know I don't skate.
Come on! You can do it!
KRISTOFF: Look out.
Reindeer coming through.
I got it, I got it. I don't got it, I don't got it.
Hey, guys!
That's it, Olaf.
(OLAF CHUCKLES)
Glide and pivot. And glide and pivot.
ELSA: Go.
(LAUGHS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(LIVELY INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENCHANTING INSTRUMENTAL
(DREAMY INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(DRAMATIC INSTRUMENTAL
(GROANING)
Oh!
(SIGHS)