TOHO CO., LTD.
GODZILLA
Produced by Tomoyuki Tanaka
Screenplay by Takeo Murata
and Ishiro Honda
Story by Shigeru Kayama
Photography by Masao Tamai
Music by Akira Ifukube
Special Effects
directed by Eji Tsuburaya
Starring
Momoko Kochi
Akihiko Hirata
and Takashi Shimura
Directed by Ishiro Honda
What was that?
Yes? Southern Sea Salvage,
Ogata speaking.
What?
Right, I understand.
As soon as possible.
Emiko, I'm sorry...
What is it? An accident?
The Coast Guard received
a distress call.
I'll have to cancel
our date tonight.
I'm sorry I can't go with you,
but you can still see it
if you hurry.
It's a shame, but it's your job.
Well, you'd better hurry.
Southern Sea Steamship Company
vessel, the "Eiko-maru,"
a 7,500-ton freighter,
was reported lost...
on August 13 at 19:05 hours.
Its last position,
latitude 24 degrees north,
longitude 141.02 degrees east.
Contact was lost
for unknown reasons.
All units in sectors 3 and 4
stand by for action!
Thank you for calling me.
Thank you again.
What could have happened?
We have no idea.
It seems like there was
a sudden explosion.
Communications suddenly halted
shortly after we received
their SOS.
Well, the "Bingo-maru" is
approaching the area now.
We'll learn more soon enough.
They are here.
Certainly. The "Eiko-maru" and
"Bingo-maru" are both owned
by the Southern Sea
Steamship Company.
Yes. They don't know how.
Can't you tell us
if any survivors were seen?
Please wait a little longer.
We have a helicopter and two
ships searching the area now.
We won't be sure of anything
until we get their report.
Excuse me,
why not send more ships?
Two ships are not enough
for this!
No, we're not limiting
the search party to two ships.
We'll make every effort
to conduct a thorough search.
Until then, please be patient.
Hey!
Help us, please!
We're here! Hang in there!
It was incredible.
The ocean just blew up!
Blew up?
So far, three survivors were
picked up by a fishing boat.
They are being taken
to Odo Island.
We have sent the vessel "Kotaka"
to assist them.
Which ship
were the survivors from...
the "Eiko-maru"
or the "Bingo-maru"?
We are still investigating,
but their names will be released
soon enough.
I hope the three men know
what happened.
We need to know more
about the accidents.
Just a moment! Please, wait!
What's the matter?
I can't believe it.
I just can't believe it!
The fishing boat sank
the same way.
News desk! Ah, Mr. Yamana?
Mr. Yamana, the other search
boat was sunk!
In the same area... yes.
Yes, in the same way!
We're tired of hearing
the same thing!
Please tell us what happened!
Please give us a chance
to investigate!
Don't you know what's going on?
I'm sorry,
but you must be patient!
Wait, please wait!
A drifting sea mine, or an
underwater volcanic eruption?
One shipwreck after another!
I can't imagine,
could it be a volcano?
Izuma! Is there something
out there?
Ah, it's a raft!
Hey, there's a raft out there!
A raft is coming this way!
A raft is coming!
Hey! Over here!
Build up the fire!
It's Masaji! It's Masaji!
Masaji!
Masaji! Hold on! Masaji!
Hang on!
Brother!
Masaji! Masaji!
Masaji!
He did it...
What?!
A monster...
What did this?!
Masaji! What did this?!
It's no good!
We didn't catch anything!
It can't get any worse
than this!
Then...
Godzilla must have done it.
The old man and Godzilla,
both relics from days past!
Hey! What do you know
about the old days?!
If you all keep thinking
like that,
you'll all become prey
for Godzilla!
Anyhow, there must be
some kind of animal in the sea.
That's why
we can't catch anything.
But a creature that big would...
I knew it was stupid
to open my mouth!
I try to tell you all,
but nobody listens!
Shinkichi, let's go.
Ah, sir! Sir, sir!
Godzilla?
It's the name of a monster
that lives in the sea.
It will come from the ocean
to feed on humankind to survive.
In the old days, during times
when the fishing was poor,
we used to sacrifice girls
to prevent him
from eating us all, yes!
Now, this exorcism ceremony
is all that remains
of the old traditions.
Godzilla?
Shinkichi!
Shinkichi! Stay inside!
Brother!
Brother! Run, brother!
Hey, hey!
Shinkichi, what's wrong?!
Brother!
Odo Island Representatives
Mr. Ooyama.
There have been 17 houses
destroyed with nine deaths...
I have heard that there
were other damages.
Could you please tell us
how bad they are?
Odo Island Village Mayor,
Mr. Inada.
Certainly, of course.
Twelve cows and eight pigs died.
I'm not lying!
It was hard to see in the dark,
but it was an animal!
I know it goes
against common sense,
but the more I think about it,
the more I am convinced
that it was definitely not
a normal hurricane.
The way the houses
and helicopter were destroyed,
it seems as if they were crushed
from above!
Now, finally,
we will hear the opinion
of expert paleontologist
Professor Kyohei Yamane.
I suppose my opinion
is a bit premature
before a thorough investigation,
but we are all aware of
the discovery in the Himalayas
of the alleged
"snowman footprints."
It is a mystery
we have yet to solve.
The earth has many deep pockets,
abyssal regions
that contain secrets
we have yet to discover.
For this incident,
I request the formation
of a fact-finding party
for a full investigation.
Good Luck,
Odo Island Research Party!
Good-bye!
We'll see you soon!
It was surprising to see
Dr. Serizawa at our departure.
He rarely leaves his laboratory.
I don't know if he believes
this will be our final journey.
Well, what could go wrong?
Of course, we can avoid
dangerous waters,
but anything can happen.
For the time being,
please don't use the water
from this well.
It's dangerous.
This is horrible!
We can't use the well anymore?
Professor, if there was
radioactive fallout,
wouldn't the wells on the other
side of the island be affected?
Yes. Why is it that the wells
in this area
were the only ones affected?
It doesn't make any sense.
Mr. Hagiwara, I think
this depression might be
the footprint of a creature.
Would you agree with me?
Is that true, Professor?
This footprint is radioactive.
Everybody, it's very dangerous
here! Please step back!
Step back! Step back!
Emiko, look!
It's a trilobite!
A three-lobed creature that has
long since been extinct!
Professor!
You shouldn't be touching that!
Professor, what is that thing?
This is...
an incredible discovery!
It's on the other side
of the hill!
It's on the other
side of the hill!
Father!
What is it?
Tanabe, I saw it!
A creature
from the Jurassic Period!
Where is it?
Emiko! Emiko!
Emiko!
Father!
This way! This way!
What is that?
Those are footprints.
About 2 million years ago,
this brontosaurus
and these other dinosaurs
roamed the earth
during a period
the experts called Jurassic.
During the following
geological period,
the Cretaceous,
a creature somewhere between
the marine reptiles
and the evolving
terrestrial animals was born.
I am convinced there was such
an intermediate creature.
This creature, according
to Odo Island folklore,
is called Godzilla.
As we look at this photo
of Godzilla's head
from a hill on Odo Island,
we can estimate
that this creature
stands approximately
50 meters tall.
So then, how can we explain
the presence of such a creature
during the present day?
It probably survived
by eating deep sea organisms
occupying a specific niche.
However, recent experimental
nuclear detonations
may have drastically altered
its natural habitat.
I would even speculate
that a hydrogen bomb explosion
may have removed it
from its surroundings.
Incredible!
Really!
I have strong evidence
to support my theory.
First, the organism
we found embedded
in Godzilla's footprint,
a trilobite.
This is a photo of the creature.
This is it.
This creature has been extinct
for two million years,
yet here it is
in perfect physical condition.
Next is the sediment
that we found
in the trilobite's shell.
That sediment is sand.
There is no doubt that this sand
matches the deposits found
from the Jurassic period.
This sand is similar
to the red clay
found in the stratum
of that particular period.
Professor, how do you know
that this has something to do
with the atomic bombs?
Because
our Geiger counter readings
of the radiation in this sand
indicate the presence
of Strontium-90.
Professor Tanabiya will explain
this better in a moment,
but basically, this sand
that came from Godzilla
has absorbed
a massive dose of radiation,
the type generated
only from an atomic bomb.
Order, please! Order, please!
The evidence suggests
that Godzilla itself
must have absorbed an enormous
amount of atomic radiation.
Order, please! Order, please!
Chairman! Chairman!
Mr. Ooyama.
I believe
Professor Yamane's report
is of such extreme importance,
it must not be made public.
What are you saying?!
Because it is so important,
it should be made public!
Yes! Yes!
Be quiet!
What I mean is, if this Godzilla
is the product from the use
of atomic weapons...
Exactly!
That's exactly what it is!
She's right!
That's my point!
World affairs are fragile enough
as it is!
If this were to be made public,
can you imagine
the consequences?
The truth is the truth!
That is what makes it
such a delicate matter!
The improper handling
of such a notion
would engulf the country
in a panic!
The government, the economy
and international relations
would plunge into total chaos!
You stupid idiot!
What are you saying?!
You dare to call me an idiot?!
Apologize! Apologize!
The truth must be made public!
Counter-Godzilla Headquarters
Established.
Seventeen Ships Already Lost.
It's terrible, huh?
Contaminated tuna
and radioactive fallout,
and now this Godzilla
to top it all off!
What will happen if he appears
out of Tokyo Bay?
First, he'll probably eat you
in one bite.
You're horrible!
They seemed certain about
the accuracy of their report.
How could we create
such a thing?
I guess I'll have to find
a shelter soon.
Find one for me, too!
The shelters again?
That stinks.
Counter-Godzilla Headquarters
Isn't there any way they can get
rid of this creature?
Longitude 138
to 138.07 degrees east.
Latitude 33.04
to 33.08 degrees north.
These are the coordinates of
the anti-Godzilla frigate fleet.
Depth charges will be dropped
in the area.
So vessels in the vicinity
should be warned.
That's all.
Is that all?
In response
to the public outcry,
the government is attempting
to get rid of the monster
known as Godzilla.
A frigate fleet has been ordered
to begin
a massive depth-charge attack
in order to get rid
of the creature.
The 10 vessel fleet left port
at 10:00 a.m.,
heading for the coast
of Odo Island.
At 10:19 a.m.,
they received orders
to commence with their attack.
What's wrong with them?
The professor is a zoologist.
He doesn't want them
to kill Godzilla.
Father! Father!
Father...
Please leave me alone
for a while.
Emiko, please turn off
the light.
Yes.
Godzilla! It's Godzilla!
Watch out! Watch out!
Please don't panic!
What a bother!
Have you tried solving
the problem together?
They're sticking
to their point of view.
How much longer will they
keep us waiting like this?
For as long as they want.
It's annoying!
Please, Professor. Have a seat.
Excuse me.
Thank you for coming.
You're welcome.
This is quite a problem,
Professor.
If this keeps up,
we'll have to suspend
the international ship routes.
Have you found a way?
Is there something we can do
to defeat him?
So, that's it?
Professor Yamane,
let's be honest.
If there's a way to defeat
Godzilla, we'd like to know.
It's impossible!
He absorbed massive amounts
of atomic radiation,
but Godzilla still survived.
What do you think
could kill him?
Instead, we should focus
on why he is still alive.
That should be our top priority!
Professor Yamane's argument
is absolutely correct!
This isn't the time
to behave like idiots.
We should focus
on scientific research!
Yes, but research at what cost?
You're right!
That's the question!
Hagiwara, interview
this gentleman.
Dr. Serizawa?
Yes, he's Professor Yamane's
future son-in-law.
Oh? The girl's fiance?
I'm sure my father
will understand.
There's no reason
for him to apologize.
But I can't help feeling uneasy
when I think about Serizawa.
If it wasn't for the war,
he wouldn't have received
such a terrible scar.
Ogata...
Ever since I was a child,
I've always thought of him
as an older brother.
Even now, my feelings for him
have not changed at all.
Emiko, thanks.
Miss, Mr. Hagiwara would like
to see you.
Mr. Hagiwara?
Yes, the reporter.
Hello! Excuse me.
Thank you.
What do you want?
Um... I'd like
to ask you a favor.
The truth is, I tried
to talk to Dr. Serizawa,
but he refused to see me.
So, I was wondering if you could
introduce me to him?
It's for our daily newspaper.
I'm sorry, but I need your help.
It's perfect.
I should go along with you to
speak with Serizawa personally.
You're right, but I should break
it to him my way.
Please let me go
to speak with him first.
You're right. Well, go ahead.
Thank you. I'm sorry,
but we should go.
I have a ride waiting outside.
I'll try my best to talk to him.
I'll help Shinkichi
with his studies. See you later.
Serizawa Research Laboratory
There must be some mistake.
I haven't spoken to anyone
about the importance
of my research.
It's the truth.
A journalist in Switzerland
met with a German scientist
who stated that your project
would be
an incredible breakthrough
in anti-Godzilla operations
in Japan when completed.
I don't have any German
scientist associates.
Really? Then what is the nature
of your research right now?
No. I'd rather not speak
about it.
Well, thank you for your time.
No, I'm sorry
that I wasn't much help.
Excuse me.
I'll stay a little longer.
Really? Then, I'll be going.
I wanted to find out
what his research was all about.
He's very moody,
but please try to ask him again
at another time.
I will. Good-bye.
Have a safe trip.
Well, what are you really
studying now?
My father is also wondering
what you are studying
these days.
Emiko, would you like to see it?
Yes.
This must be
strictly confidential.
Sure.
I'm risking my life
in this project.
Would you be able
to keep it a secret?
Follow me.
Wow!
Get back!
Emiko, you're the only one
I've shown this to.
Don't forget it.
Yes, I'll keep my promise.
Welcome back. We missed you.
Welcome home.
Did anything happen?
No, it was nothing.
Has Emiko come back?
Yes!
Godzilla!
Godzilla has come back!
Ogata!
I couldn't tell him about us.
I am Yamane, Professor Yamane!
I'm sorry, but I've been ordered
not to let anyone pass!
Then tell your commander
not to use lights on Godzilla!
They will only make him angry!
He can't be bothered
by that now!
Professor,
let's go to that hill.
Get back, please!
International Researchers
to Assist!
We are preparing to construct
a 30 meter high, 80 meter deep
barbed-wire fence
along the coast.
We will send 50,000 volts
of electric current
through the fence in hope of
electrocuting Godzilla to death.
We will have
to evacuate the people
along the coast, of course,
and maintain a safe distance
of 500 meters
from the entire fence perimeter.
The Coast Guard and the Army
will work
to implement this defense plan.
Hurry! Hurry!
This is a Security
Command Announcement.
At 16:30 hours, Godzilla was
sighted north of Kasonzaki,
moving in a northeast direction.
A maximum security alert
has been issued
for the coastal zones
in the Tokyo vicinity.
Third District. Third District.
Check! Check!
Third district!
Check!
This is a special news report.
All residents of the Minato,
Shinagawa and Osaku districts
are to begin evacuating
immediately.
Repeating, all residents
of the Minato, Shinagawa
and Osaku districts are
to begin evacuating immediately.
Please keep your radio on
for further reports.
Emiko, today I'm going to ask
for your father's consent.
Will that be all right?
Welcome home.
What happened, Father?
All they can think about
is killing Godzilla.
Why can't they try to study him
from a radiological perspective?
It's an unique opportunity!
Professor, I agree with them.
Ogata, I do not take
this matter lightly.
Godzilla is something
that no one in the world
has ever seen,
and only those of us in Japan
can study it!
But, Professor, that's
no reason to do nothing
while this monster
ravages our country.
Isn't Godzilla a product
of the atomic bomb
that still haunts
many of us Japanese?
Don't you think we should study
what keeps a creature
like this alive,
regardless of the radiation
it absorbs!
But...
All you want is
to kill Godzilla, too?!
Go away! Get out of my house!
I'm very sorry.
No, I shouldn't have
upset him like that.
No, Father has been like this.
Emiko, give me a chance
to see him again.
This is a special bulletin!
This is
a special bulletin!
Godzilla was spotted
moving toward the coastline
several minutes ago.
The barbed-wire fence
along the shoreline
is about to be charged
with high voltage electricity.
We repeat...
Direction, 25 to 30 degrees!
Distance, 850!
Fires are raging through
the Shihabara district.
We have no way to put them out.
This is Central Command,
come in, unit 465.
Central Command,
this is unit 465.
The fire that started
in Mitadai-machi
has spread to other districts!
This is Central Command,
come in, unit 215.
Central Command, unit 215.
Our defense lines have broken!
Armored division #49
has been destroyed!
The current position
of the target is unknown.
We are awaiting further orders,
please!
Attention all units!
Initiate Security
Command code 129!
Initiate Security Command
code 129!
Prepare to repel attack
while carrying out
firefighting procedures.
Concentrate efforts
to rescue casualties.
Initiate Security Command
code 129!
Initiate Security
Command code 129!
We'll be joining your father
in just a moment!
A little longer,
a little longer,
and we'll be with your daddy!
This is unbelievable,
absolutely unbelievable!
Yet, the unbelievable
is happening at this moment,
right before our very eyes!
Right now, Godzilla is leaving
behind a sea of flame!
From Ginza-Owari to Shinbashi,
Tamachi, Chiba and Shinabara,
it's all become a sea of flames!
Now, Godzilla is starting
to move again!
It appears that he is moving
beyond the city limits!
To all of our viewers,
this is not a play or a movie!
This is real,
the most extraordinary story
of the century!
Is the world going
to be destroyed
by a two million-year-old
monster?
All personnel to the shelters!
All personnel
to the shelters!
Quickly, please!
Operational Command Staff,
proceed to shelter 306!
We are reporting to you live
from a short-wave transmitter.
Godzilla is now approaching
this broadcasting station,
heading toward our TV tower!
There is no time for us
to take cover!
We don't know
what will happen to us!
He is getting even closer!
It looks like our doom!
I'm watching as he grabs
onto the tower!
He has incredible strength!
This broadcast is over!
Good-bye, everyone, good-bye!
Godzilla has turned Tokyo
into a sea of flames!
He is moving from Ueno
to Asakusa and Shinagawa,
apparently heading
for the river!
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it!
He's running away!
He'll be back!
What can we do?
Damn it!
How can we get rid of him?!
Godzilla has retreated
back into the sea.
Professor Yamane has been asked
to work on a plan
to defeat the monster.
No details are known
at this time.
That is the news for now.
Mr. Ogata
from Southern Sea Salvage.
Mr. Ogata from
Southern Sea Salvage.
There has been a change
in the scheduled timetable.
Please report
to the briefing room
for further instructions.
Thank you for your help.
Your mother will be okay.
Emiko...
Ogata, I have something
important to tell you!
I can't stay quiet anymore!
I must betray him.
Betray?
Yes. I made a promise
to Serizawa.
Serizawa?
It's a secret I've been keeping,
even from you!
But, now, I have
to break my promise!
It happened on the day
that Mr. Hagiwara and I
went to see him.
That's when it happened.
Get back!
What was that?
Yes. All of the oxygen
in the water was disintegrated.
The organisms in the tank
died of asphyxiation.
Their remains were liquified
by my Oxygen Destroyer.
Overall, it's a device that
splits oxygen atoms into fluids.
My...
I intended to devote my work to
the study of the element oxygen.
But, in the course
of my research,
I came across
an unknown form of energy.
In my first experiment,
I discovered a powerful force
that scared me beyond words.
I didn't eat
for two or three days!
Just a little piece of this,
dropped into the water,
could turn the entire Tokyo Bay
into a graveyard!
Why are you working
on such an awful project?
Emiko! I perform my work
strictly as
a research scientist!
But what if...
what if your discovery
is used
for some horrible purpose?
You're right.
Used as a weapon, this would be
as powerful as a nuclear bomb.
It could totally destroy
humankind!
But I believe I can find a use
for the Oxygen Destroyer
that will benefit society.
Until then,
I won't reveal its existence.
That's why I didn't say anything
to the reporter.
If I am forced to surrender
this device
in its present form...
I'll make sure the results
of my experiments are destroyed
in the event of my death.
I understand.
I won't tell anyone about this,
not even my own father.
I had to break my promise.
So that's it?
But, Emiko, considering
what Serizawa said,
and the fact that this thing
can be of help,
I'm sure he will forgive you
for this.
Hello. Welcome back.
Serizawa.
What? Oh, it's you.
I have a favor to ask you today.
Well, have a seat.
What do you want from me?
I want to use
the Oxygen Destroyer.
What Oxygen Destroyer?
I don't know
what you're talking about!
Serizawa,
why are you pretending?
Pretending?
Serizawa, I broke the promise
I made to you.
So I told him everything!
Please let him use the device!
I'm sorry! Please forgive me!
Emiko wanted to help
after seeing the destruction.
Please try to forgive her.
Your device is our only hope!
Ogata, if Emiko told you
everything about my device,
you should know
why I can't let you use it.
I must refuse!
Serizawa!
No!
Why is it wrong
to use it for this?
Please go home!
Serizawa!
Open the door, please! Serizawa!
Serizawa! What are you doing?!
Leave me alone!
Do you want to destroy years
of research?
Let go!
Stop, please!
Serizawa!
Ogata!
Ogata, forgive me.
If my device can serve
a good purpose,
I would announce it
to everyone in the world!
But in its current form,
it is just a weapon
of horrible destruction!
Please understand, Ogata!
I understand,
but if we don't use your device
against Godzilla,
what are we going to do?
Ogata, if the Oxygen Destroyer
is used even once,
politicians from around
the world will see it.
Of course, they'll want
to use it as a weapon.
Bombs vs. Bombs,
missiles vs. Missiles,
and now a new super weapon
to throw upon us all!
As a scientist,
no, as a human being,
I can't allow that to happen!
Am I right?
Well, what do we do
about the horror before us now?
Should we just let it happen?
If anyone can save us now,
Serizawa, you're the only one!
If... you use the device
to defeat Godzilla,
unless you reveal what you have
done, who will know about it?
Ogata, humans are weak animals.
Even if I burn my notes,
the secret will still be
in my head.
Until I die, how can I be sure
I won't be forced by someone
to make the device again?
What am I going to do?
"Oh Peace, Oh Light, Return,"
the prayer for peace
that took place
all over the country today.
Here we see the Tokyo chapter
of this event.
Listen to the young voices
as they put the strength
of their lives into their song.
May we live
without destruction
May we look to tomorrow
with hope
May peace and light
return to us.
Serizawa!
Ogata, you are right.
But this will be the first
and last time
that I will ever allow
the Oxygen Destroyer to be used.
Don't cry, Emiko.
This is the only way to be sure
that it won't fall
into the wrong hands.
We are getting closer
to the moment of truth.
We will soon know if Godzilla,
the monster
that has terrorized the world
will be finally buried forever
in the ocean depths.
At this time, Geiger-counter
readings are being used
to pinpoint Godzilla's location.
Ogata, get me a diving suit.
What are you saying?!
You have no experience
in using a diving suit!
Serizawa... Ogata is right.
Let him do it.
Professor, this is
the only Oxygen Destroyer
I have!
To use it properly,
I have to do it underwater.
All right.
We'll do it together.
No. I'll do this myself.
You're crazy.
I won't allow someone
with no experience
to go down alone!
Hey! Get another
diving suit ready!
Okay? Please don't
go down alone!
Will the only Oxygen Destroyer
in the world
be powerful enough
to do the job?
Its inventor, Dr. Serizawa,
remains silent.
All we can do now
is pray for its success.
Professor...
I never thought
I'd reveal it in this way.
I'll be praying for you.
All right!
You two be very careful.
Ogata, we're counting on you.
Right!
The time has come.
Right now, Dr. Serizawa
is being lowered into the water.
They've reached the bottom!
Pull!
Start pulling!
Serizawa! Serizawa!
Serizawa!
What's going on?! Serizawa!
Ogata, it worked!
Both of you, be happy.
Good-bye... farewell!
Serizawa! Hey, bring him up!
Serizawa!
Serizawa...
This exhilaration,
this jubilation, we have won!
We can see that Godzilla
will never rise
from the ocean's depths again!
This victory
could not be achieved
if it weren't for the young
scientist, Dr. Serizawa.
He wanted us to be happy...
I can't believe that Godzilla
was the only surviving member
of its species...
But, if we keep on conducting
nuclear tests,
it's possible that another
Godzilla might appear...
somewhere in the world, again.
Salute!
At ease!