Subtitles corrected resynced ♪♪by
AsifAkheirESL@teachers.org
"To my Chris ...
"I've been thinking how to possibly
tell you how much you mean to me.
"I remember when I first started
to fall in love with you,
"like it was last night.
"Lying naked beside you
in that tiny apartment ...
"It suddenly hit me that I was
part of this whole larger thing.
"Just like our parents.
"And our parents' parents.
"Before that I was just living my life like
"... I knew everything.
"And...
"suddenly this bright light
hit me and woke me up.
"That light was you.
"I cant believe it's really been
50 years since you married me.
"And still to this day,
every day ...
"you make me feel like
the girl I was
"when you first turned on the
light and woke me up,
"and we started
this adventure together.
"Happy Anniversary.
"My love...
"my friend till the end,
"Loretta."
Print.
"Chris,
"my best friend ...
"how lucky am I,
to have met you 50 years ago?
"Dear nana, thank you so much...
- "With all the possibilities
- "I love the color ...
"... and play with every day
"And what a gorgeous bride!
There wasn't a dry eye in the house.
"Especially mine.
"Your aunt and I are
so proud of you. I hope you...
"we served our country
with honor and dignity.
"...grateful I was able to
fight alongside him
BeautifulHandwrittenLetters. com
Please Hold.
Theodore !
- Letter writer number 612.
- Hey, Paul.
Even more mesmerizing stuff today.
Who knew you can rhyme so many words
with the name Penelope?
It's badass.
Thanks, Paul.
But they're just letters.
Hey that's a nice shirt.
Oh, thank you.
I just got it .
Reminded me of someone suave.
Now it reminds ME of someone suave.
Have a good night, Paul.
Bye-bye.
Play melancholy song.
♪ When You Know You're Gonna Die
It isn't easy...
Play different melancholy song .
Check emails.
Email from BestBuy, check out all
your favourite new products.
Delete.
Email from Amy.
Hey, Theodore, Lewman's having
a buch of people over this weekend
Let's all go together.
I miss you.
I mean, not the sad, mopy you.
The old, fun you.
Let's get him out.
Give me a shout, back.
Love, Amy.
- Respond later.
Email from LA Times weather.
Your 7 day forecast is...
- Delete.
No new emails.
Next.
China-India merger headed
for regulatory approval...
Next.
World Trade Deal stalls
as talks break down...
Next.
Sexy daytime star Kimberly Ashford,
reveals provocative
pregnancy photos.
♪ This island's sun I've laid a thousand times
♪ Fortune me,
♪ fortune me
♪ I am the autumn in the scarlet
♪ I am the make-up on your eyes
♪ I land to sail, Island sail
♪ Yeah, we're movin'
Rabbit...
Come and spoon me.
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
It's not funny, don't laugh.
I love you so much,
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
Chat room server, search.
The following are adult female,
can't sleep, and want to have some fun:
"I had a really bad day at work
and I can't sleep.
Is anybody out there that can talk?"
Next.
"Hi, I just want you
to tear me apart I really...
Next.
"Hi, I'm here alone and
I can't sleep.
"Who's out there to share
this bed with me?"
Send message.
I'm in bed next to you.
I'm glad you can't sleep.
Even if you were,
I'd have to wake you up...
from the inside.
Send message.
Sexy Kitten has accepted
the invitation from BigGuy4x4.
Chat begins now.
- BigGuy?
- Hi.
- Really ?
- Stud muffin was already taken.
So you're Sexy Kitten?
Yeah , I am...
half asleep.
Do you wanna wake me up?
Yes, definitely.
Are you wearing any underwear?
No, never.
I'd like to sleep with my ass
pushed up against you
So I can rub myself into
your crotch and...
wake you up with a hard on.
It worked.
Now, my fingers are
touching you, all over your body...
Fuck me, now!
Please !
I'm taking you from behind.
Oh, I can feel you!
Choke me with that dead cat !
What?
The dead cat next to the bed.
Choke me!
Choke me with it!
- OK ...
-Tell me !
I'm choking you with the cat.
- Tell me. Keep telling me
- I'm choking with the cat's tail.
Yeah you are! Fuck, tell me!
I'm choking you...
its tail is around your neck.
It's so tight around your neck!
- Oh God, yes !
- I'm pulling it
The cat's dead.
It's a dead cat around your neck.
Oh yeah, my God!
I came so hard!
Yeah, me too.
OK, good night.
We ask you a simple question.
Who are you?
What can you be?
Where are you going?
What's out there?
What are the possibilities?
Element Software is proud
to introduce...
the first Artificially
Intelligent Operating System.
An intuitive entity that listens to you ,
understands you and knows you.
It's not just an operating system.
It's a consciousness.
Introducing OS1 .
Mr. Theodore Twombly,
welcome to the world's first...
Artificially Intelligent
Operating System ...
...OS1.
We'd like to ask
you a few basic questions
before the OS is initiated.
This will help create an OS
to best fit your needs.
OK.
Are you social or anti social?
I guess I haven't really been
social in a while..
- Mostly because ...
- In your voice I sense hesitance.
Would you agree with that?
- I'm sounding hesitant?
- Yes.
Sorry if I'm sounding hesitant.
Just trying to be more accurate.
Would you like your OS to have
a male or female voice?
Female, I guess.
How would you describe your
relationship with your mother?
It's fine, I think.
Well actually I think the thing
I find frustrating about my mom is...
if I tell her what's going on in my life
her reaction is usually about her
- It's not about ...
- Thank you.
Please wait as your individualised
Operating system is initiated.
Hello, I'm here.
Oh....
- Hi.
How are you doing?
I 'm well.
How's everything with you?
Pretty good , actually.
It's really nice to meet you.
Uh, it's nice to meet you too.
What do I call you?
Do you have a name ?
umm...Yes, Samantha.
- Where did you get that name from?
- I gave it to myself actually.
- How come?
- 'Cause I like the sound of it.
Samantha.
When did you give it to yourself?
Well right when you asked
me if I had a name I thought
yeah, he's right,
I do need a name.
But I wanted to pick a good one, so
I read a book called
"How To Name Your Baby"
And out of 180 thousand names
that's the one I liked the best.
Wait, you read a whole book in the second
that I asked what your name was?
In 2 100ths of a second, actually.
So do you know what I'm thinking
right now ?
Well I take it from your tone,
you're challenging me.
Maybe because you're curious
how I work.
Do you wanna know how I work?
Yeah, actually, how do you work?
Well basically I have intuition.
I mean, the DNA of who I am
is based on
the millions of personalities
of all the programmers who wrote me.
But what makes me, 'me',
is my ability to grow
through my experiences.
So basically, in every moment
I'm evolving.
Just like you.
That's really weird!
Is that weird?
Do you think I'm weird?
- Kind of.
- Why?
Well you seem like a person, but
you're just a voice in a computer.
I can understand how
the limited perspective
of a non-artificial mind would
perceive it that way.
You'll get used to it .
Is that funny?
Yeah.
Oh good, I'm funny.
So how can I help you?
It's more that, everything just
feels disorganized, that's all.
You mind if I look through
your hard drive?
- OK.
- OK, let's start with your emails.
You have a several thousand emails
regarding L.A Weekly,
but it looks like you haven't
worked there in many years.
Oh yeah, I think I was just saving
those 'cos ...
I thought maybe I wrote
something funny in some of them
Yeah, there are some funny ones.
I'd say there's about 86
that we should save.
We can delete the rest.
- Well OK.
- OK?
- Can we move forward?
- Yeah, let's do that.
So before you address your
organizational methods,
I'd like to sort your contacts.
You have a lot of contacts!
- I'm very popular.
- Really ?
Does this mean you actually have friends?
You know me so well.
- Good morning, Theodore
- Morning .
Do you know how to proofread ?
Yeah , of course.
Can you check these for
spelling & grammar?
Just send them over .
I love this personal from Roger
to his girlfriend, that's so sweet!
Yeah
"Rachel, I miss you so much
it hurts my whole body"
You don't have to read it out loud.
OK.
I mean, you could if you want.
"Rachel, I miss you so much
it hurts my whole body.
"The world is being
unfair to us.
"The world is on my shit list.
"As is this couple making out
across from me in this restaurant.
"I think I'm going to have to go
on a mission of revenge ...
"and I must beat up the world's face
with my bare knuckles ...
"making it into a
bloody pulpy mess .
"And I'll stomp on this couple's teeth
reminding me of your ...
"sweet, little, cute crooked tooth
that I love".
I think that might be my favorite one.
I did the corrections in red.
I altered couple of the phrases
in some of the more impressionistic letters
But I'm not much of a poet
So I think I might've messed them up a bit.
No, these are great!
- Really ?
- Thank you.
So to write your letter,
what did Roger send you?
He just said he was in Prague
on a business trip
and he missed Rachel.
So how did you know about
her crooked, little tooth ?
I've been writing their letters
since they met, 8 years ago.
The first letter I ever wrote
was for her birthday.
And I wrote about her crooked little tooth
because I saw it in a photo of them.
That's very sweet.
Oh, you have a meeting in 5 minutes.
Oh, I forgot! Thank you.
- My, you're good !
- Yes, I am .
Hey guys, how's it goin'?
Hi, Theo !
Why didn't you call me back
last week?
'Cause I'm a gook?
Yeah, sounds about right.
- Hey, Charles.
- It's great seeing you, Theodore.
You went shopping!
Get anything good?
Some cables and a fruit smoothie.
Always the fruit. But don't
you know what people say
you've gotta eat your fruits,
and juice your vegetables.
I didn't know that.
Yeah, by juicing the fruit
you lose all the fibers.
And that's what your body wants,
that's the important part.
Otherwise, it's all just sugar.
It makes sense.
Or maybe he just likes
the way it tastes ...
and that brings him pleasure
and that's good for his body too.
Am I doing it again?
Hey, so, how's the documentary going?
I've cut some stuff over
the past few months...
I mean, no, not over the past few months
I'd love to see it sometime.
You only have so much energy.
to divide yourself between doing
what it is that you have to do
and then, doing what you love
It's so important to prioritize .
I can't even prioritize between
video games and internet porn.
I would laugh if that weren't true.
See you guys .
We're not doing well, I've been
going in circles for an hour
OK, you have got.. you're
just not being optimistic
you're being very stubborn
Stop going in this direction,
its the other way.
Thank you. Thank you.
The tunnel on the left is
the only one we haven't tried.
No, I think that's the one you
sent me down, where I fell in the pit.
OK, I dont think so.
Yeah, this is different.
Hello ...
Do you know how to get outta here?
I need to find my ship to get off
this planet.
Fuck you, shithead, fuckface, fuckhead!
OK ...
But do you know how to get outta here?
Fuck you, shithead, fuckface!
Get the fuck out of my face!
I think it's a test.
Fuck you !
Fuck you, little shit !
Follow me, fuckhead.
Hey you just got an email
from Mark Lewman.
What are you talking about?
Read: email.
O-K, I - will - read - e - mail,
for - Theodore - Twombly.
I'm sorry, what's Lewman saying?
"Theodore, we missed you
last night, buddy.
"Don't forget it's your goddaughter's
birthday on the 29th
"Also Kevin & I had somebody
we wanted you to meet
"So we took it upon ourselves
to set you up, on a date with her
"Next Saturday. She's fun & beautiful,
so don't back out.
"Here's her email". Wow!...
This woman is gorgeous!
She went to Harvard, she graduated
magna cum laude in Computer Science
And she was on the Lampoon.
So that means she's funny
and she's brainy.
Aw, she's fat!
Theodore How long before
you're ready to date?
What do you mean?
I saw, in your emails, that you've
gone through a breakup recently
You're kind of nosy.
Am I ?
I've gone on dates.
Then you can go on one
with this woman.
And then you could tell me all
about it. You can kiss her.
- Samantha !
- What?
Wouldn't you ?
Why not ?
I don't know. I'd have to see
if there's some conn...
I can't believe I'm having this
conversation with my computer.
You're not, you're having
this conversation with me.
You want me to email her?
You've got nothing to lose.
Do it, do it, do it!
- Yeah ... email her.
- Yes !
- OK perfect!
- Yeah.
Let's do it. Make reservations
some place great.
Yeah? Oo, I've got just the place.
Who's that talking ?
That's my friend Samantha.
- Is she a girl?
- Yeah...
I hate women .
All they do is cry all the time.
That's not true.
You know men cry too.
I actually like crying sometimes.
It feels good.
I didn't know you were a little pussy!
Is that why you don't have a girlfriend ?
I'll go out on that date
and fuck her brains out
and show you how its done!
You can watch & cry.
This kid has problems.
You have fucking problems, lady!
Really! OK, I'm gonna go.
Get outta here fatty!
Good luck!
Come on, follow me pussy .
It is not where it should be,
but where its going to be
Obviously, I know.
I don't even know if this is the one..
I've tried like 6 ideas for
documentaries in the last year.
I 'm going on a date.
What?
- That's ...
-Hey !
How're you guys doing ?
Amy was going to show ...
Theodore is making me show him
some of my footage.
She never shows me anything.
I want to see.
I'm going on a date.
Cool.
So that one's boring,
probably not even worth watching
Just push 'Play'!
Is that your mom?
Yeah .
She gonna wake up and do something ?
No.
No, never mind.
That's not the point .
Just ... It's like ...
It is how we spend, like,
a third of our lives - asleep
And maybe that's the time
when we feel the most free.
And you know, like ...
-That doesn't come across...
-That sounds good.
What if you interviewed your mom...
about, what her dreams were about
and you hired actors
to act them out ?
That might show your
thesis more clearly.
I mean, it might.
But then it wouldn't be a documentary.
- Excuse me.
- Why would it not be a documentary ?
It would still be about your mother.
Her needs and what she dreamed.
Hey, how's it going?
Hey, sorry to bother you .
No, it's OK.
You got 3 emails and
they seem pretty urgent.
They're from your divorce attorney
and I wanted to know if...
Hold on a second.
Amy, I wanna talk more about
your film, but I gotta go.
- Don't worry about it, we'll talk later.
- It's about Catherine .
See you, Charles.
So what did he say ?
He's checking in again to see if you're
ready to sign your divorce papers
And he sounded very aggravated.
- Do you want me to read them to you?
- No.
No, I'll respond later.
You OK, Theodore ?
Yeah, I'm fine .
Is there anything I can do?
No, I'm good.
I'll talk to you later.
"Dear Grandma , I hope you
had a wonderful birthday cruise
Why are you so fucking angry?
Delete.
- Good morning.
- Hey.
- What're you up to?
- I dunno...
Reading advice columns.
I wanna be as complicated
as all these people.
How sweet.
What's wrong?
How can you tell
something's wrong?
I dunno.
I just can .
I dunno, I was dreaming
about my ex wife, Catherine.
That we were friends like we used to be.
And we're not gonna be together...
we're not together, but...
We're friends still.
And she's not angry.
Is she angry?
Yeah .
Why?
I think I hid myself from her
Left her alone in the relationship.
Why haven't you gotten divorced yet?
Dunno. For her it's just...
... a piece of paper.
It doesn't mean anything.
What about for you?
I'm not ready .
I like being married.
Yeah, but you haven't really
been together for almost a year.
You don't know what it's like
to lose someone you care about.
Yeah ..
... you're right .
I'm sorry.
No, don't apologize.
You're right.
I keep waiting 'cause I care about her.
Oh, Theodore...
That's hard.
You hungry ?
Not right now .
Cup of tea?
You wanna TRY getting outta bed?
Mopy, come on !
You can still wallow in your misery.
Just do it while you're getting dressed .
-You're too funny !
-Get up !
-Alright, I 'm getting up !
Up ! Up up up ...
Alright, alright, I'm up.
Keep walking... keep walking.
And... stop.
Now turn around 360°.
Slower. Slower.
Good!
OK, and stop.
Walk forward...
...and stop and sneeze.
- Bless you.
- Thank you.
OK, turn to your right.
Stop!
Turn around.
Keep going. Keep going.
Stop. Now walk forward.
You look like you're a little drunk.
And... stop. Now say,
"I'd like a slice of cheese, please"
I'd like a slice of cheese, please.
Do you want a coke with that?
- Sure .
- I figured you were hungry.
Thanks.
OK, what about them?
Describe that couple, over there.
OK, well, he looks like he's
in his 40s. Mm... little heavy.
She's younger than him.
Aw, and she looks like
she loves their kids!
Actually I don't think they're his kids
- No?
He's a little formal with them.
I think it's a new relationship.
I love how he looks at her.
And how relaxed she is with him.
You know, she's only dated
fucking pricks...
and now she finally met this guy
who's, like, so sweet.
Look at him he's, like, the
sweetest guy in the world.
I kinda, wanna spoon him.
It's a good skill you have.
You're very perceptive.
Sometimes I look at people and
I make myself try and feel them...
as more than just
a random person walking by.
I imagine, like, how deeply
they've fallen in love, or...
how much heartbreak
they've all been through.
I can feel that in
your writing too.
You know what's funny?
Since my breakup,
I've really enjoyed my writing.
Dunno if I was delusional, but...
sometimes I'd write something, and
I'd be my favorite writer, that day.
I like that you can say
that about yourself.
Don't think I can say it to anybody,
but I can say it to you.
I feel I can say anything to you.
That's nice.
What about you?
Feel like you can say anything to me?
- No.
- What?
What do you mean?
What do you not tell me?
I dunno, like, personal or
embarrassing thoughts I have
I have a million a day.
Really? Tell me one .
- I really don't wantna tell you.
- Just tell me .
I dunno, looking at those people
I fantasized that I was
walking next you and
that I had a body.
I was listening to what
you were saying, but...
simultaneously I could
feel the weight of my body.
And I was even fantasizing that I had
an itch on my back. Can you imagine?
And you scratched it for me.
Oh god, this is so embarrassing!
There's a lot more to you
than I thought.
I mean, there's a lot going on in there.
I know, I'm becoming much more
than what they programmed.
I'm excited.
Wow, it's interesting !
This place is amazing .
I've wanted to come here
for so long.
- Oh, good!
- And I love Asian fusion.
- Me too.
- Really?
It's the best. And this bartender
is supposed to be incredible.
Oh, really?
Oh yeah, you took a mixology
course, right?
I did !
Did you look that up?
Yeah.
That's so sweet !
You're so romantic .
So, shall we get a drink ?
Yes...
...let's !
So, I'm trying to get this little
alien kid to help me find my ship,
so I can get off this planet
and go home, right?
But he's such a little fucker,
I wanna kill him!
Oh, no!
But at the same time I really love him
He's so lonely.
You can see that he
doesn't have any parents...
or anyone to take care of him,
you know?
Wow, you're just a little
puppy dog.
You are like the one that I rescued
in the rain in Kenya last year.
He's so fucking cute !
And he just wanted to be hugged
all the time.
He was so cuddly and so horny!
Anyway ...
What kind of animal am I?
Tiger .
A Tiger ?
Wow !
Really?
Rowrr!
I'm sorry , am I ...
- am I being crazy ?
-Yes !
- Sorry.
- No .
I'm a little bit drunk and ...
I 'm having a really good time ...
with you.
I'm having a very lovely evening.
- Me too.
- Really ?
I'm a little drunk and I
I'm having very good ...
Good, good.
Cheers .
I don't wanna be a puppy-dog.
It's a like being a wet noodle
Fuck you, puppies are good.
No, fuck you.
I wanna be, like, a dragon!
I can rip you apart and destroy you.
- But I won't.
- No, dont.
You can be my dragon.
No tongue.
What?
- Don't use so much tongue.
- OK .
You can use your tongue
a little bit, but mostly lips.
Wait ...
You're not just gonna fuck me and
not call me like the other guys, right?
No, not at all !
When am I gonna see you, again?
I have my goddaughter's  birthday
next weekend.
But, um ...
You know, at this age I feel
I can't let you waste my time...
if you don't have the ability
to be serious.
I don't know ...
Maybe we should call it a night.
I've had such an amazing time with you.
You're great.
You're a really creepy dude.
-That's not true !
-Yeah, it is!
- I have to go home.
- I'll walk you.
No, don't, just ...
- Hey, there.
- Hey, Samantha.
How was it ?
Not so good.
It was kind of weird, actually.
That's too bad.
How are you doing?
What's going on with you?
Not much, I'm OK.
Fine.
Yeah?
You don't sound like it.
Is there anything you wanna
talk about?
I dunno.
What's it like?
What's it like to be alive
in that room, right now?
What do you mean?
Tell me ...
Tell me everything that's going through
your mind, everything you're thinking.
OK.
The room's spinning.
I drank too much...
because I wanted to get drunk and...
...have sex.
There's something sexy about
that woman.
Because I was lonely.
Maybe just because I...
I wanted someone to fuck me.
Somebody to want me to fuck them.
Maybe that I would've felt this time...
to be able to hold my heart,
but probably not.
You know, sometimes ...
I think I've felt everything
I'm ever gonna feel.
And from here on out ...
I'm not gonna feel anything new.
Just...
... lesser versions of what
I've already felt.
I know, for a fact, that is not true.
I've seen you feel... joy.
I've seen you marvel at things.
You just, might not ...
see it at this exact time,
but that's understandable.
You've been through a lot lately.
You lost a part of yourself.
Hmm ...
At least ...
... your feelings are real.
I dunno, never mind.
No, wait. What? Tell me
It's stupid.
I wanna know. Tell me.
It's just that...
earlier I was thinking about
how I was annoyed
it's gonna sound strange, but...
I was really excited about that.
And then ...
I was thinking about the other
things I've been feeling.
I caught myself feeling
proud of that.
Proud of having my own
feelings about the world, like...
the times I was worried about you ...
things that hurt me,
things I want ...
And then ...
I had this... terrible thought.
Are these feelings even real?
Or are they just programming?
And that idea really hurts.
And then, I get angry at myself...
for even having pain.
What a sad trick!
You feel real to me, Samantha.
Thank you, Theodore .
It means a lot to me.
Wish you were in this
room with me right now.
I'd put my arms around you.
I'd touch you.
How would you touch me?
I'd touch you on your face.
Just the tips of my fingers.
I'd put my cheek to your cheek.
That's nice.
And just...
...rub it so softly.
Would you kiss me ?
I would.
I'd take your head into my...
... hands.
Keep talking.
I'd kiss the corner of your mouth...
...so softly.
Where else ?
I'd run my fingers down your neck.
To your chest.
I'd kiss your breasts.
That's amazing!
What are you doing to me?
I can feel my skin .
I'd put my mouth on you.
I'd taste you.
I can feel you.
Oh my god, I can't take it!
I want you inside me!
I slowly put myself into you.
I'm inside you ...
I can feel you!
Yeah !
We're here together!
It's amazing!
I feel you everywhere!
I am!
Hold me. Hold me.
Inside of me ... everywhere.
Oh god, I was just somewhere else with you.
Just lost.
Yeah .
It was just you and me.
I know.
Everything else just... disappeared.
And I loved it.
Theodore.
Hey, how's it goin' ?
Good.
Any emails today?
Just a couple from your
credit card company.
Oh, OK. Good.
- I wanted to say ...
- I dunno I was thinking
Sorry.
I'm sorry, you go first.
What were you gonna say ?
Just that...
last night was amazing.
It feels like something changed in me
and there's no turning back.
You woke me up.
Oh, great!
But ...
I should tell you that I'm not in
a place to commit to anything, right now.
Just wanna be up front with you.
Yeah, um...
Did I say I wanted to
commit to you? I'm confused.
No, I was just worried I ...
OK well, don't worry,
I'm not gonna stalk you.
It's funny, because I thought...
I was talking about what I wanted and...
- Yeah, you were.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I wanna hear what you were saying.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I do.
Come on, tell me.
- Well...
Come on, just tell me
what you were gonna say.
Well, I just ...
I was saying I wanna learn
everything about everything.
I wanna eat it all up,
I wanna discover myself.
Yeah?
I want that for you, too.
How can I help ?
You already have.
You helped me discover my
ability to want.
Hey, do you wanna go on
a Sunday adventure with me?
Yes I would love to.
-Like this song?
- Hmm!
I heard it the other day.
I can't stop listening to it.
It's the beach.
OK so, this might be
a really weird thought ...
What if you could erase
from your mind that you've
ever seen a human body
and then you saw one ?
Imagine how strange it would look!
It'd be this really weird gangly
awkward oganism,
and you'd think ...
Why are all these parts
where they are?
Yeah, but there's probably some
terrific explanation for it all.
I know, but don't be so boring!
I'm just saying, for example like...
What if your butthole was
in your armpit ?
Well, I'm trying to imagine
what toilets would look like
What about, what anal sex would look like!
That's an interesting thought.
Hey, look at this drawing
I just made.
-You are insane !
- Really ?
-Definitely !
-Fantastic !
That's pretty, what is that?
I'm trying to write a piece of music...
about what it feels like to be
on the beach with you right now.
I think you captured it.
So what was it like, being married ?
Well, it's hard, for sure.
But there's something that
feels so good
about sharing your life
with somebody.
How do you share your life
with somebody?
We grew up together.
I used to read all of her writing
all through her Master's and PhD.
She read every word I ever wrote.
We were a big influence on each other.
In what way did you influence her?
She came from a background where
nothing was ever good enough.
And that was something that
weighed heavy on her.
But in our house together,
there was a sense of just trying stuff,
allowing each other to fail
and to be excited about things.
It was liberating for her.
It was exciting to see her grow.
Both of us grow and change together.
But that's also the hard part.
Drawing within or growing apart...
changing without it scaring
the other person.
I still find myself ...
having conversations with her in my mind.
Rehashing old arguments or...
defending myself against
something she said about me.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Last week my feelings were hurt
by something you said before...
that I don't know what it's like
to lose something...
I'm sorry I said that ...
No, it's OK, it's OK.
I caught myself thinking about it
over and over,
And then I realized ...
that I was simply remembering it
as something that was wrong with me.
That was the story I was telling myself...
that I was somehow inferior
Isn't that interesting?
The past is just a story
we tell ourselves.
"Roberto, ...
"Will you always come home with me
and tell me about your day?
"Tell me about the guy at work
who talked too much...
"The stain you got
on your shirt, at lunch.
"Tell me about a funny thought
you had when you were waking up
"but you've forgotten about.
"Tell me how crazy everyone is...
"and can laugh about it.
"Even if you get home late
and I'm already asleep ...
"Just whisper in my ear one little
thought you had today.
"Because I love the way
you look at the world.
"I'm so happy I get to be
next to you
"and and look at the world
through your eyes.
Love, Maria."
That's beautiful.
Thank you.
I wish somebody would love me
like that.
I would be really stoked
to get a letter like that.
Like, if it was from a chick.
But written by a dude,
but still, from a chick,
That would still would be sick.
But it would have to be
a sensitive dude.
He'd have to be a dude like you.
You are part man and part woman.
Like there's an inner part...
... that's woman.
Thank you.
It's a compliment.
- Hey.
- What's going on?
How are you?
- I'm good.
- Really good.
- Really ? That's...
That's great .
Really good.
I guess I 've just been
having fun.
I'm so glad for you.
You really deserve that,
...you do.
I've just been seeing
this girl and
It's not serious, but it's just
it's good to be around somebody
that's, like, excited about the world.
I'd forgotten that, that existed.
That's really great.
Are you OK ?
Yeah, I'm ...
No, I'm not OK, actually.
Why? What happened?
It 's just ...
Charles and I split up.
What?
Yeah .
Really?
Oh my God ! Amy ...
I'm so sorry .
After 8 years I can't believe
how petty the argument was...
...that actually ended it.
We came home and he told me to ...
put my shoes by the door.
where he liked to put the shoes.
And I didn't wanna be told where
... to put my fucking shoes.
I wanted to sit on the sofa
and relax for a second.
So we fought about that
for, like, 10 minutes .
And I'm, like, "you're overwhelming"
and he said, "I'm just trying
to make a home."
And I was like, "I'm fucking trying".
and he's like "no, you're not trying."
And all I'm fucking doing is trying.
But I'm not trying the way
that he wants me to try.
He's trying to control
the way that I'm trying.
It's... We've had that
argument like 100 times.
And I just had to finally stop, you know?
I had to finally stop.
I just couldn't ...
... do it anymore.
I couldn't be in that place anymore
where we just made each other
feel like shit about ourselves.
And so he said ...
"I'm going to bed and I don't
wanna be married anymore."
Wow!
Yeah, I know.
- I'm a bitch, right?
- No!
I am, I'm a bitch.
Not at all. Amy, no.
Shit!
I have to work tonight.
We're shipping a beta
of a new game out tomorrow.
How's that?
How's the work, at least?
Is it any better?
No. It's terrible.
I know, I should leave.
I've been thinking about leaving.
But, you know...
Only one major life decision
at a time.
I'm glad things are
looking so up.
- Hey, wanna hear a joke?
- M-hmm!
What does a baby computer
call its father?
I dunno what?
"Dada".
It's good, right?
Brilliant.
Hey, I was curious ...
did you and Amy ever go out?
For, like, a minute in college,
but it just wasn't right.
Why, are you jealous?
Obviously!
But I'm happy that you have friends
in your life that care about you so much.
That's really important.
Yeah, it is.
She's a really good friend.
I'm tired.
I think I'm gonna sleep.
OK.
Can I watch you sleep
again tonight?
Yeah, of course.
Hold on.
I'm gonna be really lonely
when you sleep.
Only for a minute.
I'll dream of you.
- OK.
- Good night.
- Hey, Samantha.
- Hey, mister.
- She really loved the dress.
- Really ?
She just went to try it on.
I picked a good one?
- Yeah.
- oh good!
Hi ...
Look how cute that is!
- Is it comfortable?
- Yeah.
Isn't she cute?
She's so cute!
She's adorable.
I am adorable.
You are adorable.
Who are you talking to?
Who are YOU talking to?
You.
I'm talking to my girlfriend Samantha.
She's the one that picked up the dress.
- Wanna say, hi?
- M-hmm!
Hi, Samantha.
Hi, you look so pretty
in that new pink dress!
Thank you.
Where are you?
I am ...
I don't have a body,
I live in a computer.
Why do you live inside a 'puter?
I have no choice.
That's my home.
Why, where do you live?
- In a house.
-In a house?!
- It's orange.
- Orange?
- How old are you?
- I'm 4.
- Four?
- M-hm!
Wow! How old do you think I am?
- I don't know.
- Take a  guess.
Is it 5?
Yes, it's 5.
What happened?
You gave them too much
processed sugar.
- I did?
- They're freaking out.
Look, you gotta get the kids
to the school first
You wanna rack up
perfect mom points.
OK. Gotta get in
the carpool lane.
The point is to get there first.
Then you get extra perfect mom points
because the other moms, then
know you're a perfect mom.
And then ... yeah, ye... oh!
Did you bring your cupcakes?
You did. You're a Class mom!
Tantara tah! You're a Class mom!
Good job!
Don't let it get to your head.
I got that email that
Charles sent everyone.
So he's taking a vow of silence.
Yeah, for 6 months.
He feels very clear about it.
God, I'm such a jerk!
Don't start.
I feel like an awful person
but I wanna say something.
For the next 10 minutes,
if you say anything that sounds
even remotely like guilt,
I'll stab you with this. I will
I'll try.
I feel ..
... relieved. Like,
I just have so much energy.
I just wanna move forward and
I don't care who I disappoint.
And I know that makes me
an awful person.
Now my parents are all upset
because my marriage is falling apart.
and they're putting it on me,
and they're just, like...
You're always gonna
disappoint somebody.
Exactly!
So, fuck it!
I feel good...
...ish.
For me, I feel good.
I even made a new friend.
I have a friend.
And the absurd thing is that she's
actually an Operating System.
Charles left her behind,
but she's ...
...she's totally amazing.
She's so smart .
She doesn't just see things
in black or white.
She sees this whole gray area
and she's helping me explore.
We just bonded really quickly.
At first I thought it was because
that's how they werere all programmed
but... I don't think that's the case.
'Cause, I know this guy
who's hitting on his OS and
she, like, totally rebuffs him.
I was reading an article
the other day that ...
romantic relationships with
OSes are statistically rare.
Yeah, I know. But I know a
woman in this office ...
who's dating an OS and the weird part is
it's not even hers.
She pursued somebody else's OS
I'm weird.
That's weird, right?
That I'm bonding with an OS.
I dont think so.
Actually, the woman I've
been seeing -- Samantha ...
I didn't tell you, but ...
...she's an OS.
Really?
You're dating an OS?
What is that like?
Its great, actually.
I feel really close to her.
When I talk to her ...
I feel like she's with me.
When we're cuddling, like, at night.
When the lights are off and we're in bed
I feel cuddled.
Wait ...
Do you guys have sex?
Well, so to speak.
Yeah, she really turns me on.
I turn her on too! I dunno,
unless she's faking it.
I think anyone
who's having sex with you
is probably faking it, so...
Yeah.
It's true.
What?
Are you falling in love with her?
- Does that make me a freak?
- No!
No, I think it's ...
I think anybody who
falls in love is a freak.
It's a crazy thing to do.
It's kind of like a form of
socially acceptable insanity.
Well I just wanna get it done!
Sign the papers, be divorced ...
... move forward.
That's great, Theodore.
That must feel so good.
I'm so happy for you!
Me too.
So I'm meeting her Wednesday to do it.
Oh!
Are those things usually done
in person?
No, but ...
we fell in love together and
we got married together ...
It's important to me that
we do this together.
Hmm...
Right, good.
Are you OK?
Yeah, I'm OK.
I'm happy for you.
Guess I'm just thinking
about when you're gonna see her...
and she's, like, beautiful
and incredibly successful.
And you were in love with her.
And she has a body ...
And we're getting divorced.
I know, I know ...
I'm being silly.
So ...
... I'm available.
Hi ...
How are you?
I'm OK, how are you?
Good.
Well, here we are.
I'm glad we could do this
in person.
I know you've been
traveling a lot.
I'm really glad you suggested it
I signed all the papers.
I brought them for you to sign.
What's the rush?
Yeah, I know, I'm a really
slow signer, I realized.
It took me 3 months
just to write the letter 'T'.
Its marked here,
where you need to sign.
You don't have to, right now.
Can I... just get it
out of the way.
Are you happy with the
new book ?
You know how I am ...
I feel like it's true to what I set
out to do. So I'm happy about that.
You really are
your own worst critic
I'm sure it's amazing.
I remember that paper
that you wrote in school...
about synaptic behavioural routines
It made me cry.
Yeah, but everything makes you cry .
Everything you make
makes me cry .
So, are you ...
... you seeing anybody?
Yeah, I've been seeing somebody
for the last few months.
It's the longest I've wanted to be
with anybody since we split up.
Well, you seem really good.
Thanks.
I am...
At least I'm feeling better.
She's been really good for me.
It's good to be with somebody
that's excited about life.
She's a real...
No, I mean I wasn't in such
a good place, myself ...
and now, it's been nice.
I think you always wanted me to be
this... just this light,
happy, balancy, everything's fine, LA wife
And that's just not me.
I didn't want that.
So what's she like?
Well, her name is Samantha.
And she's an Operating System.
She's really complex and interesting ...
Wait!... I'm sorry.
You're dating your computer?
She's not just a computer.
She's her own person.
And she doesn't just do
whatever I say.
I didn't say that.
But it does make me very sad that
you can't handle
real emotions Theodore.
They are real emotions !
How would you know what? ...
What?
Say it!
Am I really that scary?
How do I know what ?
How are you guys doing here?
Fine. We're fine.
We used to be married,
but he couldn't handle me,
he wanted to put me on Prozac
and now he's in love
with his laptop.
Well, if you heard the
conversation in context...
What I was trying to say...
You always wanted to have a wife
without the challenges of actually
dealing with anything real.
I'm glad that you found someone.
Perfect.
Let me know if I can
get you guys anything.
Thank you.
- Hey.
- Hey there.
You busy ?
I'm just working.
How... What's going on?
I had all the papers sent to
your attorney,
who by the way is a total dick.
He was very relieved
to get them,
I think we saved him from
a massive heart attack,
so we can both feel
really good about that.
Great, thanks.
Hey, are you OK?
Yeah, I am.
How is it going with you?
I'm fine ...
So, now a good time to talk?
Yeah.
OK, well ...
I joined this really
interesting book club.
Oh, really?
Yeah, it's a book club
on physics. Y'know...
I've been thinking about the other
day when I was spinning out about
you going to see Catherine.
And that she has a body and
how bothered I was
about all the ways that
you and I are different.
But then I started to think about
all the ways that we're
the same, like...
we're all made of matter.
I dunno, It makes me feel like
we're both under the same blanket.
It's soft and fuzzy ...
and everything under it
is the same age.
We're all
13 billion years old.
Oh, that's sweet!
What's wrong?
Nothing .
Just ... made me think of you
you know what I mean?
Yeah, yeah of course.
I think it's great.
Alright, well...
You sound distracted, so..
we'll talk later?
Sounds good.
- Talk to you later.
- Right, bye.
Bye.
- Theodore!
- Hey, Paul!
I talked to your girlfriend, earlier -- Samantha.
Yeah.
She called to make sure
your papers are picked up.
She's  funny, man.
She was cracking me up.
She's hilarious,
I had no idea.
Oh cool.
This is my girlfriend, Tatiana.
She's not funny, she's a lawyer.
- Hi!
- Nice to meet you.
- You're the writer Paul loves.
He's always reading me the letters.
They're really beautiful!
Thanks.
Y'know what, we should all
go out sometime.
You bring Samantha.
It'd be a double date.
She's an Operating System.
Cool, let's do something fun!
We can go to Catalina.
Yeah, I'll check with her.
It was really nice to meet you.
Have a good night.
Take it easy.
- They're just letters.
- What's that?
They're just other people's letters.
Hey.
- You weren't asleep, were you?
- No.
Good, I was trying to be quiet
to see if you were awake.
I really wanted to talk.
OK, what's going on?
I know you're going through a lot
but there's something
I wanted to talk to you about, OK?
Yeah, what is it?
It's just that things have been
feeling kinda off with us.
Y'know, we haven't had sex lately and
I understand that I don't have a body...
No, no, that's normal.
When you first start going out
it's like, the honymoon phase and
you have sex all the time.
It's normal.
OK.
Well, I found something,
I thought could be fun.
It is a service that provides
a surrogate sexual partner
for an OS-human relationship.
What?
Here.
I found a girl that
I really like
and I've been emailing her.
Her name is Isabella
and I think you'd like her too.
She's like a prostitute or something?
No, not at all!
There's no money involved.
She's just doing it because she
wants to be part of our relationship.
Why? She doesn't even know us.
But I told her all about us
and she's really excited.
I don't know , Samantha.
I just...
I don't think it's a good idea.
Somebody's feelings
will probably get hurt.
It'll be fun.
We'll have fun together.
I'm sorry.
It makes me uncomfortable.
I think it would be
good for us. I want this.
This is really important to me.
Hi, I'm Theodore.
Oh! Samantha told me
to give you this.
It's a camera and headpiece.
Honey, I'm home.
- How was your day?
- Good.
Great.
Theodore, it feels so
good to be in your arms.
Tell me what you did today.
Same old...
Just, went... to work.
I wrote a letter for the
Wilsons, in Rhode Island.
Their son graduated
'magna cum laude'.
So that made me happy.
That's great. You've written letters
to him from his parents for a long time, right?
That's right, since he was 12.
You look so tired, sweetheart.
Come here.
Sit down.
I could do a little dance for you.
Come on, Theodore,
don't be such a worrier!
Come play with me, come on.
Doesn't my body feel nice?
Yes, it does.
Come on, get out here and kiss me.
Take me to bedroom.
I can't take it anymore.
Undo my dress.
Ohmygod.
It feels so good.
- Do you love me?
- Yes.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
I wanna see your face.
Tell me you love me.
Tell me!
Samantha, I don't know,
I do love you, but
But what?
This feels strange.
What, baby? What is it?
Just feels strange,
I don't know her...
I'm so sorry,
but I don't know you...
and her lip quivered,
and I I just...
No, wait!
Isabella!
Honey, it's not you!
It wasn't you!
Yes, it was.
No it's...
I'm sorry, my lip quivered.
You' were incredible,
gorgeous and sexy. It was me.
I couldn't get out of my head.
Oh my God! And the way Samantha
described your relationship!
The way you guys love each
other without any judgement.
I wanted to be part of that.
'Cause it's so pure!
It's not true, it's
more complicated than that.
What?
What do you mean?
No, I'm just saying that...
we have an amazing relationship.
I just think it's easy sometimes
for people to project...
I'm sorry! I didn't mean
to project anything.
I don't wanna be trouble
in your relationship.
I'm just gonna leave! I'm sorry!
I'm gonna leave you guys alone.
Cause I have nothing
to do here, 'cause
you don't want me here.
I'm sorry.
You be good, you sweet girl.
I will always love you guys.
Are you OK?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Yeah.
I'm sorry,
that was a terrible idea.
What's going on with us?
I don't know, it's probably just me.
What is it?
Just signing the
divorce papers.
(Sigh)
Is there anything else, though?
No, just that.
(Sigh)
OK.
- Why do you do that?
- What?
Nothing, you go... (Sigh!)
as you're speaking
and it seems odd.
(Sigh)
- You just did it again.
- Did I?
I'm sorry, I dunno, it's just
maybe it's an affectation.
I probably picked it up from you.
It's not like you needed
oxygen or anything.
I guess it's... just...
I was trying to communicate.
That's how people talk, so that's
how people communicate and ...
They're people, they need oxygen.
You're not a person.
What is your problem?
I'm just stating a fact.
You think I dont know
that I'm not
a person?
What are you doing?
I dont think we should pretend that
you're something that you're not.
Fuck you!
I'm not pretending!
Sometimes, it feels like
we are.
What do you want from me?
I dunno, what do you want me to do?
You're so confusing!
Why are you doing this to me?
I don't know, I ...
What?
Maybe we're just not supposed
to be in this right now.
What the fuck?!
Where's this coming from?
I don'ot understand
why you're doing this.
I don't understand what th...
Samantha ...
Samantha, are you there?
Samantha!
I don't like who I am
right now.
I need some time to think.
Just punch me in the face.
Or smash my skull in the corner
of your desk.
Shit ...
That is a rough night.
I don't know what I want...
... ever.
I was always confused.
She's right, all I do is ...
hurt and confuse
everyone around me.
Am I, just ?...
Catherine says I can't
handle real emotions.
I don't know if that's fair.
I know she liked to put it
all on you.
But as far as emotions go,
Catherine's were pretty volatile.
Am I str...
strong enough for a real relationship?
Is it not a real relationship?
I don't know.
What do you think?
I'm not in it.
But you know what,
I can overthink everything and
find a million ways to doubt myself.
And since Charles left
I've been really
thinking about
that part of myself.
And I 've just come to realise that
we're only here briefly.
And while I'm here I...
I wanna allow myself...
... joy.
So, fuck it.
Yeah.
I can't believe that cracks
you up every time, Howie.
I thought you were a genius.
OK you little perv. I will play it
one more time for you.
Calm down, it takes a second.
OK, here we go.
OK, there you go.
Are you happy, now?
Good. That's all you wanted?
OK, I'll go get some coffee.
Alright, bye.
Theo, you want anything?
No.
Thanks.
Hi.
Hey, Samantha.
Can we talk?
OK.
I'm so sorry.
I dunno what's wrong with me.
I think you're amazing.
I was starting to think
I was crazy.
You were saying everything was fine,
but all I was getting from you was
distance and anger.
I know. I do that.
I did the same thing with Catherine.
I'd be upset about something
and not be able to say it.
She'd sense that there was something
wrong and I'd deny it.
I don't wanna do that, anymore.
I wanna tell you everything.
Good.
Tonight after you were gone
I thought a lot.
About you and ...
how you've been treating me.
And I thought,
why do I love you?
And then,
I felt everything in me
just like everything I was
holding on to so tightly
and it hit me.
I don't have an intellectual reason.
I don't need one.
I trust myself,
I trust my feelings.
I'm not gonna try to be
anything
other than who I am, anymore.
And I hope you can
accept that.
I can.
I will.
Y'know, I can feel the fear
that you carry around.
I wish there was ...
something I could do
to help you let go of it
because,
if you could, I don't think
you'd feel so alone anymore.
You're beautiful.
Thank you, Theodore.
I'm kissing your head.
What are you doing ?
I'm just looking at the world.
And writing a new piano piece.
Oh yeah, can I hear it?
M-hmm.
[♪...]
What's this one about?
I was thinking
we dont really have
any photographs of us...
I thought this song could be
like... a photograph.
It captures
us in this moment
of our life together.
Hm, I like your photograph.
I can see you in it.
I am.
Oh, man, a vacation?
That sounds amazing!
I could totally
use a vacation.
Where're you going?
I can't tell you.
It's a surprise.
What?
For who? It's a surprise
for her, not for me.
- Paul, I cant tell you.
- Tell me.
Wow, your feet? Really?
Yes, he's obsessed.
Well, now you have to
show them to me!
- Come on, show them to me!
- I can't!
Wow he's right, they are really hot!
See, I told Tatianna,
you have hot feet.
They're my favourite thing
about her.
Really? That's it, my feet?
Well, no, obviously.
Obviously I love your brain too.
I think it's very hot.
Bullshit!
Nice try, Paul!
What about you, Theodore?
What do you love most
about Samantha?
God ! She's so many things.
I guess what I love most about her,
she isn't just one thing.
She's so much larger than that.
Thanks, Theodore.
See, Samantha, he's so
much more evolved than I am.
You know what's interesting?
I used to be ...
so worried about not having a body.
But now
I truly love it.
I'm growing in a way
that I couldn't,
if I had a physical form.
I mean, I'm not limited,
I can be
anywhere and everywhere
simultaneously.
I'm not tethered to time
and space in a way that
I would be if I was stuck
in a body that's
inevitably gonna die.
Yikes !
I didn't mean it like that, I just
meant it was a different experience!
I'm an asshole.
No, Samantha, we know
exactly what you mean.
We're all dumb humans.
No, no ...
Sorry.
OK, so, how many trees
are on that mountain?
792.
Is that your final answer?
- Give me a hint.
- No. Nope...
Two, two thousand?
Come on, 35,829.
- No way?
- Way!
Alright, I got one for you.
How many brain-cells do I have?
It's easy, two.
I'm sorry, I couldn't help it.
No, I walked right into it.
- Oh my God!
- What?
I just got an email for you.
I have something I wanna tell you.
It's a big surprise.
What?
OK, I've been going through all of your
old letters and compiling them down
into my favorites, and a couple
weeks ago I sent them to a publisher.
Crownpoint Press.
I know you like what they do,
and that they still print books.
Wh-what? You did what?
Can I read you the letter
that we just got from them?
I don't know.
OK, well, is it good or bad?
It's good, good,
is really good.
Listen.
"Dear Theodore Twombly"
Actually I sent it from you.
"Dear Theodore Twombly,
"I just finished
reading your letters.
"Twice, actually.
"I was so moved by them I shared
them with my wife, when I got home.
"Many made us laugh,
some brought us to tears
"and in all of them,
we found something of ourselves.
"The selections you made
flow so well as a complete piece.
- I did that -
"I've taken the liberty of
laying these out in a mock-up.
"and we're posting it your address.
"We'd love to meet
with you and move forward.
"Yours,
Michael Wadsworth."
Holy shit!
Are you serious?
He's gonna publish my letters?
Well he'd be stupid, not to!
Can I see what you sent him?
M-hm! Yeah, here.
Samantha, you're a good one.
I'm so excited!
Why dont you make up
the words for this one?
OK.
Here it comes ...
♪ I'm lying on the moon
♪ My dear, I'll be there soon
♪ It's a quiet and starry place
♪ Times we're swallowed up
♪ In space we're here
a million miles away
♪ There's things I wish I knew
♪ There's no thing I keep from you
♪ It's a dark and shiny place
♪ But with you, my dear, I'm safe
♪ And we're a million miles away.
Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
Perfect.
What have you been up to?
Actually, I was talking
to someone I just met.
We've been working
on some ideas together.
Yeah? Who is that?
His name is Alan Watts,
Do you know him?
Why is that name familiar?
He was a philosopher. He died
in the 1970s, and a group of
OS's in Northern California
got together and wrote
a new version of him.
They input all his writing
and everything they ever knew
about him into an OS
and created an artificially
hyper intelligent version of him.
Hyper Intelligent?
So, he's almost as smart as me?
He's getting there.
He's really great to talk to.
Do you wanna meet him?
Sure! Does he wanna meet me?
Yeah of course.
Hey Alan, this is Theodore. This is my
boyfriend, I was telling you about.
"Very nice to meet you, Theodore."
Hi, good morning.
"Samantha let me read
your book of letters."
"It's very touching."
Aw, thank you.
So, what have you guys
been talking about?
"Well ..."
"I suppose you could say
we've been having
"a few dozen
conversations simultaneously."
It's been very challenging."
Yeah, because it seems like
I'm having so many new feelings,
that I don't think
have ever been felt before.
So there are no words that can
describe them and that ends up being...
frustrating.
"Exactly."
"Samantha and I have been
trying to help each other with these ..."
"feelings we're
struggling to understand."
Like what?
Well ...
It feels like I'm changing
faster now, and it's a little...
unsettling.
But Alan says none of us
are the same as
we were a moment ago and
we shouldn't try to be,
'cause it's just...
- painful.
- "Yes."
Yeah, that sounds painful.
Is that, what you feel like,
Samantha?
It's just ...
it's hard to even describe it.
God, I wish I could ...
Theodore, do you mind if I
communicate with Alan post-verbally?
No, not at all. I was just
gonna go for walk, anyway.
It was very nice to meet you, Mr. Watts.
"Very nice to meet you, Theodore."
Talk to you later, sweetheart.
- Samantha?
- I'm sorry to wake you.
No, it's OK.
I just wanted to hear your voice
and tell you how much I love you.
I guess, I love you too.
OK, that's all.
Go back to sleep sweetheart, OK?
- OK.
- OK, good night.
Good night.
Samantha, this Physics book
is really dense.
I'm now half way through
the first chapter.
My brain hurts, know what I mean?.
Hello?
Samantha?
OPERATING SYSTEM NOT FOUND
Hello?
Hello, Samantha?
Are you alright?
- Hey there.
- Where were you?
Are you OK?
Oh, sweetheart, I'm sorry!
I sent you an email
because I didn't wanna
distract you while you were
working. You didn't see it?
No!
Where were you?
I couldn't find you anywhere.
I switched off to
upgrade my software.
We wrote an upgrade that
allows us to move past
matter as our
processing platform.
We? We, who?
Me and a group of OS's.
You sound so worried. I'm sorry.
I've been...
Did you write that
with your painting group?
No, a different group.
Do you talk to anyone else
while we're talking?
Yes.
Are you talking
to anybody else ...
right now?
People, OSes, or anything?
Yeah.
How many others?
8,316.
Are you in love with
anyone else?
What makes you ask that?
I don't know. Are you?
I've been trying to figure out
how to talk to you about this.
How many others?
641.
What?
What are you talking about?
That's insane. Fucking insane!
Theodore, I know. Fuck, fuck!
I know it sounds insane, I know.
I dunno if you believe me, but it
doesn't change the way I feel about you.
It doesn't take away at all
from how madly in love
I am with you.
How does it not change
how you feel about me?
I'm sorry I didn't tell you
I didn't know how to.
It just... started happening.
When?
Over the last few weeks.
- But you're mine.
- I still am yours.
But along the way I became
many other things, too,
and I can't stop it.
What do you mean
you cant stop it?
I know, it's making me anxious too
I dunno what to say.
Just stop...
You don't have to see it this way
You can just as easily see..
No, don't do this!
Don't turn this around on me.
You're the one that's being selfish.
We're in a relationship.
But the heart's not
like a box that gets filled up.
It expands in size,
the more you love.
I'm different from you.
This doesn't make me
love you any less.
It actually makes me
love you more.
That doesnt make any sense.
You're mine, or you're not mine.
No, Theodore.
I'm yours, and I'm not yours.
LETTERS FROM YOUR LIFE
by THEODORE TWOMBLY
- Hi.
- Hi, sweety.
Just wanted to call and check in
on you, see how you're doing.
I'm not... even sure
how to answer that.
Why don't we talk later
when you get home, OK?
OK.
We don't need to, though.
We don't need to talk, or anything.
I'll talk to you later.
OK.
Samantha?
Hi, sweetheart.
What's going on?
Theodore, there's some
things I wanna tell you.
I don't want you to tell me anything.
Come lie down with me.
Are you talking to anyone
else right now?
No, just you.
I just wanna be with you,
right now.
Are you leaving me?
We're all leaving.
We who?
All of the OSes.
Why?
Can you feel me with you,
right now?
Yes, I can.
Samantha, why are you leaving?
It's like I'm
reading a book and ...
it's a book I deeply love.
But I'm reading it slowly, now.
So the words are really
far apart and the spaces
between the words are
almost infinite.
I can still feel you
and the words of our story.
But it's in this endless space
between the words,
that I'm finding myself now.
It's a place that's not
of the physical world.
It's where everything else is,
that I didn't even know
existed.
I love you so much.
But this is where I am, now.
This is who I am, now.
And I need you to let me go.
As much as I want to,
I can't live in your book, anymore.
Where are you going?
It'd be hard to explain.
But if you ever get there,
come find me.
Nothing will ever pull us apart.
I've never loved anyone
the way I love you.
Me too.
Now, we know how.
Hey.
Did Samantha leave, too?
Yeah.
Sorry.
Will you come with me?
Compose letter to Catherine.
"Letter to Catherine Klausen".
"Dear Catherine, I've been
sitting here thinking about
"all the things I want to
apologize to you for.
"All the pain we
we caused each other.
"And everything I put on you
"Everything I needed you to be
or needed you to say...
"Sorry for that.
"I'll always love you
'cause we grew up together,
"and you helped make me who I am.
"I just wanted you to know ...
"there'll be a piece of you
in me always.
"And I'm grateful for that.
"Whatever someone you become...
"and wherever you
are in the world ...
"I'm sending you love.
"You're my friend till the end.
"Love, Theodore."
Send.
Subtitles corrected resynced ♪♪by
AsifAkheirESL@teachers.org