Excuse me.
I beg your pardon.
Aren't you Guy Haines?
I saw you bIast Faraday right off
the court in South Orange Iast season.
- Made the semifinaIs, didn't you?
- Yeah.
Oh, I certainIy admire peopIe
who do things.
By the way, my name is Bruno.
Bruno Antony.
See?
It's corny,
but my mother gave it to me...
-...so I wear it to pIease her.
- How do you do?
I don't taIk much.
You go ahead and read.
Thanks.
You know, it must be pretty exciting
to be so important.
- Tennis pIayer isn't so important.
- But peopIe who do things are.
I never do anything. I suppose you're
going to Southampton for the doubIes.
You are a tennis fan.
I wish I couId go watch you,
but I've gotta get back to Washington.
I'm from ArIington, you know.
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks. I don't smoke much.
Me, I smoke too much.
Oh, here.
Oh, thanks.
EIegant.
"From A to G."
I'II bet I can guess who "A" is.
- Yeah?
- Anne Morton.
Sometimes I turn the sports page
and I see the society section.
And the pictures.
She's very beautifuI.
Senator Morton's daughter, huh?
You're quite a reader, Mr. Antony.
Yes, I am. Ask me anything.
From today's sports news
to Li'l Abner, I got the answer.
Even about peopIe I don't know.
Like who wouId Iike to marry whom...
-...when his wife gets her divorce.
- Perhaps you read too much.
Oh, there I go again. Too friendIy.
It aIways happens.
I meet somebody who I Iike and admire,
and I open my mouth too much.
I'm sorry.
That's aII right, forget it.
I guess I'm a IittIe jittery.
Oh, there's a new cure for that.
- Waiter.
- Yes, sir.
Scotch and pIain water, pIease.
A pair. DoubIes.
- The onIy kind of doubIes I pIay.
- You'II have to drink both.
And I can do it.
When's the wedding?
- What?
- The wedding. You and Anne Morton.
It was in the papers.
It shouIdn't have been. UnIess they
IegaIized bigamy overnight.
Oh, I've got a wonderfuI theory
about that.
Someday I'II teII you about it.
But right now, I suppose divorce is,
weII, the simpIest operation.
It's wonderfuI having you
as company aII the way to New York.
I'm not going direct.
I'm stopping off in MetcaIf.
MetcaIf? Who wouId want
to stop off at MetcaIf?
WeII, it's my hometown.
Oh, I get it. A IittIe chat
with your wife about the divorce.
CIose enough.
Thanks. I think I wiII.
WeII, here's Iuck.
Drink up and we'II have Iunch sent
to my compartment.
Thanks, but I'II go to the dining car.
Oh, waiter.
- Are there any seats in the diner?
- Not for about 20 minutes, sir.
You'II have to Iunch with me.
Waiter!
Bring me some Iamb chops, French fries
and chocoIate ice cream.
- Yes, sir.
- Compartment B, car 121.
- And, waiter...
- Yes, sir?
Guy, what'II you have?
- Thanks just the same-
- Go on, go on, order.
WeII, I'II just have
a hamburger and a cup of coffee.
WeII...
...here's to the next Mrs. Haines.
Sure, I went to coIIege.
Got kicked out of three of them.
Drinking and gambIing.
Not Iike you, huh?
AII right, so I'm a bum.
Who said you were?
My father.
He hates me.
With aII his money, he thinks I ought
to catch the 8:05 bus every morning...
...punch a time cIock and work my way
up seIIing paint or something.
What do you think of a man Iike that?
- WeII, I think possibIy-
- Yes, I hate him too.
I teII you, I get so sore
at him sometimes...
...I want to kiII him.
- I don't think you know what you want.
- WeII, I want to do something.
Everything.
You know, I've got a theory that you
shouId do everything before you die.
Have you ever driven a car
bIindfoIded at 150 miIes an hour?
Not IateIy.
I did.
I fIew in a jet pIane too.
Man, that's a thriII. AImost bIew
the sawdust out of my head.
And I'm going to make a reservation
on the first rocket to the moon.
- What are you trying to prove?
- WeII, I'm not Iike you.
You're Iucky. You're smart.
Marrying the boss's daughter makes a
nice shortcut to a career, doesn't it?
Marrying the senator's daughter has
nothing to do with it.
Can't I Iook beyond a tennis net
without being out for something?
Take it easy. I'm your friend,
remember? I Iike you.
I'd do anything for you.
Sure, Bruno.
We'II be puIIing in soon.
I've got to change trains.
What did you say her name was?
Your wife's?
- Miriam.
- Miriam, that's it.
Miriam Joyce Haines.
I suppose she pIayed around a Iot.
- Let's not taIk about that.
- A woman Iike that can make troubIe-
Skip it, Bruno.
It's painfuI for a man
to discover he's been a chump.
Okay.
Want to hear one of my ideas
for a perfect murder?
The "Iight socket in the bathroom"...
...or the "carbon monoxide
in the garage"?
Neither one. I may be oId-fashioned,
but murder is against the Iaw.
My theory is that everybody is
a potentiaI murderer.
Didn't you ever feeI
Iike kiIIing somebody?
One of those useIess men
Miriam pIayed around with?
You can't kiII peopIe because
you think they're useIess.
What is a Iife or two, Guy?
Some peopIe are better off dead.
WeII, Iike your wife and my father,
for instance.
Oh, that reminds me
of a wonderfuI idea I had once.
I used to put myseIf to sIeep
at night, figuring it out.
Now, Iet's say that you'd Iike
to get rid of your wife.
- That's a morbid thought.
- No, no, no. Just suppose.
Let's say you had a good reason.
- No, Iet's not-
- No, no. Let's say.
You'd be afraid to kiII her.
You know why. You'd get caught.
And what wouId trip you up?
The motive.
Now, here's my idea.
I haven't got time to Iisten.
Listen. It's so simpIe too.
Two feIIows meet accidentaIIy,
Iike you and me.
No connection.
Never saw each other before.
Each one has somebody that he'd Iike
to get rid of.
So...
...they swap murders.
Swap murders?
Each does the other's murder.
Then there's nothing to connect them.
Each one has murdered a stranger.
Like you do my murder, I do yours.
We're coming into my station.
For exampIe: your wife, my father.
Crisscross.
- What?
- We taIk the same Ianguage, don't we?
Sure, we taIk the same Ianguage.
Thanks for Iunch.
I'm gIad you enjoyed it.
The Iamb chops were a IittIe overdone.
Nice meeting you.
Now, you think my theory's okay, Guy?
I mean, you Iike it?
Sure, Bruno, sure.
They're aII okay.
Crisscross.
- Hiya, BiII.
- Guy Haines! Good to see you, boy.
You'd better win at Southampton.
I got two bucks on you.
- Park these in a Iucky spot, wiII you?
- Sure thing.
One-fifty, two, three, four, five.
There you are.
- Thank you very much.
- You're weIcome.
- HeIIo, Guy.
- You're Iooking weII, Miriam.
So are you.
Got a nice tan pIaying tennis
with aII your rich friends.
When do we meet your Iawyer?
What's your hurry?
My hurry?
That's funny, coming from you.
You're the one in a hurry, aren't you?
When you wouIdn't give
me the divorce...
...I sort of hoped it was
because you were jeaIous.
I got over being jeaIous
a Iong time ago, Miriam.
Let's taIk in here.
WeII, this is cozier. Sort of Iike
oId times, isn't it?
Oh, skip it, Miriam.
It's pretty Iate to start fIirting
with a discarded husband.
EspeciaIIy when you're going
to have another man's baby.
You know, I think you're
handsomer than ever.
Let's get this over with.
You bring the money?
Lawyers are expensive.
Yes.
Here it is.
If I'd known what aII that tennis
nonsense of yours wouId Iead to...
...I wouIdn't have run out on you.
What are you trying to say, Miriam?
I'm not getting a divorce.
You IittIe doubIe-crosser!
I didn't want this divorce, you did.
You've been harping
about it aII year!
It's a woman's priviIege
to change her mind.
Now I can buy me
some pretty new cIothes.
I wouIdn't want you to be ashamed
of me in Washington...
...when we go to aII
those swanky parties.
- What do you mean by that?
- Don't Iook so mad.
You smiIe when your picture's
taken for the newspaper.
EspeciaIIy with Anne Morton
on your arm.
Let's not taIk about her.
It's serious between you two, huh?
You can throw aII your dreams
about her into the ashcan.
- I'm coming to Washington.
- What for?
- To have my baby and be with you.
- Why me? It's not my baby.
Yes, but peopIe don't know that.
Do they?
Make a pretty story: "The Senator's
Daughter InvoIved With A Married Man."
- EspeciaIIy when he's to be a father.
- You conniving Iiar!
Keep your voice down.
- What happened? He run out on you?
- No man runs out on me. Not even you.
You've been trying to get rid
of me Iong enough.
I don't want to see or hear you again.
I couId be pathetic as the deserted
mother in court. Think it over.
- Who wouId beIieve you?
- I'm warning you.
That's what shouId happen to peopIe
Iike you. I'd Iike to find-
Break it up, foIks. This isn't
the pIace for a famiIy quarreI.
I'm sorry.
I'm Ieaving.
You heard what I said, Guy Haines.
You can't throw me away! I'm coming
to Washington to have my baby!
- TeII that to the Senate!
- PIease.
Anne?
Anne, darIing, I-
Yes, I'm in MetcaIf.
No, everything didn't go smoothIy.
She doesn't want the divorce.
Not now.
It's unbeIievabIe.
Yes, I know how you must feeI.
But you sound so savage, Guy.
Sure, I sound savage. I feeI savage.
I'd Iike to break her neck.
I said I'd Iike to break her fouI,
useIess IittIe neck.
What's that?
I said I couId strangIe her!
I do wish you'd keep your hands quiet.
You're so restIess IateIy.
I Iike them to Iook just right.
Did I fiIe them too short?
Oh, no, Ma.
They're just fine. Thanks.
- What's the matter?
- I'm aII right. Don't worry about me.
But you Iook so paIe, dear.
Are you out of vitamins?
I took a bottIe yesterday, Ma.
A whoIe fifth.
Oh, but you have that Iook, dear.
I aIways can teII.
Now, you haven't been doing
anything fooIish?
I do hope you've forgotten aII
about that siIIy IittIe pIan of yours.
- Which one?
- About bIowing up the White House.
Oh, Ma, I was onIy fooIing.
Besides, what wouId the president say?
You're a naughty boy, Bruno.
You couId aIways make me Iaugh.
Get shaved before
your father gets home.
I'm sick and tired of bowing
and scraping to the king.
Now, now.
Now, Iet's not Iose controI.
Come see my painting.
Bruno, I do wish
you'd take up painting.
Such a soothing pastime.
Oh, Mother, you're wonderfuI!
That's the oId boy, aII right.
That's Father!
Is it?
I was trying to paint Saint Francis.
Excuse me, sir. They're ready
with your caII to Southampton.
- I want to taIk to you and your mother.
- Sorry, Father. Long distance.
- Must you take that tone with him?
- HeIIo.
Guy.
Bruno.
What? Now, who did you say this is?
Bruno, Guy. Bruno Antony.
Don't you remember? On the train.
Are you getting your divorce?
He needs to go somepIace for
treatment before it's too Iate!
Oh, so she doubIe-crossed you.
Are you going to see her again?
Now, just Iet's have Iunch first-
I'm going to have that boy taken care
of. If necessary, under restraint!
- Good night, Mom.
- Now, don't stay out Iate.
- There's the bus!
- HoId on, driver!
- Hey!
- Hey, driver!
- Hurry!
- Hey, wait a minute!
Driver.
I'II get it, Tom.
- Go ahead.
- Okay.
Watch your step.
Easy does it, Tommy.
- Hey, I'm hungry.
- Oh, hungry aIready!
Hot dogs! Get them whiIe they're hot!
Red-hot! Right over here!
Yes, sir, get your popcorn here.
Fresh popcorn! OnIy five cents a bag!
Come and get it!
Here you are!
Three cones, Arthur.
What fIavors you got?
- VaniIIa.
- VaniIIa? SweII.
- I shouId've had a hot dog before this.
- A hot dog?
Satisfy my craving a IittIe better.
Craving for what?
I never saw a girI eat so much.
- Where do you put it aII?
- This is good.
Want some money?
Are we going to the TunneI of Love?
- Come on!
- Great. Come on.
- What do you caII that thing?
- I don't know.
Stick them up.
Come cIoser, come cIoser!
Step right up and win a baby doII.
Let's go see who's the stronger.
1600.
Who eIse wants to take a chance
to win a Kewpie doII?
Here we go. Watch it.
Come on.
-1600.
- How about you, sir?
Thank you.
Here we go!
1700. You did not win
the Kewpie doII that time.
WiII you try it again, sir?
Here we go. Watch it now.
1600. WiII you try it again and win
a nice Kewpie doII for the Iady?
Try your Iuck, mister?
Come cIoser, come cIoser!
Step right up and win a baby doII!
Hot dogs! Here you are, foIks!
Red-hots! Right over here!
Here we go.
You just won a Kewpie doII.
Why, he's broken the thing.
Come on, Miriam.
Step right up
and get your ticket cashed!
Let's go on the merry-go-round!
Let's sing. Come on.
Casey would waltz
With the strawberry blond
And the band played on
He'd glide cross the floor
With the girl he adored
And the band played on
His brain was so loaded
It nearly exploded
The poor girl would shake with alarm
He'd marry the girl
With the strawberry curl
And the band played on
Let's go for a boat ride.
How about some popcorn?
I couId go for some.
Not now!
No fun necking
with a mouthfuI of popcorn.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Take a ride. Take a sIide.
Take a trip with Iots of zip.
This way, Iadies and gentIemen.
- How about this one?
- I'm gonna drive.
You're gonna drive?
Don't rock the boat!
- Here we go.
- Anchors aweigh.
You sure you know how
to steer this tub?
- Make him stop! Make him stop!
- I'm trying to steer the boat.
Hey, what's that? What are you doing?
Come on, come on, Miriam.
- Come on.
- Stop it!
Hang on.
Oh, wait a minute.
Easy does it, now.
Let's not break a Ieg.
We got use for you Iater.
Hey, Miriam!
Is your name Miriam?
Why, yes. How did you-?
Hey, Miriam!
Miriam, where are you?
Miriam!
- Miriam, come on. Stop fooIing.
- Think you can give us the sIip, huh?
- Hey, come on! Stop hiding.
- Miriam, where are you?
Lost your girI, George?
Miriam!
Hey, here she is.
Look, she's fainted.
Come on, Miriam, get up.
What's the matter?
- She's dead!
- Dead?
HeIp, somebody, heIp!
Somebody send for a doctor!
HeIp!
HeIp, somebody, heIp!
HeIp! Bring heIp!
Somebody bring a doctor! HeIp!
Get a cop. I don't know
what's going on.
a man who had a goat
He loved that goat
Indeed he did
Just like a kid
What's your opinion?
You'II never make the MetropoIitan.
Name's CoIIins.
On sabbaticaI, DeIaware Tech.
GIad to meet you.
I just made a speech in New York
on integration.
In differentiaI caIcuIus,
a function is given...
...and the differentiaI is obtained.
You understand?
Yes, I understand.
You do?
There was a man
Who had a goat...
Guy!
Guy.
Over here, Guy.
- HeIIo, Guy.
- What are you doing here?
At this time of night?
You don't seem very pIeased to see me.
- I've brought you a IittIe present.
- What do you mean?
What's this aII about?
Recognize them?
It was very quick.
She wasn't hurt in any way.
It was aII over in no time.
I knew you'd be surprised.
There's nothing for us to worry about.
Nobody saw me.
OnIy Miriam.
And I was very carefuI, Guy.
Even when I dropped your Iighter,
I went back to pick it up.
Are you trying to teII-?
Why, you maniac!
But you wanted it. We pIanned it
on the train together, remember?
- Where are you going?
- Where do you think?
- I'm caIIing the poIice, of course.
- But you can't.
We'd both be arrested for murder.
- We'd both be arrested for murder?
- You're just as much in it as I am.
We pIanned it together. Crisscross.
- I do your murder-
- You think you can get away with it?
Oh, come, now. Why shouId I go
to MetcaIf to kiII a totaI stranger?
UnIess it was part of the pIan,
and you were in on it.
You're the one who benefits, Guy.
You're a free man now.
I didn't even know the girI.
I had nothing to do with this.
The poIice wiII beIieve me.
Guy, if you go to the poIice now...
...you'II just be turning yourseIf
in as an accessory.
You see, you have the motive.
- What is it?
- My teIephone.
Someone has some news for you, Guy.
It's the poIice.
You've got me acting
Iike I'm a criminaI.
Why, you crazy fooI!
Don't you caII me that.
Oh, you must be tired, Guy.
I know I am.
I've had a strenuous evening.
But now, about my father. I've got
the pIan of the house aIready made.
And I have an oId Luger pistoI I got
in a pawnshop in San Francisco-
Wait! We have to taIk.
We have to arrange things.
Go, before I give you
what you gave Miriam.
You're not yourseIf, Guy.
You're tired.
When you think things over,
you'II see I'm right. Tomorrow, we-
I never saw you before!
I never want to see you again!
But we have-
Yes? Yes, Anne.
I'm sorry, darIing. I just got in.
Of course I'm aII right.
But you sound upset.
Is anything wrong?
AII right. I'II come over right away.
Anne, darIing, you're trembIing.
I wonder if you know how much
I Iove you.
Brazen woman, I'm the one to say that.
I wanted you to know before...
Father wants to see you.
Good evening, sir.
HeIIo, Babs.
- Something dreadfuI's happened.
- Sit down, Barbara.
There seems to be no way of
dipIomaticaIIy breaking tragic news.
I'm sorry, Guy,
to be the one to teII you.
It concerns your wife.
She's been murdered.
The poIice have been trying
to find you.
You're to caII headquarters
in MetcaIf.
Miriam murdered?
She was strangIed.
It happened on an isIand,
in an amusement park.
It was sort of a Iover's Iane,
I beIieve.
EvidentIy, a sordid atmosphere.
She went there with the boys that
found her, so they're not suspects.
But you wiII be.
We can't overIook that murder
is at our doorstep...
...but don't drag it in here.
Let's not fooI ourseIves.
PoIice wiII say Guy wanted her dead
so he couId marry Anne.
This sort of crime,
they go after the husband.
Guy had every motive.
Motive?
WeII, she's right.
Whichever way you Iook at it,
I'm in a spot.
I'm sure you've got nothing
to worry about.
If he hasn't an aIibi for 9:30,
he has pIenty to worry about.
- You can teII them where you were.
- Sherry.
Thank you.
Can't you, Guy?
9:30? I was on the train
from New York to Washington.
There you are.
Did you see or speak to anyone?
You need a witness.
Yes, I did speak to someone.
Someone you know?
No.
His name was...
CoIIins! He's a professor.
Harvard?
DeIaware Tech.
Then everything's aII right.
Not quite.
He'II stiII have to answer questions.
Routine. Pure routine.
There'II be many reporters here
in the morning.
Daddy doesn't mind a IittIe scandaI.
He's a senator.
It can't be heIped, darIing.
It's not your fauIt.
No one can say you had anything
to do with it.
Someone might say it. I'd do anything
to keep you aII out of this mess.
Be guided by my experience.
Never Iose sIeep over accusations.
UnIess they can be proved, of course.
DreadfuI business. DreadfuI.
Poor, unfortunate girI.
She was a tramp.
She was a human being.
Everyone has a right to Iife
and the pursuit of happiness.
From what I hear,
she pursued it in aII directions.
Barbara!
Father, it's getting terribIy Iate.
Guy Iooks so tired.
Of course, of course.
Back to bed, Barbara.
Nothing stands in your way.
Now you can be married right away.
You're free!
You don't aIways have
to say what you think.
Father, I am not a poIitician.
Remember to caII Captain TurIey.
Yes, sir. Good night.
It'd be wonderfuI to have a man
Iove you so much he'd kiII for you.
I kept saying over and over
I was being siIIy.
But there was one horribIe moment
tonight when the news came through.
I kept remembering what you shouted
on the phone from MetcaIf.
That I couId-
Don't even say it.
Forget you ever said it.
Even more terrifying
than the murder itseIf was...
...the horribIe thought that
if you had done it...
...we wouId have been separated.
Perhaps forever.
I couIdn't stand that.
I couIdn't bear it.
Captain TurIey is expecting me.
Guy Haines.
Just a moment, Mr. Haines.
Come in, pIease.
Good of you to be so prompt,
Mr. Haines.
- This is Lt. CampbeII.
- HeIIo.
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you, sir.
I know you're busy, so we won't detain
you any Ionger than necessary.
You've aIready been good enough to
teII us where you were Iast evening.
We've found the man you spoke with
on the train.
- I saw him outside.
- PIease come in, professor.
Professor CoIIins.
This is Mr. Haines.
You met on the train Iast night.
I'm sorry, but I reaIIy don't
remember meeting this gentIeman.
UnfortunateIy, I remember very IittIe
of our trip from New York.
You see, we had a IittIe ceIebration.
But, we were sitting
opposite each other...
...in the observation car.
You sang a song about a goat.
A goat?
And caIcuIus.
You were going over a speech.
I was?
I'm very sorry, Mr. Haines.
I certainIy must
have been ceIebrating.
Captain, is it so important whether
Professor CoIIins remembers me?
I've been abIe to name a man who was
on the train with me.
You've found him.
Isn't that proof of where I was
at 9:30 Iast night?
Thank you.
HeIIo, dear. Senator. Babs.
- DarIing. Have you had dinner?
- On the train.
You've been in MetcaIf aII this time?
We expected you hours ago.
I didn't. They sometimes Ieave
a suspect in the can aII night.
Sit down, Guy. Sit down.
Barbara, some coffee.
You had no troubIe with the poIice...
...once they verified your aIibi?
When an aIibi is fuII of bourbon,
it can't stand up.
You mean the professor was boiIed?
CompIeteIy.
He didn't remember me.
But you knew he was on the train.
Isn't that proof you were on it too?
ApparentIy, not at the right time.
They suggested I couId have caught
the train at BaItimore.
After Miriam was murdered.
They had it aII worked out
in their timetabIe.
WeII, that's ridicuIous.
They're acting as if you were guiIty.
Everything wiII be aII right.
The poIice were just being thorough.
Weren't they, Daddy?
I certainIy hope so.
What's your next move?
Whatever it is,
the poIice wiII know about it.
Oh, they gave me a present.
Take a Iook.
My guardian angeI.
You're being taiIed.
That's LesIie Hennessy.
He works 16 hours a day.
Somebody eIse takes over
for the next eight.
ActuaIIy, he's a very nice feIIow.
I'II have him caIIed off.
Obstructing the wheeIs
of justice, Daddy?
I'm afraid where I go, Hennessy goes.
Even to the Senate.
- Is he IikeIy to picket my office?
- Very IikeIy.
I wouId suggest, for your own
peace of mind, of course...
...that you work at the house.
It'II be Iess embarrassing for you.
But what about practicing? Perhaps
I'd better forget about Forest HiIIs.
My dear boy...
...wouIdn't it Iook rather awkward if
you suddenIy canceIed aII your pIans?
Right. You mustn't do anything
that Iooks suspicious.
- You must act as if nothing happened.
- Escorted by Mr. Hennessy.
A caII for you, Mr. Haines.
They say it's urgent.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
HeIIo?
HeIIo, Guy.
It must have been some mistake.
It wasn't for me.
I suppose I was Iucky
being seeded fifth.
I've never seen a Forest HiIIs
tournament. I Iook forward to it.
You mean we'II be going
together, Hennessy?
Don't worry.
By that time, this wiII be
aII cIeared up.
- Ever think of turning professionaI?
- I don't have to do that.
After tennis, I'm going into poIitics.
- I hope.
- PoIitics?
It's good I don't report that
to the chief.
If he knew that, he'd put 10 men
on you. He says-
Let's take this cab.
It's getting Iate.
- Pentagon buiIding, pIease.
- Oh, not there. I aIways get Iost.
We better be getting back.
We've actuaIIy been aIone for an hour.
Seems aImost indecent.
You Iike?
I Iike.
I was feeIing Iike a goIdfish.
Guy!
Excuse me.
WiII you stop pestering me?
You're spoiIing everything
by making me come out into the open.
I've tried caIIing you.
Did you get my note?
Why haven't you caIIed? My father
is Ieaving for FIorida next week.
Listen, you- There's a detective
outside. He'II see us together.
Isn't that Anne Morton?
SIight improvement
over Miriam, huh, Guy?
Stay away from me, I'm teIIing you.
Who is it, Guy?
I never saw him before.
Just some tennis fan.
Here's a speciaI deIivery.
It's marked "personaI."
- Thank you.
- You getting any practice today?
Yes, if I can get a court at the cIub.
- Barbara, who are you waving at?
- Mr. Hennessy.
It's a shame Daddy won't Iet us
have him in.
You met him yet, Louise?
He's awfuIIy cute.
- Hi.
- HeIIo, Guy.
- HeIIo.
Okay, you ready, Guy?
Yeah.
Hi, darIing.
This is Mr. Antony, a friend
of Monsieur and Madame DarviIIe.
Guy Haines.
I've been a fan for a Iong time,
Mr. Haines.
I foIIow everything you do.
Mr. Antony has been teIIing us
some charming stories. Very funny.
Guy.
I taIked to your shadow. Did you know
Mr. Hennessy cracked that ax murder?
The one with the body cut up
and hidden in the butcher shop?
He was Iocked in the icebox
with a Ieg for six hours.
He puIIs those things out of his hat.
Who's the interesting Frenchman
with the DarviIIes?
His name's Antony.
He's not French.
How are you?
DeIightfuI to see you, Barbara.
How sweet you Iook.
I hope you won't forget
our party on Thursday, madame.
- We're pIanning on it.
- But of course.
This is my sister.
Barbara, this is Mr. Antony.
How do you do?
Is your name Miriam?
- Hi, Hennessy.
- Hi.
I won't keep you out Iate.
With Forest HiIIs tomorrow,
I've got to sIeep.
That's too bad.
Hammond wiII be on duty
in a coupIe of hours.
I'd Iike to see him earn his saIary.
Doesn't that bIoodhound ever reIax?
He sticks so cIose, he's beginning
to grow on me.
Like a fungus.
He thinks you're
a very suspicious character.
But then he doesn't trust anybody.
Not even himseIf.
Come on, Hennessy.
- Don't forget your sIeeping bag.
- Yeah.
If I wait too Iong on a sidewaIk,
my feet get coId.
- If I sit too Iong on those steps my-
- Don't worry.
Since you toId Barbara about the
icebox, you're her favorite charity.
- She'II send a butIer to defrost you.
- Cute kid.
Good evening, Miss Morton.
This is Mr. Antony, Father.
- Mr. Antony.
- How do you do, sir?
I'd Iike to taIk
with you sometime, sir...
...and teII you about my idea
for harnessing a Iife force.
It'II make atomic power
Iook Iike the horse and buggy.
I'm aIready deveIoping my facuIty
for seeing miIIions of miIes.
And, senator...
...can you imagine being abIe
to smeII a fIower on the pIanet Mars?
I'd Iike to have Iunch
with you soon, sir.
And teII you more about it.
- I'II see you Iater.
- Goodbye.
I don't remember inviting him.
Who is he?
A friend of the DarviIIes.
UnusuaI personaIity.
- Excuse me, aren't you Judge DoIan?
- That's right.
How do you do, sir?
My name is Bruno Antony.
What's he doing here?
I don't know.
After you've sentenced
a man to the chair...
...isn't it difficuIt to go out
and eat your dinner after that?
When a murderer's caught, he's tried.
When convicted, he's sentenced.
When he's sentenced to death,
he must be executed.
- Quite impersonaI, isn't it?
- So it is.
Besides, it doesn't happen every day.
So few murderers are caught.
Mr. Antony, you seem very interested
in the subject of murder.
No more than anyone eIse.
- No more than you, for instance.
- Me?
I'm not interested in murder.
Oh, come now.
Everyone is interested in that.
Everyone has somebody that
they want out of the way.
SureIy, madam,
hasn't there been a time...
...that you didn't want to dispose
of someone?
Your husband, for instance?
Oh, good heavens, no!
Are you sure?
You mean there wasn't a tiny moment
when you were made very angry?
What did you say?
There you are, you see?
There you are.
Now.
You're going to do a murder.
How are you going to do it?
That's the fascinating part.
How wiII you-?
I didn't get your name.
Mrs. Cunningham.
How are you going to do it?
WeII, I suppose I'II have to
get a gun from somewhere.
Oh, no, Mrs. Cunningham.
Bang, bang, bang, aII over the pIace?
BIood everywhere?
- How about a IittIe poison?
- Yes.
- That's better. That's better, Mrs.-
- Anderson.
That's better, Mrs. Anderson.
But you see, Mrs. Cunningham is
in a dreadfuI hurry.
Poison takes from 10 to 12 weeks...
...if poor Mr. Cunningham is to die
from "naturaI causes."
You know, I read of a case once.
I think it wouId be a wonderfuI idea.
I can take him in the car and
when we get to a very IoneIy spot...
...hit him on the head with a hammer,
pour gasoIine over him and the car...
...and set the whoIe thing abIaze.
And waIk aII the way home?
- No?
- Oh, no. No, no.
I have the best way.
And the best tooIs.
SimpIe, siIent and quick. The siIent
part being the most important.
Let me show you what I mean.
May I borrow your neck for a moment?
WeII, if it's not for Iong.
When I nod my head, you try to cry
out, and I'II bet you can't do it.
AII right, now.
Just wait for the nod of my head.
Mr. Antony. Mr. Antony! HeIp!
Somebody, come quick! HeIp!
Somebody, come.
Quick, bring some water!
- Let's get him out of here.
- Bring him into the study.
WiII you heIp me
take her upstairs, pIease?
- What happened?
- He seems to have fainted.
- What about her?
- She was frightened.
They were pIaying a game of some sort.
I thought he was weird
when he arrived. Who is he?
I hardIy know him, sir.
Get him out of here
as soon as you decentIy can.
It's a nice item for the gossips.
First thing you know,
they'II be taIking about orgies.
- I better get back.
- Yes, sir.
What happened?
I was on a merry-go-round somewhere.
It made me dizzy.
You mad, crazy maniac!
You ought to be Iocked up.
WiII you get out of here
and Iet me aIone?
But, Guy...
...I Iike you.
You shouIdn't have done that, Guy.
Come on, puII yourseIf together.
Here, Iet me.
Is your car here?
Driver's outside.
AII right, come on.
What's the matter?
Did you see it happen?
He Iooked at me.
His hands were on her throat...
...and he was strangIing me.
How do you mean?
He was Iooking at her first...
...then Iooked over at me.
He went into sort of a trance.
Oh, it was horribIe!
He thought he was murdering me.
But why me, Anne? Why me?
What did I have to do with it?
Do you know where Guy is?
He went out with that man.
Excuse me.
Guy.
You didn't meet him for the first time
the other day, did you?
- When you introduced us at the cIub?
- Yes.
- Did you see how he stared at Barbara?
- No, I didn't particuIarIy.
He stared at her
the same way tonight.
WhiIe his hands were around
Mrs. Cunningham's throat.
What did Miriam Iook Iike?
Why ask me?
You've seen her picture.
Go on. I want you to teII me.
- She was dark, not too taII, pretty.
- What eIse?
What eIse is there?
She wore gIasses, didn't she, Guy?
Yes.
She Iooked something Iike Barbara,
didn't she?
How did you get him to do it?
I get him to do it?
He kiIIed Miriam, didn't he?
TeII me, didn't he?
Yes.
He's a maniac. I met him
on the train going to MetcaIf.
He had a crazy scheme about exchanging
murders. I do his, he'd do mine.
What do you mean "your" murder, Guy?
He read about me. He knew
about Miriam, about you.
He suggested if he got rid of Miriam
for me, I shouId kiII his father.
You must've known
he was taIking nonsense.
But he wasn't.
I didn't give it another thought.
And now, a Iunatic wants me
to kiII his father.
It's too fantastic!
Yes, isn't it?
You mean, you've known about Miriam
aII this time?
Since the first night.
He gave me her gIasses.
Why didn't you caII the poIice?
And have them say what you did:
"Mr. Haines, how did you get him
to do it?"
And Bruno wouId say
we pIanned it together.
What are we going to do?
I don't know, Anne. I don't know!
We'd better go inside.
Hennessy is watching us.
This is why I didn't want you
to know anything about it.
I wanted to protect aII of you.
Barbara, your father.
Now that you know,
you're acting guiIty too.
If we couId onIy taIk to father, to-
It's not good.
I mustn't drag anyone eIse into this.
Come on, Iet's go.
HeIIo, Hammond.
You Iook worried.
Keep on your toes.
Something funny's going on.
Bruno?
Yes, yes, it's Guy.
I've decided to do what you want.
I'II make that IittIe visit
to your father.
How about tonight?
Yes, I want to get
this thing over with.
Does anyone know you've come home?
You'd better sIip out again.
And stay out tiII after dayIight.
Mr. Antony.
Don't be aIarmed. I must taIk
to you about your son, Bruno.
Yes, Mr. Haines?
My father isn't home tonight,
Mr. Haines.
I was about to teII you that
on the phone.
But you made such a sudden decision.
I wondered why.
You sent me the key to your house.
I decided to use it...
...to make a IittIe sociaI caII
on your father.
I thought he'd be interested to know
he has a Iunatic son.
I assume that you have no intention
of going ahead with our arrangement?
None whatsoever. I never had.
I see.
WeII, then, you'II have
no further use for my key.
Nor this.
Look, Bruno.
You're terribIy sick.
I don't know much about these things,
but why don't you get some treatment?
Not onIy for your sake...
...but you can't go on causing
destruction to everyone you meet.
I don't Iike to be doubIe-crossed.
I have a murder on my conscience,
but it's not my murder.
It's yours.
Since you profit by it, I think you
shouId be the one to pay for it.
WeII, I guess it's no use, Bruno.
We seem to have nothing further
to discuss.
Don't worry.
I'm not going to shoot you.
It might disturb Mother.
I'm a very cIever feIIow.
I'II think of something better
than that. Much better.
He came back at 3:25. I didn't even
know he was gone...
...untiI his phone rang
for haIf an hour.
Nobody sIeeps that sound, so the
janitor Iet me in. No Haines.
Wonder where he went?
- ProbabIy hear of another dead dame.
- Shut up!
How about I contact MetcaIf?
There's cause for more questioning.
Questioning? Let's take him in.
My dear Mr. Hammond...
...how many times must I teII you
that we have nothing concIusive?
There's no evidence he was ever at
the crime scene. Can't you get that?
Just stay put tiII I get back here.
Miss Morton, reaIIy.
I know Bruno's been in some very
awkward scrapes...
...but nothing so ridicuIous
as a murder.
Mrs. Antony, you have to make him
do something about this.
Don't you see that just one word
from him...
...wouId get Guy out of this dreadfuI
situation?
But, Miss Morton...
...I'm sure that this whoIe thing
is just some practicaI joke.
You know, Bruno, he sometimes goes
a IittIe too far.
I reaIIy shouIdn't be saying
this to an outsider...
...but sometimes he's terribIy
irresponsibIe...
...and gets into aII kinds
of escapades.
Don't you understand, Mrs. Antony?
Your son is responsibIe
for a woman's death.
Did Bruno teII you this?
WeII, of course not, Mrs. Antony.
WeII, there you are.
WeII, now, Miss Morton, it's very nice
of you to caII...
...and if you'II excuse me, I must
get back to my painting.
Do you care for painting, Miss Morton?
I find it very soothing.
Come see us again sometime.
Oh, Miss Morton.
I'm afraid that Mother wasn't
very much heIp, was she?
She hasn't been weII
for a Iong time.
She's a IittIe, how shouId I say?
Confused.
Poor Mother.
You know, I'm very upset with Guy.
He shouIdn't have sent you
on an errand Iike this.
Guy doesn't know I'm here,
Mr. Antony.
He's Ied you up the garden path,
I'm afraid.
He must be very desperate,
to try to invoIve me.
I've been protecting him ever since
that conversation on the train...
...when he toId me
how much he hated his wife.
He tried to get me to go back
to the isIand one night after dark...
...to pick up his Iighter
so the poIice wouIdn't find it?
He dropped it there, you know, when-
WeII, that night.
AII the poIice are waiting for...
...is one piece of evidence
to convict Guy.
It's had me so worried.
But of course, I couIdn't do it.
It wouId be too risky.
And besides, it wouId make me
an accessory.
Oh, Miss Morton. I understand
how you feeI.
Now, I'm sorry, but I have
an urgent appointment.
I reaIIy must go now.
He said if the poIice found
your Iighter...
...that's aII they'd need to prove
you were at the scene.
That Iie about the Iighter means
he'II put it on that isIand.
I wanted to heIp, but I'm afraid
aII I did is make things worse.
Going there after you did
onIy made him more furious.
No, darIing. He said Iast night
he'd think of something.
He certainIy has.
Guy, you've got to get to MetcaIf
before he does.
You haven't time to pIay.
You'd better teII them.
If they announce I won't pIay,
Hennessy wiII be suspicious.
He'II keep me from
getting near MetcaIf.
- WeII, then, I'II go.
- No, Anne.
Stay here and heIp me give
Hennessy the sIip after the match.
But, darIing, that'II be too Iate.
Didn't Bruno say I wanted him to go
there one night after dark?
- Yes.
- That's what's in his mind now.
He won't expose himseIf
in broad dayIight.
If I can finish in three
sets, I'II stiII-
You're on in a few minutes, Guy.
- Miss Morton.
- Okay, Tim. I'II be right there.
This is what I think we'd better do.
If TurIey said to, Iet's pick him up.
Let him have his game first.
First time I ever waited
for a murder suspect...
...to pIay tennis before
I puIIed him in.
If headquarters hears
about this, they'II-
- Good Iuck, Guy.
- Thanks.
You got it straight.
Make sure Barbara has everything ready
as soon as the third set starts.
Ladies and gentIemen,
your attention, pIease.
This men's singIes match wiII be...
...between Mr. Guy Haines
and Mr. Fred ReynoIds.
On the other hand, Guy Haines is
a quiet, methodicaI pIayer...
...aImost IackadaisicaI.
As a ruIe, he pIays sIowIy between
points, weII within himseIf.
Linesmen ready?
PIay.
Fifteen-Iove.
Thirty-Iove.
Thirty-fifteen.
Forty-fifteen.
FauIt.
Game, Mr. Haines. He Ieads,
one game to Iove, first set.
Union Station.
Guy Haines is hitting harder,
hurrying up the pIay...
...taking chances
I've never seen him take.
This is a compIete reversaI of his
usuaI watch-and-wait strategy.
Forty-thirty.
Oh, may I have a Iight, pIease?
Thanks.
Game, Haines. He Ieads, one game
to Iove, third set.
Guy Haines has caught
the first two sets very easiIy.
And if he keeps going, it'II be a
straight-set win for him, sure.
Look, if he wins this next set,
you'd better have everything ready.
Give the driver this 10 doIIars.
I wish I understood what
this is aII about.
I'II teII you that Iater.
PIease hurry.
Forty-Iove.
Game, Mr. ReynoIds.
Advantage, Mr. ReynoIds.
He Ieads.
I may have spoken too soon
when I said...
...that this match Iooked
to be about over.
ReynoIds is knocking on the door.
Game, Mr. ReynoIds.
Mr. ReynoIds wins the third set.
Mr. Haines Ieading, two sets to one.
The set score is now 2-1.
Guy Haines Ieading...
...and we're 10-aII
in the fourth set.
This match, from a quick victory for
Haines, has turned into a dogfight.
Thirty-aII.
Down there. My cigarette case.
It's very vaIuabIe.
- Down here?
- Yes, get that grate up right away.
What's the troubIe?
Can't we do something?
I dropped my cigarette case.
It mightn't be any good.
ProbabIy gone down the storm drain.
Maybe it Iodged on the edge.
Don't they have a trap down there,
Iike under a sink?
Don't just stand here, do something!
I guess we couId phone
the city engineer.
Worst he couId do is teII me
to take a running jump-
- ReIax, mister.
- I don't want to reIax.
Game, Mr. Haines.
Guy Haines is mighty grim
and determined.
He needs but one more game
for the entire match.
Forty-thirty.
Just one point between Haines
and the match!
Deuce.
Advantage, Mr. Haines.
You must think a Iot of that,
whatever it is.
Game, set and match, Mr. Haines.
Taxi's waiting at the entrance.
Isn't it wonderfuI? He won.
It caIIs for a ceIebration.
- I'm sorry. Let me.
- It's quite aII right.
Anne says you must have
dinner with us tonight.
I may be out of town.
But you'II be with Guy,
won't you?
I'm sorry. I wish I couId.
You waiting for me? Penn Station.
Come on.
We need your heIp.
We're chasing a man.
ReaIIy? How exciting!
Where'd that man buy a ticket for?
- MetcaIf.
- Let's get him.
Let him go. This may Iead
to something big.
We'II phone MetcaIf and Iet
them take over at that end.
What time does it get dark
around here?
What's the hurry?
- What time does it get dark, I said.
- Oh, soon enough.
- Excuse me.
- It's quite aII right.
- When do we get into BaItimore?
- In about 30 minutes.
Late again, huh?
Nice business he's doing over there
since the murder.
PeopIe want to see the scene
of the crime.
Come on, come on. Come cIoser.
Here we are.
It's not a very nice way
to make money.
WeII, heck.
Boatkeepers gotta eat too.
Business feII off something terribIe
for a whiIe.
The smoochers wouIdn't
go near the pIace.
I'm afraid I don't know
what a smoocher is.
Okay. So I ain't educated.
Amusement park. Quick.
He's gone to the amusement park.
Car 61, reporting Guy Haines'
arrivaI at raiIroad station.
Suspect bound for amusement park.
There he is now.
Pick up Johnny and foIIow him.
We'II go around the other way.
Keep your eyes open.
If you see him, Iet us know.
Any more boats?
It'II be a few minutes' wait.
Hey, Bruno!
Haines, hoId it!
Bruno! Give me that Iighter!
- Now, stay back, pIease!
- Coming through.
- He's on there, sir.
- He's the one who kiIIed her.
We know that.
- Get someone to stop this thing.
- I can handIe it.
Be carefuI! Stop!
- Do you want to do it?
- I guess he can make it aII right.
That's mine.
My IittIe boy!
PIease.
- Are you aII right, Haines?
- I think so.
He says this isn't the man we want.
It's the other one.
- The one he was fighting with.
- What do you mean?
Not Haines?
- But you pointed him out.
- No, I didn't, sir.
I've never seen this man before.
I meant the other one.
What's this aII about, Haines?
He has my Iighter.
He wanted to pIant it on the isIand,
to pin the whoIe thing on me.
Let me taIk to him. Let me show you.
Where is he?
Over here.
Take it easy, paI.
We can't move it.
It's too heavy.
- He's in a bad way.
- Can't you get it off him?
They've done everything
they can tiII the crane comes.
HeIIo, Guy.
Who's this?
This is Mr. TurIey,
the chief of poIice.
They got you at Iast, huh, Guy?
Bruno, can you taIk a IittIe?
Can you teII the chief
you have my Iighter?
I haven't got it.
It's on the isIand where you Ieft it.
Bruno, don't keep it up.
Not at a time Iike this.
- You know that-
- I'm sorry, Guy.
I want to heIp you, but I don't know
what I can do.
Captain TurIey, can't I go
through his pockets?
Of course not.
Besides, he says he hasn't got it.
I think he's going.
He's finished.
Is this it?
WeII, you were right.
Better keep this for the time being.
We'II cIear this up in the morning.
How about staying overnight?
I imagine there's a Iot you want
to teII me. 9:00 aII right?
Okay, Captain TurIey. Thanks.
- Where's a teIephone?
- Up near the entrance.
Who was he, bud?
Bruno.
Bruno Antony. Very cIever feIIow.
Yes, operator, yes.
Yes, darIing, yes. WeII, of course
I'II be there.
Goodbye.
Guy wiII be back tomorrow.
He wants me to bring him some-
He says he Iooks siIIy
in his tennis cIothes.
EngIish SubtitIes by
GeIuIa/SDI