♪ [ Jazz Guitar] ♪
♪ Hold that tiger ♪
♪ Where's that tiger
Where's that tiger ♪
♪ Here's that tiger
♪ Here's that tiger ♪
♪ Where's that tiger ♪
Here's that tiger ♪
♪ Hold that tiger
Hold that tiger ♪
Six years ago...
on the morning of May 20, 1927...
I was fast asleep when my
bedside phone began to ring.
I looked at my alarm clock.
It was almost 5:00.
I knew there was only one
person in the whole world...
who would call at such an hour.
And when I picked up the phone,
I knew I was right.
'Hello, ' I said. There was
quite a bit of noise on the line.
'Aaron, Charles Lindbergh here.
Sorry about the noise.
I'm calling from Roosevelt Field,
and we're doing engine tests.'
'That's okay, Slim', I said.
'What can I do for you?'
'Well', he said,
'remember that flight across the
Atlantic I was telling you about?'
I told him I remembered.
He'd been telling me about it...
for months and made me
swear to keep it a secret.
'Here's the situation', Slim said.
'The fact is I'll be shoving off...
in a few hours... around 10 to 8:00...
and I wanted to ask you about food.'
'Food?' I said.
'Yes', he replied.
'I anticipate the flight
to take about 34 hours...
and I wanted your opinion
on what kind of food to bring.'
'Well', I said, 'you can't go
wrong with a cheese sandwich.
And don't forget the mustard.'
He laughed.
'I knew I could count on you, Aaron.
I'll cable you from Paris.'
'Good luck', I told him
and hung up the phone.
Like everyone else,
I listened to the radio...
for news about his flight...
but I wasn't worried about his
safety because I knew he had...
a special collapsible lifeboat behind
his pilot seat in case of emergency.
But when the Spirit of St. Louis
landed in Paris...
33 1/2 hours after takeoff...
I yelled so loud the windows shook.
Two days later I received
a telegram.
It said, 'Sorry to
disturb your sleep...
but alas, 'twas good
to hear your voice.
Take it from
your good friend Chaz...
the cheese I chewed was choice."'
The end.
Thank you, Aaron.
That was... very inventive.
My mother was the maid of honor
at Charles Lindbergh's wedding.
Really?
Our last report for the day
will be read by Billy Thompson.
The American hero he's chosen
is John D. Rockefeller.
"I chose John D. Rockefeller
as my American hero...
because, although he's one
of the richest men in the world...
he has never forgotten
his humble beginnings.
That's why he gives
generously to charity...
and hands out dimes
to the poor unfortunates...
he encounters on the streets."
- Hello, Aaron.
- Hi, Mr. Sandoz.
Sullivan!
Every day it's something.
No wonder you got caught.
Taking a kid's dessert!
I told you a thousand times,
only take food from the fat kids...
and you never take a kid's dessert.
A kid will leave his whole lunch
untouched and just eat the dessert.
- I know.
- Did you get sent to Mr. Stillwater?
Yeah.
You didn't tell him
where we live, did you?
No. He had his hands clamped onto the back
of my neck like a vulture or something.
- I couldn't talk.
- Good.
Come on, come on!
Hey, look.
- Big Butt Burns.
- Hurry up! Get out of the street.
Hey, hold it there.
You, come on! Let's go!
Move it along!
Hey, lady, get out of the street.
Come on, buddy. Come on.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
When you gonna teach me marbles?
I keep telling ya:
All the important stuff can't be taught.
You just have to learn.
Who knows all the important stuff?
- Dad.
- Lester. And who taught him? Nobody.
- But I wanna be as good as you.
- Look.
Pick two.
Not that one.
No, not that one.
Definitely not that one.
Well, which ones can I have?
Here.
- Start practicing.
- But you kept the good ones.
- Want me to take 'em back?
- No.
Stop complaining.
Come on.
- Hey.
Took your father up a while ago.
He was readin' some letter.
Was it from a company?
He's expecting a letter from a watch
company. There's big money in watches.
Now, how would I know
who it was from?
Well, was it typed
or was it written by hand?
- By hand.
- It's probably nothing, then.
- Hey, stop!
- Let me get a few things...
You're
stepping on a black one.
Shh. Listen.
- What?
- Come on.
I just want my paints.
Just the watercolors and a few brushes.
I gotta do
what Mr. Desot tells me.
But...
How am I supposed
to earn money to pay my rent...
if I can't use my supplies?
- That's a puzzle, all right.
- So what would your price be...
to let me have five seconds
in that room?
A lot more than you got.
Ow! Aah!
Mom, we just...
Did somebody die?
Nobody died.
Well, what is it, then?
Your mother and I
have made a decision.
- You made the decision.
- You agreed to this!
I agreed we didn't have a choice.
That's not the same thing.
Tell them, Eric.
Sullivan will be
going away for a while.
What?
Uncle Nathan sent a letter
saying he'd keep him...
until we can get back
on our feet again.
That way we save
at least a dollar a week.
I could make a dollar
in a week, Dad.
Oh, you can make that much, huh?
He's finishing eighth grade.
- He's already the breadwinner!
- Eric.
He's too young!
You could send me.
We're sending him,
and that's final!
And what was the big idea of bursting
in here like the hotel was on fire?
That's no way to enter a room, sir!
We saw Sandoz
get locked out of his room.
On the third floor?
You said it could never
happen on the third floor.
I carry a lot of influence with Desot.
Don't you worry.
How do you think I got us
a room with a double exposure?
Triple, if you count the transom.
He knows Sid Gutman is going
to give me the Hamilton Watch line.
He knows I've got
this WPA job coming.
When that happens...
I call up my pal Donald Miller...
and we move to the Carleton Court
Apartments, where we belong.
Can I take Skippy?
"Can I take...?"
No, you can't take Skippy on the bus.
He's going on the bus?
Why aren't you driving him?
How can I drive him
when the Repleviners are waiting...
to take my car
any minute they see it?
And where would I get
the money to pay for gas?
I can't even afford to get
your mother's tooth fixed.
He's perfectly safe on the bus.
He's a big boy, aren't you?
Huh? You see?
- Hold on.
- Where are you going?
I have to leave a note for Lester.
Is there a law
against knocking on his door?
- He said it disturbs his mother.
- Is she sick?
- I've never seen her.
- Of course she's sick.
She's got back trouble from bending over to
pick up secret messages all day. Come on.
...irritated nasal membranes...
and helps to shrink puffy,
cold-swollen nasal passages...
...giving you more room to breathe.
Be a good boy.
Sullivan, see you soon,
big boy, huh?
Come on, Sull.
I don't wanna go!
Don't worry, okay? I'm gonna earn
some money and get you back.
- How?
- Well, I'm not sure yet.
But I know Lester'll have
some ideas.
And don't worry about Skippy either.
I'll take good care of him.
See ya.
All right, try me again.
True or false?
Walter Eamons had to go to the hospital
because he played with his belly button...
so much it got infected,
and they had to operate.
Definitely false.
It's true. He's gonna be
out of school for three weeks.
All right, one more.
True or false?
Today after school...
I snuck into Sportsman's Park
through the left-field bleachers.
I passed by the railing
to go to the bathroom...
and saw Pepper Martin
going out to third.
He saw me and threw me
a piece of Wrigley's gum.
- True.
- False.
Gotcha.
Well, the trouble
with this game is...
I have to accept your word
for what's true or false.
- That's true.
- Hmm.
Night.
You said you were gonna play,
and you're gonna play,
- You ain't leavin' until you do.
- But it's not fair.
Put your marbles
on the ground or else.
- I ain't got time to argue with you!
- You okay, Billy?
Scram, small-fry.
This little sissy said he'd shoot
for ten marbles. Now he's welshin'.
- But their marbles are clearly inferior.
- So's your old man.
I'll tell you what. We'll shoot
partners, us against you.
I'll put up five and Billy
will put up five against your ten.
- Sure.
- You bet.
All right.
One, two, three, drop.
We'll let you go first.
- Go ahead and shoot first, Billy.
- Okay.
- Damn!
- How could you miss that?
Excuse me.
Pow!
Wow!
Well, gentlemen, the game is over.
You were lucky.
- Sore losers.
- Yeah.
I never played marbles
before I came to Dewey.
No kidding.
Wanna come over
for a soda or something?
Yeah.
Look, Billy.
There's that salesman...
- I was telling you about.
- Oh, yes.
I don't understand.
Who would buy a candle
you can't even light?
I was just gonna change into
some playclothes, if you don't mind.
Sure.
Criminy!
- This is signed by Pepper Martin?
- Yes. My father got it for me.
I've never really used it, but maybe
it will be worth money someday.
Your father must be really nice.
Listen, Aaron,
how are you about birds?
I'm in favor of 'em.
I have a canary at home.
You have a canary?
Me too!
How many birds
did you say you have?
Well, you know,
right now, just the one.
But he'll take
a grape from my lips...
and fly to my finger
right when I put it out.
- That's nifty.
- Yeah. Why do you have so many?
I breed them. It's my hobby.
I sell them to Mr. Farley
at the shop on DeBaliviere.
You sell 'em?
- How much do you get?
- About three dollars a bird.
Gosh!
Hey, why don't you go into business?
I'll arrange it with Mr. Farley.
- Yeah, but I only have Skippy.
- I'll give you a female.
Females aren't worth anything
because they don't sing.
Really?
That... That's all I need?
Well, you need a breeding cage like
this one, but any big cage will do.
And then you need
a few odds and ends.
Here, this is put out by
the Miss Finch Birdseed Company.
It tells you everything.
Here's a pretty sexy-lookin' dish.
Hey.
Are you sure
you can't stay for dinner?
Um... no, ma'am.
My mother's hosting a mah-jongg
tournament, and she wanted me to be there.
You're hosting
a tournament in your house?
Well...
no, you see, we're living in a hotel until
our new house is finished being built.
The tournament is in the ballroom.
What kind of house
are you building?
Just a regular house like this one.
And what does
your father do, Aaron?
He flies airplanes.
- Wow!
- My, that's interesting.
So that's how you know
Charles Lindbergh.
Right.
So... what kind
of flying does he do?
Uh...
Well, it's sort of
for the government...
and I'm not supposed to discuss it.
Can't you tell us anything?
Billy, you heard what Aaron said.
It's supposed to be secret.
I'm sure he prefer we didn't
breathe a word of it to anyone.
Isn't that right, Aaron?
Yes, ma'am.
I know you took it.
I seen ya. Hand it over!
I don't have no apples!
I know you took it!
Now gimme that apple!
Give it here!
- You ain't got no apple, huh?
- No!
Let me tell you something.
This is my street.
This is my corner.
I know everything that goes on.
I catch you kiping apples
one more time...
I'm gonna run your little chicken ass in!
Now get out of here! Beat it!
Slow down!
What you got in there?
A canary.
- Thought you already had a canary.
- Yeah, I do.
A male one.
This is a female.
I'm gonna breed canaries.
There's big money in canaries.
Uh-huh.
I don't know where
you get all that vitality.
- Hi.
- Hi, Ella.
- What have you got?
- A canary.
I thought you already
had a canary.
I do, but this one's a female.
I'm gonna breed canaries.
We had a canary once.
Canaries are kinda nervous,
don't you think?
I think I'd rather have a cat.
I'd name her Stephanie.
- What are you gonna name your bird?
- I have to... go put her in her cage.
Oh, okay.
Uh, see you later?
Yeah, okay. Sure.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- What have you got there?
- Billy Thompson gave me a canary.
- Aaron, we already have a canary.
- I know we already have a canary.
This is a female.
Mr. Farley at the pet store said he'd
give three dollars apiece for babies.
My goodness... three dollars.
Are you sure?
Yep. And Billy said...
the average female
lays about four eggs...
so that's $12.
We can bring Sullivan home.
That would be wonderful.
- Where's Dad?
- Out selling candles.
Nobody's gonna buy those candles.
You can't even light 'em.
Why can't he sell something useful?
He's doing the best he can.
- Lester was here?
- I suppose so.
It was slipped under the door.
♪ Missing the thrills
of nights that we've known ♪
♪ Can't we talk it over
before it's over ♪
- ♪ Before you whisper good-bye forever♪
- Hey.
Must you wear that
filthy thing on your head?
Ma, it's a hat.
You wear it on your head.
What the hell are you doin'?
You know anything about golf, eh?
Not really.
Shit.
Sullivan got sent away
to live with my uncle.
At least you got
a brother to get sent.
Doesn't it cost
a lot of money to play?
You're not gonna play, brain.
You're gonna caddy.
I'm in good with the caddy master.
Thing is, first couple of times,
you gotta split your fee with him.
- It's still 50 cents to get you started.
- I could use 50 cents.
Yep, you and all of Missouri.
- You know any of the clubs?
- Uh, I know the putter.
Stupendous.
All right, it's easy.
You got your woods, driver,
brassie, spoon, cleek.
And you got your irons: one iron,
mid-iron, mid-mashie, mashie iron...
spade mashie, mashie niblick pitching
niblick, and regular niblick.
Give him whatever he asks for.
I'll make sure you go with me.
You won't have any trouble.
- I gotta go.
- Where you going?
I gotta go put these back
before Ben finds out.
How'd you get 'em
out of the storeroom?
Aaron, can I speak to you
outside for a minute?
Sure.
Aaron, it's been brought
to my attention...
that the address we have for you
in our records is no longer current.
Yes, that's because we moved.
Well, um, when you move,
you need to let the school know...
because we might need
to get in touch with your parents.
Also, if you've moved
out of the district...
you might be going
to the wrong school.
It is possible you should be going
to Clark instead of Dewey.
I know, but we're still
in the same district, I'm sure.
Well, can you tell me
where you're living now?
Yeah. The Carleton Court
Apartments...
4519 Riley Street.
But if you're gonna send
something there...
make sure to address it
to Donald Miller.
- Donald Miller?
- Yeah. Um...
my father works for the government,
and sometimes his mail gets stolen.
We think it might be foreign spies,
but we're not sure.
So if you put
Donald Miller's name...
whoever's taking the mail
will let it go through...
because they won't know
it's really for my father.
I see.
- For Donald Miller?
- Yeah.
I know it sounds complicated...
but it's the only way
to make sure my father'll get it.
I understand. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Flor Fina!
So the little bohunk's
snipin' butts again!
That's why you're such a runt...
you're snipin' butts all the time.
It's not a butt.
It's a cigar band.
You're a lyin' little thief, just
like that Yid what's-his-name!
Lester.
- Last name!
- Silverstone!
Silverstone.
So, uh... where's your old man?
Did he take a steamer
back to Krautland?
No, he's still here.
I ain't seen him drivin' around lately.
Did they snatch his car?
No.
Where's he keepin' it?
In a back lot?
He's gotta be hiding it somewhere.
I don't know. I guess so.
You guess so?
Come here.
You better watch yourself.
Black square.
Hey!
Yeah, you.
Come here.
You want a job?
Go give this to three-one-zero.
That's 310, you hear?
What do I get?
You get on my good side.
- Ah, Aaron.
- Hey, Mr. Mungo.
I see Brother Ben
has drafted you into service.
Yes, sir.
You like this cane?
Yeah, it's really superb.
Made from the leg bone of a rhinoceros.
Cost me a hundred dollars.
- A hundred dollars?
- Years ago...
when people like me were using
currency to light their cigars.
Speaking of which...
how's your cigar band
collection coming?
Pretty good.
I'll keep an eye out for you.
Thanks.
- Good-bye, Aaron.
- Good-bye.
Ah, here he is.
Hi.
- What's wrong?
- Well, your mother has...
Eric.
A...
the specialist said
I have to go back...
to the sanitarium for a while.
But he was very optimistic.
He said I might only
have to stay there...
a month or two.
I'm just worried about you
being here all alone.
What are you talking about?
He won't be alone.
I'll be here with him.
I'm just worried about...
who's going to take care of you.
He knows how to take care of himself,
but you wanted to wait, so we did.
But we're to be there by 6:00.
You know how far it is.
You can, um...
You can come visit me every Sunday.
Not the first two, but after that.
They won't let him inside.
You know how strict they are.
- Where are you going?
- I'm gonna say good-bye to her.
- You just did!
- That wasn't a real one.
You know how emotional
your mother gets.
You don't want to make
a big scene, do you?
Huh?
Okay. Big boy.
Lucky bastard!
Damn, slice!
Oh, here we go.
Say, clean this ball off for me,
will you, sonny?
Hey!
What's taking so long over there?
- Excuse me a second, please.
- Sonny!
Throw me the goddamn ball!
Didn't you put the ball
in the paddle?
No, I put it in there.
Superb.
What's this kid trying to do to me?
He keeps handing me niblicks.
No wonder I'm high ball.
And now you've lost
my three-dollar Kro-Flite.
Now I'll probably miss
the damn putt!
Don't worry about it.
- How was I supposed to know?
- I said don't worry about it.
Go home.
I'll take care of this.
There's other ways to make money.
A transcribed moment of perfect ease.
Lunched with Bill, honey
He wants us to come out Thursday
I don't want to.
We have to go on the streetcar.
Yes, Your Ladyship.
It seems there was a depression.
That isn't fair. It's
that long walk up that hill.
- Hello?
- Who is it?
Ella.
Hi.
Um, I was wondering
if I could see your baby canaries.
They haven't hatched yet.
Oh. Can I come see them
when they do hatch?
Sure.
Thanks.
I... well...
Would you like to have a hot dog?
Would you like
to listen to some music?
Well...
I love this song.
Would you like to dance?
I dance better on a full stomach.
Come on.
It's halfway over already.
Okay.
You haven't done this before.
No.
Uh...
- That was my foot.
- Oh. Sorry.
It's okay.
♪ Never thought I'd fall ♪
♪ But now I hear love call ♪
♪ I'm getting sentimental
over you ♪
♪ Things you say and do ♪
♪ Just thrill me
through and through ♪
Ella? Ella?
Mrs. McShane!
Aaron, raise her head up.
Here. Shh.
Shh...
♪ Won't you please be kind ♪
♪ And just make up your mind ♪
♪ That you'll be sweet and gentle ♪
♪ Be gentle to me ♪
She'll be all right.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it, I swear...
Oh, Aaron, it is not your fault.
Ella hasn't had
one of these in a long time.
Was it awful?
Ella?
We should let Aaron be on his way.
I want to know
if I did anything really bad.
You were sick,
and now you're better.
It doesn't happen very often.
J-Just when we run out of medicine.
Well, I have to go back to my room.
Will you come visit me again?
Sure.
Promise?
Promise.
Krilby, that new soap for the bath...
presents a transcribed
minute message... "The Tip."
Just a minute, boy,
till I open this suitcase.
Put this bar of soap in the bath.
Yes, sir, but the hotel
furnishes bath soap.
I'm not taking any chances.
I carry Krilby soap.
Here's a tip for you.
- Thank you, sir.
- And here's another tip for you:
Just try bathing with Krilby...
And you'll never go back
to sissy soaps again.
There's a man who has discovered
the secret of better bathing...
Aaron...
how do you spell "proprietor"?
P-R-O-P-R-I-E-T-O-R.
"I-O-R."
What is that anyway?
Aha! This is the application form
for the Hamilton Watch Company...
with a personal recommendation
from Mr. Sid Gutman.
It's a bit more concrete
than the canary business,
I'm telling you. But
it's only a formality.
I've got the job
practically in my pocket.
What about the WPA job?
What happens if you get both?
Having two job offers will be the
least of our problems, believe me.
How do you make this soup?
This is good soup.
- It's saltier this time.
- It's tasty.
- Yeah. Pretty good.
- It's good.
You were telling the truth.
But of course.
For all I know, you promise
lots of things to lots of people.
For all you know...
that's true.
I usually operate...
on a cash-only basis.
I'm making an exception.
I understand.
You got a name?
Thomiros.
Mr. Thomiros.
What kind of name is that?
Greek.
Aaron, I, uh...
I just wanted you to know
I put your address...
into the records
the way you told me.
Oh.
Okay. Thanks.
Hey! Hey! Come here!
Come here, you little bohunk.
You don't know
what trouble you're in.
You told me your old man
parks his car in a parking lot.
What is that right over there?
What do you call that?
- That can't be my father's.
- Oh, so I'm a liar now?
Let me tell you something.
I know that's your father's car,
and I'm gonna give him a ticket...
It can't be. He parked in the alley
behind the Davidson house.
Aha!
Stupid, stupid!
Lester, look.
The Repleviners.
- Burns told them where the Ford is.
- Where is it?
Behind the Davidson house,
but I don't have the keys.
- Come on.
- It doesn't have gas!
- Come on!
- All right.
What, you gonna push?
Get in.
All right, hit the brake.
Hit the brakes!
Hit the brakes, Aaron.
Hit the brake.
Hit the brakes!
Shit.
Watch out!
Gotcha!
Scared ya?
Look what I found.
- Dad.
- Aaron.
- You're not gonna believe this.
- I have to show you something.
- Patrolman Burns...
- This way. Come have a look.
Watch it.
I told you they were the best, huh?
Aren't they beautiful?
It's a king's ransom. Look at this.
Here. Signed by the president
of the Hamilton Watch Company...
stating I'm an official representative
for Iowa, Kansas, and Oklahoma.
What about Missouri?
I didn't get
the territory I asked for.
But you know,
beggars can't be choosers.
You leaving right now?
Don't you worry.
I've got it all arranged.
You see, most of the watches
are just display models.
They don't have any works inside.
But I took two who had works, and I
gave one to Manny at the Woodbine...
so by the end of the day, you just walk
in and they give you a nice big dinner.
It won't be roast beef, but
something healthy like liverwurst.
The other one I gave to Desot...
and he gave us
$17 credit on our bill.
You see, as long as you pay them a
little something, they won't bother us.
And here is 25 cents
for spending money.
There you go. Here.
You're gonna miss graduation.
Aaron, you know...
of course I want to be there...
seeing you getting your diploma.
But I have no choice.
I have to be in Davenport, Iowa,
first thing Monday morning.
You can see Sullivan!
- I wanna give him some marbles.
- No. No, I won't.
Keokuk isn't on my route.
They have me spread out
all over the map.
- You know when you're gonna be back?
- I just can't tell.
But I'll be back as soon as I can,
because I'll be very worried.
Is there any place
I can write to you?
What happens if I need to get
in touch with you for something?
I guess there isn't.
I'll be moving from town to town.
It's bad luck
your mother is sick just now.
I should put this off,
but you know how jobs are.
They're not gonna let you
leave with that.
Mr. Desot said I could take a few things,
as long as I let them inspect it.
After all, I paid them $17.
Hey, walk me over to the car.
The car!
Lucky for me,
you boys saved the car.
Otherwise I wouldn't
have been able to go.
Yeah.
Well, I'd drive you back...
but I can't let
the Repleviners see me.
Listen to me, Aaron.
You're going to be okay.
You're a smart boy.
You're very smart.
I tell you
how smart you are.
When you were less than a year old,
your mother was in the
sanitarium with consumption...
and you would cry every night.
The first few times, I picked
you up, and you stopped,
so I realized you wanted attention.
So the next time, I got a glass of
cold water and stood over the crib...
and I said, "This is a glass of cold
water. Stop crying, or you'll be sorry."
But you kept crying, so I poured
the water in your face...
and you stopped crying
just like that.
From then on,
when you cried, all I had to do...
was show you the glass of water,
and you'd stop crying.
Now, that's a smart baby
for you, eh?
You be a mensch.
Hmm?
And then to be fooled
by a wooden horse.
A wooden horse!
Oh, Aaron. Hello.
Thank you.
Come in.
Lydia, this is Aaron.
- Aaron, Lydia.
- Hello.
Lydia, uh, works for the hotel.
Don't you, Lydia?
Uh, what is it that you do?
She's in the customer service department.
It's difficult work.
But it pays well.
And there's always an opening
for someone with a certain...
type of ambition.
♪ Maybe he's lonesome ♪
♪ Maybe he's blue ♪
♪ Maybe he's unhappy ♪
♪ Maybe I am too ♪
- Smart-ass.
- Thank you.
♪ Maybe, who knows ♪
Oh, no.
I did it as a favor, actually.
Oh.
♪ Maybe he's loving
someone else instead ♪
I love it.
Outclassed by a street urchin.
Yes.
A lesson for us all.
♪ Cryin'
It fills my heart ♪
♪ My broken heart ♪
♪ Morning, dawning ♪♪
Excuse me.
Can you tell me where Manny is?
- You wanna talk to Manny?
- Yeah.
Mr. Navarro...
there's somebody here
who wants to speak with Manny
Are you Manny?
I'm the owner.
What do you want with Manny?
Well, my father sort of had
an arrangement with Manny.
Yeah? Huh.
It turns out a lot of people
had an arrangement with Manny...
but Manny never asked me
about no arrangements.
So I just fired
the son of a bitch.
B-B-But my father gave him a watch.
An expensive watch.
I didn't notice no watch, kid.
He said he was gonna give
me a meal at dinnertime.
Look, I just told you:
The bastard stole from me,
I fired him... end of story.
Well, what can I get
with a quarter?
You could buy a plate lunch.
I need something that'll last.
Yeah?
How about 20 dinner rolls?
That should last you.
- Hi, Mrs. McShane.
- Hello, Aaron.
I was wondering if maybe Ella
wanted to see my baby canaries...
before I bring them
to the pet store.
Uh, I'm sure she would, Aaron,
but she really can't.
She's had another attack,
I'm afraid.
Oh.
Actually, I think we're going
to be leaving soon...
to stay with my sister in Illinois.
Her husband's a doctor...
and I think
it'll be better for Ella.
Well, Mr. Yano?
They're very nice birds,
aren't they?
Yes, Mr. Farley.
Very nice. Very healthy.
- All females.
- Are you sure?
Oh, yes, very sure.
I'll be darned.
A whole litter like that.
- Bye.
That's a tough break.
I don't understand.
What happened?
You got five females.
Females don't sing, so there's
no market for them. I'm sorry.
They're not worth anything?
I can't bring them back home.
The most I could do
is give you 50 cents for the lot.
Look, I'm really sorry
it can't be more.
That's the first time
I've known that to happen.
Go in. She'll love it. It's wonderful.
Go on. Go.
It's all right.
♪ Don't save your
kisses Just pass them around ♪
♪ You'll find my reasons ♪
♪ Are logically sound ♪
Oh, Stephanie.
Then each of you
will be called by name...
and given your diploma.
You'll then return
to your assigned seat and wait...
till all the names
have been called.
You've been a wonderful class.
Enjoy your summer.
Aaron?
Hi.
I was wondering if you were going
to the reception at Billy Thompson's.
Yeah, I'm planning on it.
Afterwards, my parents are going
to take me out for a special dinner...
and they said
I could bring someone.
I thought maybe you'd like to go.
Yeah!
That-That-That sounds fine.
Great. I'll see you at Billy's,
and we can leave from there.
Yes.
I-I mean, good.
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye.
Bye.
Mail for 309.
WPA!
Criminy!
Yeah, who's there?
It's me... Aaron.
Hi.
Hey, I told you my mom's sick.
You can't keep knocking.
What is that?
This is all I have to
wear to graduation.
The pants don't button,
the shirt's up there...
All right, I'll get you something.
When's the ceremony?
- Noon tomorrow.
- Wow. Shit.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
I could've got something easy.
- I didn't know until just now.
- All right.
Well, I got an idea.
Might be a little risky.
You up for it?
- Well...
- Good. Come on.
You sure we should be doing this?
The hotel stole
this stuff from these people.
- What about Ben?
- Ben's a trained dog.
My mom used to tell me...
you could teach a dog to walk
on its hind legs. It's still a dog.
Yeah.
Looks like somebody's
got you tied up.
It's a picture
Mr. Sandoz did of me.
Not bad.
What is it?
It's payday.
I think I got something.
Hey, Les.
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
Don't mention it.
And I really mean don't mention it.
What do you think?
Looks wonderful.
I wish I was going
to your graduation.
Well, I... You'll be better off
with your aunt, right?
I guess so.
But what are you gonna do
here all alone?
I don't know. I'll be okay.
Oh, Aaron, knowing you is the only
good thing that happened to me here.
Congratulations...
all of you.
I now take great pleasure...
in presenting the Admiral George
Dewey Achievement Award...
to that member
of the graduating class...
who possesses that combination...
of scholastic ability
and good character...
that best exemplifies
what we seek...
in our young people
going forth to a higher education.
Please come forward...
Aaron Kurlander.
That's you, Aaron.
You won. Go on up.
Each winner of the Admiral George
Dewey Award for Achievement...
could be described...
as hardworking...
creative, and honest...
and Aaron Kurlander
is no exception.
He serves as both an example...
and an inspiration to us all.
Thank you, Aaron.
Well, how do you like it?
- What?
- The car. How do you like the car?
Oh, it's colossal.
Stupendous. Whose is it?
What do you mean?
It's mine.
- How'd you get it?
- Well, you know.
Anyway, what are you doing after this
party at Billy what's-his-name's?
Dinner with Christina Sebastian.
Wow! A real date, huh?
You got all your moves polished up?
Lester, look, she's not
that kind of girl.
Oh, okay.
- Hey, Aaron, can I see your medal?
- Yeah, sure.
Oh. Thanks.
- Hi.
I was just wondering
if you'd like to dance.
Sure.
Have you ever danced before?
Once, but it didn't go too well.
Well, it's very simple.
Don't worry.
♪ I'm lonesome and blue
but when I look at you ♪
Congratulations on your award.
Oh, yeah, thank you.
Who was that boy
that dropped you off?
Oh, that was Lester.
He kind of takes care
of me sometimes.
I see.
Will your parents
be joining us for dinner?
No. That's, uh...
that's impossible.
- Were they at graduation?
- No, they weren't.
Are they away?
- Sort of.
- Where?
I can't really say.
You don't know where they are?
Don't they tell you?
Well, they're not able to...
exactly.
But they could just call, couldn't they,
or write to you if they...
They're missing.
They're missing?
What do you mean?
Well, uh, my parents are archaeologists,
and they were on an expedition...
and nobody's heard from them in a
while, so I guess they're missing.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I hope they're okay.
Are people looking for them?
Yeah, there's a search party
and everything.
I'm not that worried.
They've been lost lots of times.
- ♪ If I had a girl like you ♪♪
- Oh.
I need to sit down for a moment,
if you don't mind.
Sure.
What's the matter?
Aaron just told me his parents
are missing on an expedition!
My grades were just as good...
but everyone knew they were going to
give the award to the teacher's pet.
Then all the girls feel sorry for
him because he's a charity case.
What a phony!
And did you see that outfit?
I haven't seen clothes that funny
since the circus was here.
They don't even look
like they're his.
My brother says there's a poor kid
like him every year...
and they always
get special treatment.
Did you hear about Aaron...
They're lost on an expedition.
Say, Aaron,
Walter Eamons said...
that Betty Haskins said
that your parents...
were captured by natives
on a tiger hunt.
But I thought your father was
a pilot flying for the government.
Excuse me.
I have to use your bathroom.
- Aaron!
- Aaron, congratulations!
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Did you graduate?
Yeah.
Got somethin' for you.
Really?
Someday
I'll teach you how to pop.
Thanks.
But my father said he paid
a $17 credit on our bill.
That's true, Aaron, but that
still leaves an unpaid balance...
of $172.
The watch held the bank off
for a week or so...
but now they're gonna take action.
Three days, Mr. Desot.
My father's out in Kansas.
- I don't even know where.
- I understand...
but there's nothing
I can do about it.
I spent 25 years in this hotel.
Started off as a clerk.
Now the bank gives the orders.
But you could call
and tell them...
my father has a job
but he's traveling, right?
They simply don't care
what I have to say about this.
I don't have any power.
They wanna get rid
of everyone on the third floor...
and just rent rooms
to the dancehall girls.
That's where the money is.
All they care about is the money
I would suggest that you...
contact your nearest relative
and see if they can't help.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Hey, Mom?
Mom?
Um, is Mrs. Kurlander up there?
Aaron?
Hi.
I can't believe it's you.
I'm so glad to see you.
I miss you.
So? How are you?
Have you heard anything from Dad?
He sent me a postcard
from Oklahoma.
He said the car broke down.
- Why? Is everything all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, everything's fine.
I was just wondering where he was.
When do you think you'll be coming home?
The doctor said the spot is closing
much sooner than he expected.
When are they gonna let you out?
I don't know exactly, but soon.
Hey, Mr. Sandoz!
Mr. Sandoz!
It's me... Aaron!
I really think
there's a misconception
that he's totally in
love with himself...
because after all, he did have
a girlfriend... named Echo.
- Echo.
Who is it?
It's me... Aaron.
- Ah, Aaron.
- Hi.
- I was just wondering...
- Come in, come in.
You remember Lydia, don't you?
- Yeah.
- Why don't you put something on?
I have something on.
He doesn't mind. Do you?
See? He likes it.
- What?
- Woodbine.
Oh, come on in.
Over here.
Where's the corn?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
We're out of corn today.
Jesus Christ!
Cash or credit? Ha!
No, I'll sign for her.
Perhaps you could spare one or
two bites to young Aaron here.
Oh, no.
Really, I couldn't.
When young Aaron works for his meal
the way I did, he can have some.
- That wouldn't be feasible, would it?
- With you, who knows?
Uh...
the reason I came is I was wondering if
you'd like to buy my cigar-band collection.
Your cigar-band collection?
You were the only one
who seemed interested.
I see, but why this sudden desire
to sell off this prize possession?
Well, I'm kind of low
on money, so...
- Join the club.
- They're trying to lock me out.
Who?
The bank that runs the hotel.
I thought Mr. Desot ran the hotel.
Well, Mr. Desot told me
if I didn't pay some money...
the bank was gonna lock me out.
I'll tell you what:
Come around tomorrow afternoon...
and we'll have a word
with Mr. Desot.
Really?
- You mean it?
- I mean it.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, right.
- Thanks a lot.
- You're welcome.
Good. All right.
We'll see you tomorrow, then.
- Bye.
- Good-bye.
What?
"Dear Nathan,
something important has come up...
that I must tell you about.
It seems that some time ago,
the children in Sullivan's class...
were exposed to a new disease
called "kidney box fever."
The symptoms
don't show up for a few months...
and the disease can be cured quite
easily with a blood transfusion...
from a relative,
especially a brother.
Therefore, I think it's best
if you send Sullivan home...
right away,
while there's still hope.
Best regards, Eric."
Lester?
Mrs....
You goin' out?
Yeah. For a minute.
Move, move.
Get the door.
Hey! Lester!
Come on, get in!
I got him, just like I said,
the little Yid.
And you better watch yourself.
We're cleaning up
all the dirt around here.
I got something of his
I oughta give him.
- I said get in!
- Why can't I give it to him?
- It's his. I oughta give it back.
- Go ahead.
- Make it snappy.
- Here.
Here's your knife, eh?
Thanks a lot.
- Get in!
- Come on.
Let's go.
Hey!
Come back and pick up them tools,
and we'll call it even.
Let's go! I know you're in there.
It's not fair!
It hasn't been three days yet.
So what's a day or two
to a deadbeat?
- I'm gonna tell Mr. Desot.
- How you gonna do that?
Homing pigeon?
- Mr. Mungo's gonna talk to him.
- Mr. Mungo?
He can't even get the Woodbine
to bring him food no more.
I'd say he's almost
as bad off as you are.
You're gonna have to come
out of there eventually.
Me, I'll just be
out there in my chair...
eating three meals a day
till you do...
unless you wanna
surrender right now.
No!
I'll be seeing you.
Hello?
Mr. Mungo?
This is KMOX, the voice of...
Thank you.
And now, ready to go again,
Pepper Martin...
How's it goin' in there?
"Hello, Billy." "Hello, Aaron."
"How are you?"
"I'm fine."
"What did you have
for lunch today?"
"I had filet of sole."
"Oh."
"What did you have?"
"I had a dinner roll...
and some water."
No.
Yeah, ham.
Mmm!
Bastard.
Bastard! Son of a...
Son of a bitch!
Shit! Son of a bitch!
Uncle Nathan sent me
when he got Dad's letter.
- He killed himself?
- Mm-hmm.
Right across the hall.
Gee.
And the McShanes
moved to Illinois...
and Mr. Sandoz
is living in a Hooverville.
So you're the only person left?
Pretty much.
I have to tell you something.
What?
Okay. Wait.
Move your hand out a little.
Now try it.
That's pretty good.
You kept your hand on the ground.
But you gotta get
your knuckles down like that.
You really gotta twist your arm.
That was fast, but...
Shh.
Aaron! Why do you...
Wh... Why do y...
Sullivan?
Dad!
Sullivan, what are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
- Uncle Nathan said...
- That's sort of a long story.
Oh, never mind. Tell me later.
It's so good to see you both.
I knew you could take care of yourselves.
You know why I came home?
Because I've got the WPA job.
- I'm a clerk, first-class.
- Great!
Wow!
You know what's great?
It's the salary.
Sixty-five dollars a month.
- Sixty-five dollars!
- Yeah!
Didn't I tell you not to worry?
But hey!
Let's not sit around.
Let's get your mother...
and see Donald Miller
at the Carleton Court Apartments.
- How about that?
- What about all our stuff?
We buy new stuff.
After all, $65 a month.
No!
I'm not leaving
my stuff here for Ben.
But I've got it all arranged.
Your mom is waiting.
Donald Miller is waiting.
We could move...
into the new apartment right away,
Aaron, the only way
you could take your things...
is if I pay the bill,
and I'm not going to pay...
the bill, okay?
Why is it so important to you?
It just is. We'll meet you
at the Carleton Court.
"We"?
Sullivan, you're coming with me.
I'm staying with Aaron.
Well, I'm going.
You'll never get
your things past Ben.
Never.
What are we gonna do?
Back up!
I'm gonna drop it.
I'll get the suitcases.
You take the other stuff.
Okay.
Who're you looking
for there, slick?
None of your business.
Dressed awful warm, ain't ya?
A friend of mine once said...
you could teach a dog
to walk on its hind legs...
but it's still a dog.
What did I tell ya last time?
Now gimme that apple!
Or I'll put your little
chicken ass under the jail!
- Gimme that apple!
- Hey, big butt!
Better watch your step,
you big bohunk.
You don't know what kind of trouble
you're in, you little...
Get out of here!
You little bastard!
Get out of here! You...
You son of a bitch! You!
I can let you boys stay in here
until your parents show up.
Then I'll give the keys
to your father.
Oh, thanks.
- What are these?
- They're paints.
- We're gonna deliver them to Mr. Sandoz.
- I get it.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Yes, I can hear you.
Wow!
- Aaron? Sullivan?
- Hello!
They're here!
- Mom!
Oh!
Hello! Hi!
I think you're taller.
He's grown a bit.
- I think you're taller.
- Yeah.
Mom...
there's a lot of stuff in here.
Don't you want to say
hello to your mother?