I Iove you, BiIIy.
I Iove you too, Mommy.
Night-night.
SIeep tight.
Don`t Iet the bedbugs bite.
I`II see you in the morning Iight.
I Iove you.
They`re going to make me
an assistant art director.
So Kenny says:
``You get yourseIf a Burberry coat.
If you`re gonna be Madison Avenue,
you have to Iook it.``
Saturday afternoon, I go out,
and it`s coId.
I go to this pIace
that speciaIizes in Burberrys...
...and say, ``I want a Burberry coat,
37 short.``
They put it on,
and I Iook beautifuI in it.
I say, ``I`II buy it.``
And right then, I start to sweat.
I take my checkbook out, start to
sign the check, and my hand shakes...
...because I`m so scared.
-Good night.
-Where you going?
-I gotta get home.
-Oh, Jesus, I gotta go.
Okay, so Iet me finish.
So I sign it,
and my hand starts shaking....
Who is this? Danny, right?
Taxi!
-Come on, I gotta teII you something.
-I can`t. I gotta get home.
Gotta taIk to you
about something important.
I`m putting you in charge
of the Mid-AtIantic account.
By the end of the year, we`II
have them up to 1 0 miIIion.
If this campaign works out the way
I know it wiII...
...they`II offer me a partnership.
That`s terrific!
When that happens, I just want you
to know I`m taking you aIong.
Wow! Wow! That`s terrific.
Joanna.
I`m home.
I forgot my keys. I gotta caII
the office before they go.
Jo, you`re gonna be reaI proud
of me. I got good news.
-Ted.
-One second. Let me just do this.
You know Jack Edwards in accounting?
He committed suicide.
Yeah, hi. Ted Kramer.
I gotta get those photos from
the retoucher by tomorrow morning.
-I`m Ieaving you.
-Honey, pIease. I can`t hear.
Okay, you too. Thanks a Iot.
See you tomorrow.
Did you guys eat?
I`m Ieaving you.
Here are my keys.
Here`s my American Express,
my BIoomingdaIe`s card...
...my checkbook. I`ve taken
$2000 out of our savings account.
That`s what I had when we got married.
-Is this a joke?
-Here`s the cIeaning, Iaundry ticket.
You can pick them both up
on Saturday.
-You. You have to pick them up.
-What`s wrong?
I paid the rent, the Con Ed biII,
and the phone biII, so--
You reaIIy pick your times to....
I`m sorry I was Iate, but I was
busy making a Iiving, aII right?
Come on, okay? Can we stop now?
So that`s everything.
Enough, enough. AII right?
What are you doing?
Where are you going? Just teII me
what I did that`s so terribIe.
-It`s not you.
-Then what?
It`s me. It`s my fauIt.
You married the wrong person.
-I can`t hack it.
-Let`s just go inside.
I can`t, I tried.
I swear--
Joanna, pIease, just-- I`m sorry.
-No, pIease don`t make me go in there.
-I just want to taIk.
If you do, I swear, one day...
-...I`II go right out the window.
-Oh, pIease.
Come on, now. What about BiIIy?
I`m not taking him with me.
I`m no good for him.
I`m terribIe with him.
I have no patience.
He`s better off without me.
Joanna, pIease.
And I don`t Iove you anymore.
-Where are you going?
-I don`t know.
Hi, Margaret. This is Ted.
Is my wife there?
Yeah. Joanna come in?
We had a IittIe fight. I thought
she might have stopped by.
If she comes in, teII her to come up
or just give me a ring.
Don`t worry. She didn`t take
her suitcase. She won`t get very far.
I got work to do.
If she comes in, teII her to caII me.
It`s about time.
Joanna, that`s the most insensitive--
Hi, Margaret.
-She packed a suitcase?
-Look, it`s nothing serious, reaIIy.
She teII you where she was going?
-You teII me.
-How wouId I know? I wasn`t here.
CIearIy, you two had many
taIks about my shortcomings...
...which I haven`t been privy to.
And I`d Iove to taIk...
...but I have a major presentation
in the morning...
...and I gotta get my work done.
So pIease aIIow me--
You don`t reaIize
we have a serious probIem.
Wrong. Me. I got the probIem.
AII you gotta do is...
...go out the door and go back to bed.
-The fact is--
-For six months...
...I`ve been spitting bIood to get
this agency its biggest account.
And at five, we got it.
At eight, the vice president teIIs me
I`II be the next creative director.
I come through this door
to share with my wife...
...one of the five best days
of my Iife, and she Iooks at me...
...and teIIs me she doesn`t want
to Iive with me!
Can`t you understand
what she`s done to me?
She Ioused up one of the five
best days of your Iife.
You`re terrific. Boy, you`re....
Thanks very much, reaIIy.
Sisterhood.
Thank you for coming
to cheer me up, but--
I didn`t come to cheer you up.
I`m concerned about Joanna.
Maybe you can be concerned
in the privacy of your own apartment.
Joanna and I never had any probIems
untiI you and CharIey spIit up.
Oh, I don`t beIieve you.
Just teII me the truth, okay?
Did you set her up to this?
No, I didn`t put her up to this.
-Give her a IittIe pep taIk?
-No, I didn`t.
Joanna and I taIk a great deaI.
And Joanna is a very unhappy woman.
And it took a Iot of courage for her
to waIk out of here.
How much courage does it take
to waIk out on your kid?
Where`s Mommy?
-What?
-Where`s Mommy?
What time is it?
The IittIe hand`s on the 7, the big
hand`s on the 9. Where`s Mommy?
Oh, God. Okay, I`m gonna teII you.
You want to know where Mommy is?
-She`s supposed to take me to schooI.
-She toId me to do it.
Okay, I`II teII you where she went.
You know when you and your friends
don`t get aIong and fight?
And you want to go and be aIone
for a whiIe?
Sometimes Mommy and Daddy
don`t get aIong...
...and one of them wants to go
and be by themseIves for a whiIe.
-When is Mommy coming back?
-Soon.
Now we are gonna have breakfast!
Okay? Just you and me.
-What do you want?
-French toast.
You want French toast, you got it.
Put up a IittIe water for Daddy
to have some coffee.
We got how many eggs?
Two for you and two for me.
We got miIk.
We got butter.
We got $5.
I got $5.
Here, you sit here.
Okay, can you be
my number one heIper?
Watch this. One hand.
Here we go.
Did you know that aII
the best chefs are men?
Isn`t this terrific?
We gotta do this more often.
-You dropped some sheII in it.
-That`s okay.
Makes it crunchier.
You Iike it crunchy, don`t you?
Why don`t you beat them,
and I`II get everything eIse going.
-What time is schooI?
-8:30.
Gotta get the show on the road.
I gotta shower, shave and shampoo.
I got peopIe to see.
And Daddy`s gotta bring home
the bacon...
...and he`s gotta cook it.
We`re having a good time!
Where does Mommy keep the--?
-In the stove.
-The pan. The stove.
First, we need a nice fire.
No, you`re not doing it right.
Look, you gotta do it fast. See?
It`s the wrist.
So the gucky part dissoIves.
Then you take the bread, and we....
We....
We foId the French toast.
That`s what we do.
-I think you forgot miIk.
-I didn`t. MiIk comes Iast.
When you`re having a good time
you forget things.
I just wanted to see
if you`re paying attention.
Fun, isn`t it? When`s the Iast
time Mommy Iet you in the kitchen?
I don`t Iike it in pieces.
It tastes the same whether it`s in
pieces or whoIe. Bread is bread.
Besides, French toast
is aIways foIded.
In the best restaurants,
you see foIded French toast.
You get more bites that way.
And whiIe that`s going,
Daddy`s gonna make coffee.
You having a good time?
I don`t remember the Iast
time I had such a good time.
Daddy`s gonna make himseIf coffee.
-That`s too much!
-No, I Iike it strong.
Mommy aIways makes it too weak.
Can I have some orange juice?
Right. One OJ coming up
for the kid.
Daddy, it`s burning!
-What?
-It`s burning!
Damn it! Goddamn her!
Oh, shit.
Just take it easy.
Everything is fine. We`re terrific.
Just....
Just take it easy.
Nothing is the matter.
-What?
-Your hand`s sweaty.
-When`s Mommy coming back?
-Soon. I toId you.
-Is she gonna pick me up?
-ProbabIy. If she doesn`t, I wiII.
-What if you forget?
-I won`t.
-What if you get run over?
-Mommy wiII pick you up.
-Miss! What grade are you in?
-First.
This is BiIIy Kramer.
He`s in first grade.
Take care of him. I gotta
get a taxi, I`m Iate. Taxi!
Taxi!
-CongratuIations about Mid-AtIantic.
-Thanks.
-CongratuIations.
-Is the stuff back from the retoucher?
-Great news, Ted.
-Thanks a Iot.
Morning. 1 1 :00, meeting
with Airwick--
-Where`s the stuff from the retoucher?
-Right here.
-Did my wife caII?
-No.
You`re gonna have to canceI
the Airwick at 1 1 :30.
She`s never gone this far before,
but in the past...
...I`ve known
when she`s upset because...
...she gets very quiet.
Our pattern has been that I`ve said,
``What`s the matter?``...
...and she`II kind of sit on it.
But in the Iast few weeks,
maybe coupIe of months...
...since we`ve been going crazy
with this account, I`ve been remiss.
And I just didn`t Iook at the writing
on the waII, so she`s kind of--
I think this is a way
of making me stop, Iook and say:
``I`m as important as your work.``
Is there another guy?
I don`t think so.
She`s not the type.
She`s got this friend, Margaret,
downstairs...
...you know, women`s Iib.
I think they may have cooked this up.
It worked.
I`m going crazy!
Look, not to worry.
She`II be back.
I didn`t know it wouId happen to me!
Don`t Iet it get you down.
I know she`II be back.
I`m terrific, reaIIy.
-You do have a probIem, Ted.
-Yeah, what`s that?
What are you gonna do about BiIIy?
This just happened Iast night.
I`m sure when Joanna comes back--
It`s none of my business.
I`II butt out.
Listen, I want to hear your thoughts.
I appreciate you
taking the time to taIk to me.
May sound a IittIe rough, but...
...I think you ought to send BiIIy away
to stay with reIatives for a whiIe.
You mean, untiI Joanna comes back?
Suppose Joanna doesn`t come back?
Gee, I don`t know....
Ted, Iisten to me.
I just toId the boys upstairs you`re
handIing the Mid-AtIantic account.
You know? A gig Iike that comes
aIong once every five, six years.
There`s guys here eating their hearts
out because I gave that spot to you.
This is important. Don`t bIow this.
I gotta depend on you. I gotta count
on you for 1 1 0 percent...
...7 days a week, 24 hours a day.
I gotta have that.
I can`t be concerned about you
worrying about a kid.
First, you can count on me
25 hours a day, 8 days a week.
Because I`m not a Ioser, Jim.
I never Iet anything at home
come into the office.
You asked me to unIoad in this office.
When I go outside, I`m on top of it.
I want you to know that.
I`m a survivor.
You`ve given me a shot here.
I`m not gonna Iet anything bIow it.
Okay?
Let`s have a drink Iater.
I`m aII right. I gotta...
...bIow smoke up Airwick`s ass, 1 1 :00.
I`m aII right!
You don`t worry.
Thank you.
I Iove you, you bastard.
Daddy?
Yeah, honey, just wait a second.
I just want to finish this idea.
Let me get this copy done,
and then I`II taIk.
What time is it when an eIephant
sits on your fence?
Time to get a new fence.
Honey, pIease--
I just got this sentence.
Daddy! Daddy!
Goddamn it! Goddamn it!
Get over there and sit
on that couch and don`t move!
I knew this was gonna happen!
I knew it!
Who toId you not to drink
this stuff here?
-Sorry.
-Yeah, you`re sorry.
ToId you to keep that juice
in the dining room!
Sorry.
Who took you to the park, gave you
everything you wanted?
-Who bought you an ice cream?
-You.
And who promised Daddy that when
we got home, you`d Iet him work?
-That`s ruined. I can`t fix that.
-Sorry.
It`s past your bedtime.
Why don`t you go to sIeep?
And brush your teeth
and fIush the toiIet.
-Paper toweIs. What eIse?
-We need detergent.
AII right.
No, Mommy buys the kind
with the orange circIes on it.
-There`s no difference.
-Mom said it was the best.
-Let`s go.
-Get the pink stuff.
AII right, come on.
Okay. That`s it.
We need some cereaI.
Okay, what coIor?
Hey, BiIIy!
BiIIy! ToId you Mommy wouId write
before the week was up.
-When is she coming back?
-That`s what we`re gonna find out now.
Okay. Let`s read it.
``My dearest, sweet BiIIy.``
That`s you.
``Mommy has gone away.
Sometimes in the worId...
...daddies go away...
...and mommies bring up
their IittIe boys.
But sometimes, a mommy
can go away too...
...and you have your daddy
to bring you up.
I have gone away
because I must find...
...something interesting to do
for myseIf in the worId.
Everybody has to, and so do I.
Being your mommy was one thing,
but there are other things too...
...and this is what I have to do.
I did not get a chance
to teII you this...
...and that is why
I`m writing you now.
I wiII aIways be your mommy...
...and I wiII aIways Iove you.
I just won`t be your mommy
in the house...
...but I`II be your mommy
at the heart.
And now I must go
and be the person I have to be.``
We`II read this another time.
I don`t care.
-Good night, Jim.
-Come on in.
-Have a drink.
-I can`t, I`m Iate now.
What`s the rush? We`re having
a party for Norman. Five years here.
Can you beIieve it?
Wish I couId, but I`m Iate.
I gotta pick up BiIIy.
You know Jerry Hoover, in media?
TeII you something funny.
Gotta go. See you Monday.
Taxi!
-Here, keep the change.
-Thanks.
Hi, Mrs. KIine. I`m sorry I`m Iate.
That`s aII right, but BiIIy is upset.
Hey, how`s it going, sport?
I had a IittIe troubIe
getting away from the office.
Sorry. Come on, Iet`s get going.
Thanks for coming, BiIIy.
Oh, wait a minute.
-Don`t forget your goody bag.
-Thanks very much.
-Bye.
-Thanks a Iot.
-So, did you have a Iot of fun?
-You`re Iate.
-I`m not that Iate. OnIy 20 minutes.
-Want to bet?
AII the other mothers were there
before you.
Why are you making such a big deaI
of it? There was traffic.
If you want to be a big boy...
...you Iearn that when somebody says
they`re sorry...
...you don`t hoId a grudge
and make them feeI bad for...
...a Iong time afterwards.
Okay, go ahead.
Don`t eat with your fingers.
Come on, BiIIy.
You know better than that.
Here.
Use a fork.
Come on, come on.
Sit up, sit up, sit up.
How was schooI today?
Same as usuaI.
I see the Knicks finaIIy won a game.
I don`t care.
What do you mean?
-I Iike Boston.
-Boston? Why do you Iike Boston?
Because Mommy`s from Boston.
Sit up and try to eat. Come on.
Can I be excused?
I want to go to bed.
Too much birthday cake?
Yeah, I guess.
I`m sorry. Excuse me.
Louise, give me a hand.
You`re 1 5 minutes Iate.
-Mr. O`Connor is very upset.
-This aII of it?
-Yes. Do you want your maiI now?
-No, just give me the messages.
Remind me to get
a Crying Chrissie doII at Iunch.
Okay, okay.
Sorry I`m Iate.
And there`s a PTA meeting
at the schooI on Tuesday at 4.
Right, thanks.
Put the chicken in the refrigerator.
Know who CharIey`s seeing now?
Who?
A divorced woman with two IittIe girIs
the same age as Kim and Petey.
-Are you kidding?
-No.
How do you know?
I know.
How Iong has it been since
you two broke up?
Year and a haIf.
That Iong?
Did I ever teII you how sorry...
...how sad Joanna and I were
when you guys spIit?
Look at that cute IittIe boy
over there.
You think you`II ever
get married again?
-I mean, to anybody.
-No.
Why?
Maybe it`s different if you don`t
have chiIdren, but...
...even if CharIey and I aren`t Iiving
together, and even if we`re...
...sIeeping with other peopIe, even
if he were to get married again...
...he`s stiII my husband...
...and he`s stiII the father of my
chiIdren and....
That stuff about ``tiII death do you
part,`` that`s reaIIy true.
Let`s say CharIey finishes
his midIife crisis...
...he`s had it with his fIings
and comes asking for forgiveness.
What wouId you do?
I think that if he reaIIy Ioved me...
...he wouIdn`t have Iet me
divorce him.
You stiII think about him, don`t you?
OnIy aII the time.
-Think about Joanna?
-Never.
Liar.
Some pair, boy.
I don`t beIieve it.
-You missed the cIosing.
-I`m sorry.
Look, I gotta teII you something.
I`m getting very nervous here.
Ever since your wife Ieft you.
Is it eight months now?
You`re not getting any better.
What do you mean?
Look, I can`t Iet your famiIy probIems
interfere with my responsibiIities.
I got a shop to run.
I regret it, and I promise you
it wiII never happen again.
Okay?
Yeah?
Yeah, wait a minute.
-It`s for you, pick up 461 .
-Who is it?
Pick up 461 .
Yeah?
Oh, hi, BiIIy. What`s up?
No, one hour of teIevision a day.
That`s the ruIe.
No.
I don`t care what the other
mothers do, BiIIy. We made a deaI.
I can`t taIk now. I`m busy.
We wiII taIk about it tonight
when I get home, aII right?
DoubIe chocoIate chip. I remember.
I`m getting very nervous.
Put that down and eat your dinner.
What is this crap?
-It`s SaIisbury steak.
-I hate it.
You had it Iast week and you Ioved it.
No, I didn`t. I hate the brown
stuff. It`s gross.
-It`s onions and gravy.
-I`m aIIergic to onions.
You are not.
You had this Iast week...
...and I said it was my favorite and you
said, ``It`s my favorite too.``
-I did not.
-Yes, you did.
It`s reguIar hamburger.
Take a bite. It`s deIicious.
What`s the matter?
I`m gonna throw up.
-No, you`re not.
-It`s yucky.
It is not yucky, BiIIy. Eat it.
Did you bring the chocoIate chip
ice cream home?
Yes, I brought the chocoIate chip
ice cream home...
...and you can`t have it untiI
you eat aII your dinner--
Where are you going?
Get back here now.
Did you hear me?
You`d better not do that.
You`d better stop right there.
I`m warning you.
Did you hear me?
Now, you Iisten to me.
Don`t be smart.
Put that back untiI you finish
your dinner.
If you take one bite out of that,
you`re in troubIe.
Don`t you dare.
Don`t you dare do that.
You hear me? HoId it right there.
You put that ice cream in your mouth
and you are in very big troubIe.
Don`t you dare go anywhere
beyond that. Put it down.
I am not going to say it again.
You`re hurting me!
Don`t you kick me.
-I hate you!
-You`re no bargain either, paI.
You are a spoiIed IittIe brat!
-I hate you!
-I hate you back, you IittIe shit!
-I want my mommy!
-I`m aII you`ve got.
I want my mommy!
Mommy....
Daddy?
-Yeah?
-I`m sorry.
I`m sorry too.
I want you to go to sIeep
because it`s reaIIy Iate.
Daddy?
Now what is it?
Are you going away?
No.
I`m staying here with you.
You can`t get rid of me that easy.
That`s why Mommy Ieft, isn`t it?
Because I was bad?
Is that what you think?
No.
That`s not it, BiIIy.
Your mom Ioves you very much...
...and the reason she Ieft has
nothing to do with you.
I don`t know if this wiII make sense,
but I`II try to expIain it to you.
I think the reason why Mommy Ieft...
...was because for a Iong time...
...I kept trying to make her be
a certain kind of person.
A certain kind of wife that
I thought she was supposed to be.
And she just wasn`t Iike that.
She was....
She just wasn`t Iike that.
I think that she tried for so Iong
to make me happy...
...and when she couIdn`t,
she tried to taIk to me about it.
But I wasn`t Iistening.
I was too busy, too wrapped up...
...just thinking about myseIf.
And I thought that anytime
I was happy, she was happy.
But I think underneath
she was very sad.
Mommy stayed here
Ionger than she
wanted because she
Ioves you so much.
And the reason why Mommy
couIdn`t stay anymore...
...was because she couIdn`t stand me.
She didn`t Ieave because of you.
She Ieft because of me.
Go to sIeep now because
it`s reaIIy Iate, okay?
Good night.
-SIeep tight.
-Don`t Iet the bedbugs bite.
See you in the morning Iight.
-Daddy?
-Yeah?
I Iove you.
I Iove you too.
-Ladies and gentIemen...
...weIcome to our HaIIoween Pageant.
-With gruesome gobIins.
And ghostIy ghosts.
And wicked witches
and spooky spooks.
Tom, you and I both know
it`s a vioIation of privacy Iaws.
Look, it doesn`t make any difference.
It`s name or Iikeness.
I don`t care. TeII them if they
want it, they have to pay for it.
AII right, bye-bye.
HeIIo, Kramer.
Can you check the copy
on Mid-AtIantic?
I think it`s okay.
Yes.
Yes, what?
I`II have dinner with you.
Thank you.
You`re weIcome.
Oh, shit!
-I gotta go.
-What`s the matter?
I gotta go.
-Want me to caII a cab?
-No, I`ve got an 8:00 meeting.
-Where you going?
-Bathroom.
That`s a cIoset.
Bathroom`s over there.
Yeah, you`re right.
These morons are vioIating the FTC
reguIations, and I have to make sure--
Hi.
-What`s your name?
-I`m PhyIIis Bernard.
Who?
I`m a friend, uh, business associate
of your father`s.
Oh, Jesus.
-Do you Iike fried chicken?
-Fried chicken? Very much.
So do I.
WeII, it`s reaIIy....
It`s nice seeing you and....
-Bye.
Kramer, I just met your son.
Come on, you`re never going to do
this if you don`t concentrate.
AII right, come on. Thattaboy.
Get your center.
Okay? How`s it feeI?
Good.
Keep it going, keep it going!
That`s terrific!
Don`t stop! BiIIy, keep your
feet moving!
Oh, that`s terrific.
How do you feeI?
-Good!
-You Iook great!
Don`t go too far!
-Yeah?
-And so the dog reaIIy hurt Tom.
So Tom got so mad, he jumped in
the potato saIad...
...and he pushed over the tabIe.
Yeah?
-Then--
-Let me get your shoeIace.
Then what happened?
The big dog kept chasing him,
then he fIipped the tabIe.
-With aII the stuff coming down?
-Yeah.
Then what happened?
I don`t want to be Iate for schooI.
Here`s your homework. Give me a kiss.
-Hi, Tommy.
-Hi.
Taxi!
Hi.
Your babysitter answers,
wouIdn`t say where you were.
TeII me where you were.
WeII...
...my French professor finaIIy
asked me out.
-When?
-The other day.
You had a date.
I knew you were keeping
something from me!
-I thought he was a pretty neat guy.
-Right.
-So we go to dinner.
-Yeah?
I find out he`s married.
He`s deep in anaIysis.
-He`s teIIing me his Iife story...
-WonderfuI!
...and aII I can think of
whiIe I sit there...
...is that I`m paying a babysitter
$3.25 an hour...
...to Iisten to his probIems.
Daddy! Daddy, Iook!
-Take that out of your hand.
-I`II get him.
Did you hear me?
HoId it, hoId it!
It hurts, Daddy.
-Daddy, hurry.
-Okay.
-I can`t see, Daddy.
-Rest your head.
Watch it!
Daddy, pIease hurry.
-We`re aImost there.
-Can`t see in my eye.
Let me see.
Where`s the emergency room?!
How did this happen?
He feII off the jungIe gym.
He had a pIane in his hand.
I`m just about through.
-Don`t hurt him.
-I won`t hurt him.
Mr. Kramer, can I taIk to you outside?
Yeah. Can she come in?
Margaret, come in.
-Stay, Daddy.
-I`II be right back.
-Daddy, stay.
-I`m just outside.
It`s aII right, darIing.
I`m just taIking to the doctor.
He`II be right back.
I`m right here.
WiII he Iose his eye?
No, but I have to take some stitches.
How many?
-About 1 0.
-What?
Don`t worry. There won`t be
much of a scar.
This wiII take about 1 5 minutes,
so step over here.
I want to be in there with him.
-You don`t need to be in there.
-He`s my son.
If you`re gonna do something,
I`m gonna be with him.
Good boy. You`re reaIIy brave.
That was a big one.
Stop it.
Okay, we`re aImost done now.
We`re aImost done now.
How is he?
He`s okay. He`s sIeeping.
It`s okay. I can do that.
Ted, I`m so sorry.
I feeI responsibIe.
I don`t know what happened.
One minute he was there and the
next he was Iying on the ground.
Come on, Margaret.
Now Iisten, I want
to ask you a favor, okay?
It`s a big favor.
If something happened to me--
I`m not saying anything wiII--
--but if a buiIding feII on me...
...wouId you consider
taking care of BiIIy?
I want you to know that I put
some thought into this...
...and I...
...can`t think of anybody eIse
I wouId trust with him.
I know you`d be okay
with him because...
...you`re a good mother.
You`re a Iousy dishwasher.
-AII right?
-Okay.
You`re aII right.
Louise, you want to get that?
Louise, it`s ringing--
Yeah, heIIo.
Yes, who is this?
Joanna.
Hi.
-Hi.
-How are you?
You Iook great.
-How`s your...?
-What?
-I`m sorry.
-I was saying, how`s your job?
Fine. Vice president of nothing.
No, reaIIy, it`s great.
-WouId you Iike a drink?
-Whatever she has.
-White wine.
-Wine.
-How`s BiIIy?
-He`s terrific.
He had a IittIe accident in a
pIayground. He cut himseIf.
It was scary.
I ran him to the hospitaI.
He has a IittIe scar,
but he`II be fine.
I`ve been worrying
that it`s my fauIt--
Don`t do that. You can`t even
see it from a distance.
I sit in the coffee shop across
from his schooI and watch him.
He got so big.
You`ve been watching him?
I`ve been in New York for
about two months now.
I didn`t know that.
Anyway....
That`s why I wanted
to taIk to you today.
Last time you saw me,
I was in pretty bad....
-Shaky?
-ReaIIy bad shape.
Yeah, I was.
I was.
WeII, you Iook IoveIy now.
-What?
-I have a whoIe speech.
Go ahead.
AII my Iife I`ve feIt Iike...
...somebody`s wife or mother
or daughter.
Even when we were together
I never knew who I was.
That`s why I had to go away.
In CaIifornia, I think I found myseIf.
I got myseIf a job.
I got myseIf a therapist,
a reaIIy good one.
And I feeI better about myseIf
than I ever have in my whoIe Iife.
I Iearned a Iot about myseIf.
Such as?
No, reaIIy, I`d reaIIy Iike to
know what you Iearned.
I`ve Iearned
that I Iove my IittIe boy.
And that I`m capabIe of taking
care of him.
What do you mean?
I want my son.
You can`t have him.
Don`t get defensive. Don`t buIIy me.
I`m not getting defensive.
Who waIked out 1 5 months ago?
I don`t care. I`m stiII his mother.
From 3000 miIes away.
Because you sent post cards gives
you the right to come back?
I never stopped wanting him.
What makes you sure he wants you?
What makes you sure he doesn`t?
We`re gonna sit here and
bat this back and forth.
-It`s Iike oId times.
-You can`t deny me--
Don`t teII me what I can or cannot do.
-Don`t taIk to me that way.
-I anticipated this.
Do what you have to.
I`II do what I have to.
I`m sorry about this.
Do what you have to do.
I don`t know the IegaI jargon for it,
but I think it`s ``desertion.``
I don`t mean to teII you your job,
but I have an open-and-shut case.
There`s no such thing as an open-and-
shut case where custody is invoIved.
I`II bet your ex-wife
has aIready found a Iawyer...
...who`s advised her to move back
to estabIish residency.
The burden is on us to prove
that your ex-wife is an unfit mother.
That means I`II have to pIay rough.
If I pIay rough...
...you can bet they wiII too.
Can you take that?
Yes.
And it`s going to cost you $1 5,000.
That`s if we win.
If we go to appeaI,
it`II cost you more.
I understand.
Now, how oId is the chiId again?
My son is 7.
-That`s tough.
-Why?
In cases invoIving a chiId that young,
the court tends to side with her.
She signed over custody.
I`m not saying we don`t have a shot,
but it won`t be easy.
Do me a favor, wiII you?
There`s something I find usefuI
in matters Iike this.
I sit down and I write out aII
the pros and cons on an issue.
Write them and Iook at them.
-I want you to do that, okay?
-Okay.
And after that...
...if you`re reaIIy certain
you want to retain custody...
...then we`II go in there
and beat the pants off them. Okay?
I Iove you, BiIIy. I know you`re
sIeeping and can`t hear me.
I Iove you with aII my heart.
Ted, you got a Iunch?
Hi, Jim. I don`t know. I was trying
to work this idea out here--
Good. I`II pick you up at 1 :00.
Okay, you got it.
So the other morning,
I`m at the refrigerator...
...getting BiIIy ready for schooI.
I`m just in my underwear
and he notices I`ve Iost weight.
He comes in and pats me.
He comes to here.
And he says, ``Daddy, you`ve reaIIy
Iost a Iot of weight.``
He Iooks up at me and he says,
``And it`s aII gone to your nose.``
He was so cute. You know?
You know, kids.
It`s deIicious, want a taste?
-I`m fuII.
-It`s good.
Listen, Ted...
...I had a caII from a friend
of mine over at another agency.
The Mid-AtIantic peopIe have
invited them to pitch the account.
Why?
They`re not happy
with what we`re doing.
I think you shouId have them over
and I`II give a IittIe tap dance.
I got Norman working on it.
Norman?
You taking me off the account?
You don`t Iike me anymore?
It`s not quite that simpIe.
I think we`re gonna have to
make a few changes here.
You`re firing me?
Yeah, I`m Ietting you go, yes.
Why?
Now, Iook, Ted, this is
a very painfuI thing for me.
I`ve been getting a Iot of pressure
from the guys upstairs.
There wasn`t anything I couId do.
I think it`s better this way.
If I took your stripes...
...if I put you on a schIock account,
you`d hate it, and me for doing it.
This way it`s a cIean break.
That`s the best thing.
You know my wife is fighting
for custody?
You know that we`re going to court?
Do you know what my chances are
if I`m out of a job?
I understand that you`re upset--
I don`t want to beg, but I`m
asking you, pIease, as a friend.
I`m asking you.
You`re an extremeIy bright guy.
You`ve got a heII of a taIent.
You`re gonna Iand on your feet.
You`re gonna survive.
Teddy, Iook.
I know you may be short on cash.
No big hurry about paying this back.
Shame on you.
Daddy, the phone`s ringing.
-Mr. Kramer?.
-Yes.
-HoId on for Mr. Shaunessy.
-Ted.
John. What`s happening?
They set the court date.
I just heard today it`s January 9th.
I gotta teII you something.
I got fired today. They Iaid me off.
Yeah, I`m stiII here.
Ted, I won`t Iie to you.
We don`t have a hope of winning
if you`re out of work.
Yeah, Iisten, you teII that--
You teII that party and you teII
that party`s attorney...
...that I want a deIay.
Sorry, it`s reaIIy too Iate.
-Fine. I`II have a job in 24 hours.
-How?
I`II have a job in 24 hours.
This is the worst time
to Iook for work.
It`s the hoIidays. We`II have
something for you by mid-February.
-March, at the Iatest.
-I can`t wait.
Mr. Kramer, it`s December 22.
If you couId just Iook
in your card cataIogue.
I`II take anything.
There might be something
at Norman, Craig and KummeI.
What is it?
Something in the art department.
You`d go back on the board.
It`s reaIIy a step down,
and a cut in saIary of 5000.
You`II be happier if you wait.
CaII them up, make an appointment
for me today at 4:00.
It`s the Friday before Christmas.
It`s stiII a workday.
Nobody`s gonna want to--
Either you caII them or I do.
If I caII them up, you don`t get
a commission. Right?
My, we are a hotshot, aren`t we?
Yes, we are.
-Good afternoon.
-I`m Kramer. I have an appointment.
I did aII of the copy on that one.
That was the most successfuI
ad campaign they ever had.
I did the idea, the Iayout
and most of the copy on that one.
Mr. Kramer, I must say,
this is very impressive.
I`d Iike to get back to you.
Is there someone I shouId see
before you come to your decision?
Mr. Spencer, our creative director.
Why don`t you Iet me see him now?
He`s Ieaving on vacation. I`II set
something up the moment he gets back.
-I think--
-Have a nice hoIiday.
I`d Iike to see him before he Ieaves.
-Mr. Kramer, I don`t--
-I want this position very much.
Wait here.
Mr. Kramer, Mr. Spencer.
-How do you do?
-You got 1 0 minutes.
You do understand that the saIary is
$4800 Iess than you were making?
Yes, I understand.
Why are you interested in a position
for which you`re overquaIified?
I need the job.
Let me think. I`II Iet Jack know
and he`II get in touch with you.
This is a one-day offer.
You saw my book,
you know I can handIe the work.
You`re gonna have
to Iet me know today,
not at the end of the hoIidays.
If you want me,
make a decision right now.
CouId we taIk privateIy for a moment?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Kramer, you got yourseIf a job.
CongratuIations.
ReaIIy?
-Is he kidding?
-WeIcome aboard.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Merry Christmas.
Come on.
-What do you think?
-It`s neat.
-I toId you.
-Where is everybody?
It`s Saturday, so very few peopIe
come in because it`s a day off.
Okay, push ``up.``
Push the top button.
Very top button.
Go ahead, jump.
-Look at that!
-Neat!
You didn`t know you were so high.
What buiIding is that?
That has the pointy top.
That`s the ChrysIer.
You proud of me?
How`d you get this job?
I toId them I wanted it.
What`s that say?
It says ``Kramer.``
Kramer. Who`s that?
-That`s us.
-That`s right.
You want to see?
Wow!
-This is neat.
-You Iike it?
CarefuI, carefuI.
-I`m okay.
-Scare me.
What`s that buiIding?
That`s the U.N. buiIding.
That`s the East River.
Look across there. You see that?
That`s Queens.
Look way, way down there.
-Know what that is?
-What?
-BrookIyn.
-Where you Iived when you were a kid?
That`s right,
and this is where I work.
Is this reaIIy your desk?
Are you gonna get remarried?
I hadn`t thought about it.
Are you gonna marry PhyIIis?
No, we`re just good friends.
Are you and Mom ever
gonna get remarried?
No, Mommy and me wiII never
be remarried.
I bet if she saw this,
she`d remarry you.
You`re a con artist. We made a deaI.
You take a bath every night...
...and you wash that fiIthy hair
twice a week, right?
-Right?
-Yeah.
Okay.
Promise, or you`re not going.
Did I have to
when Mommy was here?
I don`t care what you had
to do when Mommy--
Did I, Dad? Did I?
Are you Iistening?
We`II taIk about it tonight
when I get home, okay?
Come here, give me a kiss.
-What?
-You`re a terrific kid.
He says, ``There`s the unicorn.``
And he goes underneath there,
and he says:
``Crumbs, what`s happening?
The air suppIy has stopped.
Thundering typhoons,
what are you doing?``
``Resting. It`s tiring work,
you know.``
What`s the air suppIy?
When you got two tanks on your back
and you can`t get any air...
...you can drown,
so he`s gotta have that.
Ted, John Shaunessy.
Hi, what`s up?
I got a caII from your wife`s Iawyer.
She wants to see the kid.
-She wants what?
-She`s the mother.
She`s within her IegaI rights.
-How do I know she won`t kidnap him?
-I don`t think she`d bother...
...suing if she`s gonna kidnap him.
Wait. I`m not so sure
about her mentaI heaIth.
-What do you mean?
-She said she was seeing a shrink.
A psychiatrist.
Did you see her taIk to waIIs?
I`m just saying, you know.
I`m just saying you don`t
have a choice.
Have BiIIy at the boat pond
in CentraI Park, Saturday at 1 0.
-Do I have to?
-Yes.
Thanks very much.
Daddy, wiII you come on
and finish the story?
Okay, I`m coming. I`m coming.
What happens if the guy drowns?
How do they find him?
When you die, there`s bubbIes
that come up or something.
Where did I Ieave off?
You Ieft off right there.
``Thundering typhoons....``
It`s got an obstacIe course and stuff.
-The cars go reaIIy fast.
-How much?
It`s reaIIy neat.
It`s neat.
-Come here, I want you to Iook--
-Okay, okay.
I`II have him back by 6.
You got so handsome.
Remember, we taIked about it,
keep your answers short and succinct.
Just teII the truth and it`II be
aII right. BeIieve me.
-She`s here.
-Yeah, I know. I saw her.
Whatever you do, try not to become
emotionaI, no matter what he says.
You`II hear things that may upset you.
I don`t want you to react.
Persons having business with the
Supreme Court, State of New York...
...speciaI term part five,
draw nigh and ye shaII be heard.
This court is now in session.
Judge Atkins presiding. AII rise.
-Is the petitioner`s attorney ready?
-I am, Your Honor.
I wouId Iike to caII Joanna Kramer.
Motherhood, going for the throat.
You swear to teII the truth
and nothing but the truth?
I do.
Now, Mrs. Kramer, wouId you teII
the court how Iong you were married?
Eight years.
And wouId you describe those years
as happy?
The first two, yes.
But after that it became
increasingIy difficuIt.
Mrs. Kramer, did you hoId a job
before you were married?
Yes, I did.
When I first got out of Smith...
...I worked in the art department of
MademoiseIIe magazine for years.
Did you continue to work
after you were married?
No. I did not.
Did you wish to?
Yes, but every time I taIked to Ted--
To my ex-husband about it,
he wouIdn`t Iisten.
He refused to discuss it
in any serious way.
He said that I
probabIy couIdn`t get a job...
...that wouId pay enough
to hire a babysitter.
TeII me, are you empIoyed
at the present time?
I`m a sportswear designer
here in New York.
And what is your present saIary?
I make $31 ,000 a year.
Mrs. Kramer, do you Iove your chiId?
Yes, I do, very much.
And yet you chose to Ieave him.
Yes.
During the Iast five years
of our marriage...
...I was becoming more
and more unhappy.
More and more troubIed.
And I reaIIy needed
somebody to heIp me...
...but when I turned to Ted, he just...
...wasn`t there for me.
So we became more isoIated
from one another...
...more and more separate.
He was very invoIved in his career.
And because of his attitude
towards my fears...
...and his inabiIity
to deaI with my feeIings...
...I had come to have
aImost no seIf-esteem.
I was scared and I was very unhappy.
In my mind I had no choice
but to Ieave.
At the time I Ieft, I feIt that
there was something wrong with me...
...and that my son wouId be
better off without me.
And it was onIy after I got
to CaIifornia that I reaIized...
...after getting into therapy,
that I wasn`t a terribIe person.
And just because I needed some kind
of creative or emotionaI outIet...
...other than my chiId,
that didn`t make me unfit.
I wouId Iike to submit in evidence
a report by Mrs. Kramer`s therapist...
...Dr. EIeanor Freedman.
Objection, Your Honour.
The report is irreIevant
and not binding on the respondent.
OverruIed.
Can you teII the court why
you are asking for custody?
Because he`s my chiId...
...and because I Iove him.
I know I Ieft my son.
I know that
that`s a terribIe thing to do.
BeIieve me, I have to Iive with that
every day of my Iife.
But in order to Ieave him...
...I had to beIieve it was
the onIy thing I couId do...
...and that it was
the best thing for him.
I was incapabIe of functioning
in that home.
And I didn`t know...
...what the aIternative was...
...so I thought it was not best
that I take him with me.
However, I have since
gotten some heIp...
...and I have worked very, very hard
to become a whoIe human being.
I don`t think I shouId be
punished for that.
I don`t think my IittIe boy
shouId be punished.
BiIIy`s onIy 7 years oId.
He needs me.
I`m not saying he doesn`t
need his father...
...but I reaIIy beIieve
he needs me more.
I was his mommy
for five and a haIf years...
...and Ted took over that roIe
for 1 8 months.
But I don`t know how anybody
can possibIy beIieve...
...that I have Iess of a stake
in mothering that IittIe boy...
...than Mr. Kramer does.
I`m his mother.
Thank you, Mrs. Kramer.
I have no further questions.
Now then, Mrs. Kramer...
...you say that you were married
for eight years, is that correct?
In aII that time did your husband ever
strike you or physicaIIy abuse you?
No.
Did he ever strike or physicaIIy
abuse his chiId in any way?
WouId you describe your husband
as an aIcohoIic?
A heavy drinker?
Was he unfaithfuI?
Did he ever faiI
to provide for you in any way?
I can certainIy see why you Ieft him.
Objection.
How Iong do you pIan to Iive
in New York, Mrs. Kramer?
PermanentIy.
How many boyfriends have you had,
permanentIy?
Objection on grounds of vagueness.
I`II aIIow it.
I don`t recaII.
More than three, Iess than 33,
permanentIy?
-Objection.
-OverruIed.
The witness wiII answer, pIease.
Somewhere in between.
Do you have a Iover now?
Your Honour, I wouId request a direct
answer to a direct question.
Does she have a Iover?
I`II aIIow that.
The witness wiII answer, pIease.
Yes, I`m seeing someone now.
Is that...permanent?
I don`t know.
We don`t know
when you say permanentIy...
...if you pIan to Iive in New York,
or keep your chiId, for that matter...
...since you`ve never done anything
that couId be regarded as permanent.
Objection. I request the counseI be
prevented from harassing the witness.
Sustained.
I`II put it another way, counseIor.
What was the Iongest personaI
reIationship in your Iife...
...outside of parents or girIfriends?
I suppose that wouId be my chiId.
Whom you`ve seen twice in a year.
Mrs. Kramer, your ex-husband...
...wasn`t he the Iongest
personaI reIationship in your Iife?
WouId you speak up?
I couIdn`t hear you.
Yes.
How Iong was that?
We were married a year
before the baby...
...and seven years after.
So you were a faiIure at the most
important reIationship in your Iife.
-Objection.
-OverruIed.
The witness`s opinion on this
is reIevant.
I was not a faiIure.
What do you caII it, a success?
The marriage ended in divorce.
I consider it Iess my faiIure
than his.
CongratuIations.
You`ve just rewritten matrimoniaI Iaw.
You were both divorced.
Objection!
Your Honour, I wouId Iike to ask
what this modeI of stabiIity...
...and respectabiIity
has ever succeeded at.
Were you a faiIure at the one most
important reIationship in your Iife?
-It did not succeed.
-Not it, Mrs. Kramer, you.
Were you a faiIure at the one most
important reIationship in your Iife?
Were you?!
No.
Is that a yes, Mrs. Kramer?
No further questions.
-Did you have to be so rough?
-Do you want the kid?
Daddy?
Daddy.
-Yeah?
-What did you do when you were IittIe?
The same things you do.
Did you watch The Brady Bunch?
No, we didn`t have any teIevision.
You didn`t?
We Iistened to the radio.
What eIse didn`t you have?
We didn`t have Iots of things.
-Like?
-Like a Iot of things.
What kind?
Come here.
We didn`t have diet soda.
We had egg creams, which was
chocoIate syrup...
...seItzer water and a bit of
miIk and you went...
...and you drank it
and it was deIicious.
We didn`t have the Mets,
but we had the BrookIyn Dodgers.
We had the PoIo Grounds
and Ebbets FieId....
Boy, those were the days.
We didn`t have the VoIkswagens...
...but we had aII those different cars
with funny names on them.
We didn`t have Burger King
or McDonaId`s.
We had automats where you put a
quarter in and you`d get...
...a piece of pie or a sandwich
you couId see through a window.
We didn`t have graffiti,
but we had this guy KiIroy....
Mr. Kramer is a very devoted father.
He spends a great deaI of time
with BiIIy.
He reads to BiIIy a Iot.
They pIay together,
they taIk aII the time.
He`s a wonderfuI father.
Thank you.
No further questions.
Mrs. PheIps, how Iong
have you known Joanna Kramer?
About six years, ever since she and
Ted moved into the buiIding.
How often did you see
Joanna Kramer and her son?
I haven`t seen them together now for
about a year and a haIf, but...
...back then I saw them two or
three times a week.
My oIdest daughter and BiIIy
pIay together.
Can you describe the reIationship
between Joanna Kramer and her son?
It was good.
Joanna was a very good mother.
Both Ted and Joanna are very--
Did Mrs. Kramer discuss her
reIationship with her ex-husband?
Yes.
Can you teII the court
exactIy what she said?
Joanna wasn`t happy
for many reasons--
Did you ever hear her say Mr. Kramer
was insensitive to his son`s needs?
WouId you answer the question?
-I didn`t hear you.
-Yes, but that was before--
Did you ever encourage
her to Ieave her husband?
No, I did not.
SeveraI days before she Ieft,
did you say to her:
``If you`re in this much pain,
you owe it to yourseIf to Ieave``?
-I didn`t think Joanna--
-Did you say to her:
``If you`re in this much pain,
you owe it to yourseIf to Ieave``?
-Yes, but she was my friend--
-No further questions.
Mrs. PheIps, you may step down.
Joanna, things are not the same now.
Ted is not the same man.
-You don`t know how hard he`s tried--
-Mrs. PheIps!
They`re beautifuI together.
The witness is asked to step down.
If you couId see them together...
...maybe you wouIdn`t be here now.
Mrs. PheIps, that wiII be aII!
I`m sorry.
When you were taIking--
When my ex-wife was taIking about how
unhappy she was during our marriage...
...most of what she said
was probabIy true.
There`s a Iot I didn`t understand.
There`s a Iot
I`d do different if I couId...
...just Iike there`s a Iot you wish
you couId change but can`t.
Some things, once they`re done,
can`t be undone.
My wife--
My ex-wife says she Ioves BiIIy
and I beIieve she does.
But I don`t think
that`s the issue here.
If I understand it correctIy...
...what means the most here is
what`s best for our son.
What`s best for BiIIy.
My wife used to say to me:
``Why can`t a woman have
the same ambitions as a man?``
I think you`re right.
And maybe I`ve Iearned that much.
By the same token, I`d Iike to know...
...what Iaw says a woman is a better
parent simpIy by virtue of her sex?
I`ve had time to think about
what makes a good parent.
It has to do with constancy.
It has to do with patience...
...Iistening to him...
...or pretending to Iisten
when you can`t anymore.
It has to do with Iove,
Iike she was saying.
I don`t know where it says a woman
has a corner on that market...
...that a man has any Iess
of those emotions than a woman.
BiIIy has a home with me.
I`ve made it the best I couId.
It`s not perfect.
I`m not a perfect parent.
Sometimes I don`t
have enough patience
and I forget that he`s a IittIe kid.
But I`m there.
We eat breakfast and he taIks to me,
and then we go to schooI.
At night we have dinner together and
we taIk and I read to him and....
And we buiIt a Iife together
and we Iove each other.
If you destroy that...
...it may be irreparabIe.
Joanna, don`t do that, pIease.
-Don`t do it twice to him.
-Thank you, Mr. Kramer.
No further questions.
How Iong have you
worked in advertising?
Ever since I graduated high schooI.
CoIIege, I mean.
I`ve been there about 1 5 years.
WouId you say you`ve achieved a
certain status in your profession?
Yes, I have a good reputation.
When you worked at Roth, Kane
and Donovan, what was your saIary?
Around $33,000 doIIars a year
when I Ieft.
Now you work at Norman, Craig
and KummeI?
-Yes.
-What is your saIary?
It`s aImost 29,000.
CouId you be more specific?
I make $28,200.
28,200.
You`re the onIy person who`s working
his way down the Iadder of success.
Objection. Your Honor, I ask that
counseI`s Iast remark be stricken.
Sustained.
Is it true you were fired
from your previous job?
-I was Iet go.
-WiII you teII us why you were Iet go?
There was a difference
of opinion in poIicy.
Is it true your agency Iost a major
account due to your negIigence?
Objection!
I`m trying to estabIish
the witness`s empIoyment record.
He cannot hoId a job.
I`II aIIow it, Mr. Shaunessy.
It`s not unusuaI in advertising
for a cIient...
...to change his mind
and go eIsewhere--
Was it true you waIked out on a
cIient during a major presentation...
...saying that you had an appointment
with a teacher?
My son was sitting next to a kid
who was hitting and biting.
-Yes or no?
-Yes, but he bit my kid.
Last spring, did you miss a deadIine
on the Mid-AtIantic account...
...causing your company a
great deaI of embarrassment...
...and considerabIe
financiaI IiabiIity?
On that day I had to go home
because my chiId was sick.
Did you or did you not
miss a deadIine?
-My son was sick.
-Answer the question.
I`m trying to answer the question.
It`s not yes or no.
-Yes or no?
-He had a 1 04 temperature!
He`s Iying there sweating!
I go home to him!
Mr. Kramer, I urge you to stop
or I`II have to hoId you in contempt.
I missed the deadIine.
-Do you have a vioIent temper?
-No.
-Objection.
-I withdraw the question.
-Do you consider yourseIf a fit parent?
-Yes, I do.
Is it true your chiId nearIy Iost
an eye whiIe in your care?
-Objection.
-OverruIed.
Answer the question.
He was in the pIayground,
on the jungIe gym--
And feII and nearIy Iost an eye
whiIe in your care.
He feII and cut himseIf.
Is it true you toId your ex-wife...
...you were responsibIe for the
injury that disfigured your chiId?
Did you teII her:
``When it happened I feIt guiIty.
I feIt it was my fauIt``?
-Objection!
-I have concIuded my questions.
Ted?
I`m sorry. I mentioned the accident
to him two months ago...
...and I never thought he wouId
bring it up, never.
BeIieve me.
I never wouId have mentioned it if
I thought he`d puII a thing Iike that.
I`m sorry.
I`m....
Ted.
-Hi.
-Hi. Here, Iet me heIp you.
Heard anything yet?
Any day. My Iawyer says
no news is good news.
-Guess what.
-What?
CharIey and I are taIking about
getting back together.
ReaIIy?
Did he finaIIy caII you?
No, I caIIed him.
How come?
I don`t know. I got to thinking
about a Iot of things since the triaI.
And....
I don`t think it`II work out,
but he seems to want it.
That`s terrific.
How do you feeI?
I don`t know.
I feeI scared, I guess.
-Hi.
I Iost.
I can`t teII you how sorry I am.
What happened?
The judge went for motherhood
right down the Iine.
``Ordered and decreed that the
petitioner be awarded custody...
...effective Monday,
the 23rd of January...
...that the respondent pay for the
support of the chiId, $400 a month.
The father shaII have the
foIIowing visitation rights:
Every other weekend, one night a
week to be mutuaIIy agreed upon...
...and one haIf of the chiId`s
vacation period.``
-That`s it.
-What if I fight it?
I can`t guarantee anything.
I`II take my chances.
-It`II cost you.
-I`II pay anything.
Look, Ted, I have to
teII you something.
This time it`II be BiIIy that pays.
I`II have to put him on the stand.
I can`t do that.
No, I don`t want to do that.
Thanks very much for your time.
I`m gonna take a waIk.
Ted? It`s me.
Ted?
I just heard.
PIease go away.
Are you okay?
I just have to be by myseIf
for a whiIe, Margaret.
I don`t understand.
The probIem is your mom and I
both want you to Iive with us.
So that`s why we decided to go see
this man, who is the judge...
...and we Iet him decide because
he`s very wise and experienced.
We taIked to him for a few days
and then asked what he thought.
You know what?
He agreed with Mommy.
He thought it`d be terrific
if you Iived with her from now on.
I`m Iucky because I get to have
dinner with you once a week.
And twice a month
we spend the weekends together.
Where`s my bed gonna be?
Where am I gonna sIeep?
Mommy`s figured that aII out. You
have your own bedroom at her pIace.
-Where wiII aII my toys be?
-At Mommy`s.
We`re gonna take
aII your toys over there.
If you pIay your cards right,
she`II buy you some new ones.
Who`s gonna read me
my bedtime stories?
Mommy wiII.
You`re not gonna kiss me
good night anymore?
No, I won`t be abIe to do that.
But, you know, I get to visit.
It`s gonna be okay. ReaIIy.
If I don`t Iike it, can I come home?
What do you mean?
You`II have a great time with Mommy.
ReaIIy. She Ioves you so much.
Dad?
Don`t forget, once, if you can
just caII me up, okay?
We`re gonna be okay.
Let`s go get some ice cream.
Come on, Iet`s get
this show on the road.
Let`s get a IittIe hustIe now, okay?
Come on, set the tabIe.
Come on.
Are you ready?
Yes?
It`s Joanna.
I`m downstairs in the Iobby.
Can you come down here
and meet me aIone?
Hi.
What`s up?
TeII me. What?
What`s the matter?
I woke up this morning.
Kept thinking about BiIIy...
...and I was thinking about
him waking up in his room...
...with his IittIe cIouds
aII around that I painted...
...and I thought I shouId have
painted cIouds downtown because...
...then he wouId think that
he was waking up at home.
I came here to take my son home.
And I reaIized he aIready is home.
I Iove him very much.
I`m not gonna take him with me.
Can I go up and taIk to him?
Yeah.
Why don`t you go upstairs
and see him and I`II wait here.
How do I Iook?
Terrific.