The year is 1893.
Champaner...
A small village in the heart
of India.
The people of Champaner
depended on agriculture...
...like those in thousands
of other villages.
A British Cantonment bordered
the village.
Two miles south,
beyond the Cantonment...
...was the fort of the Raja
of this province.
The British protected
the Raja's domain from attacks...
...by neighbouring rulers.
They also promised the other Rajas
protection from this Raja!
Thanks to this double-dealing,
the British collected a tax...
...from the Rajas - which was paid
by every farmer in the country.
Lagaan...
The submission of a portion of
the farmer's harvest...
...to the Raja as tax.
Every Raja collected Lagaan
from villages under his rule.
The Raja would keep one share
and give the rest to the British.
In this way,
the British fist grew iron strong.
Like thousands of villagers
across the country...
...the farmers toiled
day and night on empty bellies...
...and paid taxes to the Raja
year after year.
Last year it rained...
but very little.
And this year,
there has been no rain so far.
Parched eyes scan the sky.
You're standing there again, Mai.
What are you gazing at?
When will the sky darken
with clouds!
How I long to see it...
A month of the rainy season is gone by.
Not a drop of rain yet!
I'm coming...
By God's grace, we have
drinking water at least.
Or we'd be parched to the bone.
Such are His ways...!
That's true, Mai.
But the fields are thirsty.
How'll the grain ripen!
Don't lose heart, Hari Bhai.
If the sky doesn't give water,
we'll dig deep into the ground.
We'll tear up the earth and get water.
It's what I told Bhuvan.
Where is he?
He went out in the morning.
It's time to eat.
Send him home if you see him.
Yes, Mai.
Stop! You little pests! Stop!
I'll wring your necks!!
Oh, no!
The Great Chicken War again!
Goli, you freak! See if I don't
ram you down a gun barrel!
Go to hell, Bhura!
Come here, I'll show you!
You just wait, I'm coming!
I'll thrash you so bad
you won't get up from bed for days!
How dare you hit my kids?
I'll hang them upside down
and burn chillies under them!
Hassle my hens, will they!
And you bleat once more
and I'll burn your slingshot!
Is that so, ha!
Oh, stop this daily ruckus!
You fight worse than cats and dogs.
But his boys tease my hens!
So? Are they hens or girls!
He acts like they've been molested!
Your hens aren't going to get
married, you know.
Look, Bhura, they are just kids.
And, Goli, control your boys.
Okay... Now tell me,
have you seen Bhuvan?
No. You seen him, Bhura?
No.
Why?
Left, right, left.
Scumbags!
Sons of unmarried jackals!
Strutting around
in the blazing heat!
One day you're going back
to your frozen little island...
...whimpering!
I see Saturn glaring balefully at you.
Hey, Guran. Why bother
reading their lousy fortune?
They won't even care.
Read my fortune, won't you?
Come on, tell me.
Will I get the Prince of my dreams?
Why not?
If you truly love him,
he'll give you your wedding bangle.
You'll be his bride.
Really? You heard, Jigni.
- Yes!
But...
- But what?
I see an obstacle.
What obstacle?
Tell me quickly, Guran.
Gauri!
- Later.
Read my fortune.
What is it, Kaka?
Was Guran telling
your fortune?
No... er... yes.
He's mad.
He's got no clue about the present
and just babbles about the future!
No, Hari Kaka. He's not mad.
Have you forgotten Aunt Durga?
She was childless for nine years
after marriage.
Then Guran said she'd have a son.
And wasn't Somu born?
Then there is Kesariya...
All right,
that lunatic is not mad.
Now tell me.
You saw Bhuvan anywhere?
I haven't seen him
but I know where he will be.
Amazing! Our little girl surely
keeps tabs on him, doesn't she?
Hey, Lakha! What is it to you?
I see! It concerns me and
I'm not to open my mouth!
Wear wedding bangles for me.
Lakha, what nonsense is this!
I really mean it, father.
Look. You've grown old
and our Gauri here doesn't care for me.
Here, look at this!
See how badly I am hurt.
Hurt?
It's my father you need, not me.
Bapu!
- What is it?
Lakha has a gash on his hand.
Well, Lakha. You seem to cut
your hand more than you chop wood.
What can I do, Isar Chacha!
I always seem to be wounding
myself... so badly.
Kaka, I'll go fetch Bhuvan.
Listen.
If you see him, tell him...
...Mai is waiting for him.
Yes, I'll tell him.
One...
Two...
Three.
Bloody hell! Missed again.
Quick! Before it disappears.
Over there!
Wesson, you go around.
Let's corner the blasted animal.
One...
Drop the stone.
Finally! Got the damn creature.
Good shot.
- Thank you.
Now for something a little bigger.
Arrest him.
Sir, this darkie was hiding
in the bushes...
...with this stone in his hand.
He'd been distracting
the deer all the time.
Now I understand...
...why I missed five times.
Protector of animals, eh?
He's a farmer, sir.
From Champaner.
Well, you must be
a very good runner.
Try saving this one.
Next time I will shoot you.
Captain Russell, sir.
Raja Puran Singhji is waiting
for you at the Cantonment.
Puran Singh!
What could he want now?
BHUVAN...!
Why're you screaming
your head off?
I was looking for you.
Since I couldn't see you...
Was I lying dead somewhere!
- How should I know...
God! What am I saying.
But why are you so angry?
Oh, never mind.
What do you want?
I've got something special
to tell you.
What?
Sit down, won't you?
So tell me.
Guran read my fortune today.
So, what's the misfortune?
So mean! I won't tell you.
All right. Tell me.
Come on, tell me.
Guran said...
...I'll put henna on my hands
this year...
...I mean get married.
Wow! That's great!
Such happy news.
You'll be dancing with joy.
Who's the boy?
How would I know?
Guran didn't tell me that.
But Guran said for sure...
The house I marry into will have
a Neem tree in the courtyard...
A big field beside the house...
...two cows, a pair of oxen
and three goats.
Guran said my home
will be a little heaven.
How wonderful!
You're really lucky.
Lucky! You call this lucky?
Well, a little heaven of a home.
What more do you want?
God knows what'll become of me!
Well, Bhuvan, tell me one thing.
What kind of girl do you like?
I...
I will like only the girl
whom my Mai likes.
Whom Mai likes?
- Yes.
Oh, God!
- What happened?
Actually...
...I came to tell you that
your Mai wants you.
You tell me now
after all this time!
You sit here now.
I'm going.
Bhuvan, I am sorry!
Rajaji!
How did your hunt go?
The British are the best
when it comes to hunting.
The British Empire is
the best in the world.
Isn't that so?
- Absolutely.
But I am getting worried.
- About what?
When all the game in
the jungle is finished...
...what will your guns target next?
We're fortunate that
you came to visit us.
But I don't know the reason.
I've brought you a request
on behalf of my subjects.
Request?
Good morning, Eliza.
- Good morning.
Your Highness, may I present
my dear sister Elizabeth.
She just arrived from London.
Elizabeth, His Highness,
Raja Puran Singh Chala of Champaner.
It's my rare good fortune
to meet you.
Rajaji, she doesn't know Hindi.
Of course.
Charmed to meet you.
Pleased to meet you,
Your Highness.
Sir.
- Smith.
Elizabeth, I'd like you to meet
my deputy, Lieutenant Patrick Smith.
How do you do, Lieutenant Smith?
- Pleased to meet you.
Gentlemen.
Well, Rajaji.
I am at your service.
My people haven't worshipped
at the Siddheshwar temple...
...for the past three years.
They believe...
...performing puja will end
the hardships they faced last year.
But...
- But...
The temple is in the land ruled
by Raja Diler Singh...
...who is your cousin and enemy.
And your very dear friend.
I'm sure Diler Singh won't
say no if you talk to him.
No, thank you.
I'm a vegetarian.
I mean vegetarian.
So, what do you think, Captain Russell?
Is it possible?
Well, he could be persuaded.
Your work might be done.
But on one condition.
Condition? Yes, tell me.
Eat the meat, Your Highness.
You eat this meat...
and I'll talk to Diler Singh.
As I told you,
I'm a vegetarian.
I am a vegetarian!
Just one piece of meat.
You eat it
and consider your job done.
Andrew.
Eat the meat.
How's my eating meat
connected to the temple?
It's not connected.
I just want to see
you eating meat.
To do my duty,
I can't be false to my religion.
I'm sorry.
All right then.
You'll have to pay me double tax.
Double Lagaan...!?
Look, Rajaji!
Last year, I agreed to cut
the tax by half at your request.
And delayed, at that.
You have to clear the arrears
this year. So, double tax.
But it hasn't rained yet.
The British Raj doesn't bathe
in India's rains, Rajaji.
Rain or no rain.
I must maintain this Cantonment.
The army costs money.
It has to be paid, fed and clothed...
...for your protection.
How will the farmers pay?
Come on, Rajaji.
It's only double the tax.
And moreover...
...you don't eat meat, right?
Hey, Arjan.
What's Bagha so thrilled about?
I can't understand either.
It must surely be
something special.
Hey, Bagha!
What are you beating that drum for?
Clouds!
Dark and dense...
Dark and dense
come the swirling clouds
Darkly dense
roar the spreading clouds
The clouds'thunderous sting
reverberates
Oh, look!
How lethally does lightning flash
The clouds make my heart race
The clouds make every heart race
O black cloud!
Pour down rain
Not lightning's flashy sword
wield the arrows of raindrops
The spreading clouds
bring rain in their wake
Swirling darkly
the clouds come
My leaping heart says
Dance with joy
Our days are transformed
Step out of the house
The clouds will
rain down nectar
Gone are days of hardship
Sing the melodies of monsoon
Dark and dense
come the swirling clouds
Darkly dense
roar the spreading clouds
When joyous rain pours
Who then will remain athirst!
The koel will sing
perched on the parapet
The songbirds will sing
Of the new days that are to come
Light shall smile at darkness
Love's rain will drench
hearts and bodies
On the earth
Oh, see, water's mirror
Wherever you go
You will see everywhere
This one splendid sight
The earth here wears
a rainbow-hued veil
Hang swings on the trees
and stretch your legs high
O black cloud!
Pour down rain
Not lightning's flashy sword
wield the arrows of raindrops
Now comes the intoxicating season
To spread a carpet of green
Bringing along
the season of rain
Anklets of lightning
adorn her dancing feet
The cloud is her veil
The season comes to bedeck
this bridal earth
Every bough will wear
a bracelet of blossoms
Joy will now rain
upon every courtyard
Now every bud will bloom
Every path will ring
with laughter now
The wafting breeze
makes the season balmy
Doused is the scorching heat
burning body and soul
O black cloud!
Pour down rain
Dark and dense
come the swirling clouds
Darkly dense
roar the spreading clouds
The clouds'thunderous sting
reverberates
Oh, look!
How lethally does lightning flash
Oh! Dear God!
We celebrated too soon.
One can't say
what God is punishing us for.
There'll be no rain this year too.
Bloody lunatic.
Always says inauspicious things!
- Black-tongued wretch!!
Hear! Hear this proclamation.
Orders of Raja Puran Singh,
your liege and master.
This year, you shall pay twice
the regular amount...
...of wheat, rice and maize.
The order of double Lagaan will
apply to the whole province.
How can this be possible!
- This is tyranny!
Double Lagaan!
Demon! Why don't you just skin
us alive, and be done with it!
Our plight isn't hidden from the Raja.
Even then, double Lagaan!
What wrong have we done?
Why should we pay double?
We didn't pay tax on time last year.
And we paid only half.
But, father, it was Rajaji who waived it
because it didn't rain.
Sweets one year and
abuse the next!
It means we're being punished
for it now! Well done, Rajaji!!
Quiet, Lakha!
I won't hear one word against
our Rajaji.
He and his ancestors have
protected us all these years.
So? Was that any favour?
It's the tree's duty to shelter.
All I want to know is...
How long'll hungry stomachs
sing his praise! Fill his coffers!
Try and understand, Arjan.
This demand is the doing
of those damn White Sahibs.
Whether we put it into
the right hand or the left...
...it's we who pay, Chief!
I say we all go to the palace
and talk to him.
He's seen these clouds as well.
We'll say we can't pay Lagaan
this year. Not a grain!
What if Rajaji refuses even
after hearing us out?
Then all the separate fingers
will close into a fist, Chief.
Meaning? You'll fight?
If it's necessary, even that.
Have you gone crazy!
If you offend Rajaji...
...not only you - we will
all be ruined!
Is your life now all joy and comfort?
Aren't you suffering?
Whatever happens, I won't let
the whole village come to harm.
What do you want?
Sell our homes? Our cattle?
Even ourselves?
What justice is it to demand
double Lagaan?
Come on, Benson.
Pitch it up a bit.
Running.
Chief, there's our Rajaji.
Hey! Where're you going?
Please, brother, we've got to meet
His Highness. It's most urgent.
All right.
But the game is going on.
Sit here. You must wait till
the game gets over.
All of you sit down.
What are they playing?
God knows what
these Feringhees are playing.
It's rather like our game of
Gilli-Danda, you know.
Why're these Whitey buffoons
playing a kid's game then?
Any clouds up there?
Wasn't that a wonderful shot?
You are not supposed
to touch the ball.
Bloody darkie!
Arrest him!
Long live Your Highness.
What are you people doing here?
Forgive us, Your Highness.
We came to meet you,
not to see their silly stupid game.
We are desperately worried and
this Feringhee just hits Bhura!
I didn't like what you said.
Forgive them, Captain Russell.
They've come to me with their problems.
Their lot is sad.
And this boy is an innocent.
He's not so innocent...
It was you in the jungle, wasn't it?
All right.
We'll decide this after the game.
Leave him.
Come on, chaps.
Back to the game.
We'll talk after the game.
As you wish, Your Highness.
Well done, Smith.
Well done.
Long live Your Highness.
All right, Headman.
What's the matter?
You know there's been no rain
so far, Your Highness.
If we can live on what we have
this year...
...we may just be able to get by.
So, our liege lord!
We've come to plead with you...
Cancel our Lagaan this year.
You are like our father!
Listen, Headman.
I can understand
what you are all going through.
But... my hands are tied as well.
These Feringhees won't spare
even their own kin.
You'll have to pay double Lagaan.
We'll die of hunger!
- We'll starve!!
Problem, Your Highness?
These farmers have brought a petition.
And that is?
They want to be excused from
paying Lagaan this year.
I told them it's not possible.
But... it is possible.
How?
I will tell you.
All right. I'll cancel the tax.
But... there is a condition.
Condition!
What condition, Sahib?
You...
Come here.
What was that you said
about our game?
What did he say?
Yes... A silly stupid game.
What do you know about this game?
We've played it since we were children.
We call it Gilli-Danda.
And you... who knows what
you call it.
Cricket!
So you mean to say
you can play this cricket?
Yes... it's easy.
All right.
I'll cancel the Lagaan...
But you must defeat us in the game.
The condition is...
You beat us at this game and
you won't have to pay Lagaan.
I'm serious.
You beat us in this game...
...and I'll cancel your tax.
But if you lose...
You'll have to pay triple tax,
that is three times the Lagaan.
All right?
Tell me. You accept the wager?
Sir, I think the cat's
got his tongue.
Quiet.
All right. I will raise the stakes.
If you defeat us in this game...
...I'll cancel not only this year's
Lagaan but next year's as well.
Do you accept?
Bhuvan!
Don't say anything.
Don't say a word.
- Yes, just be silent.
All right.
I'll raise the bet even higher.
Not just one year...
I'll cancel Lagaan for the next
two years. That means three years!
And not just for you
but for the whole province.
Now do you accept?
He's digging a pit
to bury us in, Bhuvan.
Chief, you speak up now.
- Yes, Chief, you speak.
Sahib!
Shut up!
You tell me.
Will you pay double Lagaan?
Or do you accept the bet?
I accept the bet.
Did he agree?
- Yes, he did.
All right.
So it's decided... the game will be
played after three months.
This'll kill us, Your Highness!
- We will die!
This is unfair.
So's life.
No Lagaan if you win.
But if you lose...
We have to pay thrice the amount!
And this Bhuvan here agreed
to this impossible condition!
What have you done, Bhuvan!?
From double to triple!
Total ruin!
I told you there could be
a great calamity, didn't I?
Was there any choice?
I ask you, did we have a choice?
What else could we do?
Isn't double Lagaan unjust?
Are we strong enough to pay it?
Tell me, can anyone here pay it?
This isn't a calamity, Chief.
It's an opportunity. A chance.
I didn't accept out of bravado.
You have to get burnt
to save your home from fire.
I know we are weak.
But this way, we have hope.
And I want to turn this hope
into reality.
This game is for our fields
and harvest.
Have you forgotten? If we win,
we'll be happy for three years.
Three years...
Just think.
No Lagaan for three years.
You know what that means?
It means our grain will be ours.
Only ours.
Not a grain to be given to anyone.
The welfare of our children,
our entire village, is in this.
Our sweat will run as blood
in our veins.
Marvellous!
Small eyes dreaming
such big dreams!
Yes, Arjan, I have a dream.
And only those who dream
can make them come true.
Isar Kaka,
three months is time enough.
We can learn the game
and defeat them too.
Even a whole year's hitting with
a stick won't teach you...
...this Whitey game!
I know the game isn't easy, Lakha.
But, Chief, it's not impossible either.
I want all of you to be with me.
Nobody in the village will be
with you in your madness!
But, Ismayeel...
- Enough is enough!
We've only one hope now.
We'll all go to Rajaji once again
and beg him to save us.
What are you thinking, Mai?
About what happened today, son.
I swear on you, Mai!
I did what was right.
I feel rage in my heart
when I pay Lagaan to the Raja...
And he gives it to those Whiteys
with their dirty grasping hands!
You tell me, Mai.
Who ploughs this earth
to sow the seeds?
We do.
Who waters it?
Why should we fill their coffers
with our produce?
The White Sahib said Lagaan
may be cancelled for three years.
How could I remain silent, Mai?
Tell me, should I have stayed mute?
What are you looking at, Mai?
You talk just like your father.
He was so spirited.
And he spoke the truth.
Well, go and sleep now.
Don't let this burden your heart.
Gauri! What are you doing here?
I came to meet you.
To... to tell you I am with you.
I have faith... in you
and in your courage.
That's all I came to say.
Bhuvan Bhaiyya, I lost my gilli.
Make me another.
What's this?
I'll tell you.
It's not at all difficult, Tipu.
Whiteys play it wearing pants
and call it Kirkut.
And we wear loincloths
and call it Gilli-Danda. Get it?
Our fathers and grandfathers have
been playing Gilli-Danda.
Go over there...
Back... further back.
A little more... stop.
Now catch the ball, okay.
Catch it properly, Tipu.
Come on, toss it to me.
I'll show you.
Saw that?
It's very easy.
Why, even you can learn it.
This game is just like
Gilli-Danda.
Catch it now...
Very good!
What a catch! What a catch!
Well done, Tipu.
Isn't it easy?
Now throw the ball.
I'll show you how to hit it.
Wow! That's some throw!
You do that so well, Tipu!
Hey, Gauri, pass it to me.
Hey, Gauri! What're you doing?
Go heat the water.
Take it, Tipu.
Now watch me this time.
It's very easy.
Damn! The stick slipped.
Oh! My hands are sweaty.
This should do the trick.
Okay, Tipu, throw.
And don't feel bad...
But I'll give it
a real hard whack this time.
A real hard whack, ha!
Wow!
Hey, Bagha, throw the ball.
Can I say something, father?
- What?
I feel that Bhuvan is doing
the right thing.
All right, all right.
Go see if the water is boiling.
That's it, Bagha.
Hit it hard.
Oh, very well done, Bagha!
Bhuvan, I am also with you...
like Bagha.
Who are all these people, father?
Ramprasad and Namdeo.
Headmen ofTantpura and Bhind.
But with so many people...!
Who is Bhuvan here?
- That's Bhuvan.
There he is!
Stop, Ramprasad.
Think of the village
code of honour.
I've no quarrel with your village.
I must teach that cocky Bhuvan
of yours a lesson.
Why should we suffer for
what he's done?
You big mouth!
Who are you to decide for us?
I have only done what is
good for all of us.
To hell with your do-gooding!
You must beg the White Sahib's pardon.
And as for your game,
to hell with it! Understand?
No? You are asking for
trouble now.
Be calm, Ramprasad.
It'll be as you say.
But, Chief...
- Enough is enough!
No more buts!
We must go to our Rajaji.
The issue now is not Lagaan
or the game...
...but of British honour.
And Captain Russell's ego.
Talk to the White Sahib
once more, Your Highness.
Forgive him, Your Highness.
Bhuvan is naive, impulsive.
He got carried away.
It doesn't matter what he is.
He has challenged the British
on behalf of you all.
He's ready to beg the British
Sahib's pardon. All of us are.
I'll agree to 100 whiplashes...
But I won't beg pardon.
What're you saying, Bhuvan!
It's too late to beg pardon.
Now pay for what you've done.
But what shall we do, Highness?
I suggest... you learn their game.
Why're all these other guys
standing around on the field?
Like in Gilli-Danda, to catch
the gilli... I mean the ball.
That is out, sir.
Why does he point his finger
at the sky?
That's what I'm
trying to understand.
He must be thinking of his Ma.
She's sitting up there, huh?
Bowl it on the offside.
Excuse me.
I might just take a walk.
Of course, my dear.
Damn! This bug's after me!
Be quiet.
Look! The White lady is
coming here.
Damn! It got in!
Hell!! Out!
Miss, what happened?
Are these darkies bothering you?
It's all right. They're farmers.
I know them.
Thank you. Carry on your game.
I know what you were doing
behind that tree.
You were trying to learn the game.
No, Memsahib. We were only
trying to understand the game.
Oh, I thought you were
trying to learn the game.
What's she saying,
Bhuvan Bhaiyya?
I think she is telling us to go.
All right, Memsahib.
We'll go.
No, wait.
Ram Singh!
Yes, Memsahib.
What can I do?
Ram Singh, I want you to tell them...
...that I would like to help them
learn the game.
Yes, Memsahib.
Memsahib says she'll help
you understand this...
What if your brother learns
of this, Memsahib!
Ram Singh, can I trust you?
Of course, Memsahib.
No one should know about this.
All right, Memsahib.
No one will know.
Memsahib says she wants to
help you understand this game.
Really?
But why?
Isn't she Feringhee too?
The man wants to know...
...why would you want to do this
as you, too, are British.
Tell him... because I know
what happened to them is unfair...
...and I want to give them
a fair chance.
Memsahib knows injustice
has been done to you.
That's why she wants to give
you an equal chance.
Thank you. We'd be very happy.
He's happy to receive your help
and he thanks you.
Good.
Wonderful!
Tell him I'll meet him tomorrow.
Same time but not here.
And certainly not in their village.
Some other place maybe?
Memsahib will meet you
tomorrow at the same time.
But not here. Nor in the village.
Have you any other place?
I got it.
Behind the hill near the village.
You can meet him next to the hill,
near the village.
I know the place.
- All right.
What's his name?
Memsahib wants to know
your names.
He's Guran, that's Bagha.
This is Tipu.
And I am Bhuvan.
No, no! Bhuvan.
Bhu... van.
There! That one sprouted right, huh?
My name is Elizabeth.
Memsahib's name is Elizabeth.
Ali... and what?
My God! My tongue'll get
into a twist saying it!
It's a nice name...
Whatever it may be.
All right, Memsahib.
We're going. Namaste.
He'll never agree, Bhuvan.
He will agree.
Greetings, Bhabhi.
- How're you, Bhuvan Bhaiyya?
What're you up to, you imp?
Have you eaten, Goli?
- Yes.
I didn't see you all day,
Bhuvan Bhaiyya.
What to do. I was busy
preparing for the game.
How's your game coming along?
It's just the beginning.
We're learning the ropes.
Do you know everyone here
is making fun of you?
They say, "Some players
Bhuvan has got, ha!"
One's Bagha and the other, Guran!
One can do nothing else
but beat a drum.
And the other keeps staring
like a madman.
Oh, no. It's not me,
the others say all this.
Is that so!
We also have a White lady with us.
She teaches us the game.
A White lady?
Don't tell me tall tales!
What do you think? Ask them.
Is this true, Gauri?
Yes. There's some White lady.
That means you will really play?
Is there a choice?
I don't have so much land like
you that I can sell off a piece!
What do you mean?
Why should I sell my land?
I'm not selling any land!
Will your Granny pay the double
Lagaan then?
Well, I'd better be off.
Hey, Bhuvan.
Do you think I could be
of any use?
No! Your buffalo would
be more useful!
Silly, you will be the
most useful of all!
Really! How?
You'll throw the ball the way you
swing that slingshot of yours.
What aim! It's deadly!
Slingshot...
Then... we won't have
to pay Lagaan?
Yes, Goli.
We'll eat our bellyful.
Will our dream ever come true?
No, Bhuvan. It hurts too much
to dream like that.
Have faith, Goli.
He who has truth and courage
in his heart shall win in the end.
Beautifully said!
Every saint and seer has said
He who has truth and courage
in his heart
It's he who wins
at the end
Come, yes, come on
However long the path may be
This body of yours
shall not grow weary
Come. Hear the call
of the road
Let not the road
remain waiting for you
You come along
You are the king of this earth
Know this for sure
Go forth to meet hardship
head on
Don't ever accept defeat
Listen, O my friend
What's this fear you have?
This earth is ours
So is the sky
Listen, O my friend
What's this fear you have?
You just come along
Hear me, O my friend
What's in your heart
is in my heart too
The dream you have
is also my dream in life
Yes, we go ahead
with hope lit in our eyes
May this light of our hope
never go out
May never a storm
put out this light
Listen, O my friend
What's this fear you have?
This earth is ours
So is the sky
Listen to this, my friend
The balmy easterly breeze
will join our song
Pleasure will cast
its intoxicating spell
If we call out in unison...
The season of flowers
will also come
Oh, yes
Happy days shall be here again
with no trace of sorrow
Let's all together create
a festival ofjoyous colour
Tell me why you stay
alone this way
Listen, O my friend
What's this fear you have?
This earth is ours
So is the sky
Every saint has said
As has every seer
He who has truth and courage
in his heart
It's he who wins
at the end
The lady hasn't come yet.
I am here!
Not you, silly.
We're waiting for the White lady.
Not a lassie but a lady!
She has come, Bhuvan Bhaiyya!
Tell me this, Bhuvan.
Why's that White witch
ready to help you?
Simple. She took a fancy to
Bhuvan Bhaiyya.
Is that so?
Cheeky brat!
Who are they?
Oh, wow! You learnt
our language very fast.
Ram Singh taught me.
Who are they?
You already know Tipu,
Bagha and Guran.
This is Goli, he's Isar Kaka.
And this is Gauri.
We'll meet again.
You should say,
I'm glad to meet you.
Oh, gosh.
I'm sorry.
I'm glad to meet you.
We're glad to meet you too.
So, Bhuvan,
what do you know about the game?
What?
Memsahib is asking you
what you know about the game.
Oh, lots!
There are six sticks.
Three this side and three that side.
Two fellows stand with planks
before the sticks.
One comes running near
the sticks and throws a ball.
The chap with the plank hits
the ball hard with his plank...
...and then everyone runs
helter-skelter.
One of them grabs the ball
and gives it to the first guy.
He runs again to throw the ball
at the guy who twirls the plank.
That's all. It goes on all day.
Throw the ball, twirl the plank.
Throw and twirl! Right?
Memsahib, I can't translate all that.
No need, Ram Singh.
I understood most of that.
He knows nothing.
This is what a cricket field looks like.
Suppose this is the playing field.
And this is what a cricket pitch is.
This is the strip on which
the game is played.
There are three main aspects
to cricket:
Batting, bowling and fielding.
The game has three parts.
Wielding the bat, bowling
the ball and guarding the field.
My God! Even our great uncles
can't pronounce these things!
What did he say?
He said this language even
his ancestors won't understand.
All right, we better make it simpler.
Cricket is played by two teams,
say, yours and the English.
Each team has eleven players.
Five batters, five bowlers...
Yes...
What happened?
Nothing.
Memsahib, I think we should leave.
It's getting late.
This is enough for today.
Let's begin with the Lord's
name on our lips.
Catch it.
Look. Try pouncing on the ball
and catch. Don't let it fall.
Bhuvan, the White lady said
there must be eleven in a team.
We are only five.
Why only five? I'm here too.
Whatever that White lady can do,
so can I.
All right, Gauri.
We're six, not five.
Isar Kaka, as you thought of
our village and joined us...
The others will also come
and join.
Or we will drag them in.
Hey, Goli!
Catch the ball.
Who threw this ball?
- Goli Chacha did.
Goli, you jackass!
I won't leave you today.
There it starts again!
I'll crack you open like an egg!
Will you stop your
infernal squabbling!
Isar Kaka, don't you interfere.
- Stop it, you fools!
Gauri, our sixth player.
Hey, Bhura.
Oh, wow!
You saw how a ball is to
be caught, Isar Kaka?
That was something to see!
Like a bird diving for fish.
Oh, that's how it's done, is it?
Of course! Here, Bhura, do it again.
Show them all,
'specially this Goli here.
He's hopeless.
Just doesn't know how to catch.
All of you come here and
watch carefully.
Get ready, Bhura.
Watch carefully.
Saw that?
Brilliant, Bhura!
- That was something!
But where did you learn it?
I'll tell you.
The ball comes straight.
But hens! They run zigzag.
To catch hens,
you've got to be quick and agile...
...like Bhura.
Bhura will teach us all now,
won't you, Bhura?
I'll teach you... but...
But what?
What about my hens?
Bhura, these hens of yours
are a real pain!
Hearing of the wager and
cancellation of Lagaan...
...all the senior officers were
greatly concerned.
Colonel Boyer, Major Warren
and Major Cotton summoned...
...Captain Russell to express
their anger at his audacity.
At ease, Captain.
You know Major Cotton.
That is Major Warren.
Take a seat.
Now, what is this we hear?
That you have agreed to cancel the tax
of the farmers in Champaner...
...if they beat you
in a game of cricket?
Is this true?
Yes, Colonel Boyer, sir, it is.
What on earth do you think
you're here for? To play games?
Let me remind you...
...that you are working here
for Her Majesty, the queen.
Your job is to ensure
the smooth running of your province.
Pardon me, sir,
but that's exactly what I'm doing.
I think we'll be
the judge of that, Russell.
We also understand that if you lose
this so-called match...
...you will cancel their taxes
for the next three years.
Not just Champaner
but the entire province.
But they won't win.
You're missing the whole bloody point.
Do you realize we could have
on our hands a bloody situation...
...of cricket matches all over the damn
subcontinent to cancel the bloody tax!
But there's one thing you don't know.
If they lose...
...which they will, they will have
to pay the queen three times the tax.
This is ridiculous! This officer
wants to make the government...
...into some kind of bookie
with whom he can place his wagers.
What would you have us do next?
Race horses?
This is the most preposterous idea
I've ever heard of.
Captain Russell, the British Empire
cannot function according to...
...the whims and fancies
of officers like you.
Now jolly well understand this.
If you win,
you will have had a narrow escape...
...but if you lose, you will pay
the taxes for Champaner...
...and the entire province
out of your own pocket.
And then you'll be packed off
to Central Africa.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
That'll be all.
You may go.
It was against British pride
to withdraw from this wager.
And so, Captain Russell
was warned...
If he won the game,
he'd have a narrow escape.
But if he lost,
he'd have to pay the triple tax...
...of the entire province
from his own pocket.
Moreover...
He'd be transferred to
the Central African desert.
Is that the way a soldier behaves?
You're supposed to salute
when a superior officer passes.
I did, sir.
- I didn't see it.
That's better.
I imagine your meeting
did not quite go as expected, sir.
Damn right.
The senile old hats want
to teach me how to run the show.
They've lost their sense of adventure
with age.
What's wrong with a little fun
along with the Lagaan?
Is the match cancelled, sir?
- No, of course not.
Hey! How dare you hurt my horse!
I'm going to destroy
you people now!
I'll take so much Lagaan
you won't have a rag to your backs!
You bloody slaves will remain
crushed under our boots!
However thick the sole, it wears out.
Then nails will begin to prick, Sahib!
Ram Singh!
Yes, sir.
Get him out of here
before I kill him.
Arjan. What happened?
Bhuvan, I've been blind and stupid.
I am with you now.
Tell me in what way I can be of help.
Very good! We're coming
together to form a fist.
No, Arjan! Not like that.
Lakha, Goli was telling the truth.
About what?
- The White lady.
So?
We did wrong, Lakha. But it's
still in our hands to put it right.
We must support Bhuvan.
What did you say?
Have you gone crazy!
Try to understand.
Look!
An English girl is helping us
to save our bodies and souls.
And we sit sulking!
Shame on us!
By Allah's command,
we must be with him.
Come with me. Come on.
Have you gone senile, Ismayeel?
Then get yourself a crutch
and a shroud too!
This Bhuvan of yours will
never succeed.
Ismayeel... he'll never
take you into his team!
Now catch this.
Look, Bhuvan...
It's not just your honour at stake,
it's the whole village.
I'm ashamed of all the things
I said the other day.
I swear by God, I am with you
in this effort.
It's the word of a man of prayer.
What a beautiful thing to say!
Ismayeel has raised our spirit,
hasn't he.
Who can stop us now!
With a procession of
elephants and horses...
Raise a cry of victory
to Lord Krishna.
What are you looking at, Memsahib?
These statues.
Whose images are these?
This is the temple of
Radha and Krishna.
They are statues of
Lord Krishna and Radha.
Today is Krishna's birthday.
So the idols are decorated.
It's very beautiful.
Were they husband and wife?
Oh, no, Memsahib.
Krishna was married to Rukmini
and Radha married Anay.
But the deep love they had for
each other has set an ideal.
It's like the dewdrop
on a lotus leaf...
...not united nor separated.
They have been worshipped
together from aeons.
Let's go.
If Krishna were to meet
a lovelorn Gopi in the grove
And then smile and talk
and even tease her
How can Radha
be not jealous!
For her body and heart
are on fire
Even if Krishna were to meet
a lovelorn Gopi in the grove
It's only the flower of Radha's love
that blooms in his heart
Then why is Radha jealous?
With no thought or reason
Why is Radha jealous?
All the Gopis are but stars
Radha is the moon
Why is her faith
then so half-hearted?
Faithless Krishna is forever
looking hither and thither
Then how can poor Radha
believe in herself.
Gopis come and go
but Radha queens over his heart
Dawn and dusk
by theJamuna's banks
It's only Radha
that Krishna calls out to
If someone garlands Krishna
with her entwined arms
How can Radha
be not jealous!
Her body and heart
are on fire
How can Radha
be not jealous?
If Radha is enshrined
in Krishna's heart
Why doesn't he then tell her so?
Love has its own language
its own expression
Let the eyes speak
Such is Krishna's sweet wish
These eyes of yours, O Krishna!
They destroy the peace
of many a Gopi's heart
She meets your eyes
and is lost in love
Even if she be
the fairest damsel
If love for Krishna
ripens in a Gopi's heart
Why is Radha jealous?
How can Radha
be not jealous!
Gauri, you sing and dance beautifully!
Elizabeth, this is
Lieutenant Edward Wesson.
This is Lieutenant Richard North.
How do you do?
- Charmed, I'm sure.
Excuse me. Sir, there's a villager
outside you have to speak with.
Not now.
Tomorrow, in the office.
Sir, he says he has some important
information about the match.
Excuse me.
Long live our Protector.
What's the news you want
to give me?
Bhuvan is building up
his team, Sahib. But...
But what?
Spare my life, Sahib!
But a White Memsahib
from here teaches them the game.
White Memsahib...!?
Yes, Sahib.
I saw it with my own eyes today.
She also came to attend
the puja at our temple today.
Is the White Memsahib among them?
There she is.
You are not making a mistake, are you?
Hang me on the cross
if I've made a mistake.
She is the one,
I swear on my mother!
So you too are in the team.
No, Sahib.
As if I'm crazy like Bhuvan...
...to challenge the might of
the government!
Why are you telling me all this?
Only the slaughtered beast knows
the agony of the knife, Master.
And I am being cut from inside.
Just say that my victory
lies in Bhuvan's defeat.
What is your name?
Your name?
Lakha, Sahib.
Lakha, you do this.
You join Bhuvan's team.
What are you saying, Sahib!
You will be in Bhuvan's team.
But you will work for me.
I understand, Sahib.
Yes, Andrew, what is it?
So, Eliza,
you've been sightseeing.
How's the countryside?
It's beautiful.
The mountains, the woods, the cattle...
And the villages?
I didn't see any villages.
- My foot, you didn't see any!
You were with the villagers and
what's-his-name teaching them cricket.
You thought I wouldn't come to know?
You have the audacity
to go against your own brother?
Listen to me carefully.
You will not be meeting
those villagers again...
...because you will not be leaving...
...the Cantonment.
Is that understood?
Bloody farmers.
Why're you worried, child?
Our game's improving day by day.
Goli, you throw the ball
with a lot of passion.
Why do you just stand
after hitting, Arjan?
Take off and run.
Bhuvan... Bhaiyya.
Today when I see you all
playing together...
...I am aware of the wrong I did.
I regret it very much.
Can... Can I play with you?
No... you can't play.
Why?
See the game and understand, Lakha.
It's not like chopping wood, you know.
It needs special skills.
What do you say, huh?
Yes, absolutely!
Take Goli now.
He whirls and twirls the ball
like he swings his slingshot!
And our Bhura here.
He pounces on the ball the way
he grabs at his runaway hens.
Arjan has iron hands
from all that hammering.
That's right.
As for Isar Kaka's hands...
If money doesn't slip through them,
what's a mere ball!
And we do need a medicine man
in a game of cuts and bruises.
And who doesn't know
our Bagha's strength!
Tough as teak.
As for this Guran...
Passion runs like a fever
through this possessed loony.
Saturn is strong
and Mars is mighty.
And Ismayeel...
as I remember...
We have always been rivals
in Gilli-Danda.
And I?
Oh, yes. Tipu.
Our Tipu is so bright.
Now, you tell me, Lakha.
What are you good at?
I... I can run very fast.
So... you can run fast.
Okay. Then do one thing.
Let's see you run fast
up the temple steps three times.
Fast, I said. Can you do it?
Okay, Lakha.
Now run.
Don't fall!
Even I can run faster than him!
Bhuvan, don't you ever take him.
There's malice in his heart.
No, Gauri. We need him.
All that chopping of wood has
made his hands tough and strong.
He'll hit the ball really hard.
Come on, run! Yes, run.
He's at least trying, isn't he.
Don't worry. I'll give you
ointment for stiff legs!
Hey, run up the steps!
The fellow is back.
So you saw, Bhuvan?
What do you say?
You run a tad slow, pal.
You have to be faster.
I'll improve, Bhuvan.
I'll run every day.
But take me into the team.
I can't bear the thought of
the village being dishonoured.
What do you all have to say?
- Give him a chance and see.
Okay, let's try him out.
Look, Lakha...
Cheating at games has been
a childhood habit of yours.
What if you try it here too...
What are you saying, Ismayeel!
I'm sorry. Truly sorry, I swear.
Okay, Lakha.
You are in our team.
But remember!
It's a huge responsibility.
For the Whiteys,
it's only a game.
But for us, it's our life!
Yes, Bhuvan.
I am with you.
You will play with this ball from now.
Oh, wow!
Memsahib, your support has really
lifted our spirits. Thank you.
Goli will inaugurate this ball.
Forget the ball now.
You must all eat first.
It's to fill our bellies that we
must practise so hard, Gauri.
We'll play first.
Come on, all of you.
Come here, Bhura.
Ouch, he really made me run.
Marvellous!
That was some hit, Bhuvan.
Hey, give me the ball.
Who is Bhuvan here?
I am Bhuvan.
And you are...?
I am Deva.
Deva Singh Sodhi.
I've come from Dhaulpur.
I hear you have vowed
to fight the British.
Yes. But not with sticks and spears.
With bat and ball.
Whether with sticks and spears
or bat and ball...
...I want to be in every battle
against the British.
Let me lend a helping hand
in this fight, Bhuvan.
I have played this game before.
When?
I was in the British army.
I couldn't bear it any more
one day.
I came away after slamming
a final salute to those brutes.
I hate the British!
The Memsahib is with us, not against.
What do you know about the game?
Two things, Memsahib.
When I throw the ball,
shatter all three stumps.
And when I hit the ball,
smash it to pieces.
That's good.
We saw your bowling, Deva.
Now take the bat.
Goli, throw the ball.
Goli, leave the ball.
No play until you eat.
Okay. All of you come and eat.
Come, Deva.
I'm getting late. I must go.
Bhuvan, I have something to say to you.
Yes, Memsahib.
Bye, Gauri.
Obstacle...!
Looming obstacle!
Bhuvan, it's difficult for me
to get out of the Cantonment.
I can't meet you every day now.
Anyway, you now have
the support of your people.
But that is not because of me
but for your own sake.
Because you are a good man.
And also a good friend.
You know, I've had no friends
since I was a child...
...until I met you.
I don't know
if I should say it or not...
But...
Don't say it.
In fact...
...I'm falling in love with you.
Memsahib, I don't understand English.
I'm falling in love with you, Bhuvan.
Hey, Jigni, where's Gauri?
- She went off.
Where? What are you glaring at me for?
What the hell have I done now!
Hey, Gauri.
I've searched all over the village
and you sit here!
Why did you go off in a huff?
My wish.
What do you mean, "my wish"!
You could've at least told me.
How could I?
As if you can ever spare time
from that White lady!
The moment she comes,
you flutter around like a silly pigeon.
You can't see anything else.
And today, you completely
forgot me as if I wasn't there!
Try to understand, Gauri.
Memsahib had something
important to tell me.
If it was so important,
couldn't she say it right there?
Where was the need to go off
to be alone?
You think I don't know
which way the Ganges is flowing!
Ah, poor me!
How I feel the pain...
...of the scorpion's sting!
You are jealous!
Me! Why should I be jealous!
It's totally beneath me.
You are jealous and I know
of whom you are jealous!
I will never meet you
after this day!
And don't you even try
to talk to me!
Hey, Gauri!
There's only one house
in the whole village...
...with a Neem tree
in the courtyard.
There's also a big field beside it...
And a pair of oxen,
two cows and three goats too.
And I know whose house that is,
silly girl... it's mine!
Listen to one more thing before you go.
Mai also likes you!
O my lovely lassie!
Listen to what I have to say
It is only you
that I love
What is my life
without you!
The kajal that darkens
your eyes
It's the cloud of dreams
It's because of you
that my heart is crazy
O lassie, it's true
O sweet laddie!
These words come out
of my heart
It is only you
that I love
It's only you that I take
for my beloved
Your assuring hand
stills my fluttering veil
And there is turmoil
in my heart
This is the moment
I shall never forget
O my beloved!
My heart it speaks a thousand words
I feel eternal bliss
The roses spout their scarlet mouths
Like offering a kiss
No drop of rain
No glowing flame
Has ever been so pure
If being in love can feel like this
Then I'm in love for sure
What lay in my heart
What lay hidden in my heart
leapt to my lips today
An arrow resting
somewhere in my heart
Has found its bow today
Listen, O my love!
For all our lives to come
May we remain
in this abode of love
May our entwined hands
never be parted
I shall walk beside you
in your chosen path
True to your love
Oh, I'm in love
I am in love
Yes, I'm in love
Should someone ask
I shall tell them
what's happened to me
My every limb is fragrant
because you touched me
Your fragrant body
your flaming beauty
You are the red rose
my enchanted eyes see
How can this allure
not wake my desire
Your beauty shines bright
in youth's searing light
Oh, I'm in love
Yes, I'm in love
Despite my warning, you continue
to meet those bloody farmers!
How dare you!
I'm not going to tolerate
your nonsense any more.
You can damn well do what you like
in London but not here.
You will pack and leave
for England by the next ship.
Is that clear?
Let me make some things
clear to you, Andrew.
Stop telling me what to do.
I'm not a child.
I'm not leaving Champaner
and get this straight.
I'll go to the village
as and when I so wish.
Tell me, Eliza.
What's so special about them that
you go against your own brother?
There's nothing special about them.
You're being unfair
with your silly challenge.
That's why I decided to help them.
And you mark my words.
They'll give you a tough fight.
That's it, Yardley, line and length.
Line and length.
Good.
How's that?
One short, Burton.
Full play.
How was that?
That is out, sir.
That's the end of
the day's play, gentlemen.
I'm going to announce
the batting order now.
Smith and Burton will open...
...with Smith to face...
...followed by myself at number three.
Followed by Brooks, Wesson...
...North, Benson...
- Sir.
...Harrison, Flynn...
...Willis, Yardley.
Right.
Who's to be in the team?
- I think it should be Madhav.
What's going on?
Everyone wants to see you play.
We haven't found
our eleventh player.
We'll fix it right away.
Take Bhima.
Hey, Bhima!
- No, Chief.
He's named after the mighty hero
but has backache all the time.
Then how about Kashi Nath?
- Kashi Nath!
If the old crock runs he'll split!
Kashi this side and Nath that side.
What's to be done then?
We want a big hefty man, Chief.
Let's wait and see.
Deva, you throw the ball.
Isar Kaka, you take the bat.
All of you spread out.
Deva, bowl slow to Isar Kaka.
- All right.
Hey, Kachra, throw the ball.
Stop gaping and throw it,
will you?
Hey! What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
You told me to throw it.
Come here.
Come here, I said.
I didn't do anything.
You said throw and I threw the ball.
Come here, all of you.
Eliza Memsahib, just watch Kachra.
Hey, Kachra, throw it again.
I did no wrong. Bhuvan Bhaiyya
asked me to throw and I did.
Come on. Throw the ball.
Stop. Not with the left hand.
Throw with the right.
See how it spins!
Amazing.
He's actually spinning the ball.
We have found our eleventh player!
Come, Kachra.
Isar Kaka, you'll face him.
Goli, give Kachra the ball.
Lakha, go back.
Come on, throw the ball.
What's the matter?
Why's everyone standing and staring?
No, no!
We will not play!
What's happened?
This damn Untouchable!
He can't play with us. No way!
That's right. We'll not mix
with an Untouchable.
It's unthinkable!
I am not playing.
- We too won't play.
What are you doing?
It's absolutely wrong!
You are polluting
the whole system.
To fight the English is our duty
but mixing a low-caste...
...is like poisoning milk.
I will not allow this!
Kachra, you scum!
Get lost.
Oh, my God!
Bhuvan touched an Untouchable!
You brand people untouchable
and pollute humanity itself.
Chief, why are you choking
the very air of our village...
...with this caste division!
Is it right to destroy and shatter
hearts in the name of skin colour?
Then why worship Ram who ate
a tribal woman's half-eaten berries?
The Lord who ferries us all
across this sea of life...
...was himself ferried by
a low-caste boatman.
You know all this and yet
talk of untouchability!
And you, Isar Kaka!
You are a man of medicine.
You check the ailing patient's pulse
and treat him.
Do your scriptures tell you
not to treat an untouchable?
And let him die?
If that's so, it'll be the darkest blot
on humanity. After this...
...no one will regard a man of
medicine as God's other form!
Leave all that, Bhuvan.
You want a big hefty player, don't you?
This Kachra is a cripple!
Your hands aren't deformed, right?
It's by God's grace, Lakha,
that you can say all this.
But the man you call crippled will be
our greatest strength. Wait and see.
This seemingly lifeless hand
will give us victory.
Let me remind all of you
of one thing.
This is not a game we are
playing for fun or entertainment.
This is a battle we must win!
Our only goal is liberation from Lagaan
and welfare of our village.
And for that, I will not bow
before anyone till my last breath!
Whether you support me or not,
Kachra will play.
Bhuvan, my son...
Shame can't even enter eyes
that are fully opened.
I agree with Isar Bhai.
What you said was right, Bhuvan.
Kachra will play with us.
Again and again, yes
Say this, my friend
May victory be ours!
Defeat, their lot
Again and again, yes
Say this, my friend
May victory be ours!
Defeat, their lot
Let no one win
against us
Let's walk ahead
All challengers
will bite the dust
Let's walk ahead
Even if it is pitch-dark
Let no one stay back
on the road
Let's walk ahead
If a finger rises
break it shall
When all five join
the fist is formed!
Let our unity grow
Come on, walk ahead
However seductive
the lures cast before you
Walk ahead
No one can ever win
against us
Let's walk ahead
All challengers
will bite the dust
So walk ahead
Let no one stop you
obstruct you
Break all barriers
What have you ever got
being weak and powerless
Never will we suffer again
Such will be our play
the enemy will lose
We will now take
the path of courage
We will shake up this earth
We will show everyone
Who is king
who the slave
We shall show this
overwhelmed world
What we are worth
Again and again, yes
Say this, my friend
Victory will be ours
Defeat, their lot
Now
No fear will enter our hearts
Let's walk ahead
Every shackle
will now break open
Let's walk ahead
Keep walking
Don't ever falter
You are the journeyman
of the road
The snake of tiredness
should never bite you
He that rules you
is a tyrant
He that has destroyed us
His home is in the west
We shall make sure
he will not remain
We will shake up this earth
We will show everyone
Who is king
who the slave
We shall show this
overwhelmed world
What we are worth
What has to happen
will happen
Let's walk ahead
Now
No one will bow his head
Let's walk ahead
And then, the historic day dawned
when the first rays of the sun...
...fell on the cricket field.
Good morning, Captain Russell.
- Good morning, Colonel Boyer.
This way.
- Thank you.
Morning, Miss Russell.
- Miss Russell.
Are you feeling confident, Captain?
- Yes, sir.
Decent crowd.
Hail Hanuman,
The Mighty Ape God!
Long live Your Highness.
Smash the Feringhees.
Beat them to pulp.
Crush Captain Russell's arrogance.
Long live...
- Your Highness.
Things are certainly beginning
to hot up a bit, aren't they?
Yes.
Both the teams will bat once.
The game will be played
over three days.
Which team bats first...
...will be decided by
the toss of a coin.
For this, both the teams
must enter the field.
To ensure fair play...
...senior officials had invited
neutral umpires from Kanpur.
Will you call, Captain Russell?
Heads, sir.
Heads. Your call.
We will bat.
Good luck, Captain.
- Thank you, sir.
Good luck, young man.
The batting team that scores
more runs wins the game.
Opening the batting for
the English team...
...are Lt. Smith
and Lt. Burton.
What are they doing?
Come here.
What are you all doing?
All running at
the same time!
You run and grab the ball
only if it comes to you. Got it?
Now go.
Well done, Bhura!
The ball crosses the boundary
and the English get four more runs.
No ball.
Steady, Smith, steady.
Deva crossed the line
before he bowled the ball.
So the English batsman has not
been given out.
Instead, he got an extra run.
Damn! He made me run!
Bat's over.
With this ball,
Deva's over is finished.
And eight runs were made.
Now, a new bowler
will bowl the ball.
The ball will spin.
Grab the catch.
Okay.
Spin it!
Good shot, Burton.
Why isn't the ball spinning!
- Don't know.
Catch it, Lakha!
Kachra isn't spinning the ball
at all today.
He has to be taken off.
Deva, you better get
your breath back.
Bhuvan, you bowl.
- Okay.
Aim and hit!
The first English batsman is out!
Rather looking forward to this.
Well done, Smith.
- Yes, sir.
Coming to bat now...
...is the English captain,
Captain Russell.
Sharp fielding there.
Well done.
For the loss of one wicket...
...they have scored 66 runs so far.
Shatter the sticks, Goli.
- Of course.
Will throw with the right arm
and from this side.
Right arm, over the wicket.
Very good, Goli.
Sir, did you see that?
- Yes, I did.
That's excellent, Goli!
This is ridiculous.
Sir, he may not be allowed to bowl
the ball like this. It's improper.
What's the matter?
He can't bowl like this.
- Why not?
What's wrong, Sahib?
Have you ever seen
such an action, sir?
Excuse me, sir.
Is something the matter?
You see we have a problem here.
This man swings his arm more than once
before releasing the ball.
He'll have to bowl conventionally.
Sir, I think you're being unfair
to the home team.
Unfair! How can you say that?
It's only fair they ask this man
to bowl properly.
There is no rule written anywhere
about such an action, is there?
Well, there's nothing written
about it that I can recall.
There's nothing written
about this rule.
Well, we better write
some rules, Captain...
...which, unfortunately,
can happen only after this match.
Till then, let's get on with the match.
Okay. He can bowl.
To kill a tiger or cheetah!
Bah! That's nothing!
Defeat the tyrants.
Thrash the Feringhees!
Beat them! Defeat them!
Come on! Throw the ball,
break the stick!
For goodness' sake.
Brooks, look out for his arm action.
It's damn ridiculous.
Dangerous too.
The next batsman is Lt. Brooks.
Two, please.
Thank you.
Brooks.
- Sir.
Just before he releases the ball,
he makes a grunting noise.
Something like this.
Listen for it.
- Right, sir. Thank you.
Good timing.
Losing two wickets...
...they have made 132 runs.
Capt Russell is on 38
and Lt. Brooks on 32.
Catch it, Bagha!
I don't think W. G. Grace could have
made such confident strokes.
This could be.
What are you doing, Lakha!
I missed it, Kaka.
How could you miss, son!
Where's your concentration?
We have to win.
We must win this game.
Please concentrate.
Go on, Bhuvan. Bowl.
The end of the day's play, gentlemen.
The English team has scored...
...182 runs for 2 wickets.
And with this, we come to
the end of the first day's play.
Our game wasn't good today.
What were you up to, Lakha?
You played so well during practice.
Practice was different.
We were playing among ourselves.
But why're you blaming only me?
You all went gaga over Kachra.
Saw the cripple's miracle today?
I told you before...
At least he tried.
You weren't even trying!
What did he do with all that trying?
- Shut up, Lakha.
That night, Elizabeth's eye
fell on a shadowy figure.
She tried to investigate.
My being in the team was
of some help at least.
She was amazed to see Lakha there.
She went to the village at once
and informed Bhuvan about Lakha.
I... I...
...did wrong.
What I did was very wrong.
Forgive me.
Lakha, a snake like you
must be crushed!
Stop!
I'm telling you again, stop.
Drag him out, Bhuvan.
- We'll kill him!
Calm down.
All of you calm down.
I'll talk to him.
Lakha, open the door!
No, Bhuvan. I won't open
the door. They will kill me!
I won't open it.
Nobody will do anything, Lakha.
How long will you stay inside?
They'll not budge from here.
Open the door and let me in.
I made a mistake, Bhuvan.
Forgive me.
Why did you do it, Lakha?
I lost my mind, Bhuvan.
Because...
...I was in love with Gauri.
I wanted to have her at any cost.
But she loves you.
And I hated you for that.
I hated you for that!
I wanted you to lose.
I wanted to disgrace you in
Gauri's eyes...
...and the whole village as well.
For that, you risked the life
of the whole village.
You staked their future?
Do you know what you have
done, Lakha?
Save me, Bhuvan!
Save me!
Give me a chance to repent.
Just one chance!
I swear on my mother!
I'll do whatever you say.
But give me just one chance
to repent.
I can give you one chance.
But you must prove your loyalty.
If you can't, you will not
find refuge even here!
They begin the second day's play
with the score at 182.
Hail the Great Guru's warriors!
Hail the Great Guru's victory!
You gladden our hearts!
Live long!
The next batsman is Lt. Wesson.
Nice shot!
Rather enjoyable knock.
- Lovely to watch.
Oh, great shot, sir. Well played.
Let's have some more of those.
Congratulations, Wesson.
And that's lunch, gentlemen.
271 to 3 is
an extremely good score, Captain.
Yes, I think we'll be looking at
at least 600.
Something to please the crowd.
Steady.
Bhuvan, if they continue
to bat like this...
You'll have to do something.
Yes, Memsahib.
All the bowlers have tried.
I don't know what to do.
Over.
Oh! You are doing it.
Come here. Come on.
What's this!
He's given him the ball again!
I can't understand.
Crazy chap!
Goodness gracious,
the ball turned almost three feet.
Catch it, Bhura!
Gentlemen, he's on a hat trick.
He's done it, by George.
From 295 for 3,
they are now 295 for 6!
Hail Almighty Ape!
Crack the enemy's back!
Good shot, Harrison. Good shot.
Oh! So you step out and hit, do you!
Try coming out now!
Go back! Go back home!
With your tail between your legs!
You Tea drinkers!
Fleabags! Boot wearers!
Grab it, Bagha!
Catch, Bagha! Catch!
Catch it, Bagha.
You caught it!
The score is 320 and
only 2 batsmen left!
Arjan, don't drop it!
Caught it!
With the last batsman out...
...the English innings is over.
The Champaner team will have
to make 323 runs to win.
They collapsed like a house of cards.
That leaves them
a huge mountain to climb.
Absolutely, Major Cotton.
Come on, brothers!
Get rid of Lagaan!
- Get rid of Lagaan!
Come on, brothers!
That was simply great!
Kachra's magic worked.
The Whiteys just crumbled.
I felt Bhuvan was making
a big mistake giving you the ball.
But he bowled well.
Brilliantly.
The foolish Feringhees
only looked in front.
And the ball whizzed past
their butts and knocked the bails off!
All this joking is fine.
But you have to think of how
you will make these 323 runs.
It'll be done, Chief.
Listen, all of you.
Ismayeel, Lakha, Bagha,
Deva and Arjan...
We six together are responsible
for getting these 323 runs.
The others are weak in batting.
And so, all six of us must bat
cautiously and calmly.
Deva, you and I will open
the batting.
And we should both stay put
firmly till end of play today.
Okay, brother.
Careful, Bhuvan!
Steady, Bhuvan, steady.
What're you doing, Bhuvan!
Get a hold of yourself.
The people of the village get
four more runs with this.
All right, Ram Singh.
All right.
Come on, brothers!
- Get rid of Lagaan!
Yardley!
Well done, Smith!
Oh, how could this happen!
Don't forget the crease.
Yes, very bad luck.
Who is next? Oh, it's Arjan.
Just forget how that arrogant
White humiliated you.
Just stay there till the evening.
Be careful.
Well done!
Be careful, Arjan.
You won't have a morsel to eat.
Nor a piece of cloth to wear.
They are trying to needle you, Arjan.
Stay calm.
Get that darkie, Smith.
You won't have a morsel to eat.
Nor a piece of cloth to wear.
We will take double
and triple Lagaan from you!
They are trying to provoke you, Arjan.
Stay calm.
You damn slaves will remain
crushed under our boots!
Careful, Arjan. Stay calm!
Catch it, North, catch it!
Yes!
Well done.
That's the way.
Well bowled, Smith.
Yardley...
knock his bloody head off.
Yardley.
Nice bit of sport, Yardley.
That was a nasty one.
My God, he's got some strength
in those arms.
Bagha, please be careful!
Don't get carried away.
Oh, well bowled.
Go, my son.
Come again, Yardley.
Oh, God.
What happened!
Hurry!
That must have hurt.
Take him away... easy.
Careful.
Are you badly hurt?
- Yes.
How's that?
Thank God...
That was close.
It certainly was, Your Highness.
End of day's play.
Great bowling, Yardley.
Well bowled.
We've got them on the run.
We've lost five of
our best batsmen.
What'll we do now?
O Saviour!
O Pure of Essence
Our Dearly Beloved
O Saviour!
O Pure of Essence
Our Dearly Beloved
We have no one but You
Ease our troubles
O Lord
We have no one but You
You alone
are our sole support
are our protector
We have no one but You
You have filled
the moon with light
The sun shines
only because of You
Your splendour lights
the sky with stars
O Lord
If not You, who will
preserve this life!
O Saviour! O Pure of Essence!
Our Dearly Beloved
We have no one but You
If You'd heed, O Lord
we make this plea
To those who suffer
grant this courage
May not hardship
ever defeat them
To the weak
give Your protection
So they may live in peace
To devotion
give strength
You are the Lord of
all universe
Listen to this plea
When the path is full
of darkness
Give us the boon of light
O Saviour!
O Pure of Essence
Our Dearly Beloved
We have no one but You
Ease our troubles
O Lord
We have no one but You
O Saviour!
Bhuvan has completed 50 runs!
That must be the first 50 in the history
of Indian village cricket.
Come on, run!
And with this,
Isar Kaka completes ten runs.
Very good!
- Well done!
Hold it up, Wesson.
Concentrate, field.
One more!
I lost, Bhuvan.
I couldn't run.
Couldn't run...
It was my fault.
I couldn't run.
"Tormentors of the weak!
Beware! You will pay."
"The sighs of the oppressed
shall turn iron to ashes!"
Keep the flag flying, Guran.
My goodness.
- Coming from the jungle?
Stand back. Make way.
- Don't get too close, Smithy.
Watch yourself.
What on earth is he doing?
This way, sir.
What an extraordinary stance.
It looks as if he's riding a horse.
Well struck, sir.
Umpire, he can't do that.
It's not cricket.
Hit the ball only once, Guran.
Okay.
Hail Hanuman,
The Almighty Ape!
That's called "kicking the horse."
- Indeed.
Run!
- Crack the enemy's back!
He is coming, Bhuvan!
Sock it to him!
Keep it up!
Come on, Feringhee!
Rot in hell!
One more, Guran!
I'll whack so hard
you'll whine for your Ma!
So what does your Ma say, eh?
Hail Hanuman!
Why're you shouting?
Yes!
Damn and blast you!
Goli, my son. Stay put.
Only Bhura and Kachra
are left after you.
Father, play steady.
Hit hard, Goli.
- Do us proud.
Don't scare him, idiots!
Just stay there.
Steady, Goli.
Come on, Willis,
he's nervous.
Out the first ball!
Wait, Bhura. I'll go.
- In this condition?
Interesting.
They're giving you a hat trick, Willis.
But how will you run, Ismayeel?
The umpires have decided to let
another player run for Ismayeel.
When I call you, run.
Stay behind the line, understand?
Good. Go stand there.
But inside the line!
Thank God you are here, Ismayeel.
We have got to make the rest
of the runs. There's no one left.
Don't worry, Bhuvan.
By Allah's grace,
you'll see victory will be ours.
We must not lose heart, that's all.
Look at me, Tipu.
Run, Tipu.
Stop. Stay behind the line.
Run, Tipu, run.
Stop.
- Well done, lad.
Catch it!
Was it two or three?
- Three.
The last hour of play is left now.
20 overs will be bowled
during this time.
Ismayeel has hit a six!
Well played, young man.
And with this six,
Bhuvan completes a century!
I must say this country has
a brave future in this game.
And that's Ismayeel's grand 50!
Sir, how many runs must
we make to win?
You have to make
30 runs in 18 balls.
30 in 18?
How's that, umpire?
Well done, Willis!
What a shame!
Well done.
- Good thinking, sir.
- Thank you very much.
Run along.
Your mother's waiting.
No matter, Tipu.
You played very well. Good!
Father, why is Tipu coming back?
And they have to make 28 runs
in 16 balls.
Stay put at one end, Bhura.
Don't let your wicket fall.
I'll make the runs. Good.
This one's petrified, Willis.
Get him on strike.
Come on, Willis.
Two more to go.
Willis, hold it!
Smith, third man!
Flynn, under it!
Come on, Willis!
Keep it tight, men!
You're not asleep, man!
What are you doing? Get him!
That was marvellous!
Willis, keep it tight.
Pitch it up, man.
The ball is old, sir.
- Just do it!
This is the last ball of
the over, Bhura. We must take a single.
Only one run, not two!
Gentlemen, step up.
Stop the single.
I want this man on strike.
Step up!
Good shot.
That's an over.
This guy has turned it into four runs!
You have to bat now, Bhura.
Steady.
Don't let your wicket fall.
Because of Captain Russell's
cleverness...
...Bhuvan couldn't take a single.
Bhura has to bat now.
Champaner now needs
12 runs from 12 balls.
Keep it tight, Smith.
Get him on strike.
Concentrate, gentlemen, concentrate!
Go back, Bhura!
Well done, sir. One more, sir.
- One more to go.
Save us, Bhuvan my brother.
It's all in your hands now.
You did the right thing.
Go, Kachra. You have to give
Bhuvan support now.
Just stay put, Kachra.
- Don't be afraid.
Say a prayer and go.
All right, gentlemen.
We remember this chap, don't we?
Yes, we do.
Oh, dear.
Last man in and he's severely disabled.
Now, only the last batsman is left.
And they need to make 12 runs
from 11 balls.
Wesson, short legs. Stay in closer.
- Right, sir.
Playing, field!
- North!
Come on, Smith.
And again.
Come on, Smith,
he's a sitting duck.
Be careful, Kachra.
You aren't hurt, are you?
Good delivery.
Don't be afraid.
Come on, Smith!
Take him, man.
Just touch and run!
Just once!
Run!
Well done, Kachra!
Stop.
Kachra, this is the last ball.
We must take only one run.
Be ready.
Gentlemen, close in, move in.
Save the one. Keep him this end.
Run, Kachra!
Made it!
Well done!
Six balls left and ten runs
to score for victory.
Gentlemen, I want everybody
to keep on their toes.
Be alert.
Save the twos.
Save the boundaries.
But if they take the single,
let them have it.
Let the cripple take the strike.
Yardley, I'm depending on you.
Don't give away anything.
Just get him.
Gentlemen!
Well done, Yardley.
That won't do us any harm.
Are you all right,
Bhuvan Bhaiyya?
Keep it up.
Run! Take two.
Stop! Go back!
Kachra, we have to take just one run.
Touch and run!
All right, gentlemen, close in.
Close in.
Come on, you men in the field.
Come on.
Good bowling, Yardley.
We have to take a run
from this ball.
Only the last two balls
are left, understand?
We have to take the run!
Come on, Yardley.
Dig one in, Yardley.
Take the run, Kachra.
We have to take one run!
Everybody close in.
Stop the single.
Close in!
Come on, Kachra.
Strike the ball.
Only the last ball left...
Kachra, this is the last
ball of the game.
And we need five runs to win.
You will have to lift the ball
over the boundary.
Or else... triple Lagaan.
All our lives are in your hands, Kachra.
Do something!
Do something.
Come on, Yardley.
Just once more.
Field.
Hit it, Kachra!
Hit!
Hit it, Kachra.
Hit it, my son.
Lift it, Kachra.
No ball.
No ball!
What?
- No ball.
You're kidding me.
"No ball"?
What do you mean, "No ball"?
His foot was over the line.
Yardley?
Are you quite certain, umpire?
I am not discussing it
any further, sir.
I suggest we get on with the game.
Very well.
Gentlemen, we have one more ball.
Back to your positions.
Because of their no-ball,
we have got one more ball!
We can't afford any mistakes this time.
Gentlemen, back to the boundary.
Everybody back to the boundaries.
Back!
If you lose, you will pay...
...triple Lagaan.
Do you accept?
It's this impossible bet...
...that Bhuvan has accepted!
What have you done?
Back! Back! Back!
I had told you...
...we can face a great calamity.
Didn't I say so?
You talk just like your father.
He was so spirited...
...spoke the truth.
I have faith in you...
...and in your courage.
Catch it, sir!
Please don't catch it!
Yeah!
We have won!!
He's done it!
Completely unbelievable.
Unable to bear this humiliation,
the British government...
...decided to shut down
the Champaner Cantonment.
"By the power vested in me
by Her Majesty, Queen Victoria...
...I hereby declare that
after much deliberation on the matter...
...the Cantonment at Champaner
be dissolved.
And the officers and troops
of the erstwhile Cantonment...
...shall relocate
and re-establish themselves...
...in the princely state of Raj Gardh
with immediate effect.
Signed, Colonel J. R. Boyer,
Commanding Officer, Central Provinces."
I did not believe I'd live
to see this day.
Be happy, my daughter.
Live long.
Memsahib, we will never forget
all that you have done for us.
I won't either.
And so, not just Champaner but
all the villages in the province...
...did not have to pay Lagaan
for three years.
Captain Russell had to pay
for his capricious behaviour.
Besides having to pay triple Lagaan,
he was transferred...
...to the Central African desert.
Elizabeth returned to England
holding Bhuvan in her heart.
She did not marry and remained
Bhuvan's Radha all her life.
Bhuvan and Gauri had a
splendid wedding.
Raja Puran Singh himself came
to bless the newly-weds...
...enhancing Champaner's status
even more.
Even after this historic victory...
...Bhuvan's name was lost
somewhere in the pages of history.