I'm inviting you to breakfast.
I can't, I have to go to the church.
Well, after the church then?
C'mon, we haven't seen
you for so long.
Take this, I don't want
your little baby to get sick.
It's so cold out.
- C'mon.
- OK.
You'll come?
Oh yeah.
Great.
- Could you put that whole thing on...?
- Oh yeah.
http: //subscene. com
subtitle by arigon
edited by rogard
- You owe me 5 dollars.
- Oh oh...
Until I sit at the table, I don't owe you anything.
Something is going on with him.
I am worried.
You keep saying that, I think you're--
I think the other things may be kicking in.
In all the world...
there are books and books and books of Lords.
But in all this world there
really is only one Lord.
We need never ask:
'Lord, what should I do'?
Because the Lord has told us
what to do.
Love one another.
That my friends, is the one true Lord.
Love is God in action.
The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ,
The love of God...
The fellowship of the Holy Spirit
be with you for now and for evermore.
Amen.
- This is when you want some help.
- Oh, thank you, dear.
It's my turn to drop them off at the hospital.
You know... you're a good looking fellow, Lars.
Where's your girlfriend?
I don't have one.
- Are you gay?
- No.
My grandson is gay,
I know all about the gays.
I know, but I am not gay, so...
Well... don't leave it too long,
it's not good for you.
Here.
Give this to somebody nice, for a start.
Hello, Lars.
- I guess I'll see you at work tomorrow.
- Yeah, okay, fine.
Karin, remember, he is 27 years old.
Maybe he wants to be left alone.
- That's not what he wants.
- Oh, really?
- How do you know that, exactly?
- Because...
that's not how people are.
Ah, there he goes.
Lars, c'mon, you promised.
- Is that normal?
- Five dollars.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Cindy.
Did you have a nice weekend?
That new girl is kinda cute, huh?
You and Margo? What do you think?
Lars, you gotta see this.
I am not in the mood for porn this morning.
It's not porn.
Okay... it is, but check it out, alright?
You like?
Man it's solid. Like if she'd weigh 125 pounds,
then she weighs 125 pounds.
You can customize everything,
they got all different heads and parts.
You can design your own woman.
- And Lars, Lars.
- Yeah.
They're anatomically correct.
Not gonna buy one, aren't ya?
I wish...
Look how much they cost.
Wiped out for a new Xbox.
Morning.
- Morning.
- Oh hey, yeah, good morning.
Margo is here, everybody. Hooray.
Could you put the...?
Yeah, I was thinking. We're the only ones
from the lake, we could car-pool.
Lars, it's your day for coffee, buddy.
Oh yeah.
You know what your problem is, Margo?
You're just too aggressive.
Just... chill-lax, ya know.
Shut up.
Wait, stop. Stop!
Karin, what? What?
We want you to come for dinner.
Will you come?
- You scared me.
- Sorry.
Sweetheart, sorry.
Wait.
- I can't... I can't.
- Why not? No.
Why not?
Lars, we miss you.
I brought my work home,
so I have to... I'll get in trouble.
No, you didn't.
Yeah? Did you hear that?
That's my phone, I think.
Come on, wait.
Lars, stop. Stop!
- Come on, please?
- I... I have other plans...
and I can't.
There is salmon, and cherry pie in there.
- Would you please let me go?
- No.
Okay.
- Is that all you can eat?
- Yeah, that was delicious. Thank you.
No no, you stay there.
It's my turn.
You boys talk.
Okay. Karin's been worried about you.
She thinks you got a problem...
because you spend so much time by yourself.
- I'm fine.
- That's what I told her.
It's exactly what I said.
Dad was kinda like that too, so...
Yeah, but he didn't want anyone around him.
So that's a difference.
That's not true.
Okay, you know, yeah sure,
maybe after Mom died, but...
You didn't know them before that, so...
I mean nothing you could have.
I'm just saying...
Karin and I would really like it
if you moved in.
- No, that's okay, thank you.
- The house is half yours.
Yeah, I know. But I'm fine, thanks.
Just putting that there.
- Good night. Sleep tight.
- Good night.
Oh wait. Here are some leftovers for you.
Do you have my blanket?
- Oh yeah, it's on...
- I'll get, I'll get it. Grab these.
Be right back.
It's a beautiful blanket.
- Gus says your mother made it for you.
- Yeah.
When she was pregnant.
Well she must've loved you very much,
like we do.
- Are you mad at me?
- Is he coming?
Here we go.
- Good night.
- Thanks. Good night.
What?
We talked. He's fine.
Six weeks later...
- Hello?
- Hey, Lars. Karin.
They just delivered a huge box for you.
It's in the garage.
- Oh... Okay, thanks.
- Okay, bye.
Thanks.
That's a nice sweater.
Hey.
Come on in.
That's okay. Can Karin
come to the door?
- Karin.
- Yeah?
Honey, come here, it's Lars.
- Oh... Really?
- Yup.
She is just.... doing that several kinda...
It's pregnant women's yoga.
That's good good stuff.
- Hey.
- Hi.
What's up?
I have a visitor.
You have a...?
- Yeah.
- A visitor?
That... it's great.
Yeah.
- And she's not from here.
- She?
Wow. What do you... what do you..
what do you know... did... where...?
Where did you meet this person?
- On the Internet.
- Yeah, everybody's doing that now.
That's great.
She doesn't speak much English though.
It's okay. It's the same...
It's really the same with the guys at work.
It's... not that big a deal.
Okay.
Yeah, well, ya know, she is in a wheelchair,
so I just don't want you to feel weird about it.
- No, no.
- We don't care.
And I have to ask you really,
I know it's a really big favor.
Yeah?
She's just really religious,
and because we're both young
and single, it just doesn't feel right for
us to stay in the garage...
- Oh no, no... We'll put her in the pink room.
- No, she can sleep here.
- In the pink room?
- Yeah... sure.
And there are new towels.
Just give us half an hour,
you know, pick up... and get something in the oven,
- Okey dokey.
-...get the place ready.
Yes.
- Okay, let's get us get started.
- Right.
That is...
You quiet ones...
You know what they say about the...
It's great.
- See you in a little bit.
- Okay.
Bianca is a missionary.
Or was a missionary. Right, sorry.
Because she was raised by nuns.
But now she is on a sabbatical
so she can experience the world.
Isn't that neat?
She's shy.
Well, you are.
Everything is so new...
for her, right?
- Are you hungry?
- We are starving.
Gus, will you give me a hand
in the kitchen?
That was that.
I know.
- He is crazy, right? He's crazy, Karin.
- Shhh.
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't know.
My God...Karin.
We got to put him in a hospital, I think.
Can't just put him in a hospital.
I can't afford that.
I can't believe this.
My little brother is totally, totally insane.
Put yourself together.
Gus, shh, calm down. Calm down, okay?
He's talking to a doll, baby.
We just gonna get through this somehow okay?
- I just don't know how am I gonna do that.
- I don't either,
but you're gonna be calm, okay?
Okay.
- I am sorry.
- It's okay.
Karin, Karin, she's not gonna eat.
So you're never gonna believe this...
Makes me mad.
Bianca's from the tropics...
She was-- She is Brazilian.
Half Brazilian, half Danish, that's right...
and...
somebody stole her luggage.
Yeah, and they stole her wheelchair.
That's terrible.
Yeah. Can you believe that, Gus?
- Yeah, I can believe it.
- Right.
Well it... it makes me angry.
Anyway...
I wanted to ask you a favor.
She doesn't lie, I promise you.
Karin, you don't mind lending Bianca some clothes, do you?
She doesn't have any.
Do you?
I'm not sure we are the same type, Lars.
That's okay, Karin, because...
Bianca doesn't really care about
superficial things like that. So it's okay.
- Sure.
- Yeah, that's right.
See? I told you.
Thanks.
This used to be my mom's room.
So... if you need anything, Gus and Karin
are right across the hall.
I'm in the garage.
But you know that, so...
What else?
Your towels are brand new,
thanks to Karin.
Lars, I... I think we should...
think we should go to bed, you know.
Just see you in one second.
I just wanted to say that I'm so glad
you're finally here.
Lars, I...
I think right now we...
Yeah, okay. Good night.
Wait, Gus had a good idea.
He's... he's concerned about Bianca's health.
You know just with the traveling, and...
and change of climate and everything...
What stress, you know?
I'll make an appointment with Dr. Birnman
for tomorrow. For early tomorrow.
- We'll all go.
- Yeah, you remember Dagmar?
- You think that's a good idea?
- I do, I think we should do it.
Yeah, that's a good idea, because I was gonna go
shopping for a wheelchair anyway.
- So, good night.
- Good night.
I'll see you tomorrow.
'Real Doll'
Natasha escaped from Moscow,
where she was forced to strip
for the Russian mob.
Now all she wants is an all American male to love.
Nadori left a high paying job in Tokyo
because she was unsatisfied as a woman.
Tammy dropped out the high school
to join the rodeo.
Are you the right cowboy to tame this wild billy?
The doctor will tell us what to do.
But she is family practice.
We gonna need a shrink.
No, she is.
She's a psychologist too.
She says you have to be, this far north.
What would people think?
We can't worry about that.
Right.
Right there is where my dad used to work.
Our dad.
That's the library. I have a card
you can borrow if you want to.
Well, actually I'll have to take them out for you.
But you just tell...
I don't know actually, Gus...
What was it that dad did?
Water and power.
My job is at the school department.
I miss everybody, but there's so much to do in the house.
I'll go back, just as soon as the baby's old enough
and... you're...
Yeah sure.'Readers Digest'.
Then there is 'Living' or 'Country'.
That's what I would say.
Her blood pressure is low.
- Is that serious?
- Could be. I'll have to wait and see.
It's fine.
Mine is probably low too.
I want you to bring her in every week
for special treatment.
Can you do that?
Yeah, are you sure that that is necessary?
- Yes.
- Okay, okay.
What do you think?
All that's what she says, I'm sure.
You can set that up with Jo-Anne,
at the desk.
I look forward to getting to know you, Bianca.
Karin, I'm telling you, he belongs in a hospital.
No.
No. My uncle Garth went to one of these places
and he never came back.
But he needs more help than
you and I are able to give.
I told you that something was wrong
and you wouldn't listen.
If I may?
Has Lars been functional? Does he
go to work, wash, dress himself?
So far.
- Has he had any violent episodes?
- No, never.
He's a sweetheart.
He never even raises his voice.
Okay.
We got to fix him, can you fix him?
I don't know, Gus.
I don't believe he's psychotic or schizophrenic.
I don't think this is caused by genes
or faulty wiring in the brain.
So what the hell is goin' on then?
- He appears to have a delusion.
- A delusion?
What the hell is he doing with a delusion,
for Christ's sake?
That's what we have to find out.
Chances are, he's been decompensating for some time.
Guess we didn't realize.
Have there been any changes in the family
in the last year or so?
No, everything is pretty much exactly the same,
except that Karin is pregnant and Lars is nuts.
You know, this isn't necessarily a bad thing.
What we call mental illness
isn't always just an illness...
It can be a communication,
it can be a way to work something out.
Fantastic. When will it be over?
When he doesn't need it anymore.
How can we help?
- Go along with it.
- Oh no. No that's...
No no...
No I mean...
Pretend that she is real? I'm not gonna do that,
I mean, I can't. I'm just not gonna do it.
- She is real.
- Well...
- She's right out there.
- Right, I get that.
I'm just not gonna--
You know, I'm just not gonna--
I'm not gonna do it, so...
You won't be able to change his mind anyway.
- Bianca's in town for a reason.
- Right, but... but...
It's not really a choice.
Then we'll do it, whatever it takes.
Oh yeah, yeah, yup.
And everyone is gonna laugh at him.
And you.
She loves kids.
- More coffee, Lars?
- Yes, please.
May I see your funny face?
Does Bianca want some?
Yeah.
- Here we go.
- Thank you, Karin.
Gus, no? Okay.
Sure.
You're not gonna go to work today, Gus?
I don't feel good.
Bianca could help you,
you know, she has nurse's training.
No, she doesn't.
She doesn't have nurse's training, Lars,
because she's not a person.
She's a big plastic thing.
That's amazing.
Did you hear that?
Bianca just said that that's why
God made her, to help people.
You're gonna be late...
for work?
I am gonna be late.
Well, I have to go. Okay.
- I'm going to check in...
- Okay.
- And you have my number at work, right Karin?
- Yup.
I wanted to tell you that you
look really pretty today.
I hope that you'll feel better, Gus.
- Me too.
- And thanks so much for breakfast.
- Ok, gotta go. Bye.
- See you.
Well, I had to try, you know.
What? What?
It's just...
I don't know.
It is true. We've been all wrapped up
in ourselves. We have, Gus.
This is not my fault though.
Not my fault.
Come on, Bianca.
Let's make a couple of calls.
Good morning, Cindy.
You look pretty today.
Thank you.
Oh, Mr. Sunshine.
It's a while advanced,
but...
you know how excited
I get about these things.
- Alright, where are they? I know you took them.
- I did not.
- That's revenge.
- For what?
For the fake... I put on your floor.
- Oh, that.
- Lars, I'm missing 3 of my action figures.
It's your turn to get coffee.
Okay, listen up Margo, those action figures
are extremely important to me, alright?
They worth a lot of money, and if I don't see
every damn one back on my desk pretty soon,
then you can tell your Teddy bear
to watch his back.
I'll return them... one at a time.
You're going to Cindy's party?
Oh, no.
I was hoping you would,
I really wish you would.
Well, maybe.
That'd be great.
Do you think I can bring my girlfriend?
Yeah, yeah, I'm totally bringing somebody.
- I didn't know there were sex dolls.
- Love dolls, that's what they call 'em.
- I saw a special in 'People'.
- So you are serious? Bianca has a...
So she is really just one of the girls...
I am sorry.
[speaking Spanish (?)]
No way.
She has a sister?
I wish I had a woman that couldn't talk.
It's not that funny. It's not that funny.
We don't want anything to do with her.
She is a 'golden calf'.
- We all know what happened with that.
- Well, he's not worshipping her.
- They're just dating?
- These young people have no willpower.
He is sick, alright. He's sick.
Yes. We were just hoping if we came to you,
you could help.
You know, just pave the way a little.
If you could just try to understand it...
We can try.
This is all, for heaven's sake.
What's the big deal?
Sally, your cousin puts dresses on his cats.
Hazel, your nephew gave all his money
to a UFO club.
And Ernie, everybody knows your
first wife was a klepto.
- She wasn't.
- Then why has she buried a pair of my earrings?
Now that's enough.
These things happen.
Lars is a good boy.
You can depend on me.
Thanks Mrs. Gruner.
He's not bringing it to the church,
is he, Reverend Bock?
The question is, as always...
What would Jesus do?
I would like to take the opportunity
to welcome all of our new visitors
to our church today.
Bianca, it's good to see you.
Lars, God bless, God bless.
- Thank you so much, Reverend.
- You're welcome, my dear.
These are for you, Bianca.
This is my friend, Mrs. Gruner.
She has a darling figure.
Those are nice, huh?
They are not real,
so they'll last forever.
Isn't that neat?
Get back here.
Watch watch watch... there we go.
Are you comfortable?
Yeah?
I'll get the chair.
Oh can you... can you put a seat belt on her?
Bianca, Gus' gonna put on your seat belt.
Can you put that on her legs because
she gets cold. Thank you.
Thanks Gus.
Where are you guys...
Where are you going?
Just one second.
She doesn't know. It's a secret,
but I can tell you.
It's just she's asking me lots of
questions all the time.
She wants to know everything about me so...
I thought I would take her to the lake
where we used to play.
- Yeah.
- Do you remember that?
Yeah.
It sounds... yeah, that sounds nice.
I gotta go.
I'm coming.
Why are you yelling?
Gus and his friends used to come here often.
In the summer they would go fishing,
and in the winter,
they would play hockey.
they would build cool forts, like,
snow hoards.
Watch your head.
Okay this is a treehouse, and a rope swing,
and a ladder.
(Mental illness delusion)
(Delusional Disorder)
You should watch me chop wood too.
I'm really good at it.
I am sorry.
I couldn't wait any longer, I wanted to
see how she was doing
After the treatment she has to rest
Doesn't work without the resting
Keep me company.
Lars,
keep me company.
Do you know how many sessions
she's gonna have to have?
No, I don't, it's a tricky illness, Lars.
But you know what I could use is
a more complete history on her, like parents...
Oh, they died when she was a baby.
- That's not fair.
- Yeah, but...
She doesn't feel sorry for herself or anything,
she just wants to be normal.
Have everyone treating her normal.
That's nice. I admire that.
Yeah, me too.
Is that your husband?
Yes, he died.
Oh no, I am sorry.
- You have kids?
- No.
You must feel really lonely.
Sometimes I get so lonely that I forget
what day it is and how to spell my name.
How about you?
You are funny.
So what's the difference between a delusion
and a hallucination?
It's false perception versus false belief.
So if Mous thinks the FBI's after him...
- The DEA.
- INS.
- IRS, ATF, AAA.
- I doubt it would be a delusion.
Now dude, they're all after us.
My dad told me that...
that wood warms you.
Three times:
First when you chop down your tree.
Then when you chop it up,
then when you burn it.
What are we doing?
Why are we doing this for him?
Oh c'mon.
That's funny.
Is it?
I don't know.
I don't know, maybe not.
So tell me about Karin.
I don't know her very well.
Oh, she is wonderful.
Gus and I are both very lucky with
Women. She's wonderful.
But she--
We don't have to talk.
Let's find you something to read.
No, it's just...
-...between us.
- Of course.
I'm worried about her.
I think she has a little problem.
- Oh, maybe you shouldn't tell me.
- No, it's okay. It's just...
I think it's because
she is insecure but...
she's just always trying to hug everybody.
You know, some people don't like that.
Some people don't like to be hugged.
But she doesn't realize that.
She takes it personally.
And things...
You know, it hurts her feelings.
I don't know what to do about that.
Do you?
But it's such a comfort sometimes
just to have somebody's arms
around you, don't you think?
- No.
- C'mon, it feels good.
It does not feel good.
It hurts.
Like a cut or a bruise?
Like a burn.
Like, like when you go outside and...
your feet freeze and then you come back in
and they thaw out.
It's like that.
It's almost exactly like that.
Same with everybody?
I'm not really with Bianca.
But everyone else.
So you don't let people touch you.
Lars, isn't that hard to get away with?
I'm not really here, because
I have all these layers.
- And that helps.
- Look...
We can't change Karin.
But...
I can help you.
That's fine.
- Pain?
- Yeah, but I can take it.
You okay?
That's enough for today.
Yeah, thanks.
Yeah, okay.
It's scientifically proven that everyone's
favourite word is their own names so...
if you just say their names a lot...
You okay?
You can see that it's gonna make them happy.
Mr. Sunshine, and this must be Bianca.
Welcome, welcome. Come on in.
I have my boots on,
I should've brought my shoes.
Don't worry about it.
Baxter, Baxter baby...
Lars, this is my husband.
Hi.
Bianca.
How are you?
Is that for me, Bianca?
Thank you.
Can Baxter get you two something to drink
from the kitchen?
Lars...?
Beer.
And for Bianca?
She doesn't drink.
She doesn't like it when I drink either
but I'm still gonna have one.
I can help you with the coats.
This is Margo, this is Bianca.
Hi.
Hi Bianca.
I'm glad you sent us that memo,
or I'd be freaked.
So bizarre.
- It's a disorder
- What a nerder.
Lars?
Look at them.
He's in love with that sluggy hunk of silicone.
- Her name is Bianca.
- Does he have sex with her?
Hell yes, that's what she's for, yeah.
Eww, Eww.
So I hear you guys are getting married?
- Yes.
- No.
I would kill that hair like hers.
Or I'd cut it like to here long
and short in the back.
Lars would never let her cut it.
Guys and long hair...
I don't care.
I know how she likes it,
that's how I like it.
That's my kind of guy.
I need wine.
I'll get it.
- Anything else?
- Oh no, thanks.
Lars, Bianca - a total babe.
Thanks.
Best thing is, man:
she even knows how hot she is.
That's what you want in a woman.
They stay with you because they don't know
how to get somebody better.
Know what I am saying?
Is she...flexible?
Yes.
Did you have fun?
I'm just happy, that's all.
'And so he solaced himself with pacing
up and down the little meadow'
'and writing and carving on the bark of the trees'
'and on the fine sand a multitude of verses.'
'All in harmony with his sadness,
and some in praise of Dulcinea.'
'But what distressed him greatly was not having
another hermit there to confess him.'
Pain?
It's okay.
That's okay. I can take that.
You must be excited,
about the baby on the way.
Don't you want to be an uncle?
- Do you ever wanna be a mom?
- I don't know.
Yes.
But I'm not able to have children of my own.
That's too bad.
Bianca is like that actually.
Yeah, she can't have babies either.
That's a shame.
When she was a baby,
her mother died in the middle of things, so
when she was being born.
Like yours.
You have a lot in common.
Lars, you know we...
we've learned a lot.
Since then, I think your things are better.
- Yeah, but it could still happen, right?
- It's highly unlikely.
It's... it's... rare.
Yes, but it'd still occur.
Lars.
Just take... take a breath.
It's okay.
I am sorry.
I am sorry. It's just so dangerous.
- It's so dangerous...
- Lars, sit down.
Put your head between your knees.
Put your head between your knees. Sit down.
Just put your head between your knees.
Bend over. Bend over.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Take a breath.
I hope they have cell phones.
We should get cell phones, huh?
Then we can call each other
whenever we want...
You know, you are doing all your things...
and I like you.
You're special.
How about afternoons?
Mondays, Wednesdays...
and then maybe all day Saturday?
Yeah, yeah. You're sure?
Ah, okay.
Bianca, is that okay with you?
Bianca wants to volunteer at
the hospital on Thursday afternoons.
You do?
What about your blood pressure?
Think of all the bald children
wouldn't they just love her?
That's true.
I'll just add a little bit of layering here,
and some texture...
kinda right there...
I don't remember what you guys think, but...
I like that.
That looks sweet.
You sure?
This is not growing back, right?
What's that sound?
By Veronica Charles.
I hear the telephone.
Ring ring ring.
- Hey.
He is not getting any better, is he?
No, probably not.
He's gonna love that thing...
his whole life and it's all my fault.
No, it's not, it's...
I don't know.
I mean, I left him as fast as I could.
I never thought about him.
And then the two of us
moved back here all fat and happy.
And he moves into the goddamn garage
like a family dog.
And I let him.
No wonder he goes and orders a fiancé in a box.
Come here.
Hello?
Bianca?
We are upstairs.
What's going on?
There's a hospital volunteer banquet.
- At the VFW.
- Doesn't she look beautiful?
Oh, she does. She looks beautiful.
We were supposed to play Scrabble.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Her schedule's on the refrigerator.
Did you check?
No, I didn't.
I guess I've forgotten.
Can I have a moment alone with her, please?
Thank you.
You are my girlfriend. I shouldn't have to
check your schedule to see you.
When you make a plan, you make a plan.
You have ten people around you all the time...
You can't have one of them to make a phone call
and let me know?
They never fight.
I thought we were going to play Scrabble,
I get excited about playing Scrabble....
I don't like his tone.
Now you listen to me.
Bianca has a life of her own.
No self-respecting woman is gonna be
at your beck and call, Mister.
- And the sooner you learn that the better.
- Oh yeah?
You're away to job all day.
What's she supposed to do?
Wait for you?
Would you do that for her?
Would she even ask you to?
She is out in the community, doing things for others
less fortunate. You should be proud of her.
- And what about me?
- Big baby,
you are just like my husband.
Should be home at eleven.
Call it girlfriend. I shouldn't have to check
a schedule to see her.
You okay?
How would she feel if I just left her.
Abandon her.
Wait wait, she didn't abandon you,
she will be back.
How do I know that?
People do whatever they want.
- They don't care.
- No, we all care.
Lars, we do care.
No, you don't.
That is... that is just not true.
God!
Every person in this town bends all backwards
to make Bianca feel at home.
Why... why do you think she has
so many places to go
and so much to do, huh?
- I don't know.
- Because of you.
Because all these people love you.
We push her wheelchair.
We drive her to work,
We drive her home.
We wash her, we dress her.
We get her up, we put her to bed.
We carry her.
And she is not petite, Lars,
Bianca is a big big girl.
None of this is easy for any of us,
but we do it.
We do it for you!
So don't you dare tell me how we don't care.
- I think it's the person's job who is upset to say...
- Umm... hey.
- Oh hey.
- Hey.
How was the game?
The cheese inspectors beat
the crap out of us.
Is everything alright?
I mean, I usually put Bianca to bed.
Yeah, you know.
Umm... okay.
Tell him...
Well, we wanted to talk to you about that.
You don't have to do that anymore.
I'm gonna do that.
You sure? Because I don't...
I don't mind, I thought that you...
Sorry.
- It's just been one of these days.
- It's... it's fine.
It's up to you, and...
Good.
- But I'll better leave you guys.
- Hey Gus.
- What's that?
- Thank you though.
- I didn't do anything.
- Yeah, you did.
I'm tired.
- Did I miss something?
- We had a big fight.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Lars, have you met Erik?
- Not officially.
You're pretty famous around here.
Well...
Healthy grip too, pal.
Yes?
In my office.
I think I'm gonna stay.
She's feeling pretty lousy today.
We'll both stay.
I asked her to marry me last week.
Congratulations.
When's the happy day?
- She said no.
- Oh. Oh no.
- Yeah, I know. I couldn't believe it.
- Yeah...
Stop it. You have no right to talk to me
like that. No, you don't.
No, you don't. I don't talk to you like that.
Could you stop yelling?
I was talking to Bianca, and...
she was saying that in her culture,
they have these rites of passages and...
rituals and ceremonies, and...
this whole kind of things, you know,
that when you do them,
or at least when you're done,
if you live through them
that you know you're an adult.
Doesn't that sound great?
It does.
How do you know?
How do I know what?
That you are a man?
Nah, I couldn't tell you.
Okay, was it sex?
Yeah, you know, yeah, yeah.
It's a... yeah, kind of...no.
Well it's a kind of sex,
but it's not... it's not... umm, you know...
I... I don't know,
I don't know, it's a...
good... good question.
Yeah, but I have to know.
Hold that thought.
You know you should ask Dagmar.
I did ask Dagmar.
She said that I should ask you.
- You know I... I can only give you my opinion.
- That's all I want.
Well, it's not like you are
one thing or the other, okay?
There's still a kid inside
but you... you grow up...
when you decide to do right? Okay?
And not what's right for you,
what's right for everyone.
Even when it hurts.
Okay...
Like what?
Like...
You know, like: you don't jerk people around, you know
and... and you don't cheat on your woman
and you take care your family,
you know, you admit when you're wrong.
Or you try to anyways.
That's all I can think of, you know?
It sounds like it's easy,
but for some reasons, it's not.
I know. Because nothing is easy.
It's like the old man, he didn't have
to take care of two kids alone.
He could have given us to an orphanage
or something, you know. People do that.
But he loved us, and he
tried to do right,
even though he didn't know how,
and even though he had a broken heart.
I shouldn't have left you alone with him.
He was too sad, it scared me...
And I just...
I just ran,
and that was selfish
and I'm sorry.
That's okay.
Okay.
You've crossed the line.
- Well you kept swiping my action figures.
- I hide them, I don't hang them.
Well, whatever, Margo, you're
too old for that thing anyway, okay?
- Take off the news.
- No.
- Take it off.
Face it, Margo, the bear is dead, okay?
Burn on you.
I warned her.
It's not just the bear.
I broke up with Erik.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, you know, I didn't even have a good reason.
At least one that's very interesting.
Why was he your boyfriend?
Because I was lonely.
Oh yeah?
Thank you.
Sure.
What are you doing on Friday night?
School board meeting.
Bianca got elected so...
- That's great.
- Yeah.
Why?
I was just thinking that maybe
we could all go out... sometime.
Never mind.
After I drop off Bianca,
I'm free.
But it's just me, so...
That would be great, Lars.
Thank you.
Nice shot.
- You've pretty too much spin on the ball.
- I know.
- Sorry, we're full up.
- Next thing is a lady tournament.
No way, dude.
Let them lady go.
You know aint nothing.
No shreddin' me.
Is that Lars?
- Hey, buddy.
- We're full.
No ploblema.
- Margo, kick your butt.
- No, Nelson. I'll kick your butt.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Hey baby you're bowling on my life.
This is exactly what I needed.
Things look so much better.
Hey, thanks for going bowling with me, Lars.
I don't wanna give you the wrong idea
about this.
I never could cheat on Bianca.
Ever.
No. Oh my God, I hope you didn't think that, Lars.
I would never do that.
Okay, good.
Yeah. Me neither.
'Cos a man doesn't cheat on his woman,
that's a...
Absolutely...
and vice versa.
Besides, I don't mean to steal anybody's boyfriend.
ONe day I'll find a man of my own and...
We'll be happy too.
Yeah, that's the way it works, I guess.
Thanks.
Snow.
I was hoping that winter was over.
No, that's just a thaw.
Winter isn't over till Easter.
Thanks again.
Good night, Lars.
I'm not sure how well these treatments are working.
No?
What do you think?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
I don't know, it's hard.
It's hard because...
I know that she loves me. But I ask
her to marry me, and she says no.
She says, I don't know.
Or she doesn't say anything.
Nothing?
When I was a child,
I'd speak as a child.
I understood as a child.
Does that feel good?
Wake up!
She won't wake up.
Bianca. I think she's unconscious, hey.
- Are you sure?
- Look at me, Bianca.
Hey, hey hey hey hey.
- Bianca is unconscious.
- Can you hear me? Bianca.
Wake up.
She looks alright, she looks alright.
She looks alright... hey hey hey hey.
- Call 911.
- Okay, okay.
911?
Well, I don't know.
Why do you always expect
me to know what to do?
They are there, call Dr. Birnman.
# O is for the only one I see #
# V is very very extraordinary #
# E is even more than anyone
that you adore #
I'm sorry, you'll have to wait out here.
# Love is all that I can give to you...#
Doctor's on the way.
- Hello? Hello?
- Lars, Lars.
What?
Bianca is very sick.
No, she's not, she's not.
C'mon, she's not sick.
She's not, Lars.
She's dying.
- But...?
- Oh God.
We're gonna keep her here until
she's stable, but...
she wants to go home with Lars tonight.
- Can I see her?
- Sure.
What?
I'm sorry, but I...
I just don't get it. I don't.
I mean, what's that gonna do to him?
How could you let this happen?
No, I'm not letting it happen, it's Lars.
It's always been Lars.
He's making the decisions.
He's the one who found her unconscious.
He's the one who said she's dying.
You okay back there?
They gave her something, so she's asleep.
Anything you want, Lars?
I want to stay together with her
in the pink room tonight.
Come down to the family room, Lars.
Let Bianca rest.
We sent Gus and Karin to the movies.
They didn't want to leave you too.
I'm glad they left.
I feel terrible with all this is happening
so close to the baby coming.
This how life is, Lars.
Everything at once.
We brought casseroles.
Thank you.
Is there something I should
be doing right now?
No, dear.
You eat.
We came over to sit.
That's what people do when tragedy strikes.
They come over and sit.
Don't you feel a little better?
I got spring fever. We're going to the lake.
You wanna come?
Hey Lars, why don't you come with us?
It'll do everybody good.
Bianca, don't you want to see
this beautiful day?
- Is there a storm coming?
- The weather said no.
It looks like a storm to me.
Well, I need to stretch my legs.
Let's take a chance.
Lars.
I think we're gonna watch the water.
Well, we won't be far.
- Holler if you need us.
- Okay.
So you think it's not the right color?
I don't know. Does it match the curtains?
- I think so, here, just be careful.
- Okay.
No no, don't run.
Lars.
Lars!
Lars asked us not to wear black today.
He did so to remind us that this
is no ordinary funeral.
We are here to celebrate Bianca's
extraordinary life.
From her wheelchair, Bianca
reached out and touched us all
in ways we could have never imagined.
She was a teacher.
She was a lesson in courage.
And Bianca loved us all.
Especially Lars.
Especially him.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm sorry, I just...
I don't know... it's just...
funerals and mom and dad, you know.
- He's unbelievable.
- Yes.
I wanted to thank you for...
Gus.
- So shall we see you in the house?
- Of course.
Sure.
She asked me not to be sad
but I can't help it.
Yeah, me neither.
But it'll all get better with time.
That's what everyone keeps saying, so...
It's true, I think, in a way.
But there'll never be anybody like her.
I suppose we should...
catch up with everyone.
Would you want to take a walk?
Yes.
transcript by arigon
edited by rogard, feb 21 2008