Resync Perfectly By Lurazo
Obviously, I miscalculated a few things.
Eddie
I know you're in there,
Why is it that, the moment your life
exceeds your wildest dreams...
"The Knife" appears in your back.
Well, I'll tell you one thing...
I will never let them touch me.
My neighbor, must have
opened his door to complain.
For a guy with a 4 digit IQ,
I must have missed something...
And I hadn't missed much.
I'd come this close to having
an impact in the world.
And now, the only thing
I had an impact on...
was the sidewalk.
You see that guy?
That was me,
Not so long ago.
What kind of guy, without a drug or
alcohol problem looks this way?
Only a writer.
strangely enough, nobody believed
that I actually had a book contract.
Well it's best rated as a sci-fi novel...
but it's really uh, my own
personal manifesto about the plight
of the individual in the 21 century.
and I sort a created a Utopian society,
where, we all sort of uh uh uh...
It's really... It, it's really, it's re-
uh.
Today was the day,
I was gonna kick its ass
Here we go. Here we go.
Here we go. Here we go
Man, It's gonna be great.
Just gotta put in the time and
stay in the room.
That's the key concept.
Don't leave the room!
A few weeks passed this way
Maybe a few months.
At least I still had Lindi.
Just like that?
Come on, Eddie...
This is hardly a surprise.
I, I'm surprised?
Let's just not do this.
I am gonna hand in 90 pages
tomorrow on Friday
You just wait to see what she says.
- Eddie!
- What?
I know how it's going.
I am, I was, your girlfriend.
That word doesn't even begin to describe
what you are to me.
Partner? Squeeze?
Paramour. Inamorata
Cleaning Lady. Bank.
Well be there that..
Well what's mine is yours too.
and you know that I want to share
the rest of my life with you.
- In fact, I was thinking...
- that we should probab...
- Don't propose.
Why not?
Because it worked out so well for you
last time.
it's true, I did marry once,
right out of college - to melissa..
I do!
briefly.
This isn't working.
Well, even though everything you
said is true, I still love you.
I gotta get back to work.
You didn't even tell me
what happened.
- I got it!
- You did?
I'm an Editor.
I have my own assistant.
You believe that?
Yeah, Of course I believe you.
You deserve it.
Thanks.
She was right. Why stick it out?
I had clearly missed the on-ramp.
We both knew what was beckoning.
The lower bunk
of my childhood bedroom in Jersey.
My Father happy to welcome me into
the challenging field of dental
supply inventory.
Eddy Morra!
Of all the useless relationships better
forgotten and put away in mothballs
Is there any more useless than,
the ex-brother in law?
Holy Shit, man!
How's it been, like Nine years?
- God!
- Hey!
You alright? You look like you're
livin' on the streets. What's going on?
Not much. Uh, I just broke up... What am I,
what's up uh, I'm writing... Writing a lot
Oh, you still trying to write?
Matter of fact, I have a book contract
- Really? - Yeah.
- That's great.
how about you? Are you uh...
You still dealing?
- Do I look like I am still dealing?
- No, you don't. No.
Come on, let's get a drink
I wanna hear about this book.
I don't know, it's two o'clock
in the afternoon.
When has that ever stopped you?
So.
- So...
- How is Melissa doing?
- Here.
- Thanks.
Wouldn't know, I don't see you her.
She moved upstate.
She got some kind of Internet,
home-sales kinda job.
Couple of kids.
Couple of kids... Who's the husband?
He walked out on her,
if you really wanna know.
But what do you care, man?
You were married for like five minutes.
Look, I don't wanna talk about her.
I want to talk about you. Okay?
Tell me about this book.
How's it going?
Well it's a... I'm behind.
I'm behind on my book,
and uh, It's pretty booked...
including my days and nights,
if you really want to know.
- Well, how much have you written on it?
- Not one word.
- Creative problems, um?
- Yeah.
Well I suppose, I can help you with that.
Just this once.
Oh, No, no, no...
You don't even know what it is.
- You're still dealing.
- Brother, I am light-years from that now.
I've been doing some consulting
for a pharmaceutical company.
What, like some off-shore lab
making fake Viagra? Come on Vern.
No. This is an exclusive product,
that's coming on the stream next year.
They've had clinical tries,
and it's F.D.A. approved.
Alright, just out of curiosity
and that's all...
Let me see it.
What's in it?
They've identified these, receptors in
the brain that activate specific circuits.
And you know how they say that we can access
only 20% of our brain?
Well what this does,
it lets you access all of it.
Vernon, look at me.
Do I look good to you?
I'm broke and I'm depressed off my ass.
I don't think that my life's
gonna take some sudden upswing
into fame and fortune,
by taking some shiny brain exotic drug.
Get. When?
Tell him we can't do that.
No. You tell em.
No. Now!
Well, I'm afraid I'm gonna have
to leave you here Eddie.
But I really, I really do wanna
do this again. So, call me.
And, that's on the house.
I don't want it.
Do not be ungrateful.
You know how much that costs?
Eight hundred bucks... A pop.
You're welcome.
All the way home,
I thought about Melissa.
How could she be a failure too?.
She'd been so smart.
Smarter than anyone around her
Clearly, there was a direct link
between this Eddie...
Slightly drunk at three o'clock in
the afternoon, and an earlier Eddie.
vomiting on his boss' desk...
or stealing his dying aunts Percocet.
So who can blame
Lindie for dumping me?
In the end, how much worse could it get?
I didn't want to see anybody.
Especially not
my landlord's nasty young wife
- Valerie, Tuesday...
- Look! Enough! Okay...
Steve handles the rent,
so you can feed your crap to him!
I suddenly had extra reason
to get away from her.
I had thoughtlessly ingested a substance.
Like the rent's not low enough!
I had gotten remarkably little information
from Vernon about what this drug would do.
you can even be a biker messenger
and come up with that. Really!
What if it was a hallucinogen?.
It's pathetic!
Oh my God! Listening to her rag -
If I were tripping, I'd jump out a window
Hello!
Are you listening to me?
Do you get it?
You are gonna be out on the streets!
And then I felt it.
I was blind, but now I see.
- What's wrong?
- What?
You don't like me and I don't blame you.
You see a self defeating,
energy sucking, piece of shit
who's sponging off your husband...
you're wishing I'd blow my brains out...
but my existence
shouldn't make you this upset
- What is it?
- That's none of your business!
Something wrong in Law school?
How do you know I am in law school?
People who aren't,
usually don't carry around dry..
academically constipated books
about a dead supreme court justice.
You are a creep aren't you?
You've been following me.
No, I just noticed the book.
You just saw the corner of it.
How did you know that?
I'd seen it before.
12 years ago in college.
sitting on the couch with a T.A.
I was trying to make...
waiting for her coming back out of the
bathroom, hoping she'd have a condom.
Somehow, my unconscious
had served that up.
A memory I'd never even recorded...
or was there the whole time and
I all I need was the access?
If you're writing a paper,
that's not the book I'd use.
Who asked you?
Hastings has it's own history.
I'd start there.
Interesting point... Grammatically,
this guy was an idiot
which sort of gives credence to the theory
that one of the clerks, he had fired..
actually wrote most of
this guy's major opinions.
you'd ruler the clerks sons... They'd
love to talk to you; exonerate their dad.
that'd give you
something that no one else has...
information from the odd museum show...
a half read article,
some PBS documentary...
was all bubbling up in my frontal lobes,
mixing itself together
into a sparkling cocktail
of useful information.
She didn't have a chance.
What, what, what are your suggestions?
We'd really worked on her paper too.
In 45 minutes, it was a polished gem.
She was pleased.
Home...
but it couldn't
be my home, could it!?
and who would live like this?
My first thought... Torch it!.
But, saner heads prevailed.
What was this drug?
I couldn't stay messy on it
I hadn't had a cigarette in 6 hours;
hadn't eaten...
So, I'm steamiest and tidy.
What was this?
A drug for people, who wanted
to be more anal retentive?
I wasn't high, wasn't wired...
Just clear. I knew what I
needed to do, and how to do it
The next morning, I sent a little
probe down into my brain.
No surge of brilliance came up
to greet me.
In short, I was back.
But something remained
- You're kidding?!
- No
- Words have appeared on paper.
- Yes.
- Written by you?
- All you have to do, is to read 3 pages
Just read 3 Pages in the next hour.
and, if you don't want to keep reading,
I'll give you back the advance.
- Okay, Eddie.
- Okay
Eddie, give me a call,
when you get in.
Eddie, I am 40 pages further in.
call me.
It's, a little grandiose
but I am still reading.
Okay, how did you do this?
I really... Call me the minute,
you get in. Call! Okay?
- Who is it?
- Hey, Vernon, its Eddie.
- Eddie who?
- Morra.
not a good time, Eddie.
Hey Vern, I really just need
to talk to you.
- Vern, what happened?
- Don't worry about it. I'm fine.
So, Eddie, you are interested after all.
That stuff's amazing.
Works better, if you're already smart.
- Vernon, who did this to you?
- Trust me, you do not want to know.
- So, uh, what, what's it called?
- Doesn't have a street name yet.
But, the boys in the kitchen, are calling it
NZT-48.
The "boys" and, the "kitchen"?
Doesn't sound very, FDA approved Vern.
FDA approved. That's a laugh.
You didn't really believe that shit. Did ya?
Okay, so what do we have here?
some unknown, untested,
possibly dangerous drug
scammed out of some
unidentified lab somewhere.
given to me by a highly unreliable guy
I hadn't seen in years
- So you want some more?
- Yes. Definitely.
Alright, we'll talk about it.
But I need a favor first.
Obviously, I'm in no condition
to go out right now
So I was wondering if you could pop down to
the uh, dry cleaners; grab my suit for me?
And maybe grab a little breakfast for us.
He knew, he had me.
Sure.
From now on, I'd happily be
his errand boy.
Wash his windows, scrub his toilets...
Anything I can do, to get my hands
on this little clear pill
that would bring back, enhanced Eddie.
Vern?
Oh God.
Hey!
HEY!
911... What's your emergency?
Hi, I need to report uh... A murder?
7B, yes.
Okay, I'll hold.
It took them forever.
And the longer I stood there,
the clearer I saw
Vern had known, whoever had done this
And one guess, what they'd
been looking for
But had they found it?
Shit. If you ever cooked,
I'd be dead too.
Police dept! Open the door please.
Police dept! Open the door!
Open the door please!
Police! Open the door!
Let's go! Open the door!
- Let me see your hands! - I'm the
one who called! - I called you guys!
So you guys tight?
Hang out a lot?
No. He's my ex-wife's brother.
I just actually met him on the street
and he asked me to come up.
- To buy drugs?
- No, No! What?
- What did this guy do?
- I do not know. He was...
I heard he was an antiques dealer.
- A dealer?
- Yeah uh, Antiques, um...
Like uh...
Like, Viennese kinda uh,
um chairs and stuff.
like, curly cue leg things.
Yeah?
That is correct. An Edward Morra.
He's here.
The victim's sister.
I hadn't heard her voice
in ten years.
- Eddie?
- Melissa?
You were there?
um, just, just before. I had run
into him on the street, and uh, yeah
Oh God
I wish I was more surprised,
he was involved in some stuff.
I better not to say anymore.
No, no, that's probably a good idea.
So uh, we should probably um,
meet or something, right...
No, I gotta do the funeral
and God knows what else...
We can't meet, okay?
Right. I guess I'll just see
you at the funeral then. uh?
No! I don't, I don't want that.
Please don't.
I call you at the point okay,
when this is over
Okay. Alright
Okay.
You know, something doesn't gel here.
Write down your number.
I'll need it to contact you later.
Worth the risk?
What would you do?
Vern's cash, combined with
an unprecedented surge in motivation
enabled me to finish the book in 4 days
A tablet a day, and what I could do
with my day, was limitless.
In learned
to play the piano in 3 days.
Math became useful
And fun...
All in.
Even half listing to any language,
I became fluent.
So that Shakespeare's text,
it is polite mediocrity.
who'd ever argue with you?
This was great.
So mom, I've been doing a little
research on aunt Helen's tumor. And...
it's totally clear, that anybody
with Familial Adomis Phalacrosis...
should be supplementing
Platinum doublet regiments...
with lico cimpenti oic acid.
I suddenly knew everything;
about everything.
Sure dude! You'd get a short term spike...
but wouldn't that rapid expansion
devalue the stock completely in two years?
No, cause there are safeguards.
Against the aggressive over expansion?
There aren't. Cause there
are no safeguards in Human nature.
Oh, we're wired to overreach.
look at history... All the countries
that ever ruled the world...
Portugal with his big massive navy.
All they got now are salt Cod
and cheap condoms.
The Brits!
Now they're just sitting in their dank
little isle and fussing over their suits.
No-one stopping and thinking...
Hey! We're doing pretty well.
We got France. We got Poland.
We got a big Swiss bank account
You know what...
Let's not invade Russia in the winter.
Let's go home. Let's pop a beer.
Let's live off the interest.
Yeah.
My brain was just pouring this stuff out.
Everything I'd ever read, heard,
seen was now organized and available
here it is, here you go
Eddie! Hey...
Listen, I'm sure you have a portfolio
but if don't...
I'd be very interested working with you.
Okay, Kevin.
I made some new friends
who invited me to the beach.
The beach, was not nearby.
All my fear, all my shyness, gone!
But mere lounging wasn't enough.
only problem,
if I wasn't moving forward
I felt like I was going to explode
- Anybody ever jumped?
- Are you crazy?
- He is gonna do it.
- He's not gonna do it.
Oh my God!
And then I began to form, an idea.
Suddenly, I knew exactly
what I needed do.
It wasn't writing.
It wasn't books.
It was much bigger than that
But it will take money to get there.
In a down market, no-one was making much.
But, no one had NZT.
Armed Vern's last 800 Dollars,
I made $2,000 in a day.
Next day, 7500
It was too slow
I'd need more capital.
Banks weren't lending to guys like me.
That's him in the corner back there.
So, uh...Liv told you that, I'm looking
for a short-term loan?
Yeah, and I told them that - forget it.
Why?
Because I don't see you before,
and I don't like you already
Why do I give you $100,000 Dollars?
Because...
I quintupled
my money 4 days in a row.
- So you got a fix on the game?
- No, not a fix.
I was able to calculate certain patterns
in the algorithms.
If you look at column 4,
This was the first...
You're good.
Okay, its a fix.
Yea, and all you people get caught.
What are you gonna do then?
Well it's not as I if have a
black book with your name in it...
If that's what you're talking about.
...and besides, I get the strong feeling...
that, you're not somebody I want to disappoint.
Don't get up. I said
don't get up. Sit down!
Okay.
Okay, you take this, you're
mine. - okay - You understand?
you don't pay...
You know what we do?
I cut you at waist.
peel your skin up over
your head and tie a knot in it
You don't die from this, You suffocate
Good luck.
My new friend, Kevin Doyle,
showed me how you can leverage.
two and a half times your cash
at day trading firm
I've been upping the dose for over a week.
It seemed to cut my learning curve.
Hey, Why you buying that?
The CEO was just indicted
But not for the big fat defensive
contract he bribed his way into
That's still on
should be announced next week
I was jacked in, booted up.
At the end of week,
My brokerage account.
contained over two million dollars.
word, quickly got out.
You have 19 messages.
four job offers,
My bank raising my line of credit
a reporter from the New York Post...
Really call me back Mr. Morra.
No one makes money that fast
This Article's gonna get written -
with or without you.
And finally, Kevin Doyle,
trying to sound casual.
Eddie, I was talking you up to my boss
and well, the impossible happened bud.
But we got you a meeting with Karl van Loon.
Karl van Loon wants
to meet you?
apparently so.
But you are not in the finance game?
What can you do for Karl van Loon?
Since when do you speak Italian?
Self improvement month.
I guess uh, somebody gave me a wakeup call.
- I hope you didn't do it for me.
- No, I just wanted to apologize to you.
And that you know, that apparently, my capacity
for self-sabotage wasn't boundless after all.
The real question is...
Why did you ever put up with me?
I was in love with you.
- So when does the book come out?
- Next year. How's your new assistant?
She's Good.
You know, I'm really
happy you're here with me.
I'm proud of you.
And...
a little intimidated.
We started up again
her place.
my place.
basically everyplace.
"In a sizzling 3 days of trading,
the unknown Mr. Morra"
"trumped the market,
prompting one top hedge fund manger to comment:"
"He's Houdini. He's a prophet
of our times. "
Okay, give me that.
- He's god!?
- You coming over later?
I can't. I don't have a key.
Oh that's right.
Can I have it back?
- No
- No?
I mean, does it have to be that key?
Can it be a new key?
to our place?
It'll be cost-effective.
And you say I am not practical.
Can I walk you to work?
What you doin, hon?
Nothing.
You should sleep.
Isn't your Van Loon meeting tomorrow?
Eddie?
Are you okay?
What are you doing out here?
When's the last time you ate something?
Here he is. Nice Article in the post buddy.
He is on his way.
Now be warned, he's mercurial.
One minute your best friend,
the next, you're a leper.
And he needs direct answers.
Anything tentative,
and you've lost him forever.
I think we should rehearse a few scenarios.
I am eating, Kevin.
Hey! Are you up for this?
You sure?
Because I got a little bit on the line here.
Have a toast plate.
Hey, Karl. Good to see you.
How are ya?
So, Eddie Morra,
What's your secret?
Medication.
I'm on a special medication.
okay.
There's a formula with a complex method-
but of course, research was a component;
massive research
I knew every helix of every scrap of DNA in
every company I bought.
Papers stacked like the Himalayas
in my office. And you know what?
- The stocks went up.
- by a hair.
Sure, the stocks rose,
but who wants to do all that work,
for a shitty little uptake?
It's not the visceral kind of spike
you want in short-time holding. So...
I dispensed with all the hard statics
and I went right to the rumor mill
So your bought your stocks based on
what the tom-toms beating in the street?
Sure. The share prices aren't really based
on how a company works
it's about how mass psychology works
So, if I found certain algorithms
in the perception of the stock...
Pattern recognition.
That's your cycle help?
Well, not everybody understands the patterns.
and that gave me a little bit more of
an uptake, but it's just a parlor trick.
so then I went to door number 3
You're really implying that you've,
some sort of ultimate formula?
Well, from 12,000
to 2.3 million in ten days.
I do have a formula, Mr. Pierce.
delusions of grandeur
I don't have delusions of grandeur
I have an actual recipe for grandeur.
I do not know who you are Eddie,
or what your game is,
But I'm sure of one thing,
you don't work in my world.
I'm up to my ass with investment guys...
and you don't have the half terrified,
half cocky line of crap; which is,
not to say, that I like yours any better,
but you obviously pick your stocks
in a way that I haven't seen before.
Take a look at these companies
and tell me what you think.
- Right now?
- Yeah. Take your time.
Sure.
These companies aren't the question, are they?
Explain.
Unless you're playing both sides of the fence.
control the whole power enchilada...
But no, these companies
wouldn't get you there in a merging markets
You would have...
Oh whoa! Whoa, this must be some, big-ass
merger you're contemplating
And there's really only one company
with enough bling to justify a merger
with Van Loon and associations.
Who've you been talking to?
Oh, I am just connecting the dots.
Is Hank Atwood really gonna go for it?
Well you're an amazing con artist,
or you're a very smart young man...
I mean, come on! The two of you together...
The whole world will have to come begging for energy
like Oliver Twist and his bowl of Gruel.
Well now you're going backwards. What else you got?
A prediction.
- It won't come off. - Why's that?
- You'd have to back off Libya
Really?
But, you don't want hear this from some schmuck
who needs a ride home.
Alright. You get your shot.
Meet me tomorrow at the Saint Regis at 10
and tell me how the gutsy little schmuck who needs a ride home,
would restructure these deals.
- And you better be prepared.
- I am at your disposal.
You don't really live here, do you?
Well, um Spart's weren't big on amenities.
Yea, and they eventually got their asses kicked.
I didn't go in. I wanted to walk,
move, digest, ingest
There are moments in life
moments, when you know, you've crossed
a bridge. Your old life is over.
Van Loon was my bridge.
I finally had my shot.
Wall Street would provide my nest egg.
but then how far could I go?
CEO? A global force? Maybe president.
time, somebody shook up the free world
and got the things done.
Suddenly, there was another skip.
How have I gone the last 20 blocks?
I got another 10 blocks
...and then...
I was way up town.
a fight? I don't know how to fight.
or do I?
if your assailants do not stop,
your insistence will distract the attacker.
off balancing your opponent,
can make use of his momentum
What bar was this?
When it finally stopped
I couldn't account for
the last 18 hours in my life
Hey, it's me.
I thought you were coming over.
Is everything okay?
Call me when you get this.
Even off NZT, I decided
to give Van Loon's files a shot.
they were hieroglyphs.
- Hello?
- Kevin, it's Eddie.
Eddie?
Listen, I can't - I can't make the meeting today.
What are you talking about?
I can't come in today.
I'm sick.
Yeah? Well, you can't have the flu right now.
He'll never give you this chance again.
I know. Listen. I just, ah...
I have all this data to analyze.
What have you been doing
for the last day?
Don't you get it? This is your test.
Yeah. Well, I can't pass the test right now.
And how am I gonna look if you don't?
- I know. Listen... - Sh! Listen to me. Pull
yourself together - get down to the meeting
Okay. Okay. I, I, I, I'll
be there. I'll be there.
- Hey. How are you, Eddie?
- Good to see you again.
Sit down.
- What do you know about Hank Atwood?
- Atwood...
Atwood... Um, He's an iconoclast...
uhm... He owns about a half of Colorado...
So, this is "prepared"? Eddie.
What is this, Atwood 101? I mean...
Doesn't everybody know about Atwood?
Where was he two years ago?
Hm?
Nowhere.
Two years ago,
he wasn't even on Forbes radar.
That was a great leap forward.
Right?
I'm baffled by this guy...
Comes out of nowhere, so strong... Has me on the
run, before I could even get to anybody in his camp.
beats me out of two properties,
investment companies up north...
We're here in the front of the hotel
where a woman...
identified as Maria Winberg,
was found dead in her room last night.
a victim of foul play..
Miss Winberg was a well known socialite...
but was also known
for her dedicated charity work around the city.
Police spent hours, questioning hotel staff
and patrons.
and an eye witness reported seeing a man
leaving the scene.
How can we convince him
that I can raise his game?
Got any ideas?
What do you think?
Hm?
You're not one of those kind of guys - are you Eddy?
we lose you, if there's a screen in the room?
These are tectonic plates
that are shifting right under us.
Pardon me one second.
Was it possible?
Could I have killed someone?
Was is it even me?
Eddie? This is Melissa..
Listen... Vernon hasn't been giving you
anything-has he? Because that stuff is dangerous.
Melissa?
Hey. Do you think we can meet somewhere?
I really need to talk to you
we're talking now.
No no, let's meet at uh,
Billy's on Grant... At noon?
You can't see me Eddie.
Please please come. Please come.
It's important. I really need to know
what you're talking about.
I realized, that there were other people,
who I might now about NZT.
Vern's other clients.
Yeah, Hi.
May I please speak with Jerry Braden?
Jerry's in the hospital..
- He's what?
- Yeah, he's not doing well at all
Yeah, hello. Is Paul Kaplan there?
Ah, no. No he's not.
uh, uh, Paul passed away - uh, three days ago
Oh my God! I'm so sorry.
Yeah, he started getting headaches,
then he collapsed at work.
Now he's in the I.C.U..
Okay, well please give him my best.
thank you.
Of all the people
I called...
three were dead,
and the rest were sick.
Hello
Hello?
Go! GO!
Eddie.
Melissa.
Hey.
Do not tell me I look good like this,
I know.
I didn't want you to see me this way.
You look good.
Well I uh...
Yes, I sorta got myself together.
NZT will do that to you..
- What do you mean?
- I mean, I took it too.
- Vernon didn't tell you any of this, did he?
- No
What, when we he told me about this amazing new drug...
I was like, "down the hatch. "
and it was. It was amazing.
I read Brian Green's, The Elegant Universe -
in 45 minutes
and I understood it.
My, my work rate increased,
just as insanely overnight...
and my boss started to hate me
They offered me his job.
And then, then I got, I got scared.
Why?
Why? Because I am not stupid.
Nobody can operate at that level
of mental activity and not crash.
I stopped taking it.
- Then?
- Then I got sick.
Headaches, throwing up
So I went back to, Veron...
he told me about all the people that were dying.
- How much you have been taking Eddie?
- I've been taking a lot.
Well maybe...
Maybe they've worked out the bugs maybe.
Maybe this is a different batch.
Yeah.
- You're off it right now, aren't you?
- Just finish the story.
Well, I didn't take anymore and I didn't die
But after a while I realized
that I couldn't
concentrate on anything for longer than 10 minutes..
I missed deadlines...
Got lazy. Slow. So slow.
That was two years ago.
I haven't been the same since.
You have some left? Good.
Well you go home and you take it.
You take the dose down,
But you don't just stop.
You'll die, if you just stop!
Try to taper off. Otherwise,
the headaches are just beginning.
I have to go.
- Do you know who makes them?
- I do not know.
I have to go.
Oh Shit! Listen listen listen listen...
- You forget about me eh?
- No no no
12:00 and you're not here!
- I'm here now.
- Come on, keep going.
- I can to write you a check.
Check.
Check
Are you out of your mind?
What do you think I am,
some financial institution?
Alright. You're right.
Maybe at least you can go to the bank.
What you got there?
- What is it?
- It's just aspirin.
Don't look like no aspirin I ever see.
I feel good man, what's in this stuff?
Well, it's just some vitamins and aspirin.
You're full of shit Eddie baby...
I'm sorry
- Tyler, I gotta go.
- I'm sick.
I'm sorry!
I couldn't make it home.
- I'll take you to a hospital.
- No no no no, honey...
I need yo to get...
It's really simple baby. I need my pills.
- Eddie, what pills? - Baby, it's
complicated. - What are you taking?
Are you on drugs?
I had no choice.
I told Lindi everything
So all this energy of yours,
all this focus, has been a drug?
Well, it was supposed to be legal.
I, I have a supply stashed.
- you want me to go get it.
- No.
No no no. I'm gonna,
I'm gonna go get it.
Give me your keys.
I'll go to your apartment.
It's not in my apartment.
I moved it.
Okay... So where did you move it?
In my house.
Unbelievable!
- Have you got it?
- Yeah.
There's someone following me.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
He got into the cab behind me,
and he's making every turn I'm making.
Better call the cops.
Can you go around him?
- Baby, what's happening?
- We're stopped dead.
He's getting out...
Eddie, he's walking over here.
Lindi...
Oh God!
Help!
This man, this man is chasing me.
He followed me from my building.
I don't know him. Please!
Yo buddy! Let's leave her alone.
Are you deaf?
I said, leave her alone!
Hey buddy, are you trying to piss me off?
What are you doing, man?
- Are you still there?
- Yeah, I'm here. What happened?
- I'm stuck! He'll find me.
- Okay, stop talking. Don't move...
- He killed two guys.
- What?
He's gonna kill me too.
No no no no no. Let me look.
Can you see him?
No.
Nothin'.
I don't know what to do.
Okay... I need you to go into the bag
and take one of the pills.
Why?
Because you'll know what to do.
You'll take it and then you'll know.
He's got a knife. Eddie,
I can't think my way out of a knife.
Just listen to me. It'll come on in 30 seconds,
and you'll think your way out. That's what it does.
He's getting closer.
Lindi, I love you.
Eddie...
Here.
It's gonna be okay.
You're gonna get outta here.
Eddie.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm so sorry
about what happened.
I want you to know that you'll
never, ever have to go through that again
Cause I can take care of us now.
I'm sure you can.
I can make us safe.
I'm back! Okay
- Who's back? Eddie.
- Me.
No! It's not you
You were different before.
- I am still the same person.
- I wasn't when I was on it.
I did things, I
would never do.
Those things saved your life.
- But they weren't me.
- Yes. You know the way it works...
I know how it works.
I get it, I totally get it. You feel invincible.
Where it will take us Lin, you can't even imagine
The things we'll be able to do
Where we'll be a year from now
The kind of life that we'll finally be able to live
Well, you might have to live it without me.
Look! I am gonna stop taking it.
There's just some things I have to do
to keep us safe and to, to set us up
And then, I'm gonna get off it... I mean,
that's the plan.
Look! I have a plan. I swear
I'm gonna get off it.
Okay
I hope you do
Looking for me?
Think you can run out on me? uh!
You think, I don't know where you are?
I was under the impression,
our business was settled.
Well I want some more of that stuff,
or I shoot you right here.
Take your pick.
This guy was not going away.
A few pills would buy me some time
- Here it is. We're done.
- We will see.
Until I found a more...
permanent solution.
Unless you see a real threat,
I never want it known that I have any security.
You'll never proceed me
You'll always follow me.
never more than 15 steps behind.
And never stand too close together.
I wanna be able to look behind me
if the opportunity presents itself.
And don't wear the same color suit.
This isn't the Matrix!
You have to know Eddie... I wrote you off.
- I was sick.
- You don't get sick
You're playing at this level -You get hit
by a car, you don't even die.
- You're absolutely right.
- I know I'm right.
I mean, I didn't know who
or what I was talking to.
105. That's who you were talking to Carl.
Delirium.
Hm hm.
- I sent over my revised projections.
- I didn't ask for your projections...
I know, but I think
If you take a look at them...
I already have.
As a matter of fact...
I fired a few people,
over your projections.
- I'm sorry.
- No, you're not.
You're relieved, that you know things,
my team missed.
The minute, the instant,
that's no longer true...
Two months after I'd started NZT...
I was brokering the biggest
merger in corporate history.
Ironically, it's gonna be crude. Crude
is gonna be where we're gonna hit em.
Which yields a projected profit of 200%.
That makes both of us
very happy campers.
I found that if I maintained an even dose,
remembered to eat
drank no alcohol...
The blackouts didn't occur
Tom is it possible to construct
an imperceptible compartment?
- In this jacket?
- In all of them.
Certainly, sir.
Safer though my stash now was,
I was not sitting around until I ran out.
Well, can I combine these ingredients
in the same exact quantity? Yes.
but, the exact method of delivery to the brain,
uhhh...
Dart to the dart board.
- Meaning?
- clinical trials, guinea pig people.
that's gonna take too long.
It is was it is. Or you'll kill people.
Look. You need 12-18 months
I'll give you two million dollars
If you can do it in 6
I found that we could cart the cost, 30%.
and uhm...
Excuse me for one sec
I thought we straightened this out, detective.
This isn't about Vernon again, Mr. Morra.
What is this about?
The witness identified the Maria Winberg suspect...
As this person.
Wanna tell me your whereabouts the night of April 2nd?
I couldn't keep this quite on my own
Enter Morris Brant, the most lethal lawyer
in New York.
You're lucky, somebody wiped the room.
It's weak circumstantial at best.
- Just between us... Were you there?
- I don't remember.
I don't want to make concessions to you...
Karl van Loon's and Hank Atwood,
had no idea
I might soon be charged with murder.
But Ci-Corps, An-Dine and others,
are jockeying
for the same industrial concessions in Libya
that both our companies are pretending,
we're not sniffing out.
How do you know this?
The governmental bribes system is itself corrupt
So of course, information about its inner-workings,
like anything, can be bought.
Go on.
If you take a look at the
lower left hand column in 2008,
five companies were jockeying for a position
before we even took notice.
Jesus, he looks frail.
- Could be an act.
- He's not even 60.
So have you decided Eddie,
whatta ya gonna do?
When this is over?
I do not know.
- You haven't given me the answer.
- You haven't you asked the question.
Well, Given the scale of my contribution...
let's say 45
Humph! $45,000?
40 million's plenty Eddie.
There's a lot more where that'll come from
You know, Eddie...
it may be on your mind,
that you're not gonna continue
to work for me anymore...
This has been the learning
experience of my life.
I hope has. I hope you don't think
you've gotten enough from me.
on to the next...
Well, in order for a career to evolve,
I'm gonna have to move on.
That you would even think that,
would only show me
how unprepared you are,
to be on your own.
I mean, you do know, you're a freak?
Your deductive powers are a gift from God,
or chance, or straight shot of sperm...
or whatever, or whoever the hell,
wrote your life script.
A gift. not earned.
You do not know what I know,
because you have not earned those powers.
You're careless with those powers.
You flaunt them and you throw them
around like a brat with his trust fund.
You haven't had to climb up
all the greasy little rungs...
You haven't been board-lined at the fundraisers...
you haven't done the time in that first marriage,
to the girl with the right father...
You think you can leap
over, all in a single bound.
You haven't had to bribe or charm or threaten
your way, to sit at this table.
You don't know how to assess your competition,
because you haven't competed...
Don't make me your competition.
Now I'll open up a line of credit for you.
You'll be wanting a few toys.
hotel rooms
were no longer an option.
What I needed, was a bunker.
There's a built in safe...
central surveillance, vault grade pneumatic doors.
It's an unparalleled three tier security system.
A fortress, with a hell of a view.
- What is the asking price?
- 8.5
I'll take it.
Right away, it was obvious, he was on NZT
Next week, I'm gonna need 20 pills.
Next week, you can go, fuck yourself.
Not that you'll feel anything.
I don't think your fortune 500 financial friends,
would appreciate the details,
of your little dilemma with the police.
Thursday, I'm gonna need the pills here.
Getting smarter...
Obviously, this can not
go on
But there is very little on this earth
that 40 million dollars can't solve
and tomorrow at 9:00,
Atwood would sign the papers.
Do you wanna call it?
- Cold feet?
- With all last night to tell us that.
- Anything?
- I'll call it again, sir.
Okay, the decision could've changed...
That makes sense - but discourtesy doesn't.
It's still on.
Oh! Based on your charts and projections?
You know, remind me... Who are you anyway?
I'm sorry Karl, I've had it with this unqualified posturing little prick.
- Look...
- Since when is this the Delta quarrel?
Don... Pull it back!
Excuse me. Mr. Van Loon, Mrs. Atwood
is in your office.
Ah. Mrs. Atwood, Karl van Loon,
My associate, Edward Morra.
Pleasure.
- I wanted to make this as confidential as possible.
- Of course.
My husband experienced some pain and
dizziness this morning.
He's currently at Lenox Hill - undergoing test.
I just want you to know we have every
intention of signing the contract.
And as soon as he is able, we will proceed.
I realize this is a useless platitude,
but if there's anything we can do...
Please don't hesitate to tells us.
Obviously, we want to be as helpful and as
practical as possible, Mrs. Atwood.
Thank you, gentlemen.
I rely on your discretion.
There wont be a proxy.
a crazy prick like him giving away power of attorney?
Well, better get better.
But Atwood wouldn't get better
because Atwood was out of NZT.
Well, why are we surprised?
How many other meteoric rises
might be explained by NZT?
At least I had some.
My life wasn't in jeopardy
You wait here.
only my money. and my liberty
I've been all over them.
We can't allow any disparity
in race or physical type
between you and the rest of the line-up.
they're as close to your clones, as I could possibly get.
It's gotta be, just one big handsome blur to this guy.
Who was out there?
the woman's husband?
the hotel maid?
Was this how, it was all going to end?
Not the dimmest clue.
- He was dithering
"He was the third from the right. No not him. "
Here you go. A thing of beauty.
You had that made?
I did.
This today... The Dow has been YO-YO-ing
amid speculation, that Van-Loon Associates,
and Hank Atwood have negotiated a merger...
Have you been talking to anyone?
NO. I haven't been talking to anybody, Karl.
I'm not stupid!
I know you're not stupid Eddie,
but don't make the classic
smart person's mistake...
thinking no-one's
smarter than you.
Where the hell have you been?
This is the second time
you've turned to vapor.
I was in the building.
I was getting coffee?
Why? Has there been movement?
Yeah! There's been movement alright.
Atwood's in a coma.
He wasn't playing us, he's dying.
What do you know about this?
I was less than usually equipped to answer.
The dullness was coming on.
I was overdue to take
my NZT.
And the pain was starting behind my eyes.
Excuse me.
You're not excused.
What, a man in your employ, can't take a piss, Karl?
Was it Brant, or someone else?
The police station? The coat room?
Mr. Morra...
Mr. Morra.
Mr. Morra!
This just came for you.
Alright, I'm gonna ask you again Eddie...
What do you know about this?
- What? About the leak?
- No... About Atwood.
What? What about Atwood?
Look...You got a long way to go
-as a liar kiddo...
-Heck Karl, I don't know what your..
Listen, what you about to say is bullshit!
I know there's something you're
hiding from me. I smell it on you!
Right now,I wanna know why
this deal is dead in the water!
Karl.
Hey!
Eddie!
Outside Lennox Hill Hospital today,
more twists and turns
in the Van Loon - Atwood merger.
There is absolutely.
no truth to the rumor of this merger.
None whatsoever!
My husband is having tests...
it's a difficult time
We would appreciate you direct,
your further questions to our attorney.
Ah, Yes...We have no
further comments at this time...
we're just awaiting the results
from the latest round of test, and hoping the best.
Thank you!
Eddie...
I know you're in there Eddie
Eddie, come out.
Come on!
Open the door.
And so, here I am.
I knew that they will kill me
slowly and horribly.
But this choice would at least be mine
But we're instinctive creatures...
We wanna live.
so my foggy brain tried to remember
where one tablet of NZT might be
it was possible.
and possible was enough.
Hey, Eddie.
You know, I want more,
so why would you upset me?
I don't like being down to this last one
You do not even know how to use it.
You don't appreciate it.
You see, I dissolve it in solution.
you shoot it.
It goes straight into the blood and brain.
lasts much longer.
So... You tell me
where the rest is?
I'm plum out..
You know, these guys are gonna find it...
Or I gonna make you tell me
Question is...
Which is gonna come first?
I guess, we gonna find out uh?.
This is a waste of my time, you know.
I'm getting out of this side of the business.
I'm branching out...
I'm starting import export company.
very exiting stuff.
I got a lot on my plate,
you're lucky I am here.
Back in the old times.
I might peel your skin back, flay you.
Flay. That's a nice word,
I didn't know this before.
I had such a poor vocabulary.
But then I discovered this thing... Google.
Did you know the small and large intestines is 20 foot long?
I had no idea, I don't believe it.
I gotta see this for myself. I'm dubious.
That's another nice word.
Anyway... I am sure you're curious too.
But don't worry.
Everything's sterilized.
We're gonna keep you alive
through the whole shebang.
You're gonna get a front row seat, baby!
not much of a triumph, was it?
because I would die here too.
only NZT could help me
and the last of it, was in
this pug's bloodstream.
Victor!
What?
Victor.
Victor?
Victor!
The police would later note,
that my apartments previous
owner was an arms dealer.
of course these intruders,
had been his dissatisfied clients
and the night was still young
Well, I'm sure you're curious to know
what happened to your boss.
I certainly am.
I mean, if my attorney was really
working for Mr. Atwood,
trying to save his life...
Why is he dead?
I mean, at what point was the pony express,
supposed to ride in
with his life saving medication?
his boss was dead.
So, I didn't matter now.
But he did not appreciate that
Morris Brant had kept the pills for himself.
and it was all still possible
after 12 months
Actually, now there's no more tickets.
Yeah, I got it.
An overbooked fund-raiser; that's a first!
Well, here he comes. I'll ask him.
Ah! That's much better.
Great job!
Edward...
I think we looking at a second overflow of bent.
There's a league of donations coming in,
and I don't think they're even
gonna try a second debate.
Great.
Hold on. There's guy from Ivan Chemcorp's
in your office.
I've a lunch.
Look...The biggest contributor,
give him his two crappy little minutes?
- Ivan Chemcorp pharmaceuticals?
- Yeah.
Finally get to meet the guys that keeps the lights on.
- Karl?
- Mr. Morra.
what a surprise!
They told me somebody from Ivan was coming across...
Yes, thats me now.
I am moving out of the energy business.
Come on!
That's like Hefner moving out of the mansion.
I bought Ivan several months ago.
I'm surprised you didn't hear.
No. No. Well, I know they keep me hoppin' here.
Well, it's gonna pay off
Senator Morra.
The Senate, well who knows?
Everything's a technicality
from here on. Isn't it, Eddie?
I think we both know where it's headed, if
you can, maintain.
Have you asked yourself,
what you're gonna do, when you run out?
- When did you know?
- Does it matter? I know now.
I wish you'd come to me at first, Eddie.
I could have bought Ivan at 33 a share.
We could have been partners.
So Ivan makes NZT.
We it'll never officially exist.
Obviously, I don't need to point out
the advantages for you..
Oh I think maybe you do.
Limitless supply.
We know you can't get anymore.
You sure about that?
I shut down your lab this
morning.
Eddie, I just wanna help you. That's all.
Keep your supply.
No disruption in service.
Give you piece of mind. That's all.
And in return... I do what?
Give a little advice maybe.
I won't be bothering much at first.
And later...What
are gonna be bothering me with?
Well, given where you're heading...
Some of our ideas are a bit ambitious.
But hey! I think they're achievable.
And what if I don't like your ideas?
Well then we'll say..."God-speed."
and your candle will have shed
a brief but lovely light.
But you know what Eddie,
let's not even go there right now.
Right now, I just want to keep you
brilliant and healthy.
Let's go get some lunch.
After you, Senator.
Thanks for stopping by, Karl.
Give us a second.
What are you doing?
You want to be president of the
United States...
or brain dead - stuck full of tubes?
I'll take my chances.
I told you...Your chances don't exist.
We shut down your lab.
You don't you think some
smart-ass and NZT
might have two or three, or even four labs?
So what. You're not making anymore.
That's right. I'm not. I thought better of it.
See once you know what's in
it, you can tweak, re-engineer...
get the bugs out.
Taper off
I'm off it, Karl.
Well on it, or off it, there's no
scenario where you are not working for me.
How you gonna pay me? In cigarettes?
- Last year you traded insider information 17 times.
- You threating me?
Like checks from Dubai, dumping
in Chile, disappeared officials
When you said the spot...
You wanna go to war with me?
And trust me when I say this
I am not even being creative.
There's no way you can be making
accusations like that
and be walking around alive.
That you wouldn't even think that
shows me how unprepared
your are to fight me.
- You're not longer equipped to fight me.
- Do you think I didn't learn anything...
that my synapses didn't change, that I kept absolutely nothing?
- You have no idea, what kind of enemy I can be...
- That van's gonna rear-end that taxi.
What?
The driver's distracted; he's
texting; he's going 30mph...
He needs 60 feet stop; he doesn't have room to work with.
I see everything, Karl.
I'm 50 moves ahead of you
and everybody else.
What makes you think I don't know the guy
with a beat on you right now?
How do you know you're gonna be
alive this time next year?
What are you doing?
Somethin's pumpin' at half-mast in there.
Walls of your heart are dilated.
Aorta's not standing up.
Soon you need to get that replaced.
But you already knew that.
You know, you should
really be glad about this.
Cause me working for you,
you'd end up as my bitch.
Maybe we should cool off and talk again
I don't think so.
Don't forget to vote.
- Edward, you good?
- Yeah! Told you I have a lunch.
- I am sorry.
- Hey, don't worry.
- How's your day going?
- I've had better.
I still can't deal with that haircut.
I don't even recognize
you on the street.
Well I'm a new man.
I've already ordered.
What?
Resync Perfectly By
LuRaZo +_=