And get bigger trade-in values, too.
Up to 110% over Kelley Blue Book for any trade!
That's huge!
For Texas-sized savings and Fort Worth hospitality
come to Nissan of Fort Worth.
Shop us 24 hours a day at Nissan-of-Fort-Worth.com.
At Texas State Low Cost Insurance,
we pride ourselves on homegrown, friendly service.
From your car to your home, we're here for you,
providing quality state-required coverage for over 30 years.
Texas State Low Cost Insurance,
best in affordable insurance for Texans like you.
Breaking news, breaking stories.
Your up-to-the-minute traffic and weather.
News Center 35 night team.
Good evening. Thanks for tuning in to your news at 6:00.
A breaking story for Central Texas tonight.
Police issued an AMBER Alert for an 8-year-old boy.
He was abducted from his home near Eldorado, Texas, last night.
We don't have a photo of him yet, but this is what we do know.
His name is Alton Meyer.
He is eight years old, white, with blue eyes and brown hair,
4 '8" tall,
- weighing roughly 60 pounds.
- It's time.
Meyer's parents reported him missing Sunday night
and believe this man, Roy Tomlin, took him.
We are awaiting details on Tomlin,
but police say he may be armed
and should be considered extremely dangerous.
If you have any information, please call 911 immediately.
Again, we haven't been provided with a photo of the 8-year-old,
but he is white, eight years old, 4'8" tall,
weighing roughly 60 pounds with brown hair and blue eyes.
Said to be traveling with this man, Roy Tomlin.
Please call 911 with any information.
We will keep you updated as we receive more.
It's time. You ready?
Yeah.
Better lose the bed sheet.
Okay.
...between planning meetings
that two consecutive overpasses
would not be knocked down during the I-35 expansion project.
And, more than anything, Ross leaders say they would've appreciated
- a heads up.
A TxDOT spokesperson says
the school district and the EMS were notified,
but the Ross mayor and fire chiefs were not.
He has more on that.
The I-35 project...
Attention, all units,
for a wanted person broadcast.
Be on the lookout for a 1972 Chevrolet Chevelle,
primer gray in color, bearing Texas license plate 159AG2,
driven by two white males
- heading eastbound on I-30.
- P op that open.
Subjects are known to carry firearms.
Any unit coming into contact, hold and notify.
Hand me those goggles.
Kill the light, Alton.
Again, no photos have been
provided of the 8-year-old boy.
He is White, 4'8" tall,
weighing roughly 60 pounds, with brown hair and blue eyes,
said to be traveling with this man, Roy Tomlin.
Please call 911 with any information.
Stay with us after the break...
What, did the Ranch put this out?
No. This is something else.
Thank you, Levi.
What you do now will decide our whole way of life.
You have four days to get the boy back here.
He won't give him up easily.
But we must get him back in time, you understand?
The Lord has placed a heavy burden on you.
Peace be to you.
And to you.
We'll begin with the reading from March 17th, 2011.
"Gulf Eclipse and the numbers came."
35,
47, 97, 52.
"Buildings tower. The light comes.
"To know the source of such things is to know our place in the world."
We're guarded by a plan unknown to us, but...
Friends, these gentlemen are from the federal government.
I'd suggest you listen to them very carefully.
Please remain calm.
We are agents from the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
We have a warrant to search the premises and detain all members of this Ranch.
There are buses waiting outside to transport you
to the campus of Jefferson High School
- in San Angelo.
Please exit the building in an orderly fashion.
- Stand up, please.
- You will receive
further details when we reach our destination.
FBI AGENT 1". Will y'all stand up, please?
Bring it this way.
Yes, ma'am. You, too.
Are we good?
It's better to get across state line.
We passed three counties. I'd like to slow down.
Lucas!
Alton, stay down.
Ma'am.
Ma'am?
She's hurt real bad!
She's gonna need an ambulance. She got a bad head wound.
Don't.
Shoot him.
Get back in the car.
Alton is more important.
Get back in the car!
- Shoot him!
- I got this!
Shot fired. Officer down.
Send medical, 10-18.
County Road 36, one mile east of marker 87.
Copy that-Will notify.
Everything's fine. You buckled in?
It's okay. Just settle down, all right?
You want your comics? Here.
He had on a vest.
You didn't know that.
You did the right thing. He's more important.
You didn't just shoot a state trooper.
Inside to the right.
Please. Ma 'am, please step forward.
We've had you under surveillance
since members of your Ranch have acquired a sizeable number of firearms
over the course of the last six months.
Do you have an explanation for this?
Well, it's not illegal to own weapons in this country yet.
What's the main economic function of your Ranch?
We have pasture land. Cattle, dairy.
But they're not for profit.
- We use them ourselves.
S EVI E RI Hi. Hello.
Hi. Sorry. Agent Miller?
Hi. Paul Sevier, NSA.
Nice to finally meet you in person. Hello.
As I said, my name is Paul Sevier.
I work for the NSA in the field of communications.
I'm sorry. Do you mind if I just kind of jump in or...
Do these mean anything to you?
Ignoring the rest of this. Polo Step?
Meridian Alpha?
Red Saber?
The number combination
53, 23, 77, 127?
Yes. They're excerpts from my sermons.
That particular one's from a reading,
January 18th, 2010.
Yes, it is. Did you write this?
Yes.
What if I told you that the words and numbers contained in your sermons
include sensitive government information
that, given the dates you provide,
were transmitted solely by satellite through a heavily encrypted format?
The decryption and dissemination of which,
other than being scientifically impossible,
would surely carry punishments of treason that are so severe,
the government probably hasn't invented them yet.
They came from the boy. It's all from the boy.
- Alton Meyer?
- Yes.
Okay, well, we knew that.
He's your son?
Adopted.
Do you know the birth father?
Yes, I do.
Roy Tomlin.
So can you tell us how an 8-year-old got this information?
He would have fits.
Can you explain that?
He would speak in tongues.
Sometimes other languages, sometimes unknown languages.
We wrote them down. They became our scripture.
These are words of the Lord.
Or the federal government.
What's the significance of Friday, March 6th?
We need to know where he is.
Y'all have no clue what you're dealing with, do you?
I prepared a room for him.
Alton, it's wonderful to see you again.
Yes, sir.
Are those windows blacked out?
Yes, there's cardboard behind the drapes.
Well, I'll... I'll let y'all get settled in.
ROY". Thank you.
Kick your shoes off.
Get some sleep, Alton.
Good night, Lucas.
Goggles.
Try and sleep.
We'll have breakfast when you get up.
Okay.
Stop what you're doing for one second
and take a look at your screen right now.
Look at his picture.
This man, Roy Tomlin,
wanted in connection with an AMBER Alert out this morning
for an 8-year-old little boy, Alton Meyer.
LUCAS". It's national.
What about the state trooper?
Nothing.
I can't believe the Ranch released this.
...near San Angelo, Texas. That was two nights ago.
I don't think they did.
The two are said to be traveling east into Arkansas,
possibly into Louisiana.
The man last seen driving a black...
I'll take the first watch. You need to sleep.
- You need anything?
- A drink.
You got it.
Do not approach him. Don't try to apprehend him.
...If you've seen this guy,
please call 911 immediately.
Hey-
lam in this for Alton. All the way.
Things with that trooper didn't need to go down like that.
He's a little boy. Brown hair, blue eyes.
Don't interfere with me again.
Roy Tomlin is said to have some sort of a relationship to the boy's family,
but the details of that relationship, extremely unclear.
We're gonna bring you the latest on the case in the next hour,
and give you everything through the night.
I've got something I want you to see.
Has anyone else from the Ranch decoded the coordinates you gave me?
No.
They only have the date.
Well...
The place is clear.
But I still don't have an answer as to why that place.
Have you ever done any studying on the concept of ley lines?
No.
Well, their validity is arguable, but I got to tell you, in the research...
Elden. I'm tired.
Of course.
Do you miss it?
Living on the Ranch?
Yeah.
Very much.
Lucas!
Alton!
Stop!
No!
I got you. I got you. I got you.
...It's okay. It's okay.
ROY". It's okay.
It's okay.
HANNAH". Things would break.
What kinds of things?
Windows, light bulbs.
Cars would shut down. That kind of thing.
It just got worse the older he got,
so they just started letting him sleep in the daytime,
and he'd be awake at night.
It's why all our services are at night now.
And what's your job on the Ranch?
Childcare.
I help look after all of Brother Calvin's children.
Alton's been with him over two years now.
And the birth mother?
She abandoned him.
FREDRKZK'. Yes, I'm done.
Communing?
That's what we call it.
To be clear,
"A visible spectrum of light came from his eyes."
Yes.
And others have described seeing things.
Did he show you things during this process?
Yes.
What kinds of things?
I wouldn't know where to start.
And Friday, March 6th. Why is this date important?
It's the day of ourjudgment.
What makes you say that?
Ibeheveit.
It wasn't images.
Not what I remember.
It was more...
It was like a feeling.
What kind of feeling?
Comfort.
And
what do you think will happen on Friday, March 6th?
If Alton is with us, we will be saved.
Barbara Meyer?
This way.
All right. I need everyone to stand up.
Exit through the front doors, please.
Single file, please. Thank you.
Lucas, can you get Alton in the van?
Yeah.
We're taking your van.
Please don't.
You know where we're going.
Please.
I had to see again.
You knew better.
Liberty 285. Code 6.
105 North Avenue, 52.
ROY". We need to stop for gas.
We could use some supplies.
I'll go in.
The less people that see you, the better.
I need to use the payphone.
What's Kryptonite?
It's the only thing that'll kill Superman.
ROY". It's made-up.
I should have never let you give him those.
He's never seen a comic book in his life.
That's why he needs them. Reading's reading.
He needs to know what's real.
He looks weaker.
He is.
He recovers?
He's fine.
He speaks Spanish?
It's something he does. Turn on the radio.
Scroll through the stations.
Be right back.
Stay in the van.
Hey-
Yeah, we're okay. We should be there in a couple hours.
WOMAN". Are you okay?
I've been wanting to see you.
Mmm-hmm.
We'll be there soon.
Why are you wearing those goggles?
Stop! Stop!
He's with me. He's my son.
Yeah, well, you ought to watch your kid.
Yeah, I got it. Thank you.
Everything okay?
You cannot leave the van. You hear me?
I'm sorry.
It's okay. I shouldn't have left you.
No.
I'm sorry.
Roy?
"Go!
Dad?
Alton. Lean your head back.
- Is he okay?
- Yeah.
Roy.
Roy, do we need to get him to a hospital?
No! No! Just keep driving.
Is this something that he does?
It's okay.
Alton.
Thank you, God.
Thank you.
Let me look at you.
You're so big.
So grown-up.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I'm Sarah.
Lucas.
How are you?
I missed him.
Come On.
Y'all must be exhausted.
Let's go inside.
I got a present for you, Alton.
You wanna see your room?
I can't keep my eyes off him.
Get some rest.
Okay.
He okay?
He doesn't look good.
He's sick.
He's getting weaker, but he'll be okay.
Should we do something?
Just stick to the plan and get him there by Friday.
Do you think that's wise?
It's all we have.
This date and place is everything.
We take him to a hospital, it's over.
But if it's between that and him dying?
It's three days. He'll make it.
I think he's right.
Yeah.
I don't know if there's a way out of all this for y'all,
but it's a shame.
You would have made a nice family otherwise.
I'm an electrician.
Certified in two states.
What do I know about these things?
He wouldn't have asked you if you couldn't do it.
Sometimes we are asked to do things that are beyond us.
Yes?
Are you Sarah Tomlin's mother?
How could someone cause a satellite to fall out of orbit?
I don't know. Ask an engineer.
Well...
Alton Meyer brought down an Air Force satellite last night.
DSP-9712.
- It was tasked with detecting a...
- Nuclear explosion.
Yeah.
This is the last image sent to us by the satellite.
We believe that's the boy standing at the center of the heat bloom.
It's not exactly a heat bloom, but that's fine.
Well, whatever it is, it set off a satellite
whose sole purpose is detecting a nuclear event.
No radiation.
None.
Could a drone be programmed
to search for that specific heat signature?
Yeah.
We've got a field office in Mobile you can base your team out of.
- What about the interviews?
- You're done with those.
Like it or not, you're the new resident expert on Alton Meyer.
Let's go.
Breaking news at this hour.
A weather satellite fell from space and crashed near a gas station.
This happened overnight in northern Louisiana,
and as we speak, a massive cleanup is underway
because the debris field from the crash is nearly 60 miles wide.
The Canadian company that owns this satellite
says the spacecraft suffered mechanical failure...
Can you tell Lucas to pull the van around back?
Okay.
It is the first time that debris has fallen in a populated area.
Our local affiliate has more from the area hardest hit by this falling debris.
Roy asked if you'd pull the van around back when you're done.
Okay.
You're not from the Ranch?
No. No.
Then how do you know Roy?
We grew up together.
We were real close for a long time,
till his parents moved him out to the Ranch, and then we fell off.
Until three nights ago, there was a knock at my door,
and there's Roy standing there with Alton.
He says that they're in trouble and they need help.
And then Alton sat me down.
And he took those goggles off.
You know when that boy does that...
That thing with his eyes...
It's powerful.
What do you do in San Angelo?
I'm a state trooper.
Alton?
Yes?
What happened at the gas station?
Did you mean to do that?
Yes.
Why?
They were watching me.
Who was watching you, Alton?
The police.
Well, how do you know it was the police?
They talk like the police on your radio.
What do they say?
They're looking for me.
Here's a receipt for her car insurance.
Isuzu Rodeo, '99.
There's a van in the driveway.
See if it's got a registration in it.
Alton.
Alton. Breathe. Can you breathe?
- Roy!
- Pull over.
- Breathe!
- Pull over!
Breathe! Breathe!
Breathe.
Okay, Okay-
What is it?
Mom?
I'm okay.
Ahhh!
Mom?
4scREAMs) %GROANS)
God.
Alton.
...Alton!
Water! He needs water.
Oh, my God.
Alton.
Roy.
He needs water.
We need to take him to a hospital!
- No.
- He's dying.
Hey, hey!
- He is sick, right?
- No!
He's dying! ROY". No! He will not die!
He is meant for something else!
No, he's sick and he needs help!
Alton?
We have to go. They're coming.
Who's coming?
There.
You take the car with Lucas.
Dad, we have to go.
That way.
Now!
Roy... Roy!
What the hell?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
I can run.
This way.
Alton.
How did you know this was here?
I didn't.
Sun will be up in a few hours.
We can wait out the daylight here.
Alton!
Here.
I'm okay.
I'm sorry.
No.
I need something.
What?
I need to be awake during the day.
In the sun.
You can't.
Ihaveto.
It could kill you.
Dad...
lhaveto.
He's not going to Atlanta.
What?
All these places mentioned in the sermons, they don't matter.
They don't?
No, he's just listening to the government talk.
He's just looking for a language to describe a location,
and all he heard was coordinates.
That's remarkable.
Now they wanna move us to an office in Atlanta.
Doesn't matter.
What?
I know where they're going.
Old habits die hard?
You still staying up nights?
What happened to your head, Elden?
...then warming up a bit
this afternoon, with a few sunny breaks
and diminishing...
So you can go one full year...
This is the part that people need to be aware of.
- Everybody out...
Roy will get him here.
If he's not dead.
I'm sorry.
Roy won't let that happen.
Yeah, I hope not.
He believes in something. You don't.
It doesn't matter.
Good people die every day believing in things.
Roy spent two years watching another man raise our son.
He did what I couldn't.
He'll do anything to get him here.
Better get some rest.
Nobody's coming with the sun up.
Dad.
It's okay.
It's still daylight.
Jesus.
He looks...
He has something to tell you.
You look wonderful.
It's still daylight.
Yeah.
No... No goggles.
Lucas, you wanna sit down?
I saw the sunrise this morning.
I think I know what I am now.
There's...
There's a world
built on top of ours.
People live there.
I think they're like me.
We saw it.
They're like you?
Yes, I think so.
I understand.
Lucas?
I believe you.
Good.
All right.
- You all right in there?
- Yeah.
Roy?
I need to talk to you.
Okay.
It's about tomorrow.
The world you saw,
it didn't last very long.
Seconds.
SARAH". And then he got better.
Yeah.
What are you asking?
What if Alton doesn't belong with us?
We need to consider that,
come tomorrow,
he may be gone.
I'm out.
So you had never seen the sunrise?
No.
Did you like it?
What color was it?
It was first red, then it was orange.
Okay.
So, then you just walked out...
%GROANS)
Alton! Alton!
- Get down!
- No, no.
That's enough. Don't you move.
- Stay down.
- No!
No!
No! No!
No! No, no!
- Alton!
- No!
Mom!
Alton!
No.
- Dad!
- No!
No! No!
No!
Doak, don't. Please.
- Roy!
- No!
Stop! Stop!
- Stop!
- Hey.
My boot. In my boot.
Get me out! Get me out!
Go!
Man, I'm sorry, Roy.
I just didn't see them coming.
Back on the road, guys.
Hey, asshole!
Back on the road now!
Roy!
FBI,
CIA, Homeland Security...
Someone has him. Someone knows where he is.
And the FBI have field offices.
Now, we could start there...
We won't find him.
He's gone.
The only thing I ever believed in was Alton.
And I failed him.
Hello, Alton. My name is Sharon Davison.
I'm a childhood development counselor.
I consult with the Federal Bureau of Investigation,
but I'm not in law enforcement.
I need to ask you some questions, okay?
There was a crash at a gas station you were at.
Do you remember that?
Who has been with you the last few days?
Have you been with your father?
I'm sorry, I didn't hear that.
Paul.
Who is that?
I want to talk to Paul Sevier.
- My name is... Paul Sevier.
Lead Operations Analyst.
They just gave me that title.
Who is this guy?
He's NSA.
What, uh...
The place that you and your father were trying to get to,
what's the significance of that location?
I will only speak with him.
Okay, everybody out.
Just get the information.
Okay, so where do we start?
That's impressive.
You know, I have to say,
I've really been looking forward to meeting you.
They think you're a weapon.
I'm not.
And the Ranch thinks you're their savior.
I'm not any of those things.
I belong in another world.
There are people there.
They watch us.
They've been watching us for a very long time.
I need to go where I belong.
Where you belong?
Hello?
- Is this Roy Tomlin?
- Yes.
I have your son.
Yes, he's fine. I'm bringing him to you.
Do you have something to write with?
Okay.
Alton!
Ready?
29 degrees, 4 minutes, 31 seconds north,
82 degrees, 41 minutes, 48 seconds west.
I'll have him there in four hours. Goodbye.
What about the backup generator?
They've all failed. I've never seen anything like it.
And the exits?
We have three. The gates to each one were open.
We can't get them closed without power.
Let's move out.
All right, moving out! Let's get this place cleaned up right away!
Move! Move!
You over there, take that side.
Let's go. Move it, move it, move it!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
SARAH; AI.
I decoded the same patterns you found in the sermons.
They know where you're going.
Everything will be blocked off for 5 miles.
You won't get through.
I can help.
Come on.
Can I come with you?
No.
Thank you.
Are those handcuffs?
I mean, obviously they're handcuffs.
You're Lucas, right? The state trooper?
Do you mind?
All right, thank you.
Too much to ask for you to punch me in the face?
You know, forget it. Never mind. Thank you.
Needs to be tighter.
Lift your arms up.
How's that feel?
Good.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
Are you scared?
Yes.
You don't have to worry about me.
I like worrying about you.
You don't have to anymore.
I'll always worry about you, Alton.
That's the deal.
Can you get this on?
We're gonna have to move fast once we stop.
I understand.
There has to be a better way in.
There's not.
We can do this alone.
You've done enough for us.
No.
Are you driving?
This is it.
You sure?
It has the fewest soldiers.
Get down on the floor.
Cover him up.
LUCAS". No room on the shoulder.
Water.
They've seen you.
Yeah, we know.
- Don't shoot!
They can only return fire!
- We're okay.
- Eyes on target.
We all right?
Yeah.
Here!
Alton!
Okay.
The steering's going.
The tread comes off those tires, it's gonna get a lot harder.
Can't keep this up.
You alive?
Could we go back to Texas now?
And you say here that he got out of the car
with the birth mother, Sarah Adams.
Yes.
Where is she now?
Your guess is as good as mine.
So you think they just walked away?
I didn't say that.
Well, then...
Just explain to me how,
with multiple types of aerial and ground surveillance
surrounding the area,
they could simply walk away undetected.
I don't know.
But if he didn't want you to see him,
you wouldn't see him.
I could tell it to you as many times as you want.
My story's not changing because it's true.
You know.
Y'all saw the same shit I saw.
But keep asking me if you want to.
I'm done.
They've sent in a specialist to speak with you.
I suggest that you answer him more fully.
Hello.
My name's Paul Sevier.