MY NEIGHBOR TOTORO
Hey, let's go
I'm happy as can be
Let's go walkin', you and me
Ready, set
Come on, let's go
Over the hill
Across the field
Through the tunnel we'll go
We'll run across the bridge
And down the bumpy gravel road
Right beneath the spider's web
Ready, set
Let's
Go
Hey, let's go
I'm happy as can be
Let's go walkin', you and me
Ready, set
Come on, let's go
The foxes and
The badgers, too
All come out to play
They all want to explore
The deep and wonderful woods all day
Look at all my many friends
Ready, set
Let's
Go
Look at all my many friends
Ready, set
Let's
Go
Thanks.
Daddy, want any caramel candy?
Thank you. I would. Anybody tired yet?
Mm-mmm.
We're almost there.
Good.
Ohh!
Mai, hide.
I thought he was a policeman.
Hi!
Hello there!
Ha ha ha! Ha ha ha!
- Whoa!
- Ha ha ha!
Sorry to bother you,
but are your parents around anywhere?
They're out there in the field.
Thanks a lot.
Hello there!
Looks like we're going to be neighbors!
Pleasure to meet you.
Good luck in the new house!
Thank you! See you soon!
Oh!
Thank you very much.
Everybody out.
Uhh! Ohh!
Hey!
Hang on.
There.
Hey, Mai, come over here a minute.
Wow!
What are those little things
swimming around?
l don't know.
Goldfish maybe or something?
So do you like it?
It's terrific!
Uh-huh.
Come on, Mai, run!
Wait up!
Wow!
- Can we?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh!
Ha ha ha!
You be careful, O. K.?
Oh, sure. Hee hee hee!
Ha ha ha!
- Oh!
Ohh!
What a lot of neat old junk.
Do you think it's haunted?
Ohh, maybe it is.
Oh, boy!
I bet I can beat you around the house!
Wait!
Ooh! Oh!
Ooh.
Ohh!
It's completely rotten.
Uh-oh, it's gonna fall down
- Ha ha ha!
- Hee hee!
Uhh! Uhh!
Oh! Hee hee!
Ooh!
Oh!
Hee hee! Aah!
Ha ha ha!
Hee hee hee!
Hey!
Ohh! Whee!
Whoo! Ha ha!
Ha ha ha! Ohh!
Wow, Mai, look up!
What?
Up there. Look.
Wow, what a tree.
It's giant!
That's got to be the biggest tree in -
Ah-choo!
Ha ha ha!
Daddy, look at that big tree
on the mountain!
That s a camphor tree.
Camphor.
Camphor tree!
Camphor!
Oh.
Uhh! Oh!
Hey, Mai. . .
Look, an acorn.
Huh?
But I want a acorn, too.
Oh, hey, wait a second.
There's some more over there.
Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
I have my own acorn right here.
Huh?
Mai, how am I supposed
to open the house up
if you're in the way?
Acorns!
I found a bunch near the back door.
They came from way up.
They came out of the ceiling.
Hmm. Some squirrels
must have dropped them.
- Ohh! Squirrels!
Or maybe some other animal,
perhaps a rat.
But I don't want a dumb rat!
Where am I going to put it?
Just bring it here.
I'll open it up for you.
Satsuki, open the kitchen door.
Here you go.
Mai, come on.
Hey!
Wait!
Hey, wait up!
You can't catch me
Can, too.
hh!
Oh.
- Aah!
Hmm.
Ready?
Mm-hmm.
Bathtubs.
Great.
Nothing up there.
No.
- Ohh!
Bathtubs are in there.
We saw something move in there.
A squirrel?
We're not sure.
Maybe they were cockroaches,
but there were millions of them.
Hmm.
Lots of little black things.
See anything?
Well, I'm pretty sure
they were dust bunnies.
Real dust bunnies,
like in my picture book?
Dust bunnies make more sense
than ghosts.
Why?
Uhh!
Ghosts are harder to see.
When you suddenly move
from a lighted room to darkness,
you can't see for a second.
That's when dust bunnies come out.
Boy. Yeah.
Come out! Come out!
- Come out!
- Come on out!
Come out! Come out!
Come out, dust bunnies!
- Ha ha ha!
Let's get to work.
We have to find the steps
that lead up to the attic.
What?
Find the way up.
We'll open all the windows upstairs.
Yeah!
Hey, wait for me.
Ha ha.
No stairs.
No.
Nothing here.
Nope. Nothing there.
Ha ha ha!
Nothing there.
Hee hee hee!
Ow.
Nobody in this room.
Nobody here!
- Hi!
- Ha ha ha!
Hey!
Ha ha ha!
Ohh!
Come here, Mai! I found it!
Hee hee hee!
Wow.
Someone up there?
Catch some ghosts upstairs?
- Ohh!
It's an acorn.
Uh-oh.
Uhh!
They must like them.
Little dust bunnies,
go away right now!
Oh.
Heh heh heh.
Hmm.
- Aah!
Aah.
Don't be scared, Mai.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
There's nobody here.
- Ohh!
Aah!
Oh.
Ohh!
There.
That's it. Easy.
Slowly.
Guess what.
Something's really living upstairs
after all!
That's wonderful. Good for you.
I've always wanted
to have a haunted house.
It's been my lifelong dream.
Uhh!
Careful!
Oh!
Ooh!
Aah!
Guess what, Sis! I got one!
Uhh!
Eh?
Aah!
Mai?
Oh.
Aah!
Huh!
Whoo whoo!
Ah! Ah! Ah.
Two fine kids.
There's nothing to be frightened about.
Nanny has the farm next door.
She's helping us out.
Nanny, this is Mai, my sister,
and I'm Satsuki.
Very pleased to meet both of you.
lf I'd known
what a hurry you were in to move,
I would've cleaned the house up.
It really isn't necessary.
Aah!
I've been so busy
in the rice paddies lately. . .
How did you get all that black on you?
I had a dust bunny right in my hand.
Ohh! Mai, your feet!
Uh-oh.
To do a little dusting. . .
You got mine black, too!
Eh?
Aha!
It appears the soot sprites
are hard at work.
What are they?
You mean those black little fuzzy things
that fly around and disappear upstairs?
Yes. They breed
in very old empty houses,
building invisible nests
and turning everything into dust.
l could see them, too,
when I was a very small child.
That you two are able to see them
makes me very glad.
It couldn't have been a spirit,
could it?
If they're not sprites,
then you have nothing
to be frightened about.
lf we keep smiling,
the sprites may gradually go away
and leave this place alone.
Yes. I'm sure that
somewhere up in that ceiling
they're busily discussing plans
for leaving the house.
Maybe they really will leave us alone.
What's wrong with them?
With dust bunnies all over the house?
I'm not afraid of dust bunnies.
Maybe you can go to the bathroom
by yourself at night.
Ha ha ha!
Come. The house needs cleaning up.
Fetch a bucket and go get some water.
From the stream?
Maybe we'll catch a fish!
- Ha ha ha!
- Hee hee hee!
You wait here, O. K.?
Did you get any fish?
Ha ha!
It's coming out!
It's coming out, Nanny!
Good. Very good.
Just keep at it
till the water gets cold.
Right.
Ha!
Oh.
Huh!
Hey, is that for us?
Is that for me?
Tell me what your name is.
Uh, it's for Grandma.
Huh?
Grandma?
Yuh-uh-uh.
Hmm?
Mmm!
Yuh-uh!
Hey, wait up! Where you going?
Kanta, don't be silly.
Hey, haven't you heard?
You re living in a haunted house!
- Ohh!
- Go away!
Yuh-uh!
Ehhhh!
Ha ha ha!
l remember doing that
when I was his age.
l hate boys, but I love Nanny's food
better than anything else
in the whole wide world.
Eat all you want.
Thanks for your help!
Bye!
Thank you so much, Nanny.
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Aah! Oh!
I'm scared the wind's going
to make the house fall down.
Maybe it will, but I hope not
because we just moved in.
Huh?
- Hmm?
- Ohh!
Aah!
- Ha ha ha!
- Ohh!
Come on. What are you waiting for?
You have to laugh loud
to scare a spirit.
Ha ha ha!
I'm not scared at all.
Uh huh ha ha.
I'm not! I mean it!
Aah! Ha ha ha!
- Ha ha ha!
Aah!
1, 2.
That's it. Give it all you got.
Come on. Yeah.
There we go.
Well, if I may humbly say so,
we're finished.
- Yay!
Uhh! There we are.
Get ready to fly, Mai!
Better hold on!
- Aah!
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
Here we go!
Nanny!
Hi!
Hello!
Where are you pedaling off to
this morning?
We're going to visit Mommy
in the hospital!
Well, be sure to give my regards!
I know she'll be very happy to see you!
Bye-bye.
Ehhhh!
Nyehhh!
That way, Daddy! That way!
- Ooh. Oh, oh.
- Ha ha ha!
Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
- Ohh!
Hee hee hee!
Mommy!
My love, I'm so happy to see you.
Daddy took the wrong road.
We had to come another way.
Well. Don't be shy.
We got off today from school.
Wonderful.
Daddy said to tell you he'll be here.
He's probably speaking to the doctor.
It's good to see you all.
Do you like the new house?
Yeah.
Ohh! You mean they live upstairs?
Mm-hmm.
Do you like fuzzy spirits, Mommy?
Yes. I wish I could go see them now.
You were right, Mai.
Mm-hmm.
We thought you might not be happy
about the house having spooks.
Are you happy with them?
Yep.
I'm not afraid of them.
Don't tell me
you fixed Mai's ponytails by yourself.
Mm-hmm.
They're beautiful.
You know, you're a very lucky girl.
She always gets mad at me.
That's because
you re always jumping around.
Satsuki, come here.
Why don't you let me brush your hair?
I'm glad it's short.
I want mine short.
When you re my age.
Satsuki, you have wire for hair,
as stubborn as mine when I was small.
I'll be able to have hair
as beautiful as yours
when I'm older, right?
Yes. I know that
because you look exactly like me
when I was young.
Hi.
Da da da-da da da
Da da da-duh
Da da da-da da da da-da
Da da-duh. . .
I thought Mommy looked a lot better.
l think the doctor
might let her leave shortly.
Does that mean tomorrow, Daddy?
Aw, tomorrow means tomorrow.
Maybe not tomorrow,
but it's pretty soon.
She said when she comes,
she'll only sleep in my bed.
You said you were big enough
to sleep by yourself.
Mommy told me it would be O. K.
- Ha ha ha!
Da da da-duh
La la la la
Daddy!
Daddy, wake up!
It's morning!
Ohh.
Daddy, get up.
Uhh!
It's Mai!
Hee hee hee!
Good morning.
I must have overslept.
We get our lunch boxes today.
I'm sorry. I completely forgot.
I made lunch for everybody.
Hey, it's burning.
Just a minute!
O. K. , this one's for you.
That one's mine.
Mai, stop that. Sit down and eat.
Go ahead. Wrap it yourself.
Ahh.
Hey!
You're late!
Must be time to go.
O. K.!
l can't believe
you've made a friend already.
Bet you sit next to her in class.
Yep, and her name's Michiko.
Ahh.
Here I come!
- Thanks for saying goodbye!
Hi. Sorry.
Why'd you take so long?
We're going to be late.
Ahh. . .
Uhmmm!
Daddy, this hat!
Am I a grownup if I wear it?
It looks that way.
Where are you going?
Going to get some flowers.
Is it lunchtime yet?
I don't think so!
Hmm.
Daddy, look. I'm the flower lady.
Heh heh heh.
Golly, wollypogs.
Hmm.
There's no bottom.
Huh?
Wow.
Acorn.
Dust bunnies.
Hey.
Huh?
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Come back!
Aha!
Hmm?
Aah!
Hey.
Ah-choo!
Ha!
Hmm?
Hmm.
Tell me who you are.
Are you a big dust bunny?
No.
I'm. . .
Waah!
To. . .
Ro!
Totoro?
That's it.
I bet your name's Totoro, isn't it?
So you're really a Totoro.
Totoro.
Sure, I will. Tomorrow.
- O. K. Bye.
- See you later.
Daddy, I'm home.
Already?
Wait. How come you're home so late?
I was playing with Michiko.
Where's Mai?
l haven't even eaten lunch.
I think Mai's out back.
Mai!
Mai?
Daddy, over here!
I think I know where Mai went.
Mai?
Mai!
Wake up!
Wake up.
Wake up, Mai! Right now!
You have no business
sleeping in this place.
How come he's gone?
How come who's gone?
Tell me who you lost.
A big Totoro was here with me.
A big one like
what's in our picture books?
Mm-hmm.
And I climbed up on top of him,
and he was furry,
and he had a big mouth,
and there was a little one
and one this big
and a great big one sleeping by himself.
Uh-huh?
Hello! Is anybody in there?
Well, I'll be.
What a great hiding place.
Daddy, Mai told me
she saw a big Totoro.
A real one?
Mm-hmm.
This way.
Ha ha!
Hey, give me a chance.
Here?
Mmm. Mm-hmm.
He was by the big tree
a little while ago.
I don't see how he could've escaped.
Mai! Mai, come back!
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Stop laughing!
I really saw him. I m not lying.
I'm not lying.
Mai.
You don't believe me.
Mm-hmm. That's where you're wrong.
l believe you're being
completely truthful about this.
But I also believe that you met
the king of the forest.
Meeting him is a sign of good luck.
There's no guarantee
you'll see him all the time.
We'll have to pay our respects.
Where do we find him?
Miss Mai will find him for us.
Oh!
Ohh, Mai, you're getting heavier
by the minute.
Daddy, the camphor tree.
What a beautiful tree.
I found it.
You sure that's the one?
Uh-huh.
What are you waiting for, Daddy?
Hurry up.
The hole's not there anymore,
but I'm sure this is where it was.
You're positive it is?
Mm-hmm.
The opening's completely disappeared.
Remember, you can see him
only when he wants you to.
Will we see him? I want to meet him.
You never can tell.
If we're lucky enough.
What a beautiful tree it is.
This tree's been here,
well, since before anyone can remember.
You know, a long time ago,
Man and trees were the best of friends.
It's actually because of this tree
that I decided to buy our house,
and Mommy will like it, too.
Let's thank the king of the forest
and get back for lunch.
I have to meet Michiko after lunch.
I'm coming, too.
Attention!
Thank you for all you've done for Mai.
Please protect her forever.
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
Last one home's a rotten egg.
No fair! You cheated!
Wait!
Hey!
Hey, wait up!
"Dear Mother,
You're never going to believe this,
but today, under that giant tree,
Mai actually met a ghost, Totoro.
Daddy says
it was the king of the forest.
Well, whoever he was,
I really want to meet him."
Kanta, you'd better hurry up,
or you'll be late.
O. K.
There.
Huh?
Mai? What. . .
Excuse me.
Yes, Satsuki?
I-i-it's my sister Mai.
What's she going to do?
Nanny! Nanny, what happened?
Dear, I'm sorry,
but she demanded to be with her sister.
But I'm going to be -
Mai, you promised to be a good girl
because Daddy's at the university
and can't take care of you.
l have a couple hours left
before I can come home,
and Nanny's been very nice to watch you.
Our Mai has been a very good girl.
Eh?
Well, I better ask permission
for her to come inside.
Because her mother's going to be
in the hospital,
Satsuki will be taking care
of her sister Mai.
Is that clear?
Yes, ma'am.
What's that a picture of, Mai?
A Totoro picture.
Shh!
Could you be a little more
quiet about it?
Bye-bye.
Want to come over and play?
I might miss the club meeting.
Come whenever you can.
Bye, Mai.
Goodbye.
We'd better walk fast,
or we're going to get wet.
O. K.
Oh, no! Hurry!
Oh!
Oh, my god.
Are you O. K.?
Yeah.
Come on.
Wow. What do we do now?
lf it's not too much trouble,
could we stay until it stops raining?
Uh. . .
Thanks.
Ha ha.
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
We were pretty lucky, huh?
Ha ha! That's funny.
It's got holes in it.
Uh-oh. Daddy left his umbrella.
Hey, we could bring it back to him.
I just forgot because I forgot.
How can you forget your umbrella
when it's raining?
Even you can't be that stupid.
You probably broke it in half.
I did not!
Hmm?
Y-y-yii!
Excuse me. Is anybody home?
Satsuki, what are you doing here?
Grandma.
Thank you for taking care of Mai.
Don't be ridiculous.
She was a treasure.
We wanted to bring back
the umbrella we borrowed.
But - Kanta's umbrella?
Why would he give you
this beat-up thing?
We didn't have one,
but I'm afraid he got soaking wet.
Anyway, please thank him for us.
l will.
I'm always telling him to wash,
so rain did him no harm.
Are you on your way to meet your father?
Yes, ma'am.
Give him my regards.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Hee hee hee!
Did someone come to the door?
I didn't hear anything.
Oh, boy, we made it!
Thank you.
Getting onboard or not?
All right, let's go.
Daddy wasn't on that one, right?
I'm sure he'll be on the next one.
Want to go back to Nanny's house
and wait?
What's the matter?
Mai, you re sleepy.
Uh-uh.
I told you it might be a while.
You don't want to go to Nanny's
and wait?
I'm sure the bus will come soon.
Just hang in there.
Well, I guess they were delayed,
but I hope not.
Come on.
Uhhh. . .
I bet you re Totoro.
Oh, we have another umbrella
if you want.
Go ahead. Take it.
Come on. I'm going to drop Mai.
You put it over your head like that.
Aah!
Huh?
The bus is here.
- Oh!
Mai, wa-wasn't that umbrella
he took with him Daddy's?
Thank you.
How nice of you to meet me.
Daddy!
I'm sorry, but the train was late.
That's why I missed the first bus.
You weren't worried, were you?
l saw him!
He was right beside me!
Me, too!
Uh. . . uh. . .
Oh, and gigantic arms.
Great big eyeballs, too.
It was scary.
I was scared.
We saw Totoro! We saw Totoro!
We saw Totoro
Hey, anyone want a ride?
I do!
O. K. , here we go!
Whee!
"Dear Mother, I'm surprised
I can write to you at all
'cause my heart is still
beating so fast,
Mai and I had something
incredible happen today.
We both met Totoro,
I really saw him.
He even gave us a gift.
It was a package
wrapped up in bamboo leaves
and tied with dragon whiskers.
We opened it immediately.
Guess what was in it!
Magic nuts and seeds."
- Oh!
Ha ha ha.
"We've decided to plant them
all out in the front
because someday
they'll be tall and beautiful.
Mai just. . .
sits there every day
waiting for them to sprout,
but they don't seem to want to grow.
l can't wait to see
what they'll be like.
Mai sends her love
and wanted to make sure
you saw her drawing."
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
"It's going to be
summer vacation soon,
and we'll be out of school.
l love you, Mother.
Please get well soon."
- Ha ha ha!
Come on, get off.
That's it! I said get off!
Come on, it's bedtime.
Daddy, will the plants come out?
I mean will they come out tomorrow?
That's tough to say.
Perhaps Totoro will be able to say
if they will.
Good night.
Wake up, Mai.
But isn't that where we planted -
Mm-hmm.
Oh! Ow!
Ha ha ha ha!
It worked!
Ah. . .
Ah!
Ah! Ah!
Ooh!
Yay!
Yay! We did it!
Hee hee!
Ah. . .
Yay!
Ah!
Ya!
- Aah!
- Now we know what makes the wind blow!
Hmm.
Huh?
Ha ha ha.
What happened to the tree?
Hey!
We did it! We did it!
Yay!
It was only a dream.
It wasn't a dream.
It wasn't a dream!
It was only a dream!
We did it!
Telegram!
Hello!
Hello! Anyone home?
Hmm.
Maybe not.
Nanny!
Ha ha ha!
Over here, Mai.
That one's perfect.
Ahh. . .
Hey!
About how ripe is this?
That's ripe.
Wow.
Your vegetable garden
is more like a mountain of treasure.
Thanks to Mother Nature.
Let's take a little rest, shall we?
There we are,
nice and cold.
Michiko will be jealous.
Mmm.
It's amazing.
They've absorbed
lots of wonderful things
from the sun.
That's what makes them so good
for the body and the soul.
Would they help my mother?
Of course they would.
My vegetable garden is bound
to make anyone feel better.
Our mother s coming home this week
from the hospital.
She'll sleep with me under my cover.
That's wonderful.
She s able to come back, is she?
She's coming home
to spend a couple of days
but has to go right back there.
I suppose she has to be careful.
Yes, she has.
We'll fatten her up
on my fresh vegetables.
I'm giving Mommy this corn
I picked for her specially.
I'm sure she'll love you for it.
Mm-hmm.
Mailman gave me this telegram
because you were out. Here.
But Daddy won't be home from
the university till after 9 :OO.
Open it now then.
A telegram is serious business.
Mm-hmm.
It's from my mother's doctor
at the hospital.
"Please contact me."
What's that supposed to mean?
Is something wrong or not?
l know something awful s
happened to her.
What am I supposed to do
if my father s not home?
Have you any way
of telephoning your father?
I have the number of his research lab,
but we don't have a telephone.
Take them to your mother's place.
Let them use the phone.
Do you understand?
Don t panic, but go quickly.
Mai, you make sure
you stay put at my house!
Mai!
Hey, Mai, don't follow me!
Go to Nanny's house.
Oh.
Hello, Operator.
I'd like to make
a long-distance call, please.
It's very important.
It's number 1354 at Station 12.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Your friend is very pretty.
What lovely hair.
Hello.
Yes.
Can you put me through
to the Main lecture room
of the Anthropology School?
To Professor Kusakabe.
Please hurry.
Yes, yes.
I'm his daughter.
It was from the hospital, Daddy.
I'm so worried.
Whoa, whoa. Slow down.
From the hospital?
Oh, O. K. It's all right.
I think I understand.
Now, I'm going to call the hospital.
What's happened to Mommy?
There's no need to worry.
I'll check with the hospital
and call you right back, O. K.?
Uh-huh.
Stay where you are.
I'm hanging up,
so you stay right there.
He'll be calling back.
So is it all right
if I stay here
by the telephone and wait?
You take all the time you need.
Hey, where are you?
Uh-oh.
Oh, no!
I'm giving this to my Mommy!
Go away!
You just better stop it right now!
Mai, the hospital said
that Mommy's condition isn't very good,
so she won't be coming home just yet.
But why?
Mai, what can we do?
lf she came home now,
it'd make it worse.
It would not!
But she'll be able
to come home real soon.
No!
All right then! Be that way!
Let's see if she dies!
No!
Don't be dumb, Mai!
Oh, I give up!
You're so stupid!
Come on, Mai.
Waah!
I'm not stupid!
I took care of the rest of the washing.
Come on, now.
It isn't the end of the world.
Your old Nanny's here to help.
Let's see that beautiful smile.
Your father's stopping off
at the hospital
on his way home, eh?
What I heard was that your mother
only caught a small cold.
She'll be home next weekend,
I believe.
That s what they said last time, too.
"It'll be a little visit,
just a few days
to see what's wrong with her.
It's just a cold."
What are me and Mai going to do
if Mommy dies?
Uh, uh. . .
What are we going to do, Nanny?
There, there.
Don't worry.
Your mother's not going to die.
Hush.
She'd never leave
two such beautiful children.
She loves you too much for that.
Don't cry.
Nanny will stay with you
until your father comes home.
Mai!
Where are you?
Mai, come back!
Did you see her anywhere?
No sign at all.
She wasn't at the bus stop?
That's very strange.
Where could she possibly have gone?
Maybe she's angry about this morning.
We had a bad argument and -
maybe she went to visit Mommy
in the hospital!
The hospital's so far from here.
It's - oh, my heavens!
It would take a grown man
three hours to get there.
Hey!
Oh, my goodness.
Please, you must get your father
right now.
Tell him little Mai has disappeared.
How could you do
something so stupid, Mai?
You always get lost.
Mai!
I'm sorry to bother you,
but you haven't seen
a little girl, have you?
She's my sister, about 5 years old.
Well, seems to me I remember someone.
Yes, near as I can recall,
she went that way.
Maybe she went through the forest.
Then again, she might've gone
in the other direction.
Are you sure it was your sister?
All sorts of folks come by here,
but I don't see them.
Mai, I'm scared.
Thank you!
Mai!
Please stop!
Aah!
Hey, are you crazy, kid?
I'm looking for my sister.
Have you seen a little girl
wandering around?
I'm afraid not.
Mai's her name,
and she's 5 years old.
She probably got lost.
We haven't seen anyone, have we?
l think she's going to
Shichikoku Yama.
We just came from there,
but we haven't come across anybody.
Well, thank you.
By the way, where are you from?
Matsugo.
You walked from there to here?
That s three hours away.
Well, good luck, kid.
I hope you find her!
Satsuki, wait!
Come here!
Kanta!
We haven't found her yet.
How about you?
Nothing.
My dad's got everyone
searching for her,
so you go home,
and I'll bike
to Shichikoku Yama, O. K.?
I'm afraid
if she visits Mommy's hospital,
she'll completely lose her -
Somebody found
some sandals by the lake.
There's no way she could get
past all those people
without somebody noticing.
Oh!
Hey, don't worry!
Nobody said they were Mai's sandals!
Did you find her yet?
Go back a bit over towards your right!
Hey, you have any poles left?
There's Satsuki.
Eh?
Look.
Mai!
Look, Satsuki.
Is it hers?
It's not hers.
What?
Ohh. . .
Merciful heavens.
You know, Satsuki,
for a while
I thought it might be Mai's.
Mom, I told you
you jumped to conclusions.
Forget it! It isn't hers!
So, what do we do now?
We keep on looking, that's what.
Whatever you do, you better hurry up.
It'll be dark soon.
I am grateful to you all.
If you could keep searching -
Don't worry. We understand.
Don't you think
we should call the police?
Well, I don't know.
Do you think the police could -
Where are you going?
Totoro,
I beg you, please protect Mai.
She ll be lost and probably scared.
I'll be good for the rest of my life
If I can just see her again.
Oh!
Aah!
What?
Totoro!
Totoro, Mai's lost somewhere.
l looked and looked,
but I can't find her anywhere!
Oh, please.
You have to help me find her.
She's probably alone somewhere
crying and upset.
Oh, Totoro, I'm scared.
What?
He wouldn't be able to.
But how come nobody sees the bus?
Oh. . .
Ha ha ha ha!
Oh!
Next stop,
Little Sister.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Mai, where are you?
But how does he make it do that?
Ohh. . .
Mai!
But, Sis, where are you?
Satsuki!
Mai!
There you are!
Satsuki!
Ha ha ha!
Oh, Mai.
I'm sorry.
Tell me one thing.
Were you bringing that corn
to the hospital?
Mm-hmm.
Next stop,
Shichikoku Yama Hospital.
You mean we can go to Mom's hospital?
You're wonderful!
I'm sorry.
It was all because of my silly cold
that the hospital sent that telegram.
The grief it must've caused all of you.
I hope you can forgive me.
It was simply a bureaucratic mistake.
I'm sure it wasn't terribly traumatic
for either of the girls.
It just means
you'll be home next weekend.
They understand.
l wouldn't be at all surprised
if they suffered more than we know,
in particular Satsuki
because she's so smart and sensitive.
Hmm, could be right.
You'd better be careful
after I get home
because I intend to spoil them rotten.
Oh, no!
Look. Mommy's laughing.
She seems pretty healthy to me.
Yep.
Oh, I can't wait to get up
on my feet again.
Neither can we.
Oh.
Hmm.
Now, that's weird.
Oh!
What happened?
Well, I'm not sure,
but I could've sworn
l saw both girls in the treetop
laughing.
That might not be as crazy as you think.
"For Mother. . ."
Totoro
Who leaves the seeds
For you to find?
Follow them
And you will see
A treasure there
Then plant the seeds
And help them grow
It may seem like a dream
But things are not what they seem
Now begins a new adventure
For you
And you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
Living in the forest trees
For such a very, very long time
There you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
You only see him
When you're very young
A magical adventure for you
It's magic for you
Rain tumbles down
The bus is late
Suddenly
A furry wet giant
Is by your side
Don't be afraid
Just open wide
Your umbrella for him
Watch him play in the rain
Now begins a new adventure
For you
And you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
And on a moonlit night
He plays a magic flute in the sky
There you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
You only see him
When you're very young
A magical adventure for you
It's magic for you
THE END