Another village destroyed.
Let's go, soon, this will also
be consumed in the Sea of Decay.
1,000 years after the collapse
of industrial civilization,
the Sea of Decay, a swamp
exuding toxic vapors,
covered an earth strewn
with rusting ruins,
threatening human survival.
NAUSICAA
OF THE VALLEY OF THE WIND
Executive Producers
Yasuyoshi TOKUMA - Michio KONDO
Original story and screenplay by
Hayao MIYAZAKI
Based on the serial graphic novel
"Nausicaa of the Valley of the Wind"
Music by
Joe HISAISHI
Producer
Isao TAKAHATA
Director
Hayao MIYAZAKI
An ohmu's tracks.
They're still fresh.
An ohmu's shell.
Amazing.
I've never seen a perfect shell.
Lovely sound.
It chipped my ceramic sword.
The villagers will be pleased.
They'll have plenty
to make into tools now.
What an eye.
I wonder if I can carry it?
It came free.
It's incredibly light.
Mushigo Palm spores.
So beautiful...
Though in this forest of death,
your lungs would rot
in five minutes without a mask.
Who is that?
What can it be?
My heart's pounding.
Those are gunshots.
An insect
is attacking someone.
Oh, I'm sorry!
Over there!
What a thick spore cloud.
An ohmu!
That must have been its shell.
Don't run that way!
Look this way!
They answered!
They're coming.
Who's that?
What a magnificent ohmu.
- Go upwind!
- Thank you!
Return to the forest, ohmu.
This is not your world.
Be a good boy.
It's blinded by rage.
I've got to calm him.
The flares stunned it.
An insect charm.
Awaken, ohmu.
Return to the forest.
It's awake.
The ohmu's returning to the forest.
She tamed that ohmu
with flares and an insect charm.
Lord Yupa!
Nausicaa,
I hardly recognized you.
It's been a year and half.
Father will be glad.
I must thank you.
You've become a great wind-rider.
Oh, no, not according to father.
Oh, of course
I'd completely forgotten about him.
A fox-squirrel.
I've never seen one.
When a winged insect snatched him,
I took him for a human child.
I had to fire my gun.
That's what enraged the ohmu.
He'd fainted
so was spared the poison.
Better not touch him.
Even young, they're savage.
Come.
Here.
Hey...
You're not scared.
See... you're not scared.
See...
You were just frightened.
Lord Yupa, may I have him?
Why certainly...
Thank you.
Kai and Kui.
Remember me?
A mysterious power.
You must be tired.
You ran so far.
Is everyone well?
What's wrong?
My father...
He can no longer fly.
Jihl...
The forest poisons?
Yes. He says it's fate
for those living by the Sea of Decay.
I should have come sooner.
Oh, no.
Thank you for coming.
Lord Yupa, there's something
I want to show you.
My secret room.
It's a secret.
I don't want to scare them.
I'll tell them you're coming.
Come soon!
Lord Yupa.
Would you carry this?
It's hard to fly with.
She certainly reads the wind well.
Not far now.
Oh...
Lord Yupa.
- Welcome.
- Are you in good health?
The waters and winds
are clear and calm.
- Lord Yupa.
- Hello all, you're well.
Lord Yupa.
We've missed you.
Princess, he has come.
Wait.
Lord Yupa.
Old Mito, you're hard at work.
Tonight I'll hear
tales of your travels.
OK, start it.
- Seems to work.
- Yes.
This is excellent.
Tomorrow, we'll send
people to get the rest.
Come, Toeto.
Lord Yupa.
This is Toeto's baby, born this year.
Oh, let's have a look.
A fine baby.
Reminds me of Nausicaa
as a baby.
Please be her godfather.
Name her that a fair wind
may favor her.
I will indeed.
I'll find her a fine name.
Thank you.
May she grow up
as strong as our Princess.
She's as strong as they come.
But we won't want her
playing in the Sea of Decay.
But that's where
I found the ohmu shell.
Put yourself in my shoes.
I'm responsible for this castle.
She's made me sick with worry.
Let her play in the Sea of Decay
if she finds us ohmu shells.
Indeed, her presence
there saved me.
Saved by the girl?
This is a fine valley.
Being here calms my spirits.
How was your journey?
It was terrible.
The Sea of Decay consumed
two more countries to the south.
It's spreading all the time.
And yet war and hunger
are everywhere.
Nothing but bad omens.
Why can't they live
as you do in this valley?
The ocean winds protect our valley.
The Sea of Decay
can't reach us here.
What do you say, Yupa?
Isn't it time you
settled in this valley?
Look at my condition.
It would please everyone.
Don't bother.
Yupa's a man who is fated
to search forever.
Fate, huh...
Obaba, what's he searching for?
Oh, my,
don't you know, Nausicaa?
Look, see the tapestry on the wall...
I no longer see it.
The figure in the left corner:
"...clothed in blue robes,
"descending onto a golden field,
"to join bonds
with the great earth
"and guide the people
to the pure land, at last."
Lord Yupa, I always thought
that was only a legend.
You mustn't tease me, Obaba.
It's the same thing.
I only wish to solve
the Sea of Decay's mysteries.
Are we humans but a tribe
destined to be swallowed and ruined
by the Sea of Decay?
That is what I wish to know.
If only I could help Lord Yupa...
Princess, Princess.
What is it, Mito?
A strange scent on the wind.
It's nearly dawn.
I'll be right there.
How is it?
It's one fine storm,
but something's amiss.
Over there! Look!
It's a ship.
Why would a ship be here?
What is it?
Lord Yupa. It's a ship.
- A ship!
- It's coming closer.
It's huge!
It's a Tolmekian ship.
It's not flying right.
It's an emergency landing.
Help me up, Gol.
Princess, you mustn't!
I'll guide them to the shore.
It's coming about.
Off you go!
Teto!
How dare they!
They must have landed before
and killed some insects.
Turn away!
You'll crash!
Turn!
- It crashed.
- The Princess.
- The cliffs.
- Let's go!
Everyone to the rescue.
Even the boys!
It's that girl, she's alive.
Where am I...
The Valley of the Wind.
Save your strength.
My name is...
Lastel of Pejite.
My cargo...
Burn the cargo...
- The cargo...
- Please, burn it.
Your cargo, I understand.
Don't worry.
It's all in flames.
Thank goodness.
Princess!
That's...
The Princess of Pejite.
An insect!
An Ushiabu's alive.
Oh, no, it's calling its friends.
- It can't fly.
- Bring guns!
No, if you shoot it,
it'll call others.
I'll kill it now.
Guns won't kill an Ushiabu.
Then what!
Wait! Mito! Bring my glider.
Princess!
Return to the forest.
You're strong, you can fly.
That's a good boy.
- Princess.
- Thanks.
Thank God.
No telling how we'd suffer
for even a single insect's death.
An ohmu...
Found one!
Come!
Here!
So those were spores
stuck to that ship.
They haven't released
any toxins yet.
We're almost done.
I know.
We can't miss a single one.
What on earth is this?
The fire didn't destroy it...
Leave this mystery
for later, folks.
Go and help burn the spores.
Be careful, now.
Why'd she bring
this bundle of trouble here.
Mito, look here.
It's pulsing.
Almost like it's alive.
Lord Yupa, what is this...
On my journey
I heard ominous rumors...
That a monster from the old world
that had slept beneath Pejite
had been unearthed.
A monster from the old world?
Giant Warriors...
The Giant Warriors!
They say they were destroyed
in the Seven Days of Fire.
This...
The Giant Warriors were all said
to have turned to stone.
But a single one slept
in the earth for 1,000 years.
In... In a way,
the thing looks almost human.
Tolmekia's a savage military state,
far to our west.
And remember the Pejite
captive who perished...
Keep up the good work.
What's that?
Tolmekian ships!
Everyone to the castle!
To the castle!
Gather in the castle!
The castle!
Father!
Obaba, hide yourself.
I'll stay right where I am.
Princess!
How dare you!
Nausicaa...
Stay where you are!
Move and this sword,
carved of insect shell
will pierce your ceramic armor.
That's Yupa...
I ask you Tolmekian warriors.
Last night, these villagers toiled
desperately to save one of your ships.
We have just now gently
laid one of your dead to rest.
Is this how you Tolmekians
treat such a nation, however weak!
If you would make war,
you must have reasons.
You should first send a messenger
to declare them.
Nausicaa...
Be calm, Nausicaa.
If you fight now,
they will slaughter the villagers.
We must survive.
Wait for our chance.
You... Little wench.
Put it down, Kurotowa.
But...
Look at this mess.
Killed them all.
Your rebuke stings.
Are you Yupamiralda,
the greatest swordsman of this region?
We have not come for slaughter.
We wish to talk.
Lay down your sword.
The Princess!
Princess!
Listen well!
Her Highness Kushana,
Division Commander
of the Tolmekian
Frontier Forces will speak.
We have come to unify
the frontier nations
and build peace in this region.
You live on the brink of extinction
beside the Sea of Decay.
Accept our rule
and join our enterprise.
We shall burn away the Sea of Decay
and resurrect the earth!
Burn away the Sea of Decay?
Is that possible?
We have revived
the miraculous skills and power
that once allowed humans
to rule this earth.
For those who submit to us,
I promise a life free from fear
of the toxins and insects of that swamp.
Wait!
You must not harm the Sea of Decay.
What's that, you old hag?
Take her away.
Let her speak.
In the 1,000 years
of the Sea of Decay,
countless times have humans
sought to burn it away.
Yet... each time herds
of ohmus, blind with rage,
have swarmed the earth,
like a tidal wave.
Destroying nations,
swallowing cities,
the ohmus' rage would not quiet
until they starved to death.
In time, the spores
took root in the ohmus' rotting flesh,
and engulfed our vast earth
in this Sea of Decay.
You must not touch
the Sea of Decay.
Enough!
No more of your ravings.
Ah! What will you do?
Kill me, too?
You!
Kill me if you will!
Easy work to murder
an old blind woman.
Just as you murdered Jihl.
Not Jihl!
- How cruel!
- He was helpless!
Shut them up!
Show no mercy to impudence!
Wait, everyone!
Please listen to me.
I don't want anymore sacrifices.
Please.
Princess...
You, too, Obaba.
We must submit to these people.
Step on it.
Hurry up!
It really is a lovely valley.
I'm against it.
We have orders to send
the Giant Warrior back at once.
An order we can't possibly fulfill.
Even our biggest ship
collapsed from its weight.
But you can't be serious
about building a nation here...
And what if I am?
You expect me to hand over
that monster as a toy for those fools?
You have a point...
I am but a simple soldier.
Such a decision is beyond my position.
You're a sly fox.
While I'm in Pejite, your priority
is to revive that Giant Warrior.
Yes.
Can this gun ship fly?
Yes, we found it here.
Get this straight.
I'm not asking you.
But take the Princess to Pejite...
Five hostages, the gun ship and food...
You pick the hostages.
Prepare everything
for the morning.
Thanks for going as a hostage.
We're fine, but look.
They're taking everything in sight.
I will slip away, return in secret
and await my chance.
We must prevent
that monster's resurrection.
Yes.
Nausicaa.
Teto, where is she?
Nausicaa! What on earth is this?
These plants
are from the Sea of Decay.
I've grown them
from spores I collected.
Don't worry, they're not toxic.
Not toxic...
The air here is pure indeed, but...
Why... with this deadly poisonous
plant blooming?
The castle windmill draws water
from deep within the earth.
The sand, too,
comes from the very bottom of the well.
With pure water and soil,
the plants from the Sea of Decay
are not poisonous.
The pollution lies in the earth itself.
Even the earth of our valley.
Why...
Who made such
a terrible mess of the world?
Did you do this all yourself?
Yes.
To cure my father's illness
and that of others.
But... I'm closing it down.
I just shut off the water
and they'll soon wither and die.
Nausicaa.
I frighten myself.
I don't know what my rage
will make me do.
I don't want to kill anyone.
Princess.
We gathered these for you.
- Chiko nuts.
- They're for you.
All of you...
So many.
You've worked so hard.
Thank you.
- They're very precious.
- It's not fair, Princess.
All aboard!
We're taking off.
There, now.
You mustn't cry.
Don't worry.
I'll be home in no time.
Really?
Why, have I ever lied to you?
No.
- Right?
- Yeah.
- Promise?
- Yes.
Go along, it's dangerous.
OK.
You promised!
Take care of the Princess!
Aren't we in Pejite yet?
My back is killing me.
Boy oh boy, did the Princess
ever pick a bunch of losers.
Hey, isn't this strange?
Why do they fly so close together?
Like they're afraid of an attack.
Toxins swirl below the clouds.
Don't move.
A gun ship!
Enemy fire!
They've hit ship number two!
I told you so.
Wow, terrifying!
Defense formation!
- That's a Pejite gun ship
- Pejite!
Damn! They got number three.
What's the Korvet doing?
Their ships just crumble.
Oh no, he's hit our tail.
The Barge tether snapped.
Hurry, Teto.
Oh, no, we're going down.
Princess!
Stop! No more killing!
No more!
Princess.
Hurry, Mito!
Princess, we're doomed.
- Maybe I can fly it.
- Are you crazy!
- Hurry, Mito!
- What? Right!
Start the engine!
Blast open the door!
Come! Hurry!
Get inside.
Mito, ready?
Ready or not!
Full throttle when we take off!
- Roger!
- Ready! Go!
Put on the toxin mask.
Drop below the clouds
to find the Barge.
You're still warm.
Don't give up, Teto.
What is this place!
I've never seen
such dense toxins.
Keep an eye on the right tail.
It's nearby.
It's still aloft.
Hey! You're right!
There it is!
- It's the Princess!
- Princess!
Don't give up, everyone.
I'll throw you a rope.
Our hook's broken.
You can't hook us in mid-air.
I don't want to crash
and become insect food!
We'll leap to our deaths!
Don't panic!
Ditch your cargo.
- Goodbye!
- Farewell!
Listen to me!
Toss your cargo!
- Kill the rear engine.
- What?
The engine noise is too loud.
Hurry!
Yes!
What?
Princess...
What are you...
Your mask, Princess!
You'll die!
Put your mask on!
I promise you'll be safe.
Trust me and dump that cargo.
We'll do whatever you say.
Please! Put your mask back on!
The Princess is smiling.
We're going to be OK.
Hurry! Lose the cargo.
- Princess, we're in a nose-dive!
- Re-start engines!
I inhaled.
Hurry, hurry.
Princess!
Everyone safe?
Don't move!
You!
Thanks for saving me.
Why'd you save her, Princess?
You're a fool.
You thought
I'd grovel in gratitude?
You know nothing of the Sea of Decay.
It isn't like the human world.
There's no knowing
what a single gunshot will bring.
That battle
hurled ships into this forest.
The insects are furious.
Look up.
The Yamma are sentries.
They'll quickly bring other insects.
We must escape now.
Throw me your extra rope.
Mito, fix the hook.
Don't move.
I give the orders.
What are you so afraid of?
You're just like
a lost fox-squirrel
How dare you!
Don't be afraid.
We just want you to go back
to your own country.
You...
They're here!
Quiet! Don't anger them
This is an ohmu's nest!
We're surrounded.
They're examining us.
Forgive us, ohmu,
for disturbing your nest.
Please understand,
we're not your enemies.
Princess!
He's still alive.
Wait, ohmu!
What's happening?
Their eyes have turned blood-red.
What will you do with the glider?
When the waters quiet,
take off and wait for me above.
If I'm not back in one hour,
return to the valley.
But...
Princess!
She's gone.
Hand it over.
All right, everyone.
We'll do as the Princess said.
Princess...
Damn!
- Who are you?
- You think only of killing.
My flares and charms
won't help now
It's quicksand!
Damn!
It's been two hours already.
More and more insects.
Princess!
Nausicaa.
Come here.
Father.
Mother's here, too.
No, I don't want to go.
Stay away!
There's nothing here.
I said, there's nothing!
Stay inside.
It's a baby ohmu.
She's being used by the insects.
Give it to me, Nausicaa.
No! It's not doing anything bad.
Insects and humans
can't live in the same world.
Please, don't kill it!
Please!
Teto...
What a strange place.
Hey!
I finally found it.
How are you feeling?
Where are we?
First, let me thank you.
I'm Asbel of Pejite.
Thank you for saving me.
I'm Nausicaa
of the Valley of the Wind.
Where are we?
No wonder you're surprised.
We're beneath the Sea of Decay.
Beneath the Sea of Decay?
Look, we fell from up there,
along with the sand.
We're not wearing masks.
That's right.
The air here is pure.
Couldn't believe it myself,
finding this place
under the Sea of Decay.
What is it?
Nausicaa, don't wander too far.
What a wonderful tree.
Even though it's dead,
water still flows through it.
Just like the sand
at the bottom of our well.
Grains of petrified wood
sifting down from above.
Nausicaa.
Are you crying?
Yes. I'm so happy.
Lastel was my twin sister.
I should have been with her.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you sooner.
Oh, no...
I'm sorry.
I nearly killed the person
who eased my sister's pain.
I see...
So it's in the Valley of the Wind.
This nut tastes really weird.
It's a chiko nut.
It's really good for you.
It doesn't taste great,
but I could eat a whole boot-full!
Why the Sea of Decay was born...
You think the strangest thoughts.
The trees of the Sea of Decay
grew to cleanse
a world polluted by humans.
They absorb toxins from the earth,
generate pure crystals,
die and turn to sand.
That's what created
these underground caverns.
The insects protect this forest.
In that case, we're doomed.
We can't possibly survive,
living in terror of toxins and insects
for thousands of years.
At least we can find a way
to keep it from spreading.
You sound just like Kushana.
No! We don't plan to use
the Giant Warriors!
You'll see when you
meet my friends tomorrow.
Let's go to sleep.
We have far to go tomorrow.
All's well.
On schedule?
The torso is solidifying well.
You're one cute monster.
Makes a poor soldier think
of dusting off old ambitions.
It's grinning.
You should've slept
beneath the earth till the end of time.
Counselor!
Her Highness' planes
were attacked by Pejite survivors.
All crashed, except the Korvet.
What about Her Highness?
Her ship exploded in flight.
Counselor.
- The villagers don't know yet?
- No.
OK, we'll head out.
You stay here and keep working.
Either fortune's finally smiling
on this lowly soldier...
Or it's a trap set to destroy me...
Mito and the others have returned,
waiting at Acid Lake, Lord Yupa.
In shame we return without her.
No, no, I'm pleased you're safe.
Releasing me?
Drown the Giant Warrior
deep in Acid Lake,
and return to your country...
Few of your soldiers remain here.
We could easily start a fight,
but why sacrifice more people?
Fire and water are powerless against it,
and it's only a matter of time
before it starts to walk.
Don't you see?
It's far too late to turn back.
My orders to invade Pejite
were motivated by fear
that another country
had harnessed its strength.
Once its presence here is known,
the great powers
will send their armies.
You have but one choice left.
Revive the Giant Warrior,
defy both great powers
and learn to live with that thing.
Look.
An insect did that?
Whoever becomes my husband
will see worse than that.
Burn the Sea of Decay,
kill the insects,
and restore the human world.
Why do you hesitate!
Steal it from us,
just as we stole it from Pejite.
We shall not give
the Giant Warrior life.
Emergency!
- What's the password?
- I'm in a hurry!
- Wind.
- Valley!
OK.
Some spores survived!
What!
They're spreading toxins
and the valley's going crazy!
Hand 'em over.
Hurry up!
Hurry, or the valley's doomed.
We need our tools back.
The tools that burn spores
can also be used as weapons.
We have no choice.
Release everything but their guns.
The Korvet's taking off.
Get through this time.
Summon all our troops
from Pejite to this valley.
Good grief,
now this is a real mess.
Hurry.
Find the Princess.
Look after the valley.
Be careful until we return.
We're going to the valley.
It's no use,
the spores are already here.
And on this side, too.
- Move!
- What are you doing!
Oh, no, here, too.
Obaba.
We've no choice but to burn it.
This forest is doomed.
If we hesitate, the Sea of Decay
will consume our valley.
Isn't there anything to be done?
This forest guarded
the reservoir for three centuries.
Damn! If only they'd never come.
This is getting out of hand.
Let's go help them.
You think so?
I think it looks the same as ever.
The insects have gone.
I wonder why my heart's
pounding so hard.
We're almost there.
My friends are just
over that mountain.
Pejite looks strange.
What is that haze?
Asbel, your mask.
Insects! All dead.
Head for Pejite.
Be careful, the Tolmekian
army must be there.
Even an ohmu...
It attacked the Great Dome.
Pejite's finished.
They wiped out the Tolmekians,
but this is...
They wiped out?
What do you mean, Asbel?
It's a Brig.
My friends' ship!
They're landing, let's go!
Asbel! You're alive!
What have you done?
We can't rebuild it.
You've seen the city.
Don't worry, if the Sea of Decay
swallows it, we'll burn it away.
But the Giant Warrior isn't here.
I know, it's in the Valley of the Wind.
How did...
We haven't exactly been idle.
We've launched our second phase.
We'll wipe out the Tolmekians
in the valley tonight.
What!
What are you going to do?
Who's this, Asbel?
Nausicaa
from the Valley of the Wind.
I owe her my life.
Valley of the Wind...
Tell me, what will happen?
You must know, Asbel!
Tell me.
They'll provoke an insect attack.
So you made them
attack Pejite, too!
You're... horrible...
We simply have to recover
the Giant Warrior before they revive it.
We're doing it to save the world.
And so you'll murder
everyone in the Valley!
Stop it! Call it off! Please!
It's too late.
Once they've started,
no one can stop them.
We've lost most of our people
to the Tolmekians.
This is the only way.
Let go! Let me fly!
It's horrible now, but the Giant Warrior
will purge the Sea of Decay
and rebuild the human world.
Liar! You're just like the Tolmekians.
No, they want to use it for destruction.
You drink water from the wells, too.
Do you know what purifies that water?
The trees in the Sea of Decay
cleanse all the lakes
and rivers that humans polluted!
And you want to destroy that!
Why did you dig up
that Giant Warrior!
What choice do we have?
Subject ourselves to Tolmekian rule?
Never, never!
Tell them, Asbel,
how the Sea of Decay came to be.
How the insects protect this world!
Please, Asbel!
What are you doing!
Don't move! Release her.
Calm down, Asbel.
I'm serious.
Release her.
Nausicaa, go and warn them!
Asbel! Let me go!
Fools.
No stopping fighting once it starts.
But he warned us to be careful...
Quit dawdling and use the tanks
to rescue our men.
Counselor! They got the last man!
Coming our way?
I don't know.
The whole village is gathering.
Why do they go berserk
over a little forest or two?
Just as it was with Pejite.
They got our tank!
Hurry, get it moving.
Don't panic.
Incoming fire!
Forward!
Hurry up!
Maybe this is it?
It's moving!
Which way?
Forward, move forward.
I know that.
Damn! Mobilize all the tanks.
She survived...
So much for my dreams...
Your Highness!
We'll hold 'em off here.
Lead everyone
to safety by Acid Lake.
All right.
It's just until the Princess
returns with the gun ship.
Hurry, everyone!
Stop gawking and help me.
My aching back.
The tanks are coming!
- Hurry!
- I know that.
Are you sure?
It's a Pejite Brig.
- I saw it peeking through the clouds.
- OK!
Watch out, she's a wild one.
Quickly.
Nausicaa, you may go free.
Go warn your Valley.
Your glider
may get you there in time.
It's waiting.
Asbel told me everything.
I'll take your place.
Put this on.
You're...
Lastel's mother.
Thank you.
I'm so very sorry.
Everything we've done is wrong.
Hurry!
- What about her?
- She'll be all right, don't worry.
Be careful.
We've treated you so badly.
Over here, Nausicaa.
Hurry.
Thank you, everyone!
Sorry it took so long.
- Can you launch from here?
- I'll try.
A Korvet!
Take cover in the clouds!
Stop firing!
Idiots! Nothing but wind
and lightning in there.
It's useless! I've lost control!
The ship is breaking apart.
We have to leave
the clouds and fight.
They were expecting us.
What are they up to?
Forcing us into the clouds
so they can board us.
Here they come.
This is your last chance.
No, I'll stay with you.
I can't abandon all those people
and the girl who took my place.
Only you can save your people.
Please, go, for our sakes!
The ship is ours.
Take no prisoners.
Destroy them.
Go, Nausicaa!
Asbel!
Princess!
Mito!
Mito! Lord Yupa!
Princess!
Hurry, everyone's in!
I'll engage the hook now.
Lord Yupa, that red lever!
This is their last stronghold.
The door won't hold.
Any time.
Show them some Pejite pride.
What is that?
A bird?
- A ship, a gun ship from the Valley.
- What!
You...
It's Lord Yupa,
here's a chance for glory!
Surrender,
your Korvet won't be back.
This guy's tough.
Princess, you're crazy.
The engine'll blow.
Just make it to the Valley.
Speed up!
Dear God, God of the Wind.
Please protect my people.
They won't budge.
They're waiting for her return.
Return?
They believe that girl
will return with their gun ship.
That gun ship's a pain.
It's our chance to attack.
Do you know what that ship is?
It's from before
the Seven Days of Fire.
The one they say
went as far as the stars...
It's too strong for our guns,
but bury it in a hole...
I, too, wish to wait.
If she really does return
from deep in the Sea of Decay...
I'd like a chance
to really talk to her.
Made up your minds?
If you'll aid our attack,
I'll let you go.
You want to end up like Pejite?
You're a Princess, too.
You're nothing like our Princess.
Look at my hand.
That's what King Jihl had.
In six more months
it will be stone.
But our Princess said,
she liked these hands.
They were the beautiful hands
of a hard worker.
You want to live
with the Sea of Decay
even as its toxins ravage you?
You use fire.
We use it a bit, too.
Too much fire
and nothing will grow.
Fire can turn the forest
into ashes in a single day.
Water and wind
sustain a forest for 100 years.
We like the water and the wind.
The sight of our forest
will grieve the Princess.
Counselor, we await your orders.
- Shut up.
- Yes sir.
Who knows what happened,
but she sure looks cute.
Let them go, Kurotowa!
Huh? You want to wait?
Feed the soldiers.
We attack in one hour.
Food, huh?
Finally, a real meal.
Someone's coming!
It's Gol and the others.
What is it?
There's no wind.
No wind?
You're right, the wind's stopped.
Obaba, what is it?
Obaba.
Someone...
Someone take me outside...
The wind's never stopped before.
Obaba, my ears hurt.
The air...
The very air is thick with rage.
We're close!
We're clear of the Sea of Decay!
3 minutes to Acid Lake!
Idle the engines.
Drop beneath the clouds.
What's this glow!
Ohmus!
The Sea of Decay is spreading.
They're headed for the Valley.
How did they stampede the ohmus...
Someone's baiting them.
Mito! Turn towards Sirius.
Yes!
It's there. Mito, a flare!
Ready.
Fire!
What is that?
How cruel...
They're baiting them
with a baby.
I'll shoot 'em down!
No, Mito!
Don't shoot!
Why not! Why shouldn't I?
Kill the baby,
and the stampede will never end!
What can we do!
They'll destroy the Valley.
Calm down, Mito.
Return the baby to them.
Let's try.
- What are you doing, Princess!
- You go ahead and warn them.
Princess!
You're not even armed.
That's not one of our flares.
- How far?
- 20 leagues.
The other side of the lake.
Is it a gun ship?
Probably.
That's a distress signal.
It's definitely the gun ship.
It's been an hour, let's go.
Why not wait?
The bloodshed is inevitable.
Infantry, advance.
Your Highness, get inside.
I'm fine here.
The gun ship!
Fire!
Hold your fire! Stop it! Stop!
Princess!
Stand-by. Don't fire.
Your Highness.
Where's the girl!
- The Princess!
- She's not here.
The ohmu, a stampede.
It's coming this way.
- What!
- The ohmu!
The Princess stayed behind
to stop them.
This is no time for battle.
Everyone run,
find the highest place you can! Now!
Obaba, I see a red glow.
It's spreading.
It's coming this way.
You hold on tight.
There's no stopping them now.
Don't panic.
There's still time.
If I have to die,
I want to die in the Valley.
No, you mustn't give up,
not while the Princess has faith.
Listen, hold them off
as long as you can.
I'll return soon.
Your Highness, not that...
It's not ready yet!
If not now, when!
Go!
Don't shoot! Listen to me!
Damn! She flies like a bird.
She's not an enemy.
She wants to say something.
Anyone who interferes is an enemy.
We'd better drop the bait
in the Valley soon, or die ourselves.
Here she comes!
Let her come in close, then fire.
Now! Fire!
- No! That's Lastel!
- Move!
Ohmu...
Don't be angry.
Don't be frightened.
I'm not your foe.
I'm sorry.
I can't ask your forgiveness.
It's too cruel.
Don't move!
You'll bleed to death.
Be good, little one, keep still.
They've found us.
They're coming.
Stop! Not with those wounds!
The lake is poison...
You...
Good baby.
I'm fine.
They're coming for you.
They're turning away.
Ohmu! Don't!
The Valley's that way.
They've forgotten us in their rage.
If I don't calm them, the Valley...
Fools! Drawing them
with their own fire.
We're safe.
We'd better get away.
Check the engine.
No, no!
We can discuss this.
Take us to them.
I must give them the baby.
What's the point, it's too late.
They'll never stop.
Drop us in front of them, then.
Take us.
But you'll die, too.
Obaba, will we all die?
If that's our fate,
we must accept it.
They don't even waver.
Let's retreat.
Idiot! There's nowhere to go.
Don't retreat!
Hold your ground
for Her Highness.
Highness...
Your Highness!
Get them!
The Giant Warrior...
Giant Warrior.
It's rotting. It's too soon.
Burn them!
What's wrong?
Are you not descended
from Earth's most evil tribe!
Incredible...
No wonder the world caught fire.
Your Highness Kushana, hurray!
Destroy them!
What's wrong with you?
Hurry up and fire!
We're done for.
The Giant Warrior is dead.
It's for the best.
The ohmu's rage
is the fury of the Earth itself.
There's no reason to live
if our lives depend on a monster.
- Princess!
- The Princess!
Not there.
- It's madness.
- Princess!
The ohmus are changing color.
Their rage has vanished.
They stopped. The ohmus stopped.
Princess!
The Princess is dead.
She calmed them
with her own life.
She saved our Valley.
Look...
What is that light?
Teto...
Wonderful.
Thank you, ohmu.
Thank you.
It's a miracle. A miracle.
Such friendship and sympathy.
The ohmus have opened their hearts.
Children, watch well and tell me
what I cannot see.
The Princess is wearing
strange blue clothes.
It's like she's walking
through golden fields.
"...clothed in blue robes,
"descending onto a golden field..."
Obaba...
The ancient legend was true.
Look!
The glider.
The wind!
The wind has returned.
VOICES
Sumi SHIMAMOTO
Ichiro NAGAI
Goro NAYA
Yoji MATSUDA
Yoshiko SAKAKIBARA
Lemasa KAYUMI
English translation by
Linda HOAGLUND with Judith ALEY
Steve ALPERT and Nao AMISAKI
English subtitles by
Aura and Nippon Cine Arts
Production
Top Craft
The End