My name is Kathy H.
I'm 28 years old.
I've been a carer
for nine years.
And I'm good at my job.
My patients always do
better than expected
and are hardly ever
classified as agitated,
even if they're
about to make a donation.
I'm not trying to boast,
but I feel a great sense
of pride in what we do.
Carers and donors
have achieved so much.
That said,
we aren't machines.
In the end,
it wears you down.
I suppose that's why I now spend
most of my time not looking forwards
but looking back,
to The Cottages and Hailsham,
and what happened to us there.
Me,
Tommy,
and Ruth.
When we are
scattered afar and asunder
Parted are those
who are singing today
When we look back
and forgetfully wonder
What we were like
in our learning and play
Oh, the great days
will bring distance enchanted
Days of fresh air in
the rain and the sun
How we rejoiced as we
struggled and panted
Echoes of dreamland,
Hailsham lives on
Good morning, students.
Good morning, Miss Emily.
It has come to my attention that three
burned cigarettes were discovered,
hidden behind a pot
in the flower garden.
I know that on occasion
students have seen
some of the caretakers and
deliverymen smoking cigarettes,
but I must emphasize, once
again, that it is much, much worse
for a student of Hailsham to
smoke cigarettes than anyone else.
Students of Hailsham
are special.
Keeping yourselves well, keeping
yourselves healthy inside,
is of paramount importance.
Have I made myself clear?
Yes, Miss Emily.
I think, one day,
I'd like five horses.
I don't know all their names,
but I know I'd like five horses.
The best
would be Thunder.
He'd be dangerous to ride,
so you can't ride him.
You can ride
Bramble.
Just so long as you don't
use your crop on him.
That's pretty.
You have it.
Look. Who's that
with Miss Emily?
Do you think
it's the new guardian?
Miss Lucy.
I think it must be.
We haven't had
a new guardian for ages.
Arthur! Arthur!
Catch it, Tommy.
Why didn't Tommy
get the ball?
Excuse me, Miss Lucy?
Why didn't Tommy
get the ball?
When it bounced
over the fence,
it couldn't have
been far from him.
The fence is the boundary
of the Hailsham grounds.
We don't go outside
the boundary, Miss Lucy.
It's too dangerous.
Dangerous?
There was once a boy who
had a big row with all his friends
and then ran off
beyond the boundary.
They found him, two days later,
in the woods. Tied to a tree.
With his hands
and feet cut off.
Dead.
And there was the girl
who climbed over the fence,
by the front gate.
And when she tried to get
back, she wasn't allowed.
And then she starved.
Out there.
Right by the gates.
Who told you
these stories?
Everybody knows them.
And how do you know
they're true?
Of course
they're true.
Who'd make up stories
as horrible as that?
Tommy, what are you doing?
What is it, exactly?
I think it must be a dog.
Is it a dog, Tommy?
It can't be a dog.
Its eyes are too small.
I think it must be
a kind of rat.
Yes, that's it.
Tommy's drawn a rat.
It's not finished yet.
That's right. You haven't
finished the whiskers.
Do you think Tommy's rat will
be selected for The Gallery?
It's not a rat.
It's an elephant.
Children,
back to work.
He's got his shirt on.
His favorite polo shirt.
He really doesn't
suspect a thing.
Looks like no one
wants you, Tommy.
What's he doing?
It's his own fault.
If he learnt to keep his cool,
they'd leave him alone.
I hate you!
I hate you all!
Kath... No, don't!
You shouldn't have...
Kathy H.
What's this from?
I don't remember.
Doctor?
It's nothing.
Just a bruise.
Hello.
Kathy. Kathy H.
Of course. Kathy H.
Come in.
So what can
I do for you?
Well,
I was wondering
what you said to Tommy.
Out on the
playing fields.
I see. Oh.
So what did I say?
I believe I was trying
to calm him down.
Because he seemed upset.
He explained he was often
teased about sport and art,
so I told him he shouldn't
get upset about these things.
The other children are only
teasing him to get a reaction.
And if it happens that he's not
particularly good at sport or art,
well, that doesn't matter.
It's not so important.
Thank you.
Kathy.
Aren't you sitting
with the girls?
Well, I just checked
and I'm pretty sure I'm
not sitting with the girls.
I'm sitting with you.
I wanted to say
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
to hit you.
I mean, I wouldn't
want to hit any girl.
But particularly
not you.
Well, it was an accident, that's all.
Tommy,
finish those vegetables.
I'm not gonna get angry
like that anymore.
Because of what Miss Lucy
told you, about being creative?
How do you know
about that?
I'm nosey.
She can't actually mean that being
creative isn't important, can she?
I mean, what about
The Gallery?
If being creative
isn't important,
then why have
a gallery at all?
I don't know.
...by arching her back, or
perhaps with the aid of a pillow,
the woman can
arrange herself...
Smile
Good morning, ma'am.
Good morning.
Can I help you?
I wanted one tea, with
milk and sugar in it.
One tea. Right.
Tommy.
Oh! One tea with milk
and sugar in it, please.
No, Tommy.
I want to hear
your own order.
Don't simply repeat
the one you've just heard.
What other drinks
do they serve in cafes?
Water.
Coffee.
So, then.
So, then,
one coffee, please, with
milk and sugar in it.
Thank you.
I think Laura likes Arthur.
All the girls
like Arthur, don't they?
Maybe.
I'm not sure you do.
He's not my type.
I think Laura and Arthur will be
the first in our year to have sex
because, if Arthur wants to,
Laura wouldn't stop him.
I'm sure you're right.
Tommy's changed.
Changed how?
Just changed.
That's all.
What about this
one by Madeleine Kane?
I think it shows more
than technical ability.
It gives a real insight
into the child.
Which is precisely what
Marie-Claude wants for The Gallery.
Yes, I agree.
Mmm.
Put these
two together.
Madame is coming.
Good morning, students.
Good morning, Miss Emily.
There are several
points of order today.
The first is that our good friend,
Madame Marie-Claude, is visiting us.
She will, as usual, be carefully
inspecting your artwork and poetry
and selecting the very best pieces
for inclusion in her Gallery.
We will, of course,
extend to her every courtesy
and make her feel
most welcome.
Second point of order, a piece
of good news for all students
who have been diligent
in collecting tokens.
After studies tomorrow,
there will be a sale.
The delivery
will arrive in the morning,
and I was assured
by the van driver
that the boxes will
contain a bumper crop.
Is it really
a bumper crop?
I should say so. Yeah,
sweetheart. It's a bumper crop.
Hey.
Aren't you buying?
If you've already spent all your
tokens, you can have some of mine.
I have tokens. I was just gonna
wait till the rush died down.
I'm sure there'll be
something good left.
What's the matter, Kath?
Well, anyway,
it doesn't matter
if you can't find
anything in the sale
because I already
found you something.
A music tape.
I don't know much about it,
if it's much good or anything.
Thank you.
* Darling *
* Hold me *
* And never *
* Never *
* Let me go *
* Darling *
* Kiss me *
* And never *
* Never *
* Let me go *
The problem is
you've been told
and not told.
That's what I've seen
while I've been here.
You've been told
but none of you
really understand.
So I've decided I'll talk to you
in a way that you will understand.
Do you know what happens to
children when they grow up?
No, you don't,
because nobody knows.
They might grow up
to become actors,
move to America.
Or they might work
in supermarkets.
Or teach in schools.
They might become sportsmen or bus
conductors or racing car drivers.
They might do
almost anything.
But with you
we do know.
None of you
will go to America.
None of you will work
in supermarkets.
None of you will do
anything except live the life
that has already
been set out for you.
You will
become adults,
but only briefly.
Before you are old,
before you are
even middle-aged,
you will start to donate
your vital organs.
That's what you were
created to do.
And sometime around your
third or fourth donation,
your short life
will be complete.
You have to know who
you are and what you are.
It's the only way
you'll lead decent lives.
There will be only one
announcement this morning,
which is that Miss Lucy,
who was guardian
to the fourth-year students,
is no longer
working at Hailsham.
A replacement will be found
for her, and in the meantime
her classes will be divided
between Miss Geraldine and myself.
It is hard, is it not,
to continue in the face
of deliberate subversion.
There are those who seek
to thwart us, this is clear.
And we are aware that the tide
is not with forward thinking.
It never is.
No, the tide is with
the entrenched mindset.
With values that
are still unexamined.
But I will not be coerced.
I will not be coerced.
And neither will Hailsham.
I didn't understand
why, after all her teasing,
Ruth would decide that Tommy was
the boy she liked most of all.
They say girls are always mean
to the boys they like.
So maybe Ruth
had liked him all along.
Maybe I should have
teased him, too.
I kept hoping
they would separate,
like the other childhood and
teenage romances at the school.
They never did.
We were moved
from Hailsham at 18
and sent to various
accommodations around the country,
to wait until we were old
enough to start the donations.
Tommy, Ruth and I
were sent to a collection of farm
buildings called The Cottages.
During our stay there,
we were told
that some of us would be
permitted to volunteer as carers.
But, apart from that, we'd be
left largely to our own devices
and even allowed to take day trips
into the surrounding countryside.
The Cottages were also
our first contact
with those who had not
grown up at Hailsham.
There were people
from White Mansion,
Oakhill, Morningdale and
other homes I'd never heard of.
Everyone seemed wiser
and more worldly than us.
None more so than
Rodney and Chrissie.
They'd already been at The
Cottages for over a year
and would soon be leaving
for the completion centers.
Ricky? I don't
know what you're talking about.
Oh, I can
help you out there.
He's talking about blue eyes, blond
hair, cute dimples when he smiles.
And biceps that
could crack walnuts.
Jennifer, get real,
I saw you with him.
Jen and Ricky sitting in
a tree, K- I-S-S-I-N-G.
That is so not true.
We weren't in a tree.
Hey.
Where you going?
I thought
I'd go for a walk.
Does that mean
you want to be alone?
I'm not even saying that
I'll apply to be a carer.
Just that several people have
said that I'd be good at it.
But then Laura went around
telling everyone
that I'd been saying I was the
most likely to get selected.
That's so not true.
So not true.
Thank you.
I'm getting
more plates.
Is there anything left for us?
I don't know.
Perhaps not.
Ruth, why do you
do that thing?
Squeezing
Tommy's shoulder.
I'm allowed to touch Tommy, aren't I?
It's the way
you're touching him.
You know what I mean. It's
copied from that television show.
That's so not...
Don't tell me
"that's so not true. "
All that behavior, that's not what
people do out there, in real life,
if that's what
you were thinking.
So what? Look, it's no big
deal. A lot of us do it.
What you mean is
Chrissie and Rod do it.
Oh, Kathy.
So that's what
this is about.
It must be really
awful for you,
surrounded by
all these couples.
I never said that.
I just think it's daft.
You copy them, and they
copy from a television show.
I'm right,
aren't I?
You don't like the fact that Tommy and
I are friends with Chrissie and Rod,
whereas you hardly
speak to anyone.
No. You're not right.
"So" not right?
Thank you, Mr. Keffers.
Hello, Tommy.
Hello, Kath.
Well, don't just hover in the
doorway. Come in. Join the fun.
Didn't know you liked
that sort of stuff.
You're very welcome to them
after I've finished.
Oh, no,
it's just sex stuff.
I expect I've seen
them all already anyway.
Kathy, what are
you looking for?
What do you mean? I'm just
looking at dirty pictures.
What, just for kicks?
I suppose you could
say that, yes.
If it's just for kicks, then
you don't do it like that.
You need to look at each
picture more carefully.
Nothing really happens
if you go that fast.
How do you know
what works for girls?
Kath, you're not
looking for kicks.
Here, give it to Ruth. See
if it does anything for her.
Hi.
I suppose you've heard what Rod
and Chrissie have been saying.
No, I haven't.
Well, you know that
Rod and Chrissie
have been thinking of
applying to be carers,
so they've been
learning how to drive.
Yeah.
Well, last weekend, they went up
to a town on the Norfolk coast,
and they think
they saw this person.
What kind of person?
A lady
working in an office.
And...
What is it, Ruth?
But they thought this
person was a Possible.
For me.
They found
your Original?
They aren't sure,
obviously,
but Rodney said that the
resemblance was really striking.
Oh, my God. Ruth!
I know.
They want to drive me back up
there so that I can see for myself.
Tommy will come, but...
Do you want me to come?
Ruth, of course.
So, exactly how much experience
have you guys had with the outside?
Quite a lot.
No, we haven't.
We did a lot of role-playing
exercises at Hailsham.
They don't count.
Okay. Well,
don't feel scared.
Okay? There's really...
There's nothing to it.
We aren't scared.
Good.
I'll get sausage,
egg and chips.
Sausage,
egg and chips, please.
Yes, sausage,
egg and chips.
Sausage, egg and chips,
me, too, please.
Well, I suppose I'd better get
sausage, egg and chips, too, then.
Five sausage,
egg and chips. Drinks?
Five Cokes, please.
It was good.
It was really good.
What?
Sorry.
You know, there's something I've
been wanting to talk to you lot about.
The problem is that back there
at The Cottages it's impossible.
Someone's always
listening in.
So,
someone was saying that some
Hailsham students in the past
have managed
to get a deferral.
Apparently those
Hailsham students
could have their first
donation put back by three
or even four years.
As long as they qualified.
If there was a boy
and a girl,
and they were in love
with each other,
really properly in love,
and they could prove it,
then they would be given
a few years together
before they began
their donations.
Where did you
hear about this?
When we were
at White Mansion.
People there were always going
on about this Hailsham couple.
When the guy was only a
few weeks from donation,
he just went to see someone. He
applied, and everything got sorted out.
I suppose you lot would know
about that sort of thing.
Being from Hailsham, you'd know
how that sort of thing works.
Who is it
you go to?
Who would we talk to
if we wanted to apply?
To be honest, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Come on.
Do you expect us
to believe that?
Everybody knows
Hailsham is special.
So what is it?
Why keep these
things to yourself?
There were lots of
stories at Hailsham.
I don't think many of them
turned out to be true.
It may be
down here.
Yeah.
That's it.
God, it must be her.
Yeah, that's her.
It's not her.
I'm not her.
No, you're not.
It was really
close, though.
Oh, shut up, Tommy! It wasn't
close. It wasn't close at all.
And I knew it wasn't gonna be
her before we even got here!
It was never
gonna be her.
They never, ever model us
on people like that woman.
Ruth, don't.
What?
We all know it,
we just never say it.
We are modeled on trash.
Junkies, prostitutes,
winos, tramps.
Convicts, maybe, as long
as they aren't psychos.
If you want to look for Possibles,
if you want to do it properly,
look in the gutter.
That's where we came from.
Hey.
We should go back.
Don't tell me
to calm down!
You walked down the pier
and you left me there.
You knew
I was well upset.
Out here.
Chrissie and Rod are pretty obsessed
about this rumor, aren't they?
About the deferrals?
Mmm.
I was thinking about it
again last night,
and if this
rumor's true
it might explain
a few things.
Such as?
Well,
The Gallery,
for instance.
We never got to the bottom of
it, what The Gallery was for.
Pictures, poetry
and sculpture.
Say something
about yourself.
That's the whole point
about art, isn't it?
It says what's inside of you.
It reveals your soul.
Yeah. So?
Suppose for a second
that the rumor is true.
That there is a special
arrangement for Hailsham students,
if they're in love.
Well, there would have
to be some kind of way
to decide if couples
are telling the truth
and not just lying
to put off their donations.
That's what The Gallery could be for.
In The Gallery they have everything
about us they need to know.
So if we say that
we're in love,
they can look into our
souls and they can see.
They'll know if it's real
love or if it's just a lie.
That's a strange idea, Tommy.
What?
No, no. I don't think that's
any stranger than any other idea.
And didn't Miss Lucy say that making art
for The Gallery wasn't even important?
Yes.
But look what
happened to her.
Are you thinking
of applying?
With Ruth?
No.
It wouldn't work.
Why?
Because
you forget that
you got lots of stuff into
The Gallery over the years,
and if I applied they wouldn't
have anything to go on.
It's all just rumors
and theories.
Yeah, I know.
Tommy.
* Kiss me *
* And never *
* Never *
* Let me go *
* Lock my heart *
* Throw away the key *
* Feel my love *
I know what
you think, Kathy.
I know you think that you and Tommy
would have made a more natural couple,
and you believe
that there's a chance that Tommy
and I will split up some day.
And when we do, perhaps that
will be your chance with Tommy.
Chance to do it
right this time.
But you see,
the thing is, Kathy,
although Tommy really
likes you as a friend,
he just doesn't
see you that way.
He told me about
the porno magazines.
We had quite
a laugh about it.
He doesn't understand
what you were doing.
But I did.
Oh!
I said I'll just be five minutes.
I want to be
a carer.
It's you who
I apply to, isn't it?
Yeah.
I said that
I'm applying.
I'll bring
the forms tomorrow,
and that'll start
the process.
By the time Ruth and
Tommy actually did separate,
my carer training
had already begun.
So I was hardly ever
at The Cottages.
It had never occurred to me
that our lives,
which had been
so closely interwoven,
could unravel
with such speed.
If I'd known,
maybe I'd have kept
tighter hold of them
and not let unseen tides
pull us apart.
Once I began working
with my donors,
I didn't have much time
to dwell on Tommy or Ruth.
Eventually,
so many years had passed
I came to think I would
never see them again.
Many carers find themselves
just going through the motions,
waiting for the day that they
can stop and become donors.
But for the most part, being
a carer has suited me fine.
I quite enjoy traveling
across the country,
shuttling from center to
center, hospital to hospital.
Here you are.
Dark chocolate.
If you knew how many shops I had
to go to before I found those.
I thought I wasn't allowed to
eat so soon before the operation.
Oh, you're not.
But I am.
And after the operation,
you can wolf down
the whole packet in one go.
For me, the real
test of being a carer
is when a donor completes
earlier than expected.
On the second
or even first donation.
Can I just have
a quick word?
Okay.
I was wondering who'd be
working on Hannah today.
I'd never say I've
become immune to the completions.
But they are something
I am able to live with.
You're Hannah's carer,
aren't you?
Hannah's carer?
Yes.
I'm sorry, it's always hard,
but there were complications.
You need me
to sign the release?
Please.
Are you going
to leave now?
We can quite easily provide
you with a bed tonight
if you've got
a long drive.
I can be back home
in under two hours.
It's always better to
wake at home, isn't it?
Is that someone
you know?
Yeah.
Actually,
we grew up together.
Oh.
How is she?
Were you close?
We haven't seen each other
now for almost 10 years.
Well, Ruth isn't as strong as
we would hope, at this stage.
She's done
two donations.
She has.
You think she'll complete on the third?
I think she wants
to complete.
And, as you know, when they want
to complete, they usually do.
Kathy.
I've been keeping
tabs on you over the years.
And Tommy, too.
What do you
hear about Tommy?
That he's done
his second donation, too,
and apparently he's
doing very well on it.
Apparently
he's in better shape
than some after
their first donation.
Good old Tommy.
I'm not surprised.
Are you surprised at me?
I expect I look
a bit broken, Kath.
It's okay.
I don't think I'd want to
survive my third donation, anyway.
You hear things,
don't you?
What kind of things?
Oh, you know.
How, maybe,
after the fourth donation,
even if you've
technically completed,
you're still conscious
in some sort of way.
And then you find out that there
are more donations, plenty of them.
No more recovery centers.
No more carers.
Just watching
and waiting.
Till they switch you off.
I don't think
I fancy that.
Is it the end
of the day already?
Do you know,
it's funny,
I think I've thought about you
every day for the last few months.
Hoping I'd see you again.
Do you know, I felt sure that I would.
Seemed impossible that I'd complete
without seeing you one last time.
It's not
the last time, Ruth.
They offered me a bed.
I was planning on
staying the night anyway.
Well.
I always knew
you'd be a good carer.
Your donors
are very lucky.
Look, I was lying
awake last night
and I suddenly had an idea
that we'd take a trip together.
Where to?
I hadn't much thought
of where, just a trip.
Although
a place
did spring to mind.
One of the boys on the other
floor was talking about it.
It's near the
Kingsfield Recovery Center.
Is it the boat? The
one left on the beach?
You've heard
about it, too?
I heard. One of the
carers who worked there.
And do you suppose,
if we're driving
all that way,
that we could
call in on Tommy?
Told you I'd been
keeping tabs on you.
Have you seen him?
No, not since
The Cottages.
No, neither have I.
How will
we find him?
His carer said
he'd be waiting outside.
Look, there he is.
Do you think he's recognized
us through the glass?
No, no, no.
Let's not get out.
Ruth's
in the car.
Oh, right.
Hey!
Hi!
Hi.
How are you?
I'm good.
Look at your hair.
Oh, yeah.
My hair.
I can't quite believe
that I have you both here.
Does it feel to you that
we're back at Hailsham again?
Like no time
has passed?
No, it doesn't.
No, it doesn't
at all, does it?
It really doesn't at all.
It's really weird.
But a good weird, I think.
I don't suppose you both heard
that Hailsham was closed?
The only schools left now, you
hear they're like battery farms.
Like Morningdale.
I'm sure that's
an exaggeration, though.
Are you sure we're going the right way?
It's locked,
it looks like.
No one said
anything about this.
No one said anything
about a locked gate.
Ruth, just relax.
It's okay.
Can walk through here.
Wow.
Hey, come on.
I wonder if that's
what Hailsham looks like now.
Do you ever hear, Kath, about
any of the students from Hailsham?
Sometimes, yeah.
I heard that Amanda completed
on her first donation.
I think that happens
more than they ever tell us.
Hmm.
Yeah, there was this
guy at my care center
who was always really scared of
completing on his first donation.
But it was all fine.
And he's just come
through his third one now,
and he's completely
all right.
It's funny,
I don't think...
Well, I know I wouldn't
have been a very good carer,
but in a way I actually
think I'm quite a good donor.
That's what we're
supposed to be, isn't it?
I'd like you
to forgive me.
I don't expect
you to.
Forgive you
for what?
For keeping you
and Tommy apart.
Should have been you two
together, I always knew it.
As far back
as I can remember.
It wasn't just because of
the rumors about deferrals.
It was because
I was jealous.
You had real love
and I didn't,
and I didn't want to be
the one that was left alone.
It's the worst thing
I ever did.
And now I want
to put it right.
I don't know how you can do that, Ruth.
I can
if you two
get a deferral.
It's too late
for that, Ruth.
Way too late. It's stupid
to even think about it.
It isn't too late. Look,
you'll see, both of you.
I wanted to do this trip because I had
something that I wanted to give you.
It's Madame's address.
That's who you apply to. That's
who you have to go and see.
How did you
get this?
It wasn't easy, but I've had
years to think about what I did.
And years to try and work out
a way to make it right.
I started doing them when
we were at The Cottages.
The day after we went
to find Ruth's Possible.
I realized that if I was ever
going to apply for a deferral,
then I'd have to
show them something.
And I've done hundreds
of them over the years.
They're wonderful.
What? Really?
Yeah.
Well, thank you.
I have never showed
anyone them until now.
They were my secret.
Just like you and those porno magazines.
You remember that?
Yeah.
Ruth said you didn't
understand what I was doing.
No, I don't think she
understood what you were doing.
She thought you were
looking at the dirty pictures
in order
to find out about sex
and to find out what you were
missing out on or something.
I knew.
I knew you were looking
for your Original.
I used to have these huge
urges to have sex sometimes.
And sometimes
they'd be so powerful,
I just thought
I'd do it with anyone.
So I thought that
had to tell me something.
Something about the kind
of person I was modeled on.
It's stupid,
but I guessed the magazines would be
the most likely place I'd find her.
You know those urges
are natural, don't you?
You know all of us had them.
You know that now, right?
"From Basrah we sailed,
"day after day, night
after night, over the sea,
"visiting island after island
and land after land,
"selling or bartering
our goods at each.
"One day, after some weeks of
sailing out of sight of land,
"we saw an island in the sea
with such fair greenery
"that it appeared like
one of the gardens of Eden.
"At once the captain made
towards this delectable land
"and, when the anchor had been
cast and the ladder lowered,
"allowed his passengers
to disembark. "
Don't stop.
Ruth got it right. Right
street, right door, everything.
We have to decide which of
my drawings we're gonna take.
Just take the best ones.
Maybe six or seven of them.
You have to help me.
Yeah, I know.
So, we'll just go there.
Mmm.
Next week.
I'll take you out for lab tests,
I'll sign you out for the whole day
and we'll visit Madame
on the way back.
We're going to do it.
I thought you should know.
You're going to apply?
Yes.
Good.
Madame?
Sorry.
We didn't mean
to startle you.
We were at Hailsham.
I'm Kathy.
This is Tommy.
We're not here to
give you any trouble.
From Hailsham?
We just came
to talk to you.
And I brought you
some things.
Some things you might
like for your Gallery.
Come inside.
Please, wait here.
Look, it's Hailsham.
Kathy, it's Hailsham.
That's exactly
how I remember it.
Please, sit down.
So...
We're in love.
And it's true love.
It's verifiable.
Verifiable. I see.
Go on.
Well,
we'd heard about
the deferrals.
And we'd worked out the
purpose of The Gallery.
Tell me the purpose.
To use our art
from Hailsham
to look into
our souls,
which would verify that
we deserved a deferral.
But the problem is
I was a little bit
mixed up back then
and I didn't
really do any art,
so you never took
anything of mine.
I know, I know that
that is my fault
and it is probably
much too late,
but I brought some stuff with me today.
This is a book
of stuff and...
Other stuff here.
Some of them I've done
quite recently,
and others
were done several years ago,
so there's a real spread.
You already have a load
of stuff from Kath already.
She got loads of stuff into The
Gallery over the years, didn't...
I'm sorry.
I never know
what to do.
I'll take it
from here.
Thank you, George.
Kathy H and Tommy D.
I remember you both.
Kathy, a bright girl,
and so creative.
And Tommy, a big heart
and terrible rages.
You have to understand,
Hailsham was the last place to
consider the ethics of donation.
We used your art to show
what you were capable of.
To show that donor children
are all but human.
But we were providing an answer
to a question no one was asking.
If you ask people
to return to darkness,
the days of lung cancer, breast
cancer, motor neurone disease,
they'll simply say no.
We used to get two or three
couples like you a year.
Not so much these days.
You're the first
for quite a while.
To apply
for a deferral?
There are
no deferrals, Tommy.
There are no deferrals.
And there never have been.
We didn't have The Gallery in
order to look into your souls.
We had The Gallery to see
if you had souls at all.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Your drawings
are very good.
If you want,
I'll keep them.
Thank you
for talking to us.
You poor creatures.
I wish I could help you.
Sorry, can we stop for a
second? I need to get out.
It's been two weeks
since I lost him.
I've been given my notice now.
My first donation
is in a month's time.
I come here and imagine
that this is the spot
where everything I've lost
since my childhood has washed up.
I tell myself
if that were true,
and I waited long enough,
then a tiny figure would appear
on the horizon across the field
and gradually get larger
until I'd see it was Tommy.
He'd wave
and maybe call.
I don't let the fantasy
go beyond that.
I can't let it.
I remind myself I was lucky to
have had any time with him at all.
What I'm not sure about
is if our lives have been so different
from the lives of the people we save.
We all complete.
Maybe none of us really
understand what we've lived through
or feel we've had
enough time.
When we are scattered
afar and asunder
Parted are those
who are singing today
When we look back
and forgetfully wonder
What we were like
in our learning and play
Oh, the great days
will bring distance enchanted
Days of fresh air
in the rain and the sun
How we rejoiced
as we struggled and panted
Echoes of dreamland,
Hailsham lives on