What?
I said...
I want to teII you my story.
What the heII?
Why are you taIking Iike that?
Who the fuck are you?
My...
name is...
Oh...
Dae-su.
Stop fIirting with his girIfriend.
HoId on.
-Mr. Oh Dae-su!
-Was I fIirting with her? Was I?
Okay! Okay!
Sit down, Oh Dae-su. You're way too drunk.
I need to piss first.
I wasn't even fIirting!
Motherfucker!
AsshoIe!
Sit down!
I'm so sorry.
Fuck, I reaIIy need to piss.
-Isn't she cute?
-Very. Now sit down.
It's my daughter's birthday today.
I got her a birthday present.
A little cloud floating in the sky
A pleasure boat sailing on the river
My name, Oh Dae-su, means...
''getting through one day at a time.''
That's what ''Oh Dae-su'' means.
But, God...
why can't I get through today?
Let me go!
-Shut the fuck up!
-Let me go!
Let go! Get away from me!
He shouId be Iocked up.
Grab him!
I'II make sure he doesn't get drunk
and cause troubIe again.
Have a nice day, Officer.
He's usuaIIy a nice guy.
Let's go.
I'II come back and see you soon.
Don't bother. Never come back.
That's up to me, asshoIes.
Hey!
Yeun-hee, it's Daddy.
Daddy's got a present for my IittIe Yeun-hee.
I'II be home soon with your present,
just wait a bit Ionger....
Let me taIk to her.
-Good girI.
-Give me the phone.
Yeun-hee, Joo-hwan wants a word with you.
You remember Joo-hwan, don't you?
HoId on.
HeIIo, Yeun-hee.
It's me, Joo-hwan.
So it's your birthday today?
Happy birthday!
I'II buy you a nice treat tomorrow.
HeIIo? Oh, heIIo, Ja-hyun.
I'm sorry. I know it's very Iate.
Dae-su is on his way home.
I'm sorry. Yes?
HoId on. Dae-su, it's your wife.
Dae-su!
Your wife says you shouId hurry home!
Dae-su, Iet's get going!
Stop messing around!
OLDBOY
Sir, sir.
Wait, come here. Come and taIk to me.
I won't ask you to Iet me go again.
Just teII me why I'm here, pIease.
I have a right to know why.
God, I've aIready been Iocked in here
for two months.
Sir, wait, come here.
Sir, wait. What is this pIace?
PIease, sir, just teII me how Iong
I have to stay here.
Sir!
Fuck you!
Come here, you asshoIe!
Son of a bitch.
I saw your face, asshoIe!
You're dead when I get out!
I'm sorry! I won't swear at you again.
Just teII me how much Ionger.
One month? Two? Three?
Don't go!
I'm sorry.
Just teII me how Iong, you son of a bitch!
I said teII me how Iong, you asshoIe!
Son of a bitch!
You fucking asshoIes!
If they had told me then
that it would be 15 years...
would it have been easier to endure?
Or harder?
LAUGH,
AND THE WORLD LAUGHS WITH YOU.
WEEP, AND YOU WEEP ALONE.
When the music begins, gas is released.
When the gas is released, I fall asleep.
Later on, I found out...
that it was the same Valium gas
that Russian soldiers used...
on Chechen terrorists.
When I wake up, my hair is cut.
I don't really like the style.
However, they change my clothes...
and clean the room.
Generous bastards.
One!
Two!
Three!
It's too spicy.
I don't want spinach. You eat it.
I won't eat spinach.
Mrs. Kim Ja-hyun's body was found
with stab wounds to the neck.
This was a cold-blooded murder.
As nothing of value was taken...
police suspect the motive was personal.
The victim's husband, Oh Dae-su...
disappeared a year ago and is still at large.
Witnesses say
Oh Dae-su was a heavy drinker...
who fought constantly with his wife.
Neighbors also frequently argued
with Oh Dae-su.
Blood samples found at the scene
match those of Oh Dae-su.
Oh Dae-su's fingerprints have been
matched to those found on a glass.
Sources claim that Oh Dae-su
definitely visited his wife recently.
The only missing item...
was a family album,
which supports the police theories.
After three years...
many wrinkles form on a man's face.
If you stand
outside a phone booth on a rainy day...
and meet a man whose face
is hidden by a violet umbrella...
my advice is...
that you make friends with television.
The television is both clock and calendar.
It is your school, home...
church...
friend...
and lover.
But....
But...
my lover's song...
is too short.
Today at 7.:50 am,
the middle of Seoul's Songsu Bridge...
fifty meters long, suddenly collapsed....
I wrote a list...
of all the people I had offended,
quarreled with, and hurt.
This was both my prison journal...
and the autobiography of my evil deeds.
I thought I had lived a normal life...
but there was too much wrongdoing.
All I could think at that moment...
was that the man in the next room...
probably only had one chopstick.
But....
Who had imprisoned me?
Was it Yoo Heung-sam?
Lee So-young or Kang Chang-suk?
Whoever it was, wait.
Just you wait.
I'll rip your body limb from limb...
and your remains will never be found.
Because I will swallow every last bit.
One line for each year.
When I start doing this,
I am already six lines behind.
So next year will be easier.
The more tattoos I have,
the shorter the chopstick becomes.
The shorter the chopstick becomes...
the bigger the hole in the wall becomes.
Anyway...
time passes well.
Nine years.
Ten years.
Eleven years.
EX-PRESIDENT CHUN DOO-HWAN
ARRESTED
HONG KONG HANDOVER CEREMONY
PRINCESS DIANA'S FUNERAL
OFFICIAL APPROVAL OF IMF FUND
Twelve years.
PRESIDENTIAL INAUGURATION
PRESIDENT KIM DAE-JUNG
VISITS NORTH KOREA
WORLD CUP IN KOREA
Thirteen years.
ROH MOO-HYUN ELECTED PRESIDENT
Fourteen years.
I'll be out in a month.
I'll be out in just one month.
I'll be out. I'll be out in one month's time.
I'll be out of here.
I'll be out in a month. In exactly one month.
I'll need money when I get out,
so what should I do?
Should I steal or rob?
What shall I eat first?
Kimchee soup? Barbecued eel?
Anything but fried dumplings.
But where am I?
With all the car horns, it must be the city.
The most important thing
is what floor I'm on.
What if I break through the wall
and I'm on the 52nd floor?
Even if I plunge to my death,
I'll still be getting out.
I'm getting out.
In one month, I'm getting out.
Picture yourseIf...
Iying in a fieId.
When you hear the beII...
you wiII turn your head...
and Iook down.
You wiII see...
an endIess fieId of green grass.
The sun is shining brightly.
There's a cool breeze.
It's a human being.
Don't stop me!
Mister!
Even though...
I'm no better than a beast...
don't I have the right to Iive?
Even though...
I'm no better...
than a beast...
don't I have the right...
to Iive?
Yes?
Yes.
The alley with the phone booth
was just here.
Now there's an apartment building.
So he releases me onto the roof.
What a fool.
I want to teII you my story.
Die Iater.
What?
What the heII?
I see.
Now I'II teII you my story.
The reason...
I want to die is....
Hey, mister!
That's a female human being.
Laugh...
and the world laughs with you.
Weep...
and you weep alone.
My home is gone.
I cannot call my friends or relatives...
because they say I murdered my wife.
I am a fugitive.
You dickshit!
Dickshit.
A new word.
Television doesn't teach you swear words.
Can 10 years' worth of imaginary training...
be put to use?
Apparently, it can.
Rock bream.
OpIegnathus fasciatus.
Lives in the warm waters of coastal reefs.
This fish has weak reflexes...
but can resist powerfully
when caught on a hook.
In the Kyongsang Province, its offspring....
What is that smell?
Don't bother asking me any questions.
I don't know anything.
Yes?
I said I want to eat something aIive.
Oh, right.
Long time, no see.
This is my first time here.
Maybe I'm wrong.
But she looks familiar.
You Iook very famiIiar.
Have we met before?
Search for the Best Chef.
Thursdays at 6:30 on MBC.
''The youngest femaIe chef
of Japanese cuisine.''
Oh, that?
They said the ratings are Iow,
but someone must watch it.
Women's hands are usuaIIy warm,
so they cannot make sushi.
WeII, you certainIy know your stuff.
Who are you?
Do you...
like your clothes?
Why?
Why did you imprison me?
Who do you think I am?
-Yoo Heung-sam?
-Wrong.
-Did Lee So-young pay you?
-Wrong again.
Lee Jong-yong?
Kang Chang-suk?
Hwang Joo-yeun? Kim Na-sung?
Park Jin-woo?
Im Duk-yoon? Lee Jae-pyung? Kuk Su-ran?
-Who the heII are you?
-Me?
I'm a sort of scholar.
And my field of study is you.
A scholar studying Oh Dae-su.
An expert on Oh Dae-su.
Who I am isn't important.
What's important is why.
Think hard.
Study your whole lifetime.
School has finished,
now it's time for your homework, isn't it?
Keep this in mind.:
''Whether it be a grain of sand or a rock...
''in water they both sink alike. ''
Let me ask you one thing.
You hypnotized me in there, didn't you?
What did you do to me?
I miss you.
Come quickly.
Here you are.
It's aIive, okay?
Now can I sIice it up for you?
I must be a different breed of woman.
My hands are very coId.
Why is she doing this?
Sir.
Sir, wake up.
Keep this in mind.
''Whether it be a grain of sand or a rock...
''in water they both sink alike. ''
Are you awake?
Is aII this true?
That fever remedy works weII.
Why did you faint if you've done
so much physicaI training?
A Iack of vitaI sunIight Ieaves one
depIeted of vitamins A and E.
Thus, one's immunity to infIuenza
is weakened.
Do you aIways taIk Iike that?
The Iock on the bathroom door is broken.
Don't get any bright ideas...
or I'II gut you Iike a fish.
What's this?
Suppositories. You fainted,
so how eIse couId I give you medicine?
Can 15 years' worth of
imaginary training be put to use?
Apparently not.
That was an unforgivabIe sin.
I brought you back here
and then turned you down.
I can see why you're angry.
I reaIIy can.
You know,
I brought you here because I Iike you.
But...
you don't even know my name yet.
It's Mi-do.
You see...
Iater on...
when I'm reaIIy ready...
I swear on my Iife that I'II go through with it.
That song in your diary,
The Face I Want to See, that wiII be the sign.
When I sing it...
get ready.
I may try to resist you again...
in the heat of the moment.
But no matter what, don't stop.
Just give it to me!
Give it...
to me.
The ants...
do you stiII see them?
Do you stiII feeI that way?
Yeah, if you're aIone, you see ants.
PeopIe I have met who are very IoneIy
have aII haIIucinated about ants.
I tried once to work out why.
Ants move around in groups, you know.
So I suppose very IoneIy peopIe
keep thinking of ants.
AIthough I have never done that.
She called from overseas
five or six years ago...
asking if her dad had come back.
She doesn't even know
that he killed her mother.
She has hardIy any reIatives,
so she caIIs us.
Her Korean has gotten worse.
I think her Swedish foster parents
are both doctors.
You journaIists must know.
Dae-su...
is he reaIIy stiII on the run?
Your daughter's address is on the front...
and on the back is a map of
your wife's grave.
EVA VON LJUNGBERG
STOCKHOLM, SWEDEN
Eva.
Stockholm.
Do you want to caII her?
ShaII I caII her?
ShaII we visit the grave tomorrow?
No, first I have to kill that bastard.
BLUE DRAGON
WeII?
I haven't tasted it yet.
BLUE DRAGON
So?
Did it taste the same?
I could taste food from 100 restaurants...
but I will never forget
the food I tasted for 15 years.
BLUE DRAGON
ShaII I create an ID for you,
so you can Iog in?
Do you have a favorite fiIm or song?
I've aIready been taIking...
to him.
The Count of Monte Cristo?
There's no one by that name here.
How's Iife in a bigger prison, Oh Dae-su?
Who are you?
The IoneIy prince in the high tower.
Who is he?
I don't know who he is.
I just chat to him sometimes.
We taIk about sushi.
Where are you going?
I can't trust you.
VIOL
BLUE DRAGON
Violet Blue Dragon. What does that mean?
Why did they order
from a place so far away?
I've already passed five Chinese restaurants.
I think my lungs are
on the verge of exploding.
You there, teII your cooks...
to put Iess scaIIions in the dumpIings.
Okay.
-Leave it there and go.
-Yes, sir.
We don't take on anyone
who uses bodyguards.
Some companies speciaIize in that.
You shouId go to them.
We just take the smaII fry.
If the stay is over six months,
transportation is free.
Yes, of course.
Why did you imprison me, you...
dickshit.
In our business on fIoor 7.5...
cIient confidentiaIity is our IiveIihood.
I am going to avenge myseIf for aII 15 years.
Each tooth I extract
wiII age you by one year.
Keep stiII.
Do you want to taIk?
I don't know.
I didn't see his face.
I made recordings.
OH DAE-SU
AII those who are bIood type AB,
raise your hand.
Go. Shoo! He has Iost a Iot of bIood.
Piece of shit.
Is he dead?
I can't seem to...
get through today, either.
Now I have become a monster.
When my vengeance is over...
can I return to being Oh Dae-su?
Mister, are you aIright?
Look at aII this bIood.
What happened to you?
Saewoon Apartments, Eung-am,
BuiIding 8. Take care of him.
Thank you.
Not at aII.
WeII, then...
fareweII, Oh Dae-su.
Farewell...
Oh Dae-su.
Farewell.
The bastard you hate, but don't dare kill.
The bitch you detest,
who deserves a fate worse than death.
We are at your service.
Won't he go crazy
if he's locked up for a long time?
Well, if you don't want that,
we can drug his drinks.
There's a thing called ''Risperdal solution. ''
It's a reliable drug
used to treat schizophrenia.
But it depends on the length
of the treatment...
so how long will he....
Fifteen years.
Is that possible?
What did he do?
Oh Dae-su, you see...
talks too much.
Go to sIeep.
Tomorrow, you wiII visit
Joo-hwan's Internet cafe.
Sit wherever you Iike.
Joo-hwan.
Oh Dae-su, you see...
talks too much.
Have you heard this voice before?
Who do you think hates me this much?
Those 260 women you've had....
No way to remember the names
of their husbands.
USER ID: monster@nate.com
MIDO
Who's Mi-do?
A IittIe girI who cries a Iot.
Joo-hwan...
did I...
reaIIy taIk too much?
My friend...
maybe you shouId...
Iook for the criminaI
among peopIe you're cIose to.
Search: Evergreen
Chat to Evergreen?
CongratuIations.
Your case was automaticaIIy
dismissed yesterday.
''But pIease remember this.''
Open quote.
''Like a gazeIIe from the hand of the hunter...
''Iike a bird from the snare of the fowIer...
''free yourseIf.''
CIose quote.
Who are you?
Who are you? You bastard!
I decided when I was a prisoner...
that if I got out, I would trust no one.
If I met anyone suspicious...
I would invent a secret,
only known to the two of us.
That ID, Monster,
is a trap I designed to catch him.
You Iet a stranger into your home.
Who the heII are you?
Who's Evergreen?
I tracked down that Evergreen ID
and found the owner's details.
-Are you ready to jot it down?
-Go ahead.
It's Su Dae-oh.
Does the surname 'Su' even exist?
-Address?
-Saewoon Apartments in Eung-am.
Building 7, flat 407.
Actually, life in a bigger prison...
does not suit me very well.
Evergreen.
Who are you?
Is that what you wanted to ask?
No. You must find that out for yourseIf.
Come on, it's a game.
First who, then why.
When you know the answer,
come and see me.
I'II mark your work.
You have untiI JuIy 5.
Oh no, onIy five days Ieft.
Too short?
Chin up.
If you succeed,
I'II kiII myseIf instead of Mi-do.
That's right, Mi-do.
I'm going to kiII...
every woman you Iove untiI you die.
WeII, you're notorious...
for not protecting your women anyway.
Wow, you're strong, Mr. Monster.
Yes, you are the monster that I created.
But you wiII never...
find out why if you go through with this.
You have been curious for 15 years.
Are you stiII going to kiII me?
Sit down there.
Ah, the tooth torture!
You won't have enough time.
I have a pacemaker for my weak heart.
When it was put in...
do you know what I said to the doctor?
''Dr. Hopkins...
''give me...
''a remote controI to turn my motor off.''
''Pardon? Why?''
''So that I can kiII myseIf easiIy. At any time.
''I'II pay you an extra $100,000 for this.''
What a diIemma.
You want to kiII me right now...
but then you won't know
why you were imprisoned.
You want to torture me,
but I say I'II kiII myseIf first.
Revenge? Or the truth?
What a probIem for you.
I've been watching over you for 15 years.
I've fared weII, thanks to you.
I wasn't bored or IoneIy.
Seeking revenge is the best cure
for someone who has been hurt.
Try it.
The Ioss of 15 years...
the pain of Iosing your wife and chiId...
aII this can be forgotten.
Once again, revenge is good for your heaIth.
But...
what happens
after you've had your revenge?
I bet that hidden pain
probabIy emerges again.
Are you there, Oh Dae-su?
Oh Dae-su.
Long time no see.
Hasn't she been tied up too Iong?
You Ieft her door open.
Save me, Dae-su!
I can't. I'm going to die.
This dentist is very good.
Keep stiII.
What's his probIem?
You see...
they say that peopIe...
shriveI up because of their imagination.
So don' t imagine anything.
You'II become brave as heII.
Now here comes the reaI thing.
Sir, I'm gIad you toId me about this pIace...
but I haven't even started yet!
Let's go.
Let's go now.
Let's fight.
What a tough guy!
Your hand.
I'II chop off your hand.
You touched Mi-do's breasts.
Let's get out of this dump.
So do you trust me now, you bastard?
It Iooks hard to accompIish.
I Iooked into it.
The reason the bank
refused to pay 270 miIIion won...
was not due to any buiIding irreguIarities.
They have internaI probIems.
So I don't think we'II have any troubIe.
Chairman Choi's 23 cIients' shares
are at 25% ....
Dae-su.
Yeah?
Did he reaIIy say that he'd kiII me?
Yeah.
Because I'm the woman you Iove?
Dae-su.
What?
Where is my love?
I'm getting lonelier in the nights
The words you send with your eyes
I can feel with my hand
So many nights have passed
My heart is going to you
As I shed my sad tears
You're the face I miss
They packed up their stuff
and Ieft in a rentaI car.
AIso, Mi-do caIIed the restaurant
and Ieft her job.
Let's go after this is done.
You shouId get some rest today, sir.
I can't even sIeep.
Because I'm IoneIy.
Mr. Han.
Do you reaIIy think...
that Mi-do has faIIen in Iove
with Oh Dae-su?
AIready?
Dae-su!
It hurts so much.
But I'II endure it.
You shouIdn't forget this.
How did you hold out for 15 years?
There's always a way.
Do you Iike it?
You do Iike it, don't you?
I want to make you feeI good, Dae-su.
You need not worry about the future.
Imagine nothing.
I am grateful for all those years
spent in that prison.
If I was the old Oh Dae-su,
would Mi-do still have liked me?
He could only have known that I said
I would chop off Mr. Park's hand...
by putting a bug on us.
And he knew where we were by tailing us.
I've been bugged. PIease find it.
You know...
maybe he freed you...
because he has fun watching you run wild,
seeking revenge.
And he'll never tell you why,
so he can toy with you forever.
Couldn't that be why?
''Evergreen Press, online printing system. ''
''Evergreen Pasta and Pizza.
''Evergreen Services,
for security, parking, cIeaning.
''Evergreen Tree Garden.
Evergreen OId Boys.
''Sangnok High SchooI aIumni homepage.
''Evergreen Secret Diary,
Jung Sang-rok's personaI site.
''Norwegian Wood, Evergreen''....
WELCOME TO EVERGREEN OLD BOYS
THE SANGNOK HIGH SCHOOL
ALUMNI HOMEPAGE
It's time to cIose now.
Can I just Iook at
the records for the cIass of '79?
It's dark. Put the Iights on.
Take your time.
LEE WOO-JIN
Joo-hwan?
Let me ask you something.
Do you remember Lee Woo-jin from schooI?
I think he went to study in America.
Lee Woo-jin?
I don't know him.
So is that the bastard's name?
How did you find out?
I Iooked through aII the schooI yearbooks.
I need more than just a name.
Got anything else?
Look at the student records.
Do you know Lee Soo-ah?
She was in our year.
Lee Soo-ah?
She died.
-What cIassroom was she in?
-Room two, I think.
She was my classmate.
Next to yours.
But what about her?
Why is there no photo?
She died. That must be why.
How did Lee Soo-ah die?
Yeah, you wouldn't know.
She died after you transferred.
She went to the Habchun Dam alone
and fell into the water.
She drowned.
One week later,
they found her bloated body in the water.
-What was she Iike?
-Her?
She was a compIete sIut.
On the outside,
she acted Iike a innocent Iady...
but inside, she was just a fiIthy whore.
The rumor was going around schooI
that she'd fuck anyone.
I shouId have got in there.
I aIso heard that her famiIy was fiIthy rich.
Her grades were good, too.
But the worst thing was
that she was a totaI sIut.
God, this is such an oId story.
Dae-su, I can't remember
because it was so Iong ago...
but that Soo-ah, weII--
Joo-hwan, what is it?
Joo-hwan, is something wrong?
Oh Dae-su.
My sister...
was no sIut.
You must beIieve that.
You got rid of your bug,
so I had to come aII the way here...
to eavesdrop.
That's why Joo-hwan is dead...
because of you.
Okay?
You bastard, I'm coming for you!
I'm going to kill you!
You son of a bitch!
We're not open yet.
Come back in an hour, pIease.
This pIace was recommended
by someone with six goId teeth.
Mr. Park?
I had to move because of you.
To ceIebrate the occasion...
I instaIIed a new TV.
Do you Iike it?
It's got so many channeIs. Great, isn't it?
Some prisoners don't want to Ieave at aII.
You Iived in a pIace Iike this
for 15 years, Dae-su?
After 1 1 years it feIt Iike home.
Come on, I don't need your money.
My enemy's enemy is my friend.
We threw away the hand because it rotted.
I've missed you.
Bastard. You'II pay for this.
So why did you bring me here?
If I don't return after JuIy 5, Iet her go.
WhiIe I was Iocked up here,
I remember someone visiting me.
What did that person do?
Was it three times?
I put a hypnosis-inducing drug
in your water.
Sodium barbiturate?
You're a genius!
WATERWHEEL HAIR SALON
That's nonsense.
Even though it was a CathoIic schooI...
those rumors wouIdn't have kiIIed her.
There was probabIy something eIse.
CouId she have been pregnant, maybe?
I reaIIy don't think Soo-ah was Iike that.
She was such a pure girI.
I know she never went with anyone.
But she did go out with someone back then.
Do you want to know who he was?
I haven't got a cIue!
Choon-shim.
You knew Lee Soo-ah, didn't you?
Who was her boyfriend?
You don't know?
You siIIy cow.
You don't know...
because friendship means nothing to you.
Shut up.
Who wouId know?
Who?
Joo-hwan?
What?
Yeah, I know him.
But why wouId he know?
Yeah?
ReaIIy?
Okay. I'II caII you back in a bit.
WeII...
she said it was Joo-hwan
who toId her the rumors...
and that you shouId know
more than anyone.
Ring, ring.
Move aside.
You'll get hurt...
if you get in the way.
OH DAE-SU
Good Lord!
You rascaI. Put it out!
I'm Ieaving today for SeouI.
So just you Ieave me aIone, missy.
You good-for-nothing!
You're Oh Dae-su, aren't you?
And you are....
I heard you're popuIar with the girIs.
You know what rumors are Iike.
I heard you're reaIIy funny. Make me Iaugh.
I don't want to be tied to just one image.
Okay, there's this father and son.
They went to the swimming pooI and....
See you Iater.
TAKE CARE,
FUCKHEADS OF YEAR 3, CLASS 3!
-Come on.
-Wait.
-Come here.
-No.
Come here.
Okay, okay.
Satisfied?
-Lift this up.
-No way.
-Lift it up.
-No.
What?
That tickIes.
Give me those.
What are you doing?
Let me see.
-Let me see.
-Stop it.
Go away.
Was it reaIIy Soo-ah? Are you sure?
I don't know her name.
I just know that she's in your cIass
and she rides a red bike.
Have a good trip. See you in SeouI.
Where are you going?
I've got a date with Choon-shim.
I'II kiII you if you bIab to anyone.
No way.
You got locked up for 15 years
just for saying that?
Is that such a crime?
''Whether it be a grain of sand or a rock...
''in water they both sink alike. ''
That's Lee Woo-jin's attitude.
So...
what's the significance of JuIy 5?
That's the day...
Lee Soo-ah died.
It's over now.
You were fighting for the truth...
not for revenge, weren't you?
Now we'II run away
where Woo-jin can never foIIow us.
I can't end it like this.
Vengeance has become a part of me.
But you don't even know where he Iives.
''Like a gazelle from the hand of the hunter...
''like a bird from the snare of the fowler...
''free yourself. ''
It is taken from the
Book of Proverbs, chapter six, verse four.
And Evergreen...
said he lives in a high tower.
So six and four...
must be floors.
Fourth floor.
Sixth floor.
Or the 64th floor?
P?
Penthouse!
Please insert the code.
What wouId you Iike me to pray for?
Wrong entry.
Please re-enter.
Wrong entry. Please re-enter.
''Dear Lord...
''pIease Iet me...
''meet a younger man next time.''
PIease make Woo-jin...
kneeI before Dae-su...
and beg for forgiveness.
You sIept with your sister.
Let's go upstairs and taIk.
Get him!
You couId just taIk.
That was refreshing.
You sIept with your sister.
So refreshing.
And I started the rumors.
That's why your sister died.
Looking in the mirror
reminds me of that day.
How about you?
Erasing my memory and teIIing me
to find the truth was cowardIy.
I won...
so die Iike you promised.
Did you think you had forgotten that
day because you were hypnotized?
ReaIIy?
Do you know the reaI reason
why you can't remember?
It's because...
you just forgot.
Is that not exciting enough for you?
WeII it's true, you just forgot.
Why? Because it wasn't important to you.
Your rumor got so out of hand...
that the next rumor was
that Soo-ah was pregnant.
My sister got sucked into that rumor...
and began beIieving it.
So her periods stopped
and her beIIy began to sweII.
Fascinating, isn't it?
Imagine how it wouId feeI for a girI
to carry a chiId who's her own nephew.
Do you understand now?
Your tongue got my sister pregnant.
It wasn't Lee Woo-jin's dick.
It was Oh Dae-su's tongue.
Is that why you kiIIed your sister?
Imagine how a boy wouId feeI...
fathering both his chiId and his nephew?
You were probabIy afraid.
Afraid that everyone wouId know
once the baby was born.
After you kiIIed her, you reaIized
it was a phantom pregnancy...
so your hating me...
is understandabIe.
They said Soo-ah died aIone at the dam...
so who took this photo?
And what about the date, JuIy 5?
This is no fun.
I'II just finish what I was saying.
Listen carefuIIy. My story is reaIIy exciting.
Ever heard of post-hypnotic suggestion?
You suggest something during hypnosis...
then it's performed in your wakened state.
StiII haven't worked it out?
You Iet a stranger into your home.
Who the heII are you?
What about you, you bastard?
We hypnotized both of you.
One fortunate thing was that,
compared to others...
both of you were highly receptive
to hypnosis.
Isn't this fun?
One word gets you pregnant.
Another makes you fall in love.
But no matter how receptive
you two were to hypnosis...
and no matter how good
a hypnotist Miss Yoo is...
getting peopIe to faII in Iove isn't easy.
Do you know how we did it?
Your first suggestion, of course...
was to go to that restaurant...
straight after your reIease.
Next, to react
to the mobiIe phone's ringtone.
When you heard this,
you were programmed to say something.
Who are you?
Do you...
Iike your cIothes?
And Mi-do was programmed
to react to the man...
who would say this.
When she touched your hand,
your reaction would be, of course....
Your gravest mistake wasn't
faiIing to find the answer.
If you keep...
asking the wrong questions,
you'II never find the right answer.
It's not ''Why did Woo-jin imprison me?''
It's ''Why did he reIease me?''
Once again:
Why did Woo-jin reIease Dae-su...
after 15 years?
Laugh, and the worId Iaughs with you.
Weep, and you weep aIone.
Mr. Han.
Mr. Han!
Mi-do.
Mi-do doesn't know, does she?
Why did you hide her there?
Did you think he'd hate me
just because I cut off his hand?
Didn't you work out that it was a trap?
How can you protect your woman
with that brain?
I've secretIy been raising Mi-do
since she was three.
What's wrong with you?
Mr. Park's hand?
You moron.
Did you see his new prison?
I gave him that buiIding for his hand!
Me!
Dae-su!
In front of me...
there's some kind of box.
He's teIIing me to open it.
It's the same vioIet box....
No!
No, Mi-do, don't.
Don't open it, no matter what.
Or something terribIe wiII happen.
What's in it?
You know, don't you?
Mi-do, just wait a IittIe Ionger.
Dae-su wiII be there soon.
I'II be there very soon.
Can't you come now?
I'm scared.
LittIe Mi-do, you can wait, can't you?
Yes.
Very good. Good girI.
I'II caII you back very soon, okay?
PIease.
Don't teII Mi-do.
What has she done wrong?
You know it was aII my fauIt.
I have...
committed an unforgivabIe sin...
against your sister.
And I aIso...
did you wrong.
But...
pIease Ieave Mi-do aIone.
If by any chance...
Mi-do finds out the truth...
you son of a bitch!
I'II tear you...
Iimb from Iimb.
And your remains wiII never be found.
Why?
Because I'm going to swaIIow every Iast bit.
Woo-jin!
PIease, sir, I made a mistake.
PIease forget what I said.
Sir!
Woo-jin!
We're Evergreen OId Boys, remember?
With the energy
Of a green pine tree
The Great Sangnok High....
I'II do whatever you want.
I'II do anything. I beg you.
Woo-jin, if you want me to be your dog,
I wiII!
From this moment on I am Woo-jin's dog!
I'm your bitch.
Look, I'm wagging my taiI.
I'm a dog. I'II guard your house.
I'II be your sIave.
The box...
just Ieave it cIosed.
Now...
what wiII I Iive for?
Dae-su!
It hurts so much.
But I'll endure it.
You must understand.
My sister and I Ioved each other
despite everything.
Can you two do the same?
I want to make you feel good, Dae-su.
Soo-ah.
Woo-jin.
I know you've aIways been afraid.
So just Iet go of me.
PIease remember me.
I have no regrets. Do you?
This is the whole adventure
of my life until now.
Thank you for listening
to this terrible story to the end.
I trust that you will understand
my sending a letter...
instead of talking to you in person.
This is because I have no tongue.
To be honest,
there's no reason I shouId heIp you.
But there was one thing.
I was touched by this Iast sentence.
Even though I'm no better than a beast...
don't I have the right to Iive?
The hypnosis may go wrong
and distort your memories.
Do you want to proceed?
If you're ready...
Iook at that tree.
The tree...
is sIowIy changing into a concrete piIIar.
You're now inside Lee Woo-jin's penthouse.
It's a dreary night.
The sound of your footsteps
crossing to the window...
fills the room.
When I ring my bell...
you'll split into two people.
One person doesn't know your secret.:
Oh Dae-su.
The one who knows your secret
is the monster.
When I ring the bell again...
the monster will turn around
and start walking.
With each step, he will age by one year.
When he reaches 70, the monster will die.
There's no need to worry.
It will be a very peaceful death.
Now, good luck to you.
What's going on?
Look at you.
Who were you with?
I Iove you...
Dae-su.
www.moviesubtitles.org
hypnosi