{\move(10,10,190,230,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000&\3c&H00FFFF&}anoXmous
{\move(400,10,190,270,100,400)\fad(0,1000)\fscx25\fscy25\t(0,6000,\fscx125\fscy125)\c&H000000f&\3c&0000a6&}https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(DISTANT,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(VOMITING)
Goddamn.
(SIGHS)
You OK?
The goddamn food
is making me sick.
(GROANS)
(COUGHING)
You gonna be able to drive?
This fucker drives itself.
(CHUCKLES)
You think that's funny?
You think that's funny?!
Give me that hot dog.
- I'm just about to eat it.
- Give me that fucking hot dog.
(SIGHS)
Open.
What are you doing?
Open your fucking mouth.
- You're making me uncomfortable.
- Open it!
- (WHIMPERS)
- Open your fucking mouth.
Get that fucking thing in there.
- Take it. All of it. That's it.
- (COUGHING)
(THUMPS, GASPING)
Fucking whore.
(GASPING CONTINUES)
Everybody all right over here?
- Hey, mind your business, pal.
- (COUGHING)
Yeah, when you slap
a woman around,
it is my business, pal.
Stay out of my shit, motherfucker.
That's Mr. Motherfucker to you.
- Harlan, come on. No, don't.
- Yeah, come on.
Harlan?
Harlan...
I don't want no trouble.
- Harlan!
- Yeah, you already started...
- (GRUNTING)
- Harlan, stop!
Come on, don't! Stop!
Harlan!
Stop it! Stop!
Stop it!
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
The fuck out of there!
Fucking whore!
(SOBBING)
Yeah, you want a problem?
Huh?!
Get back in your fucking car!
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE REVVING)
WOMAN: Somebody call 911!
(I PEARL JAM: "RELEASE")
♪ I see the world a'
♪ Feel the Chill A'
♪ Which way to go a'
Hey, bring it in!
♪ Windowsill a'
♪ I see the words a'
♪ On a rocking horse of time a'
♪ I see the birds a'
♪ In the rain a'
♪ Oh, dear dad a'
♪ Can you see me now? a'
♪ I am myself I
♪ Like you somehow a'
♪ I'll ride the wave... a'
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENTS
OVER TV)
(QUIET, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN: Come on, six.
- Come on, six.
- (PHONE RINGING)
Come on, six.
Oh, he's pulling up
on the fucking reins.
Why is he pulling up
on the fucking reins?!
God fucking...
Are you kidding me?
Hey, man, is this...
That was race eight
right there on TV two?
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- You looking at it?
- Isn't that what I said?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Man, what are you doing here?
- What are you doing here?
- Huh?
What are you doing here?
You playing the ponies now?
Well, I don't know.
Just trying to make a little dough.
Son of a bitch.
- (CHUCKLING)
- What, man? Gonna give me some shit?
I ain't giving you shit.
I'm just wondering
where you're getting
the money to bet with.
- Borrowed it.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
Who from?
Huh?
- Who from?
- John Petty.
Motherfucker gave me a tip,
it didn't pay off.
Well, of course he did.
How much he loan you?
I don't even know.
You don't even know?
You know. How much?
How much?
Fifteen hundred.
Fuck me, Rodney.
Where you gonna get that money
to pay him back with, huh?
And what else you gonna owe him?
You got a check coming in
from somewhere or...?
- No.
- You know, 'cause I ain't
got that kind of cash
lying around to bail you out.
Well, I didn't ask
for you to bail me out.
No. Don't fuck around
with John Petty.
I'm not fucking around with him.
He gave me a fucking tip,
it didn't pay off.
Come on, man.
Don't give me this shit.
- (GRUNTS)
- (LAUGHING)
Hey, uh, tell Dad that, um...
...I'll be by before work tomorrow.
All right.
- (ENGINE STARTING)
- And, you know, just...
(engine revving)
(revving continues)
(alarm beeping)
(WHISPERING) Don't go.
If I could stay, I would.
Then stay.
Leaving you ain't easy, girl.
(CHUCKLES)
Or I'll stay.
I'll stay until you get back.
What time do you get off?
Working a double.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
Russell, you work too much.
Got to bring home the bacon
to fatten you up.
You, you little Skinny Minnie.
(LAUGHS)
My Skinny Minnie.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Skinny Minnie.
No, I want you to fatten me up
with a baby.
Want to run away somewhere?
Don't change the subject.
I want to run away somewhere.
Let's do it.
- Where?
- I don't know.
I've never been east
of Scranton, but...
(LAUGHTER)
- I'm gonna fatten you up.
- (LAUGHING) Stop.
(DOOR OPENS)
Uncle Red.
Hey, buddy, how are you?
Saw your truck.
Hey, Dad.
Hey, how you doing?
- OK.
- I'm here.
That's why I'm OK.
(RUSSELL LAUGHS)
You're hot.
DAD: Your hand's so cold.
- RUSSELL: That feel good?
- Yeah.
His fever?
RED: Yeah, it's still high.
Hey, you want to get
a drink later?
Yeah. Where?
John Petty's?
- How's Lena?
- RUSSELL: Oh, she's good.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Keeping me in check.
- Big job.
- (CHUCKLING) Yeah.
You know?
Well, give her a hug for me.
You bet, dirty old bastard.
(BOTH LAUGH)
All right, Pops,
I got to go to work.
All right.
I'll see you later.
- You'll come back, huh?
- Oh, yeah.
I always come back.
- I love you.
- DAD: Me, too.
- Keep your hands warm.
- OK.
Hey, thanks for coming by.
See you, Russ.
MAN ON TV:
I have come here tonight
to stand with you,
to change America,
to restore its future,
to rise to our best ideals
and to elect Barack Obama
president of the United States.
(CROWD CHEERING)
I'm afraid we're about to lose
another Kennedy.
God bless him.
You want another?
No, I'm good.
No, Rodney was supposed
to meet me here half hour ago.
Oh, yeah, how is old Rodney?
He seems awfully quiet
last few times he was here.
Yeah, he stop-lossed again.
- He's going back next month.
- Ahh...
Those poor sons of guns. They're
holding them against their will.
They're gonna run them into
the ground, they're not careful.
Don't get me started.
Well, if he turns up,
you tell him I headed home
to see Lena?
- Sure.
- All right.
(SIGHS)
Oh, hey, I got this one.
Whoa, thanks, Dan.
Is, uh... ls John in?
I just, you know,
need to bend his ear.
Uh, he had someone
back there earlier,
but, uh, I think they might be gone.
- All right if I...
- Yeah.
HARLAN: If I have to come all the way
down here again, I swear to God,
I'll gut your fucking ass, cunt.
You hear me, Petty?
You better start following
through on your promises.
Oh, you know I can't control
some of those fuckers.
HARLAN: For 25 grand,
you'd better control them.
I ought to put a piece
of lead in your ass
- and take everything in here.
- John, you back here?
Oh, I'm sorry, should I
come back later or...?
No, it's OK.
We're finishing up.
Your mama teach you
to barge in like that?
You got a problem with me?
I got a problem with everybody.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Who the fuck are they?
Inbred mountain folk
from Jersey.
Church ain't over until
the snakes are back in the bag,
know what I mean?
What are they doing down here?
Don't ask.
- Here.
- Oh, no, I'm good.
Take it.
What's up?
Oh, here.
It's from Rodney.
I know it's not nearly all there.
I hate that you work your ass off
to pay his debt.
Rodney needs to watch it.
I like him, Russell, I really do,
but I worry that...
Hell, he might be safer over in Iraq.
Well, do you mind not
telling him I brought you that,
please, and if he don't
bring the rest of it,
I will on my next payday.
OK.
I won't say a thing.
- All right, thanks.
- (GLASSES CLINK)
(SIGHS)
RADIO ANNOUNCER: Cubs lead Pirates
ten to one in the bottom of the sixth.
Chavez off of first base.
Lilly's still looking strong
on the mound,
and Lilly delivers.
Swinging, there's a drive, deep...
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(PANTING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(GLASS CRUNCHING)
(DOOR RATTLING)
(WHISPERING) Hey.
Hey, there.
Can you...
Can you... Can you hear me?
Hey, there, little fella.
(PANTING)
Hey, there.
Hey, there...
...little fella.
Oh, God.
(PANTING) on, God.
Hey. Help.
Can you come help? Come...
(HAMMERING ECHOING)
RUSSELL: You know,
I just keep my head down.
Studying shit I should've studied
in high school, you know?
- Could be worse.
- How could it be worse?
I don't know.
I could be going to Iraq with you.
- No shit.
- (CHUCKLING)
I asked Lena to come down here.
She said some bullshit about
not wanting to see you like this.
- You shouldn't have.
- Oh, fuck that.
She don't like this place.
What are you going to do?
- She doesn't like this place?
- (GRUNTS)
What, is there someone
who likes this place?
- Come on, just give her a break.
- (SCOFFS)
And what about you?
You still seeing the, uh...
uh, woof-woof?
Woof-woof! Down.
(PANTS, LAUGHS)
Oh, man,
I almost forgot about her.
Thanks a lot.
RUSSELL: How's, uh...
How's Dad doing?
- Uh, barely hanging on, really.
- Yeah.
Make sure you give him
a big hug from me.
You know?
Yeah, but...
(GROANS)
You, uh, watch yourself over there.
OK.
- You, too.
- Yeah.
- Guess I know where to write to you.
What's up, homey?
You fucking quiet.
You walk the yard,
you don't talk to nobody.
Are you a fucking faggot?
Huh, bro?
- Get the fuck away from me.
- You want to suck my dick?
Come here.
FUCK you!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Get him off me,
you motherfucker!
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
GUARD: Hey! Break it up!
Get off me, holmes!
GUARD: Get upstairs!
- Get off me, cabron!
- Shut up!
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
(COUGHS)
(GROANING)
He was trying to hang on
until you got out.
He wanted to see you.
It just ate him up.
You put him next to Mom?
Yeah.
Um... I'm glad you were home.
(SIGHS)
How was your last tour?
It was hard.
Yeah?
I mean, this...
You know, the whole thing...
(SIGHS)
Rodney, whatever you did...
...whatever you did, you had to do.
Yeah.
(TAPPING ON TABLE)
(SNIFFLES)
(SNIFFLING CONTINUES)
I got to go-
I love you, bud.
I love you, too, man.
MAN: And surely,
he has borne our griefs
and carried our sorrows.
Yet we will esteem him as stricken.
Smitten of God and afflicted.
But he was wounded
for our transgressions.
He was bruised for our iniquities.
The chastisement
of our peace was upon him.
And with his stripes, we are healed.
(ALARM BUZZES IN DISTANCE)
(EXHALING)
(CLAPPING)
(LAUGHS)
(WHOOPING)
Come here! Man!
(LAUGHING)
Mmm.
How's it feel?
Eh, eh, eh.
(LAUGHTER)
Oh!
Look, I'm running,
I'm gonna run.
- I'm running.
- Get away! Go!
(LAUGHTER)
(SIGHS)
- You driving?
- You want to drive?
- Yeah.
Yeah?
Come on, motherfucker.
Say good- bye.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE REVVING)
Hey, Jerry!
He didn't know
who the fuck you were.
(DOOR BANGS SHUT)
RUSSELL: Well, it is What it is.
I think you're better off.
Why would you say that?
Come on, man, she left you
without even telling you.
Now she's with fucking Wesley?
She's a smart woman.
Got her reasons.
You been hanging with, uh...
...Billy and them lately?
- Nope.
- No?
What you been
doing with yourself?
- Looking for a job.
- Any luck?
' NODe.
" No?
(CHUCKLES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
On a liquid dinner?
It's the dinner of champions.
RUSSELL: Yeah.
I'll be back.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Oh, Wesley, my lunch.
Bye.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
Yeah!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
Get your ass up, white boy!
Let's go!
Get your ass up, man!
Come on!
(GRUNTING)
(SHOUTING)
You ain't shit!
Look at you! Look at you!
Come on, motherfucker!
Come on, man, let's go!
This ain't fucking Iraq.
Let's go, soldier boy.
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
Get up!
Stop!
Break it up!
Smile, motherfucker!
That's bullshit!
Goddamn it, Rodney.
Did you not hear me?
- Did you not hear me?
- (SIGHS)
Motherfucker,
I took a hit in there.
I told you I can't
really control myself
in the middle of a fight, man.
It's all a blur.
And don't fucking poke
on me again, either.
No more excuses.
No more Iraqi stories.
You just got to learn
how to take a fall
because you owe me
a lot of fucking money.
Well, I can't pay you back
your money by taking a dive
in this nickel
and dime bullshit.
You'd better figure out something
and figure it out quick.
Yeah, let's go fight up in Jersey.
Up in the Ramapos they got fights.
Don't talk to me about that.
It's not for you.
Why? I heard they're big money.
Look, Rodney, go work in the mill.
Like your father and brother.
This isn't a way for you
to make a living.
You're a good kid with a good heart.
You can do a lot worse
than living your life
like your brother, believe me.
I don't want to work
at the fucking mill, man.
I want to be just like you, John.
(JOHN CHUCKLES)
We'll talk later.
(CAR APPROACHING)
(ENGINE STOPS)
RUSSELL: Hey.
RODNEY: Hi.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
- Where you been?
- (RODNEY SNIFFLES)
Out with the boys.
Well, looks like...
...your boys play rough.
Want a drink?
(SNIFFLES)
No. The place looks nice.
(MACHINERY CLANGING)
Put it up!
(PLATE CLINKS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(CLOSES)
RODNEY: Hey.
(GLASS CLINKING)
Let me see your hands.
What?
Rodney, come here.
Let me see your fucking hands.
- Come on, man.
- Huh?
Don't give me no shit.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Is that the best you can do?
What do you think I should do?
What do I think you should do?
I don't know.
Shovel asphalt for
the highway department.
Sell fucking shoes.
Come work at the mill.
Come work at the mill. I told you
Roach would give you a job.
No, man, I'd rather
be fucking dead.
Fuck the mill.
I work at the mill, you little fucker.
It's good enough for me.
It was good enough for our dad.
The fucking mill killed our dad!
Just don't be... Hey.
Just don't be too proud
to work for a living.
There's nothing wrong with it.
What'd you say?
Nothing wrong with
working for a living.
- Working for a living?
- Yeah.
What do you call this,
motherfucker?
Is that working for a living, huh?
Is it working for a living when
I carried my best friend's legs
under this arm, and the rest
of him under this arm?
I saw a fucking baby
with his fucking head cut off!
I saw a fucking pile of feet
in the middle of the street,
and I had to clean it up!
I gave my fucking life
for this country.
That's not work?
And what's it done for me, huh??
What's it fucking done for me?!
(SCREAMING)
Fuck you.
(DOOR OPENS)
(SIGHS)
(ENGINE STARTING, REVVING)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
Get me that fight up in Ramapo.
I told you not to bring that up again.
I need one last fucking fight, John.
Just give me one good fight, please.
One good fucking fight, please!
That's all I'm asking you.
Can you please do that for me?
No, you gotta trust me when I tell you,
you don't want to set foot
in those mountains.
What is the big fucking deal?
The big fucking deal?
The big fucking deal is I've dealt
with these guys for a long time,
and when they don't get what
they want, they get nasty.
They get nasty, do they?
- Yeah. You don't know.
- RODNEY: Yeah?
Well, John, I don't really have
a lot of fucking options, man.
I can't fucking catch up
doing this small-town shit!
- Calm the fuck down.
- Come the fuck on, man!
- Come on, please! I'm sorry!
- I'm trying to protect you!
Just fucking call them up, John.
Please?
I'm not doing it, Rodney.
I'm not gonna call them.
Well, I'm not leaving until you do.
- Call them up.
- Rodney...
Just please call them up.
- John, please call them up.
- Rodney...
Please call them up.
I'm asking you for one fight.
- Please call them up.
- Fuck, Rodney!
You fuck with these inbreds,
you'll come crawling back.
If you're lucky.
(RODNEY CLAPS HANDS)
I don't really want to be doing this.
This is not fucking around.
Let me talk to them.
(TRAIN HORN BLOWS)
(CROWD SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
-(SHOUTING, CLAMORING)
-(BLOWS THUDDING)
(GRUNTING)
(CROWD CLAMORING, SHOUTING)
(FIGHTERS GRUNTING)
Yeah?
What the fuck you want, Petty?
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING IN DISTANCE)
LENA: March, march,
where are my soldiers?
Where are my soldiers?
- (KIDS CLAMORING)
- LENA: No... uh-uh! Come on.
- LENA: Hey!
- (mos SHRIEKING PLAYFULLY)
We don't want
to wake up the neighbors.
You know what? Let's wake up
the neighbors. One, two, three!
- (mos SCREECHING)
- (RUSSELL LAUGHS)
LENA: So funny! Oh, my gosh!
- (KIDS SQUEALING AND SCREAMING)
- Wait a minute!
OK, go, go, go, go, go!
-(KIDS SCREAMING)
-(LENA LAUGHS)
- We're gonna play nice, right?
- KIDS: Yeah!
What do you want?
You want to race me?
- Racer? Huh?
- GIRL: I want to go on the horsey.
- Where are the horsies? Huh?
- Over there. Over there.
- Race you over there.
- Yeah.
Lily... Lily, can you just
watch them for one second?
(INSECTS CHIRRING)
- You're staying at your dad's?
- Yeah.
You know, I'm trying
to give it some life.
I went to his funeral.
I know.
Thank you. That was...
important to me.
Thank you.
Are you back at the mill?
Just can't get enough of it,
you know?
I hear they're gonna close it.
Yeah, looks like it.
You know, cheaper to...
...uh, get steel from China.
God, I've missed you so much.
I've missed you so much.
I was hoping that, uh...
...we could work it out.
You know?
The things that were
keeping us apart and...
...you know, take that
next step is something
I want to do with you.
Because, uh...
...I can't be without you, Lena.
I can't.
I'm pregnant.
OK.
Wow.
You, uh...
(SNIFFLES)
That's, uh...
That's wonderful news.
It is?
Yeah. That's wonderful news.
I'm real happy for you, Lena.
I really am.
That's wonderful news.
You're gonna be a hell of a mom.
(VOICE BREAKING) Wow!
You're gonna be a hell of a mom!
(BOTH CRYING)
I'm so sorry.
- I have to go.
- Yeah.
OK.
(HORN BEEPS TWICE)
Hey, man!
What about it?
Goddamn, Uncle Red.
- Look like they fed you pretty good.
- Yeah.
You're fit as a racehorse.
How you doing?
Still this side
of the grass, you know.
Hey, I got something
for your daddy.
I had a feeling that was you.
- You're still raising them?
- Isn't that pretty? Yeah.
Yeah, when the weather permits.
Say, do you want to come over
to the cemetery with me?
Shit, yeah.
Rodney here?
Does he want to come?
Ah, I don't know where he is.
Let me get this shit inside...
- ...run over with you.
- Hey, grab your rifle.
Maybe we can get
a shot off before dark.
I saw a real nice eight-point
out there the other night.
RUSSELL: Yup. See if I'm
still a better shot than you.
(RED CHUCKLES)
(swans CHIRPING)
Well...
...let's go get us a buck, huh?
We can circle around these.
Seen a feral cat.
DeGroat?
I didn't drive
five and a half hours
to watch you play fucking cards.
Well, when you owe as much
as you owe me, Petty...
I guess I'm the last
person you want to see.
Step into the room,
fighter man.
Let me get a good
look at you.
- And what's your name?
- Rodney.
Is that it?
Just Rodney?
Rodney Baze.
(HARLAN EXHALING)
Well...
Rodney Baze...
I hear you're quite
the crazy fucker in the ring.
Makes me want
to jump in there with you...
...and see who walks out.
We're standing so close,
I guess we could do it right now.
(CHUCKLES)
You gonna be a good boy
and take a dive,
like Petty said you would?
Or am I gonna have to
teach you a lesson?
No, he's good. He's good.
- Teach me a lesson?
- I gave you our word.
Yeah, teach you a lesson.
JOHN: Everything's good.
Let me hear you say it.
Teach me a lesson?
Yeah, isn't that
what we talked about?
- Is this boy deaf?
- No, no, it's...
- You been hit too many times?
- (QUIET LAUGH)
Listen, we talked,
everything's good.
(LAUGHS)
Hey, yeah.
I like this one.
He's tough.
- And angry.
- JOHN: Plenty tough.
Four-tours-in-Iraq tough.
Now, why the hell you want
to come up here and fight,
or, hell, anywhere,
when you've been fighting
over there for so long?
I just need the money, man.
Mmm... Yeah.
Well... we all need money...
...don't we, Petty?
So...
...why don't me and John
discuss this deal
while you go
put your fight face on.
Didn't we just discuss the deal?
What, you think I was asking?
Hey! Don't! Keep your
fucking hands off him.
Just checking his reflexes.
You step out.
Step out and we'll...
I'll take care of this.
Step out, Rodney.
(LAUGHING)
I should've popped that motherfucker.
Well, that would be the last
motherfucker you ever popped.
Am I supposed to be scared of him
'cause he sucks on a lollipop?
(EXHALES) Look at me.
You gotta make this look good.
You can't embarrass DeGroat
in front of these guys
that he's got coming up.
Well...
...I can't promise to go down
for that motherfucker.
Did you hear me?
Did you hear me?!
- Yeah. I heard you.
- Good.
Now get your shit
and let's get going.
Come on, get ready.
Showtime.
You ain't fighting
with that shit on, are you?
It's bare-knuckle up here.
JOHN: Take 'em off.
Be careful out there.
Keep it going for a little while
and then you know what to do.
(GRUNTS)
RUSSELL: Look at that beauty.
Clean shot?
Yeah, right in the heart.
Inch either way, we'd be tracking
the son of a bitch all night,
like the last time,
you remember?
- Yeah.
- You see anything?
Not a goddamn thing.
Come on, help me.
Give me a hand with this.
(MEN CLAMORING)
(FIGHTERS GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
Aah!
Get him! Come on!
- (GRUNTING)
- Come on, sucker...
(PANTING WITH EFFORT)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(GRUNTING)
Get off me.
Get up! Get up!
(CROWD SHOUTING)
(BLOWS LANDING)
- (CROWD SHOUTING)
- (GRUNTING)
Rodney!
(GRUNTING)
(CROWD SHOUTING, CHEERING)
- (PANTING)
- JOHN: Rodney!
- Kick his ass!
- Come on, man!
- Just kick his ass!
- Rodney!
(CROWD SHOUTING ANGRILY)
Rodney!
Come on, fucker. Get up.
Get up, motherfucker.
You hear me?
You gotta hit me, make it look real.
Make it look real.
(BLOWS LANDING)
(CROWD SHOUTING)
That's it! That's it!
(CROWD SHOUTING ANGRILY)
He's done! He's done!
I made him stop!
Are you OK?
He)', you OK?
(CROWD CHATTER FADES)
You done good.
Look at me.
Bud.
Oh, Christ. You OK?
- Bud, you OK?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Impressive stuff.
All heart and fist.
That boy don't look so good.
(SNIFFLING, COUGHS)
Hey, hey, uh, don't...
Don't blow your nose,
your eyes will...
...swell up.
Hell, mercy, you took a whooping.
You looked angry out there.
I thought maybe...
...for a second you
weren't a good listener.
I was just reacting.
I just lost it a little bit.
Oh, yeah, well, hell,
I don't blame you.
I'd done the same thing,
guy pounded on me like that.
- Yeah.
- So our slate is clean.
Mmm...
Well, yes, as long as you
brought me the rest of my money.
Don't tell me you come all this way
and didn't bring me what you owe.
This was it.
Now we're even.
That was the deal.
Oh. I must've got confused.
(LAUGHS) Whatever.
You need this?
Here. Wipe your face.
Last time I'm coming up here,
I can tell you that.
Sorry as hell you had
to go through that, Rodney.
(WEAKLY) It's not your fault.
I asked you to take me up here.
It's both of our faults.
But we're through
with those Ramapo fuckers.
That crazy son of a bitch
can kiss my ass
if he thinks I'm doing
business with him again.
Strung out fucking tweaker.
Oh, what the fuck?
What the fuck is this?
OK.
OK. OK. OK. OK.
What's the game?
(INSECTS CHIRRING)
Yeah?
I think your left rear's gone down.
What?
I said...
...I think your left
rear's gone down.
What shit you talking?
(LAUGHS) I ain't talking shit.
And our slate ain't clean,
motherfucker.
(GUNSHOT)
Get that other one out.
Let's go. Go get him.
Get the fuck out.
Come on.
MAN: Get your fucking ass...
(MEN GRUNTING)
(RODNEY GRUNTING)
(RODNEY CRIES OUT)
RODNEY: "Russ...
I'm sorry about the other day.
I know you're looking out for me.
But you gotta understand
that I'm different
than I was before I left.
And I think that I always will be.
I can't explain how exactly.
My head is just full of stuff
and I can't get it out."
(SIGHS)
Oh, man.
(PANTING)
You should have kept
better company.
Don't look at me.
(PANTING)
Look away.
Fuck you.
Oh, fuck you.
You fucking coward.
I don't care. I don't care.
(GUN FIRES)
Get some shovels.
RODNEY: "But I'm gonna
turn things around.
I'm gonna do this one last fight
and then I'll be done.
Then I'm gonna shovel asphalt
or dig for coal
or I'll work with you
and Roach at the mill.
I'll do anything.
I'm gonna get things back on track.
I promise.
I love you, man.
I'll see you tomorrow
when I get back."
(PAPER RUSTLING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Morning, Russell.
Glad you're home.
Thanks.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I guess you, uh...
...heard that, uh...
...I stopped by to see Lena.
Yeah, I'm aware.
Not why I'm here.
HARLAN: I said...
I think your left rear's gone down.
JOHN: What shit you talking?
HARLAN: I ain't talking shit.
And our slate ain't clean,
motherfucker.
(GUNSHOT)
- Turn it off.
- HARLAN: Get that other one out.
We don't need to hear it again.
I've spoken to Jersey State,
Bergen County, Fish and Game.
All of them have dealt with this
Harlan DeGroat before.
The problem is that
the people up in those hills,
they don't cooperate.
Getting information from these
people is like pulling teeth.
It's a whole 'nother world up in there.
Generations upon generations
of these people
never even come down
off that mountain.
Got their own breed of justice
and it does not include us.
Even the local police
sent in several squad cars,
but they haven't been able
to get nothing yet.
So you know that I'm stuck here
with my hands tied.
What the fuck does that mean?
That they aren't gonna...
...do anything about this
or look for Rodney?
I did not say that, Russell.
I said that they're having
a difficult time
and I'm having jurisdiction issues.
But I'm gonna be on it
until it's done.
What the fuck?
- Bud.
- I mean, you know...
We know John Petty's dead.
I mean, Jesus, you know,
damn near hear him dying
on Dan's phone.
But Rodney might still be out there.
I know that this is very hard
for you, but...
...I do have a procedure
that I have to follow.
It sounds like there's
no procedure at all.
- Bud!
- No, no, no, no, no.
It sounds like they're not
doing a goddamn thing.
Now, either you're all
afraid to go in there...
...or, uh...
- ...you just don't give a shit.
- You walking down the wrong road.
I said I'm into it,
and I said I'll handle it.
Don't make this personal.
- You need to stay out of my business.
- Stay out of your business.
- Knock it off.
You know what?
While I was away, it seems that
all that you was into
was my business.
So that's what this is.
You got a problem with me.
Yeah, I got a problem with you.
WESLEY: I'm not the one who was out
drinking and driving.
Got locked up and had
to leave his woman alone
'cause of something I did,
a mistake I made.
And I don't know nothing
about what happened to Rodney.
Nothing at all.
I'm just trying to do my job.
And I'm giving you my word that
I'm gonna be on it until it's done.
Until it's done.
Mmm. Well.
Russell. Come on.
What is it?
You want me to show you out?
I'll be around.
Dan.
- RED: Where you going now?
- No, it's good.
- Hey, Russ, listen, I'm sorry.
- Hey.
I know how tough this is,
but I'm hereto help anyway I can.
Then get me an address
for DeGroat.
An address? How am I
gonna get that address?
Don't give me that shit, Dan. You know
as well as I do that John Petty has one.
Well, I don't...
I don't know.
Look, I'll see if I can dig that up.
No, no, no, don't see
if you can dig it up.
- Do it.
- Russell, listen to me.
If you're smart,
you let these boys handle it.
I know these guys.
This DeGroat is a nasty son of a bitch.
You let me worry about...
...who's a nasty son of a bitch.
We'll follow you.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING
IN DISTANCE)
Damn, looks like John still owes
money to these people.
A hell of a lot of money.
I know they had this whole deal,
but I didn't realize it was this big.
- What deal?
- Well, this bare-knuckle deal
up and down the Appalachians.
I don't know that much about it,
but my guess is,
Rodney went up there to fight.
Well, why didn't you just say
something to Wesley?
Well, I don't... I don't know.
I mean, I didn't...
I didn't know what to say.
John should've known better.
I think he did, Red,
but Rodney forced his hand.
He thought it was the only way
to pay off that debt.
I don't see DeGroat's address,
but I do know it's up in the Ramapos.
And, Russell, please
hear me when I tell you,
you'd be way better off letting
the authorities deal with him.
They're not doing
such a good job, Dan.
Well, I hear you,
but John hated dealing with them.
I'm surprised they haven't come
down hereto get their money.
Money and drugs, that's the only thing
that drove that crazy son of a bitch.
Are you ready for this?
I guess so.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
You watch your ass.
Gotta say, fellas, that is sharp.
'66 or '67?
Man, you don't see that Bolero red much.
You got the tuxedo black
and ash gold everywhere, but...
Yeah, this is sweet.
Three-ninety-six big block?
Yep.
That's a true 138 SS
right there, man.
Fucking rocket ship.
Well, I don't doubt it with
that Muncie four speed.
Hmm!
How long to restore it?
A couple years.
RUSSELL: A couple years? Worth it.
You got nitrous?
Nah, nah, just a heavy foot.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
You know who's got any candy here?
- What do you mean, "candy?"
- You know what I mean.
Yeah.
You a fucking cop?
(LAUGHS)
Am I a fucking cop?
Do I look like a fucking cop?
Who's the old man in the truck?
Don't worry about him.
He ain't a cop, either.
- What you looking for, man?
- Whatever you got. You know...
Crank, 20/20's, blue bellies,
crystals or pure.
- It don't matter.
- Wow, he knows his shit.
Yeah, we got some buzzard dust,
some mm; up at the house.
All right.
We'll get you feelin' shitty,
my friend.
Good. All right, I'll follow you?
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Yo, it's Tiny.
- You wait right here, all right?
- All right.
All right.
Brought them boys out here
looking for some of the train.
MAN: Yo, if they got
their greenbacks, that's fine.
Come on up.
(DOG BARKING)
Who the fuck are you?
RUSSELL: I'm just passing through.
I ain't asked you where you were going.
I asked you who you were.
Well, I didn't ask who you were.
We just want to get high,
and our money's green.
Well, then you come
to the right place.
But I got to say, you got
some balls coming up in here,
not knowing nobody.
But if your money's green...
...then it's all good.
That's pure glass.
Fire it up.
Looks good to me.
How much?
Nah, fire that shit up.
It'll blow your balls off, brother.
I told you, I'm good. How much?
(THROATY GRUNT)
(SNIFFLES)
(GROANS)
RUSSELL: You don't know, um...
...Harlan DeGroat, do you?
Is that a joke?
Why would I joke about that?
'Cause this is his house.
He around?
I wouldn't know.
I ain't his babysitter.
All right.
(WHISPERS) Hey, Red.
Not now.
We'll come by later.
Yo!
You forgot this.
RED: Oh, shit.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Put your hands where
I can see 'em, gentlemen.
Russell Baze?
That's right.
Chief Barnes from
the North Braddock Police
alerted us early this evening
that you were up here.
You're lucky I got here when I did.
If the locals knew why you were here,
they'd zip you up and you'd
be leaving in a body bag.
Do I need to ask if you're
carrying concealed weapons?
No, sir.
- No, sir.
- All right.
Then, given that you're an ex-con,
likely carrying concealed weapons,
you have a choice.
Either I arrest you now or
I follow you to the state line.
With respect, officer,
my brother might be up here,
and I ain't leaving without him.
I'll only do Chief Barnes a favor once.
You return and I'll
arrest you on the spot.
There's nothing you can do
from inside a jail cell.
Am I making myself clear, gentlemen?
Yes, sir, you are.
All right. Then I'll follow you out.
That boy was always troubled.
Ever since he was a little kid.
You could see it in his eyes.
Especially after your mama died.
(BOYS SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
(DOORS SHUTTING,
ENGINES STARTING)
Hey, Russell.
Wesley.
I just heard
from the Jersey police.
They found your brother.
He's dead.
OK.
A hunter's dog dug him up.
(VOICE FADING SLOWLY) Sorry.
They just called me.
The coroner's gonna
examine his body.
(FAINT) I suspect that you'll
have him back by the weekend.
(NO AUDIO)
Place is really hard to locate.
The roads are all mostly trails.
- Let me go talk to him.
- LENA: No, no, no. I got it.
- LENA: It's OK.
- Yeah?
(FAUCET RUNNING,
UTENSILS AND DISHES CLINKING)
You hardly touched your food.
RUSSELL: I ate enough.
I appreciate you coming over.
- I wanted to.
- Mmm.
We wanted to.
I'm sorry about Rodney.
I'm really sorry.
He was put through
a lot, you know?
And so have you.
But please don't do anything.
OK?
You already tried.
You're lucky you
got out of there alive.
Let Wesley handle this.
Let him do his job.
He's a good man, Russell.
- You want me to take it?
- No, I got it.
OK.
(SCRAPING PLATE)
We may not have the...
...the fire and the flame...
...but we got something good.
You know?
Can we put this behind us?
Yeah.
- Thanks for dinner.
- Mm-hmm.
You ready?
Let's go.
(DOOR SHUTS)
(SIREN WAILING)
(BIRD SCREECHING, CAWING)
(BLOW DRYER WHIRRING)
(BIRD SQUAWKING,
DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
Police!
On the ground!
Harlan DeGroat! Police!
Get down on the ground!
Get down!
(GASPING)
(COUGHING)
(GRUNTS, EXHALES)
The guy was expecting us.
Ooh, yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
OK.
Every time, it's just...
(YELLING)
MAN: Forgive me my sins, O Lord.
Forgive me my sins.
The sins of my youth...
the sins of my age,
the sins of my soul...
...the sins of my body.
My idle sins...
...my serious voluntary sins...
...the sins I know, the sins
we have concealed for so long...
...which are now
hidden from my memory.
My Jesus, forget and forgive
what we have been.
Amen.
Hey! Hey, Baze!
Russell! Come back!
Russell!
What are you doing here, man?
You can't be back here.
Wesley told me not to
let anybody back here.
- Give it up, please.
- Dan, where's that ledger?
Huh?
DAN: You can't be here.
Where's that ledger, Dan?
Russell, don't do this.
Let him handle it.
- This it?
- Russell, don't.
- You can stay if you want.
- I don't want any part of it.
(CROWD CLAMORING IN DISTANCE)
(CLAMOR CONTINUES)
HARLAN: What?
Harlan DeGroat?
Who wants to know?
I've taken over
John Petty's accounts.
- Who's this?
- Listen to me.
I'm willing to settle his debt.
And we can keep this deal going.
Who the fuck is this?
It don't matter.
You come to Braddock...
...the money's yours.
How the fuck
did you get my number?
Who the fuck is this?
(SNIFFS)
(BRAKES SQUEAKING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(SECOND DOOR SHUTS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
Hey, we're closed.
Uh... (CLEARS THROAT)
Why don't you get your fat
fucking ass in the kitchen,
fix me up a salmon burger?
See what that bitch
has in the register.
What do you say, Dan?
(TRAIN RUMBLING PAST)
- You look fit.
- Well, thanks.
- Staying out of trouble?
- Yeah, trying.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
(WHISPERING) Yeah.
So, uh...
...I hear you might have
some money for me.
Who, me?
(CLEARS THROAT NERVOUSLY)
You, somebody.
No, not me. No.
Well, do you know where
Petty keeps his money?
Uh, no... Petty, you know, he...
...he keeps everybody at arm's length.
I just tend bar.
Well, you just tend bar
from all the way back here?
- Well, I'm just...
- That's a good trick, Dan.
(GRUNTING WITH EFFORT)
So let me get this straight.
You don't know where that money is?
I don't know,
honest to God, I don't.
I swear to God, I don't know.
- You swear to God?
- Yeah.
Well, if you're invoking
a deity over this,
I guess I'm mistaken.
- Yeah.
- Mmm.
HARLAN: A long way to drive, Dan.
Shoot
(BOTH GRUNT)
- I didn't come five hours...
- DAN: I don't know!
- ...to not get my fucking money!
- (DAN YELLS IN PAIN)
HARLAN: Show me where that safe is.
DAN: OK, OK!
OK, I'll do it.
OK, all right.
Get that fucker open right now.
Wait, I gotta remember
the combination.
- Julie, call 911.
- DAN: Wait a sec, I'm trying.
- I just need another number...
- HARLAN: Three.
- ...one more number, wait...
- Two.
DAN: Just give me a second
so I can remember the numbers!
- Time's up, Dan.
- DAN: Wait!
- HARLAN: Open it!
- Wait! One more number.
Oh, God, thank God.
HARLAN: It's empty.
You kidding me?
Where's my fucking money?
Motherfuckers!
(GUNFIRE)
- DAN: No!
- (GUNSHOT, BODY THUDS)
Dan! Oh, God, Dan.
(VAN ENGINE GRINDING)
(KIDS' PLAYFUL SHOUTS ECHOING)
DISPATCH:
Got a 216, shots fired.
No suspect information at this time.
(GRUNTS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (RUSSELL GAGGING)
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH COUGHING)
You know who I am?
(RUSSELL PANTING)
(YELLING, GROANING LOUDLY)
Get up.
Keep going.
(SHOUTS)
(RIFLE CLICKS)
(GRUNTS QUIETLY)
(GRUNTS WEAKLY)
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING WEAKLY)
I'm Rodney Baze's brother.
Yeah.
Tough kid.
(swans CHIRPING)
You hear those birds?
(GRUNTS)
Don't do it, Russell!
Russell!
Drop your weapon!
Drop it!
Walk away!
Drop it, Russell! Drop it!
Russ!
Just listen to me!
Listen to me, Russell!
Russell!
Let me make this right!
For God's sake.
© anoXmous
@ https://thepiratebay.se/user/anoXmous