He even took the gramophone on safari.
Three rifles, supplies for a month,
and Mozart.
He began our friendship with a gift.
And later, not long before Tsavo,
he gave me another.
An incredible gift.
A glimpse of the world
through God's eye.
And I thought,
"Yes, I see.
"This is the way
it was intended."
I've written about all the others,
not because I loved them less,
but because they were clearer, easier.
He was waiting for me there.
But I've gone ahead of my story.
He'd have hated that.
Denys loved to hear a story told well.
You see,
I had a farm in Africa at the
foot of the Ngong Hills.
But it began before that.
It really began in Denmark.
And there I knew two brothers.
One was my lover,
and one was my friend.
It's too cold for champagne.
It's too cold for anything but.
You said you'd be at Klampenborg.
I thought I'd come, but then I didn't.
Was it fun?
Tanne.
Tanne, come on.
It's not as though you loved him.
You'd like to be
a baroness, that's all.
He lied to me.
Of course.
Would you be in bed
with him otherwise?
My brother's only dull,
but not stupid.
Pretend it's Hans.
Where would you go?
Anywhere.
America. Ceylon.
I would even go to Australia.
Perhaps not Australia.
But I've got to be away from here.
I'll give you all I've got.
That should get you into town.
God, it was fun. Money.
You could marry me.
I have to marry a virgin.
I can't stand criticism.
For the money, I mean.
Probably.
Listen to me.
I've got no life at all.
They wouldn't teach me anything
useful, and now I've failed to marry.
You know the punishment for that.
"Miss Dinesen's at home."
And you've gone through
all your money.
You're off seducing the servant girls.
We're a pair, you and I.
I mean, at least we're friends.
We might be all right,
and if we weren't, at least
we'd have been somewhere.
You don't think
you're being too romantic?
Am I supposed to think you're serious?
I had a farm in Africa.
I had a farm in Africa at the
foot of the Ngong Hills.
I had a farm in Africa.
Good morning.
Have you had trouble?
Now and then.
Have you?
I'm traveling to Nairobi.
You caught the right train then.
Get away from there!
That's all my crystal, my Limoges.
They didn't know it was Limoges.
You plan to stay then?
I've come out to marry Baron Blixen.
Do you know him?
Bror? Yes.
We plan to start a dairy.
Are you quite famous?
They stopped the train for you.
It's rude not to here.
A dairy? Isn't it a bit soon for that?
Milk at the door?
Aren't you boarding?
I'm going on.
On? To where?
Mention the ivory to Berkeley Cole.
Bror knows him.
I'm Baroness Blixen!
Not yet.
Finch Hatton, Denys!
I am Farah Aden.
We can go now.
Where is Baron Blixen?
He is at Muthaiga.
Please come.
Where is Muthaiga?
Muthaiga is a club where British
go for drinking. Please.
Listen, on the train are my
crates with china and crystal.
Do you know china?
Yes. China, it can break.
Stay.
Excuse me, I'm looking
for Baron Blixen.
I wondered if you might tell me...
Memsahibs must not be here.
I'm simply looking for someone...
Where have you been?
Arranging things. How was the trip?
You can tell me later.
Would you like to change?
My luggage is still on the train.
Room "D."
Head of the stairs.
I haven't gotten a ring.
Do you care?
Did you think I wouldn't come?
I thought you wouldn't
want to spend the money.
You will love it here.
The servants are wonderful.
Shall we get a drink?
We've got almost one
hour before the wedding.
One hour?
Is this all right?
I wondered what color you'd choose.
It's ivory. God,
I've got this man's ivory.
Whose ivory?
I'm Sarah, Lady Belfield.
Shall I stand up for you?
Short or long, Blix?
Long, please.
Give me time to adjust to it.
Settle down, all.
By the authority of His Majesty's
Government vested in me,
I declare that the Baron Bror Von
Blixen, citizen of Sweden and...
What's your name, my dear?
Damn it, Henry, I told you her name.
Karen Christentze Dinesen.
Karen Christentze Dinesen, a female
subject of the King of Denmark,
are henceforth united man and wife.
God save this company,
God save the King.
God save the King!
Thank you for this.
"Did you hear about Shuttleworth?
" "No," I said.
"He's living up country," he
says, "in a tree with a baboon."
"Male or female?" I said to him.
"Female, of course," he says.
"There's nothing queer
about old Shuttleworth."
Where's your muddleheaded husband?
The Governor's at the punch bowl,
thank you, hoping to avoid you.
Would you like to meet the bride?
Or did you come just for the whiskey?
Not for the company, God knows.
Lord Delamere, may I
present Baroness Blixen.
Baroness Blixen, Lord
Delamere, such as he is.
Baroness.
A Swede, are you?
No, Danish, actually.
The little country next to Germany.
If it comes to war,
where will Denmark stand?
On its own, I hope.
We do have that history.
Is there something we can call you
that gets round this Baroness?
What do they call you?
D, if I'm lucky.
My stupid name's Felicity,
but I do like your dress.
Thank you.
It's not much of a hat.
It's meant to be stunning.
We die of sunstroke here.
At least I'm safe from the mosquitoes.
The big ones.
You nervous?
Should I be?
You know, wedding night and all that.
So they're both of them naked
and not a shrub in sight.
Have you met Vicky Gresham?
Hello, Baroness,
I'd curtsy but I'm drunk.
May I see you, please?
Excuse me.
If you want any friends, Tanne,
I'd make them here.
There is no one else.
I want to see my house.
You may want to change.
It's a two-hour ride.
Excuse me.
My God, these people drink.
I'm sorry, I was just...
It's all right.
I'm afraid you've caught me snooping.
It's not my room, it's Denys',
and Denys won't mind.
It's a thing about Denys,
he doesn't mind.
Are you Cole?
I brought the ivory
with me on the train.
Well, thank you.
Are you taking your quinine?
Oh, yes.
He has got lovely books.
Does he lend them?
We had a friend, Hopworth.
He got a book and didn't return it.
Denys was furious.
I said, "Denys, you wouldn't lose
a friend over a book, would you?"
And he said, "No!
"But he has, hasn't he?"
Did you come out through London?
From Rome actually.
I thought you might have a newspaper.
No, sorry.
Nothing in them anyway.
I had a friend who I used to
take to the dances at Oxford.
They were in June by the river.
She always wore a new silk dress.
I think you're wearing her perfume.
No, it's very nice,
but it's not the same.
We can go now.
This is Belknap.
He runs the farm.
Good evening, ma'am.
This is your cook.
Name is Esa.
And this is Juma. Houseboy.
Come, see your house.
When you leave me, I'm
going to marry Berkeley Cole.
A man in trade.
Is that what he does?
He is thick with the Somalis.
There's a crowd of them up on his land
who think he's some sort of prince.
He sells Finch Hatton's ivory.
Belknap is a cheery sort.
Had a place of his own.
Went belly up trying to grow flax.
Does he know cattle?
I didn't buy cattle.
We're going to grow coffee instead.
That's not what we planned.
You were in Denmark, I had to decide.
We made a decision.
We don't know anything about coffee.
You plant it, it grows.
My mother put her money
up to do a dairy.
She doesn't care whether it's cows
or coffee as long as it pays.
You must be with a herd
or things go wrong.
I didn't come to Africa
to sit with silly cows.
Just tell her we changed our minds.
Next time you change your mind,
you do it with your money.
They bought you a title.
They didn't buy me.
Fetch some wine
for my lover's brother.
I think you're tired.
Be careful.
Did I tell you
Hans came to say goodbye?
Where is Baron Blixen?
He's gone to hunt.
Did he say when he would be back?
He says he can come before the rain.
Is it going to rain today?
It can be many days before the rains.
In Ohio we put up scarecrows
to keep the birds away.
Here you hope there're enough
leopards to keep down the baboons.
'Course they'll take your dog, too.
That's Africa.
How much will we plant?
1, 000 acres, the Baron says.
How long will that take?
That depends on Kinanjui.
He's the chief of the Kikuyu.
Got a deal with him to get you help.
When will be our first harvest?
These are seedlings.
It'll be three, maybe four years.
Four years!
If they bear at all.
No one's ever tried coffee this high.
And what are we going to
live on for four years?
I'm working to get home.
Now, if you haven't got it,
it'd be good if you could
tell me right now.
We will plant 500.
Chief Kinanjui, I have heard
that you are a wise chief...
Not now, please.
And I look forward to our dealings.
Your Kikuyu are good workers.
I look forward to dealing with
them honestly, and fairly.
This chief has no British.
Tell him that I am Baroness Blixen.
This chief knows that.
Tell him what I said.
What did he say?
He says these Kikuyu can do this work.
Farah, what else did he...
Your leg is very sick.
You must come to the
house for medicine.
Does he understand me?
Yes.
If you don't come, the other
boys will say you are afraid.
I myself will think
only that you are foolish.
This boy must come to
my house for treatment.
See that he does.
What else did Kinanjui say?
He says coffee must
not grow this high.
Never mind.
He's a chief, but he's a Kikuyu.
If you put a dam here to stop the
water then I can make a pond here.
Do you know how to make a pond?
This water must go home to Mombasa.
It can go home after we make a pond.
This water lives at Mombasa.
Come, then.
I wouldn't run.
If you do, she'll think
you're something good to eat.
Do you have a gun?
She won't like the smell of you.
Shoot it.
She's had breakfast.
Please shoot her.
Let's give her a moment.
Oh, my God, shoot her!
Just how much closer did you
expect to let her come?
A bit. She wanted to see if you'd run.
That's how they decide.
A lot like people that way.
She almost had me for lunch.
It wasn't her fault.
She's a lion.
It wasn't mine.
Doesn't that outfit come with a rifle?
It's on my saddle.
Better keep it with you.
Your horse isn't much of a shot.
For Berkeley.
He's brought you presents.
We stopped by your
house and then came looking.
Good Lord, you are sweet.
You're on the road actually.
We're off to Magadi to shoot some ivory.
At least I have something
good to offer you.
Did you intend to tell
Berkeley what a fool I was?
She had a lion a bit interested.
A bit? A bit,
but not enough to bite.
It's all right to take a chance
as long as you're
the only one who'll pay.
Wouldn't you say so?
I'd say that it sounds more
like something you'd say.
Thank you.
Not at all.
Where's Blix?
Hunting.
Has he been out long?
Yes.
You'll need a good chat then.
Shall we stay for supper?
Blix will have jackets we can use.
Do I have anything to say in this?
Not really, but we'll hear you out.
Then I would like you to stay.
Good.
I don't know. Do you sing?
Never.
Can you tell a story then?
I happen to be very good at stories.
I believe that.
What's happened
to the cows? For the dairy?
We changed our minds.
We'll grow coffee instead.
A bit risky, this high.
So I've been told.
Didn't seem to bother you.
I think they just haven't tried.
Every time I turn my back,
it wants to go wild again.
It will go wild.
Your man...
Kanuthia.
He's not Kikuyu?
No.
Shall I see that he's given supper?
Don't do anything for him,
thank you, Baroness.
It's true of Somalis.
The only tribe that knows horses.
And they don't drink, charge interest,
or chase other men's wives.
Got to go to town for that.
Did you know that in all of literature
there is no poem celebrating the foot?
There's lips, there's eyes,
hands, face, hair, breasts,
legs, arms, even the knees, but not
one verse for the poor old foot.
Why do you think that is?
Priorities, I suppose.
Did you think you would make one?
The problem is, there's
nothing to rhyme it with.
Put.
It's not a noun.
Doesn't matter.
"Along he came and he did put
upon my farm his clumsy foot"
We should have a story now.
When I tell a story
to my nieces at home,
one of them always provides
the first sentence.
Anything?
Absolutely anything.
There was a wandering
Chinese named Cheng Huan
living in Limehouse,
and a girl named Shirley.
Who spoke perfect Chinese,
which she learned
from her missionary parents.
Cheng Huan lived alone
in a room on Formosa Street
above the Blue Lantern.
He sat at his window,
and in his poor listening heart
strange echoes
of his home and country...
They found them
there the next morning,
in their room above the Blue Lantern.
The dead child and the warlord,
with Cheng Huan's love gift
coiled about his neck.
Had you been to those places?
I have been a mental traveler.
Till now.
Yes.
Wasn't this England?
Excuse me, Denmark?
I like my things.
And when you traveled before,
in your mind,
did you carry so much luggage?
A mental traveler hasn't
the need to eat or sleep
or entertain.
You're right.
Anyway, aren't you pleased that I
brought my crystal and my china?
And your stories, yes.
The conquering heroes come
Sound the trumpets Beat the drums
But I want you to come often.
I'd like that very much.
And you must promise
me it will be soon.
I promise.
Bye.
Did you save my life?
No, the lioness did that.
She walked away.
So I am not indebted then?
But I am.
We pay our storytellers here.
It's lovely.
But my stories are free and
your present's much too dear.
Write them down sometime.
Take care, Finch Hatton.
You wouldn't rather call me Denys?
Baroness.
Goodbye.
What are you doing?
I want you to come home.
We never spoke about children.
Did you...
Do you?
Yes.
Is that all right?
These Kikuyu want to be sick now.
Good Lord!
Your leg has got worse.
You should go to hospital.
This leg may be foolish.
It may think not to go to hospital.
This leg will do as it pleases.
But if you will take it to hospital,
I will think that you are wise.
And such a wise man as this, I
would want to work in my house
for wages.
How much wages would come
to such a wise man as that?
More wages than come
from tending goats.
I will speak to this leg.
What about air raids?
Quiet!
One question at a time.
The war's in Europe.
Will it ever reach here?
German East is only 200 miles south.
General Von Lettow is there.
Let's not wait till he
joins us at the bar.
Would we engage them?
This is our war.
You don't have to be involved, but thanks.
I've got crops coming in.
How long is this thing gonna last?
We just have to
stay and go as we must.
They won't fight if we won't fight.
We could always arm the
Masai and point them south.
Do you want the job
of collecting rifles
from the Masai when this is over?
And our women and children?
Shall we bring them into town?
We will deal with that
problem as it arises.
Will they use native troops?
I'd assume so, but not Masai!
Berkeley, what about your Somalis?
They'd make very good scouts.
We can cover the area here to the border.
We can gather information
for when the regulars arrive.
What's it about?
Have you any idea?
Not really.
Then why do you want to get into it?
It's got nothing to do with us.
They've made agreements
we know nothing about.
Victoria and the Kaiser were
relatives, for God's sake.
They divided Africa between them.
Do you know why there's a border?
'Cause she had two
mountains and he had none.
So she gave him Kilimanjaro.
It's a silly argument
between two spoiled countries.
The sooner we do this,
the sooner it ends,
the sooner we pick up
where we left off.
It may end.
But we're not gonna
pick up where we left off.
You don't have to go!
You want to go!
We've got to live here.
They don't want you.
They don't know where we stand.
I'm not so fond of their empire
I'd have you shot for it.
More likely chewed on than shot.
The farm will take care of
itself, and you've got Belknap.
The farm will not take care of itself.
That's not the point.
I didn't expect to like you so much.
You're not going to go
falling in love, are you?
Not with someone who's always leaving.
If you need me, send a
runner to find Delamere.
That's where I'll be.
That's a fine kiss goodbye.
I'm better at hello.
It's an odd feeling, farewell.
There is some envy in it.
Men go off to be tested for courage.
But if we're tested
at all it's for patience,
for doing without,
perhaps for how well
we can endure loneliness.
But I had always known that.
It didn't require a war.
I said goodbye to Bror.
Denys left without a word,
which was quite proper.
Hello, the house!
I thought you might want some meat.
Is there any word?
Nothing new.
There's not much fighting.
Awful fever, though.
I've got time for tea, I should think.
Are you for the Germans?
Did they send you out to ask me this?
We had a row about it in town.
Because of my bad English.
And whose side were you on?
Yours.
They want to send me home to school.
Mother says I'm growing up wild.
I wanted to ask you about it.
Me?
You've been around and about.
Some day, I'd like to run
my own show the way you do.
Is that what I do?
You don't seem to need us much.
May I ask you something?
I don't know much about men.
I want them to like me, but I...
I want to be let alone, too.
I'm supposed to want
to be taken, aren't I?
I've got this book,
but how do you know when to
do what they want you to
and when not to?
I suppose you ought to call me Karen.
They need paraffin and tinned food.
Enough for 300 men.
He wants you to send
a white man with the wagon.
Is he all right?
I assume. Well enough
to send a message.
And where would my husband
like this wagon sent?
He's with Delamere on the
border near Lake Natron.
That's confidential, of course.
I would bear that in mind.
Sorry, I only meant
it wouldn't do for it to
be talk around Nairobi.
We have to move you into town.
We can't protect you here.
What do you mean, into town?
With the men gone, we're
worried about the natives.
We have orders.
Women and children into town.
That is internment, Lieutenant.
Women and children.
Is that one category or two?
You'll want time
to gather your things.
I'll send an escort
here for you Thursday.
And I am a captain.
I'm not paid to fight.
No.
Where is Lake Natron?
That's south.
Bush country.
It's no place for a white man.
We should have crossed
the Sand River today.
I may have got us lost.
God is great.
What the devil are you doing here?
I'm on my way to Delamere.
Ridiculous.
We don't send women to war.
Well, I'm going.
We haven't time for this.
You don't know where you are.
I do now.
And you'll just get lost again.
I'm going on.
Talk to her, will you?
No.
She could be hurt or worse.
I imagine she knows that.
Right, I tried.
Here.
Find a spot on the horizon
each morning and steer by it.
South-southwest.
About three days.
I see.
And don't worry about us,
we'll be all right.
What is it?
Masai.
Ismail, my rifle, where's my rifle?
Get away!
Msabu's bleeding.
She does not have this ox.
This lion is hungry.
He does not have this ox.
This wagon is heavy.
It doesn't have this ox.
God is happy.
He plays with us.
Tell Blix his wife's here.
Hello, Karen.
Hello, D. Hello, Bror.
I've brought you some things.
You've changed your hair.
You needed supplies...
Send someone, I said.
You were lucky to get through.
It was really foolish.
But I did get through.
And it was fun.
When are you coming home?
Not just yet.
You're not going to help at
all with the farm, are you?
No.
I could force you.
I could cut you off.
I'll just hunt professionally.
I might do it anyway.
It's not the way
we thought it would be,
is it?
But I like it that
you're honest with me.
I like you, too.
Very much.
I had a compass from Denys.
"To steer by," he said.
But later it came to me
that we navigated differently.
Perhaps he knew, as I did not,
that the Earth was made round
so that we would not see
too far down the road.
You've got syphilis.
That's not possible.
Your husband is not ill?
No.
Not the last time I saw him.
That was three months ago.
He's on the border with Delamere.
He would have come home.
These cases vary.
He may have just a touch.
But you are very ill.
Is he the only possibility?
Yes.
You'll have to go home
to deal with it, you know?
The treatment's difficult, but they
have a thing called Salvarsan.
Arsenic.
And if I'm not cured then I
will be insane, won't I?
You ought to go soon.
I'll have to see your husband.
I will send for him.
These ought to help with the
fever till you get home.
And what are my chances?
About even, I'm afraid.
It's not what I thought
would happen to me now.
Muthaiga?
What?
Your letters.
Excuse me.
I heard you had made it.
I'd have paid anything to see their faces.
Hello.
Would you join us for a drink?
I can't. How is it that you are home?
I brought Berkeley back.
Has he been wounded?
No, fever.
More than usual,
but he'll be all right
as long as the gin holds out.
And you?
How is it with the fighting?
We're taking a beating.
It's likely to last for a while.
I still have your compass.
Why don't you keep it?
You've earned it.
Besides, I don't always want to
know where I'm going anyway.
Please don't let me keep you.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Take good care.
We're behind a story or two.
Yes. When I get back.
Back? From where?
When you get back, I meant.
I thought it was malaria.
It wasn't.
And you may be all right,
but you have to be seen.
And the others, whoever they
are, I hope they've got it.
It's my fault, no one else's.
I want to go with you.
Someone has to stay here
and run things,
and the factory must be finished.
Can you do that?
That's little enough.
I'm sorry.
Where's memsahib?
She can come soon enough.
Later that day, I left for Mombasa
and the voyage home to Denmark.
It was a longer journey this time.
The war went on.
I fought my own war.
Arsenic was my ally
against an enemy I never saw.
I stayed in the room where I was born
in Rungstedlund
and tried to remember
the colors of Africa.
There was only the medicine
and walks with my mother along
a deserted stretch of beach
and this room in my mother's house.
Denmark had become a stranger to me
and I to her.
But my mother's house,
I came to know again.
And knew I would come
back to it, sick or well,
sane or mad, someday.
And so I did,
after Tsavo.
Almost everyone's got them now.
I am cooking now.
I have heard about this.
Are you well?
I am well enough.
Then I am well enough also.
What will you do?
I have been thinking I'll hunt.
Safari sort of thing.
They say it'll be quite a
business once the war is over.
You wouldn't want to teach?
I would like these Kikuyu
to have a school.
There will be a fight about that.
Are you all well?
They say I'm cured.
I won't have children.
Have you thought about us?
Of course.
Belknap says the coffee will
flower after the next rains.
If it does, you'll have to start
thinking about hiring for the harvest
and how you'll get to market.
Where would Berkeley be?
He must be here.
Who won the match?
Have you got a story for me?
Finch Hatton.
I've been demoted.
I was Denys last time.
Would you care for some champagne?
They said you went home for a while.
Yes.
Where's Berkeley?
It's good to see you.
He's still down with fever. He'll be all right.
Who are all these people?
Bror says we'll be a colony soon.
They want it settled now.
They've got a lottery.
"Buy a ticket, win a farm in Africa."
Did you really think it
would stay the way it was?
I thought it might.
Where is Kanuthia?
He's dead.
How are you?
Would you join us for a drink?
It's time to find a pillow.
Another night then?
Have a good Christmas.
Christmas?
So it is.
This Chief says
children higher than this
must not learn to read.
Tell him that all the
children must go to school.
No, this is a Chief.
You are not a Chief.
That's absurd.
It is not good for tall people
to know more than this Chief.
When these children are tall,
then this Chief can be dead.
Bror, yes. But Denys hired out
to tourists, I can't imagine.
He's got no other trade
and we've got no choice.
The government's
put a stop to the ivory.
What will you do then?
I'll concentrate on the farm.
Hello, the house!
How is it you're home?
I'm out. Look. I didn't learn a
thing, but I'm wonderfully clean.
I'll come and see you.
You save me a dance, Berkeley.
What's this nonsense
I hear about a school?
I've taken on a young missionary.
He's promised me to do the alphabet
first, and save God for later.
Wogs can't even count their goats.
It's none of your
bloody business anyway!
Who the devil are you?
I wonder if you'd dance with me?
I think you are about to apologize.
You do stir things up.
When they said they'd like to read,
how did they put that exactly?
Do they know they'd like Dickens?
You don't think they
should learn to read?
I think you might have asked them.
Did you ask to learn
when you were a child?
How can stories possibly harm them?
They have their own stories,
just not in writing.
Why would you rather
keep them ignorant?
They're not ignorant.
I just don't think they should be
turned into little Englishmen.
You do like to change
things, don't you?
For the better, I hope.
I want my Kikuyu to learn to read.
My Kikuyu.
My Limoges. My farm.
It's an awful lot to own, isn't it?
I've paid a price for all I own.
What is it exactly that's yours?
We're not owners here,
we're just passing through.
Is life really so damn simple for you?
Perhaps I ask less of it than you do.
I don't believe that at all.
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year.
And for you, too.
Someone has left her
underclothes in the back.
I want you to take a place in town.
Are you sure?
Eats.
He eats.
Elephant.
Give me work.
We've got peace,
where is the prosperity?
Why should the prices fall now
just because they're
not killing anybody?
Tea's down just as bad.
Do they always have to whip them so?
They finally made a machine
that's really useful. Listen.
It's for you.
I can't accept it.
Why not?
Bror's moved to town.
That's a private matter, I imagine.
Did you think you would
spend the night?
Can't, thanks.
I have to go down to the Mara.
I've taken up safari work
and I've gotta find a camp.
No.
There's country there you ought to see.
It won't last long now.
I would be wasting your time.
Why don't you get your things?
If you like me at all,
don't ask me to do this.
What's your word?
Shoo?
Is that it? Shoo?
That's a fine word you've got there.
Crank it again, please.
Almost. Crank it again.
Once more.
Well done. We're off.
I don't know
the scientific basis for it,
but I know you can see further
in the African night
than any other place.
And the stars are brighter.
It's about the tents.
When I'm out with Kanuthia...
Used to be, we didn't use them.
I remember him.
There was something...
Masai.
He was half Masai, that's
what you remember about him.
They're like nobody else.
We think we'll tame them,
but we won't.
If you put them in prison, they die.
Why?
Because they live now.
They don't think about the future.
They can't grasp the idea that
they'll be let out one day.
They think it's permanent,
so they die.
They're the only ones here
that don't care about us,
and that is what will finish them.
What did the two of you
ever find to talk about?
Nothing.
So you knew I would come.
It's an early day tomorrow.
Why don't you get some sleep?
What happens tomorrow?
I have no idea.
Good night.
You would think they would run off.
You didn't.
Think of that.
Never a man-made sound, and then Mozart.
Have you clients already?
In a week. A man from
Belgium and his daughters.
His letter said, "We'd
like three of everything."
It'll be an interesting trip.
I'll be gone a month,
or an hour and a half.
Why are you doing this?
I don't know how to sow.
Do you know what they're
made of? Cloth.
Where will he land?
Trick is not to.
It must feel amazing.
It's how I imagined America to be.
Have you been to America?
No, but my father was there,
and he always told me stories about
it when I was a little girl.
Are you still close?
He died. He killed himself
when I was 10 years old.
I can fix that, I think.
"Laugh'd loud and long,
and all the while
"His eyes went to and fro
"quoth he, 'full plain I see
"'The Devil knows how to row'
"Farewell, farewell!"
You're skipping verses.
I leave out the dull parts.
"Farewell, farewell!
But this I tell To thee, thou Wedding-Guest!"
Lay your head back.
"He prayeth well, who loveth well
"Both man and bird and beast"
That's better.
Will it be so different,
hunting for hire?
Not for the animals.
Well, maybe for the animals.
Do you really prefer them to people?
Sometimes.
They don't do anything
half-heartedly.
Everything's for the first time.
Hunting, working, mating.
It's only man that does it badly.
It's only man that tires
of going through it.
Who says, "See here.
I know how you feel about me
"and you know how I feel about you.
"We understand each other, so let's
lie down and get on with it."
Why am I here?
Because I wanted you to see all this.
I wanted to show it to you.
I thought you'd understand it.
Do you think much about death?
I think about getting old.
It'd be like living with a
cranky demanding old bastard.
You are a cranky
demanding old bastard.
I had syphilis.
That's why I went home.
I know.
I never seem to get anything.
German measles once.
They say I'll have a normal life now.
But no children.
So the school.
The farm, that's what I am now.
No.
We'll need meat for the camp tomorrow.
I'll wake you at dawn.
Good night.
We might scare up a gazelle or two.
But we'll be going through
buffalo country again.
They get cocky when you're on foot.
Supper. Good size, but...
Lion.
Careful, the wind's behind us.
Back up. Slowly.
If there's a charge, drop
flat, and let me do it.
Drop!
Reload now!
Dinner in a while?
I'm glad you came.
To rose-lipt maidens.
There was a very
young girl from Denmark
who took passage on a
steamer bound for Suez.
There was a storm
off Morocco
and she was washed
ashore onto a beach.
Onto a white beach.
Onto a beach so white...
I'd like to do that.
Will that hurt?
If you say anything now,
I'll believe it.
I need to know
how to think about this.
Why?
Clear soup, the new lettuce,
chicken, just the breast.
I trust this meets with your approval.
Who is coming?
Bwana Cole is coming.
I will think on Bwana Cole.
I've got myself in real trouble now.
Now you think they should vote?
No, worse.
Denys?
Get Kamante.
He is out of hand entirely.
Does this look like a chicken?
Here is not a chicken, here is a fish.
Go away.
What do you think?
Well, I think it's
quite good, isn't it?
Be careful.
When the old mapmakers
got to the edge of the world,
they used to write, "'Beyond
this place, there be dragons."
Is that where I am?
He likes to give presents,
but not at Christmas.
He hasn't even said
when he's coming again.
If he's coming again.
Would you divorce?
Then I would have no one.
Men who missed moose in
Alaska, grizzly in America,
tigers in India, they're all
at sea now bound for here.
Berkeley is going to farm.
You could do that.
No, thank you.
You ought to look in on him though.
He didn't look all that well.
Can you stay?
For a day or so.
Is that all right?
No.
You don't need two guns on safari.
Then do the town work.
Meet the clients, do outfitting.
There's the mail.
Lots of mail.
I don't know if I'd be right for that.
You've gotta do something.
I don't actually.
My water's gone black.
We've gotta get you to a hospital,
and get you some proper care.
I'm being cared for properly.
It's some years now.
She's fond of me, I think.
Why didn't you tell me?
I suppose I thought...
I didn't know you well enough.
There's money left
in the trading account.
I'd like my share to go to Mariammo.
Berkeley, listen.
George Martin had blackwater fever
and that was five years now.
You might take along that
twelve-bore you're so fond of.
The trigger seems a bit...
And the Rigby, get Karen to try the Rigby.
It's a nice size gun for her.
Would you like me to take you home?
I am home, I suppose.
"F."
"G."
"G" for girl.
Are you packed?
Yes.
How was town?
Crowded.
I've been thinking.
With all the safari work I have
little use for the room at the club.
I don't know that
I'd be any good at this,
but how would it be if I
kept a few things with you?
You would come and go from my house?
If that's all right.
When the gods want to punish
you they answer your prayers.
Berkeley's dying.
What?
Blackwater fever.
Oh, my God.
I'll go to him.
He wouldn't want you there.
Why?
There's a woman there.
She's Somali.
She's been with him for some time.
You never told me this.
I didn't know.
"...with each one of us
now and forevermore." Amen.
Strange that Denys isn't here.
I think he is off with Berkeley.
In the days and hours
that Denys was at home,
we spoke of nothing ordinary.
Not of my troubles with the farm,
my notes due and my failing crop,
or of his with his work,
what he knew was happening to Africa.
Or of anything at all
that was small and real.
We lived disconnected
and apart from things.
I had been making up stories
while he was away.
In the evenings,
he made himself comfortable,
spreading cushions like a
couch in front of the fire,
and with me sitting cross-legged
like Scherazade herself,
he would listen
clear-eyed to a long tale,
from when it began until it ended.
Where did you get it?
Mombasa.
Get in.
When did you learn to fly?
Yesterday.
Don't move.
I want to move.
Hello, Denys.
May I see you?
I'm broke, too, you know?
I wouldn't ask,
but tips were a bit light.
Are you all right?
If I get a decent crop.
I could shoot him.
I've got this
terrible urge to kiss you.
He's smarter than I am.
It may go well.
Good luck.
You might have asked.
I did.
She said yes.
If I get eaten up sometime
bury me here, will you?
Whatever's left.
Just there at the crest of the hill.
When are you leaving?
Tomorrow.
Doesn't it matter to you
that I'm another man's wife?
What matters to me is
that you tried so hard.
What time tomorrow?
Goodbye again.
How many acres under cultivation?
Five hundred.
The rest of it's wild?
The Kikuyu live there.
Why don't you move them off?
Because they live there.
We'll take it over should you default.
We've got another year.
God is great.
He's charging 3%.
This Chief says, "Tall children
can come to school now."
Tell Chief Kinanjui that
reading is a valuable thing.
His children will remember him well.
This Chief says,
"British can read and what
good has it done them?"
Miss Felicity's Spurway.
Clear round.
She's quite something, that Felicity.
Yes, indeed.
The next competitor, Mr.
John Sutton on Castano.
How are you?
Getting old, I think.
Not you.
How is the hunting?
I'll make a living.
Where's Denys?
Uganda. Some potentate.
I thought you might be
wanting a divorce.
Has she got money?
Of course she's got money.
Is this important, Bror?
I suppose.
I'll have to accuse you of something,
or did you think you would
have it the other way around?
Fire away, whatever.
I have surely done it.
Thank you.
How do you manage it?
To keep us friends?
We started that way.
I'll be happy for you, if I can.
I remember that quite well.
When you go away on safari,
are you ever with someone else?
I'd be with you if I
wanted to be with anyone.
Do you ever get lonely?
Sometimes.
Do you ever wonder if I am lonely?
No, I don't.
Do you think about me at all?
Often.
But not enough to come back.
I do come back, all the time.
What is it?
Nothing.
Bror has asked me for a divorce.
He's found someone
that he wants to marry.
I just thought
we might do that some day.
Divorce?
How would a wedding change things?
I would have someone of my own.
You wouldn't.
What's wrong with marriage anyway?
Have you ever seen one you admire?
Yes, I have. Many.
Belfields, for one.
He sent her home
for the rains in 1910.
Didn't tell her
they were over until 1913.
It's not a joke. People marry.
It's not revolutionary.
Some animals mate for life.
Geese.
You use the animals
for your own argument.
You won't let me use them for mine.
I'd mate for life.
One day at a time.
I'd just like someone to
ask me once, that's all.
Promise me you'll do that
if I promise to say no?
Just trust you?
When you go away,
you don't always go on safari, do you?
No.
You just want to be away.
It's not meant to hurt you.
It does.
I'm with you because I
choose to be with you.
I don't want to live someone
else's idea of how to live.
Don't ask me to do that.
I don't want to find out one day
that I'm at the end
of someone else's life.
I'm willing to pay for mine.
To be lonely sometimes,
to die alone if I have to.
I think that's fair.
Not quite. You want me
to pay for it as well.
You have a choice, and you're not
willing to do the same for me.
I won't be closer to you,
and I won't love you more
because of a piece of paper.
See if you can shore it up.
Let it go.
This water lives in Mombasa anyway.
I flew as far as Narok.
You could see all the ruts
where the lorries had been.
The Serengeti was still good.
It would take a week
just getting there.
And Samburu's still good.
Where's Belknap?
I haven't seen him.
He must be in America by now.
I let him go.
I had to.
But you don't want to hear
about the farm, do you?
Have you got any buttons?
What are you doing?
Mending your shirts.
Don't do that.
You don't have to do that.
Maybe I'll try Samburu
day after tomorrow.
You just got back.
Felicity asked to come along,
and I almost said no because I
thought you wouldn't like it.
There's no reason for her not to come.
Yes, there is.
I wouldn't like it.
You want her along?
I want things that
don't matter not to.
Tell her no, do it for me.
Then what else would it be?
Why is your freedom
more important than mine?
It isn't. And I've never
interfered with your freedom.
I'm not allowed to need
you or rely on you
or expect anything from you!
I'm free to leave!
But I do need you.
You don't need me.
If I die will you die?
You confuse need with want.
You always have.
In your world, there
would be no love at all.
Or the best kind.
The one we wouldn't have to prove!
You'd live on the moon then.
Because I won't do it your way?
Are we assuming there is
one proper way to do this?
Do you think I care about Felicity?
Do you think I'll be
involved with her?
No.
Then there's no reason
for this, is there?
If she's not important
why won't you give it up?
I have learned a thing
that you haven't.
There are some things worth having,
but they come at a price,
and I want to be one of them.
I won't allow it.
You have no idea the effect
that language has on me.
I used to think there was
nothing you really wanted,
but that's not it, is it?
You want to have it all.
I'm going to Samburu
and she can come or not.
Then you'll be living elsewhere.
All right.
Is there a prince in there?
I think that you had better get up.
You had better get up.
I think that God is coming.
All gone.
How did it start?
I think God had a hand in it.
He gave me my best crop ever
and then he remembered.
Insurance?
That's for pessimists.
Where's Denys?
Who knows?
It doesn't matter.
The Baroness is broke.
It's over.
I've got to find some land
before I go for my Kikuyu.
You have trouble enough.
Just a chunk somewhere so
they can stay all together.
We're just out of coffee,
but I can give you tea.
There is no arable land that
size outside the reserve.
And if there were, we'd
not put natives on it.
Since it's theirs.
It belongs to the Crown.
What you want is quite impossible.
It always is.
Who must I see next?
You've run through us all, I'm afraid.
We have a new governor, haven't we?
Sir Joseph.
He hasn't arrived yet.
But will soon, I'm told.
You do still ask me to things.
Captain Jacques Llewllyn.
Your servant, sir.
The Honorable Hugh
Chomondeley, Lord Delamere.
Your servant, sir.
Lady Delamere.
Commissioner.
Baroness.
The Baroness Von Blixen.
I'm sorry to know that
Kenya will be losing you.
You have heard of my trouble then?
Yes, I regret it.
Do you know of my problem now?
This land you want from us...
Will you help me?
That's quite difficult.
Get up, Baroness, please.
Kenya is a hard country for women.
So there is a chivalry here of a sort.
You are a powerful man and
I've no one else to turn to.
Let's discuss this in the proper way.
You mustn't be embarrassed.
I've lost everything.
It costs me very little to beg you.
Wait.
Give her a moment, please?
This land was theirs.
We took it and now
they've nowhere else to go.
I'll look into it.
We'll do the best we can.
May I have your word?
You have mine.
Thank you.
I hope you will be
happy here. I was.
I'm sorry I won't know you.
I didn't hear it
until I got to the border.
It seems I'll do almost
anything to get your attention.
I've nearly got you packed.
My poor family.
I've got them near bankrupt, now I
have to ask them for more money.
Let me help you.
You would keep me then?
I want to be worth something now.
What will you do?
After my rummage sale, leave.
Friday for Mombasa,
and then the boat to Denmark.
Thank you, Denys.
You must have them ready
to leave before the rains.
It is good land, enough for all,
but they must not fight about it
or be any trouble to the
authorities, do you understand?
Or they will lose it.
Yes.
You must make them understand
that I will not be here
to speak for them.
This land is far?
By Dagoretti.
Not too far.
How can it be now?
With me and yourself?
You will have some money.
Enough, I think.
I do not speak of money.
Do you remember how it was on safari?
In the afternoons I would send
you ahead to look for a camp?
And you would wait for me.
And you can see the fire
and come to this place.
Yes.
It will be like that.
Only this time I will go
ahead and wait for you.
It is far where you are going?
Yes.
You must make this fire very big,
so I can find you.
Take that out to the lawn.
Have you had dinner?
Yes.
I've packed your things.
I thought I would
send them on to the club.
Is that all right?
This wasn't a very good idea.
I think we should have had
it this way all the time.
I don't know.
I was beginning to like your things.
And I was beginning to
like living without them.
You've ruined it for me, you know?
Ruined what?
Being alone.
Have I?
I'd like to come with you to Mombasa.
Can I fly you there?
Aren't you going away again?
I have some things to do
tomorrow at Tsavo,
but I'll be back on Friday.
Will that be all right?
Of course.
I've got this little thing that
I've learned to do lately.
When it gets so bad and I think
I can't go on,
I try to make it worse.
I make myself think about
our camp on the river.
And Berkeley.
And the first time
that you took me flying.
How good it all was.
And when I'm certain
that I can't stand it,
I go one moment more,
and then I know I can bear anything.
Would you like to help me?
Yes.
Come dance with me then.
You were right, you know.
The farm never did belong to me.
I may have been wrong.
I had a farm in Africa.
Friday?
Yes.
Hello, Bror.
Would you like a drink?
Please.
Denys has been killed.
His plane crashed at Tsavo.
There was a fire.
Can I take you into town?
Why did they send you?
I thought I should.
My God, you're brave.
"The sun shall not smite
thee by day, nor the moon at night.
"The Lord shall
preserve thee from all evil.
"He shall preserve thy soul.
"The Lord shall preserve thy
going out and thy coming in.
"From this time forth
and even forevermore."
Amen.
"The time you won your town the race
"We chaired you
through the market-place
"Man and boy stood cheering by
"And home we brought
you shoulder-high
"Smart lad, to slip betimes away
"From fields where glory does not stay
"And early though the laurel grows
"It withers quicker than a rose.
"Now you will not swell the rout
"Of lads that wore their honors out
"Runners whom renown outran
"And the name died before the man
"And round that
early-laurelled head
"Will flock to gaze
the strengthless dead
"And find unwithered on its curls
"A garland
"briefer than a girl's"
Now take back the soul
of Denys George Finch Hatton,
whom You have shared with us.
He brought us joy
and we loved him well.
He was not ours.
He was not mine.
If I know a song of Africa,
of the giraffe
and the African new moon
lying on her back,
of the ploughs in the fields
and the sweaty faces
of the coffee pickers,
does Africa know a song of me?
Will the air over the plain quiver
with a color that I have had on?
Or will the children invent
a game in which my name is?
Or the full moon throw a shadow
over the gravel of the drive
that was like me?
Or will the eagles of the
Ngong Hills look out for me?
You cannot come where I'm going.
There is no cooking
where you are going?
You would not like it there.
You must trust me about this.
Letters you can send on
to this address in Denmark.
When you sell the car,
if you would send the check
to Hunter & Company,
and anything else you don't
know what to do with.
Yes, ma'am.
I've been sent to ask if
we may stand you a drink.
Who is "we"?
The members actually.
All right.
Whiskey, please.
Two whiskeys, please.
Rose-lipt maidens,
lightfoot lads.
Hear, hear!
Thank you.
This is very dear to me.
It has helped me to find my way.
Thank you, msabu.
I want to hear you say my name.
You are Karen.
The mail has come today,
and a friend writes this to me,
"The Masai have reported to the
district commissioner at Ngong
"that many times at sunrise and sunset
"they have seen lions
on Finch Hatton's grave.
"A lion and a lioness have come there
"and stood, or lain
on the grave for a long time.
"After you went away,
"the ground around the grave was
leveled out into a sort of terrace.
"I suppose that the level place
"makes a good site for the lions.
"From there they have a view
over the plain,
"and the cattle
and game on it."
Denys will like that.
I must remember to tell him.