Tokuma Shoten, Nippon Television Network,
Dentsu and Studio Ghibli present
In ancient times the land lay covered in forest.
Here dwelt the spirits of nature from time immemorial.
PRINCESS MONONOKE
Yakul!
Ashitaka!
Oracle says to get back to the village.
The Old Man, too.
- Something's wrong.
- The birds are gone.
The animals too.
I'll go to him. You'd better go now.
Something's coming.
- What is it?
- Don't know. It's not human.
Oracle summoned everyone back to the village.
There!
A demon god!
Yakul, run!
It'll attack the village!
Ashitaka!
Don't touch it!
Its curse will be on you!
Yakul!
Quiet your rage, I beg you!
O forest god who cannot be
without name, why do you rampage so?
- A monster!
- Run!
Stop! Leave our village in peace!
Stop! Still your rage!
Get up!
- It's down!
- Ashitaka!
Bring Oracle!
Stoke the fire!
Ashitaka.
Don't touch it.
It's no ordinary wound.
He's hurt! Where's Oracle?
All of you, stay back!
Oracle!
Pour this water on it, slowly.
O raging god unknown to us...
...I bow before you.
Where you have fallen, we will
raise a mound and perform rites.
Bear us no hate. Be at peace.
Hear me, loathsome humans!
You shall know my agony and my hatred.
This is very, very bad.
The boar-spirit came from far to the west.
A poison within him goaded him on, rotting his flesh...
...drawing evil as he ran,
making a demon of him.
Prince Ashitaka...
show us your right arm.
Oracle!
Ashitaka, are you ready to face your destiny?
Yes. I was resolved
when I let my arrow fly.
The poison will seep into your bones and you will die.
Can nothing be done?!
He fought for the women and the village!
To simply wait for death...
We cannot change our fate.
But we can rise to meet it.
Look.
This was deep in the boar's body.
His suffering was terrible.
The iron shattered his bones and tore his entrails.
What else could have made him that way?
Something sinister waits in the lands to the west.
If you journey there and
search for evil with eyes unclouded...
you might find a way to lift the curse.
More than 500 years have passed...
since the Emperor drove us into this land.
Now we hear how his power fades...
and the fangs of his Shoguns are broken.
But the blood of our tribe likewise grows thin.
And now, bitter fate...
the youth who was one day to lead us
must journey far to the west.
The Law forbids us
to watch you go. Farewell.
- Ashitaka.
- Kaya, you can't be here.
I don't care.
Remember me with this.
Your jewel dagger.
It will protect you.
You'll always be in my heart.
Always, without fail.
And you in mine, Kaya.
Fighting?
Head them off!
There's one, get him!
His head is mine!
Stop!
My arm!
Don't let him get away.
Stay back. Let me pass!
A demon!
The mark is getting darker.
This gruel tastes like hot water.
There he is!
Is this enough?
This isn't money.
Give me back my rice!
Here, let me take a look.
Woman, this is pure gold!
If it's coins you want, I'll pay you.
Give me this.
Listen, is there
a money-changer here?
No?
I'm a simple priest, but I'd say
this is worth three sacks of rice.
Hey, wait!
That's mine, give it back!
Wait, don't be in such a hurry.
No need to thank me.
It is I who should thank you.
I saw how you dealt with those samurai.
You fight like one possessed.
You see them too?
Keep your gold hidden.
Hearts have grown hard throughout the land.
They'll rob you in your sleep.
Shall we run?
So the boar became a demon...
I followed its tracks, but lost them in the village.
I'm not surprised.
Look around you.
This used to be a fine village.
There was a flood, maybe,
or a landslide. I'm sure many died.
The land teems with bitter ghosts...
...dead from war, sick or starved
and fallen where they stood.
A curse, you say? This world is a curse.
Ah, this is good!
I shouldn't have gotten into
that fight. I killed two men.
You helped me escape.
Give me your bowl.
You need food.
Everyone dies.
Some now, some later.
Hmm, an elegant bowl.
You remind me of the Emishi of old.
A brave people far to the east...
who used stone arrowheads and rode red elk.
The trick is to avoid the jaws of death.
Or so my master used to say.
Eat, my boy. It's your rice.
Look at this.
What is it?
It was in the body of the giant boar.
This is what killed him.
Far to the west, deep in the mountains...
is a forest where none may tread.
- The forest of the Deer God.
- The Deer God?
They say the beasts there are giants, as in ages past.
I knew he'd go...
It's not far now.
Stay on your guard.
They're coming.
The wolves!
Calm the oxen. Don't rush.
Form ranks.
Keep your powder dry!
Wait until they're close.
Number One, fire!
Number Two, fire!
That was too easy.
Those were just the pups.
Where's the mother?
It's Moro.
Come on, Moro!
Got her!
She's immortal.
She won't die from that.
She did some real damage.
Let's get going.
What about those who fell?
Form ranks and move out.
He's breathing.
Hang on!
My name is Ashitaka!
I come from the east.
Are you ancient gods from the forest of the Deer God?
Leave!
A kodama? Are they here, too?
Don't move. You're hurt.
They won't harm you.
They're a sign the woods are healthy.
They'll bring the Deer God.
The Deer God? The giant wolf?
No, far bigger. The mother of all beasts.
It's gone!
Yakul's not afraid.
There's no danger here.
Please let us pass through your woods.
Let's go back. Please!
There's a trail across the river.
We'll never get through these woods.
The current's too strong to cross.
If we don't get help soon, this man will die.
Are you guiding us or getting us lost?
Sir, these sprites aren't helping us.
There are more of them!
What a magnificent tree.
Is she your mother?
That girl and the wolves...
so this is where they live...
We're getting in deeper, sir.
This way leads into the other world.
Yes, let's take a rest.
Footprints.
Three toes... still fresh.
What's wrong, sir?
Are you all right?
You're awfully pale.
I told you!
Did you see something?
No, forget it.
Hang on a little longer.
I'm sorry.
It's gone.
What is this? I feel much stronger.
Hey! It doesn't hurt.
I'm cured! No, it's broken.
Sir, you're a genius.
We're back at the ironworks!
- It's a castle.
- Lady Eboshi's ironworks.
They melt sand into iron.
Hey!
- Someone's coming from the woods!
- A monster?
It's me, Koroku the ox-driver!
It's true, he's crossing the lake!
What's all this noise?
Be quiet when I'm writing.
Koroku's back from the dead!
What?
You're not a ghost.
- Where are the others?
- There were two more.
Only we were saved.
The guards never get killed.
Step aside.
Who's the man in the hood, sir?
An outsider.
Riflemen, listen! This gentleman
carried us all the way here.
Show some gratitude.
Ouch! Don't grab me there.
You! Wait there!
First, I thank you for helping our men.
But something bothers me.
You got here in less than half the time we did...
...through the Deer God's forest,
carrying two...
Koroku! You're alive!
Toki!
You fool! How can you drive
oxen with that broken leg?
But...
Scaring me half to death!
The wolves should've eaten you.
Then I could find a better man.
Don't be so hard on me, Toki.
Toki, take your lovers' quarrel elsewhere.
And you, leaving them to die!
Some guard you are.
You don't lift a finger around here.
When there's trouble, do something!
It couldn't be helped...
Thank you. My husband's an idiot,
but I'm glad he's safe.
Good. I was afraid maybe
I'd done something wrong.
You seem very handsome.
Show us your face.
Gonza.
I would like to thank the traveler.
Bring him to me later.
Koroku.
It's good you're back. I apologize.
Don't say that, Lady Eboshi.
He'll just take advantage of you.
Forgive me, Toki.
I shouldn't have let it happen.
My lady, if you hadn't been there...
they'd all be cavorting inside the wolves by now.
Traveler, please stop and rest.
Hey! You are handsome!
We had to fight off Moro to bring this rice, you know.
Dish it out!
Where?
Is that him?
Toki was right!
- He is handsome!
- A bit young.
That never stopped you before.
Quiet out there. We lost two men.
There are plenty of handsome men here.
Cowherds!
Come to our place, traveler!
Forget this stinking barn.
Watch your mouth! We risked our lives
for the rice you're eating.
Who made the iron that bought the rice?
We work those bellows all night long.
I'd like to see where you work, if you don't mind.
Really?
We'll have to work in makeup.
Even rouge!
Don't forget, we'll be waiting.
Don't mind them, sir.
Lady Eboshi spoils them.
A good village has happy women.
But women working the bellows in an ironworks?
Their presence defiles the iron.
When she finds girls sold as slaves,
Eboshi buys their freedom.
She's kind, that's all.
There's rice on your face, old man.
But she's not afraid of ancient laws, or of curses.
Or of wolves, either.
You should've seen her fighting Nago!
Nago?
A huge boar-god. He ruled
the forest around here.
We couldn't go into the mountains.
All we could do was look up at them.
We used up the iron in the sand by the lake.
Many people had their eye on this
place. The boars got them all.
To get sand, we have to clear the trees.
Nago went wild.
There they go again!
Then Lady Eboshi came along with her muskets.
Sir? What's wrong?
Does your arm hurt?
I was thinking about that boar.
He must have died full of hate.
I'm sorry I kept you waiting, Ashitaka.
That's good iron.
We had to make tomorrow's shipment.
Let's rest now. Tell the others.
Some think you're spying
for the samurai, or the monsters.
There are many who covet our iron.
May I ask why you're here?
You must recognize this.
It shattered the bones of a giant boar,
rotted his flesh and made him a monster.
When I tried to stop him, I was left
with this scar, a curse unto death.
Where is your land? I've never seen
an elk like yours.
Between north and east.
That's all I will say.
Why, you! Answer her
or I'll cut you in two!
And when you find the one who made that?
I will see with eyes unclouded, and decide.
Eyes unclouded?
I see.
I'll show you my secret. Come.
Lady Eboshi!
Take over, Gonza.
No one dares enter this garden.
Come, if you would know my secret.
We're coming in.
We just finished.
It's still heavy.
It's light in your hands.
If the barrel's too thin, it will burst.
It's not just for me.
The women will be using them.
Won't that be a sight!
This is the new musket these people have designed.
Chinese muskets are too heavy.
This will kill monsters and pierce samurai armor.
Watch out. Lady Eboshi
wants to rule the country.
I'm sorry to rush you.
I'll send sake later.
Won't that be nice!
You stole the boar's woods and made a monster of him.
Will you breed new hatred and evil with those weapons?
I'm sorry you suffer.
The musket ball you found is mine.
That hapless boar should have cursed me instead.
Your right hand wants to kill me?
Perhaps that would lift this curse.
But my hand would not be stayed.
Must it kill us all to find peace?
My lady, Osa wants to say something.
Lady Eboshi, do not scorn the young man's strength.
Young man, I too am cursed.
I understand your rage and grief...
but I beg you not to kill our lady.
She is the only person who ever treated us as human.
She did not fear our disease.
She washed and bandaged our flesh.
- Osa...
- Life is suffering and pain.
This world and its people are
cursed, but we still wish to live.
Forgive my foolish babbling.
They're back.
They come at night to plant trees
and take back the mountain.
Ashitaka, will you stay, and work with me?
Would you seize even the Deer God's forest?
Without the ancient gods, the wild ones are mere beasts.
With the forest and wolves gone,
this will be a land of riches.
Even Princess Mononoke will be human again.
Princess Mononoke?
The wild girl whose soul the wolves stole.
She lives to kill me.
The blood of the Deer God is said to cure disease.
Perhaps it could cure these people, even lift your curse.
Lady Eboshi!
How does it handle?
Very well made.
Perfect for conquering the country.
- But still a bit heavy.
- Hard to please.
Look who's here!
Toki, let me try the bellows.
Wait!
May I try?
Let him see what it's like.
What strength!
You really came!
I told you he's an handsome man.
Look, she's fixing her kimono!
You'll never keep up that pace, traveler.
It's hard work.
Yes, we work four days straight.
Is life hard here?
Yes, but it's better than in the towns.
We eat our fill and the men know their place.
I see.
- You're leaving tomorrow?
- You should stay longer.
You can help us.
Thank you, but there is someone I must meet.
She's here.
Princess Mononoke!
It's her!
Stop!
I don't want to fight you!
She's after the Lady!
Stoke the fires.
Riflemen, keep her inside!
Steady at your posts!
She's up on the roof.
Don't get excited. Keep working.
We must keep the fire going.
- Is she alone?
- Yes. We have her cornered.
She came for you.
All right, let's go.
Can you hear me,
Princess Mononoke? Here I am.
You wish to avenge your tribe.
There are some here who seek vengeance for husbands...
killed by your wolves.
Come out!
We have scores to settle!
There she is!
Surrender, Princess Mononoke!
Stay out of the line of fire!
It's a trap. Stop!
Wolf princess, go back to your woods!
Don't die for nothing.
Go back!
I knew it!
Let him do as he likes.
Got her! She's falling.
Don't move.
A wolf's severed head can still bite.
Aim where she falls.
Fire!
Stay back!
Wake up!
No!
Get her!
Don't let her go.
Kill her!
Are you all right, sir?
Don't worry about me. Go!
Villain! You're one of them too.
Halt!
Step aside.
What are you doing, Ashitaka?
Her life is mine.
Will you marry the wolf princess?
There is a demon inside you.
And in her.
Look! This is the hatred
and bitterness that curses me!
It rots my flesh and summons my death.
You cannot yield to it.
Enough talk of your curse.
I'll cut that arm off!
Lady Eboshi!
Someone help me.
Don't worry. She'll recover.
I will take the girl!
Wait! You hurt Lady Eboshi!
Don't move!
Kiyo, no!
He still lives...
- And Lady Eboshi?
- Safe, sir.
Bring me my musket.
Sharpshooters, fall in!
They won't get away.
Toki, quick!
You're...
Sir, you may not pass.
The gate may not be opened without orders.
Please turn back.
You helped us.
We don't want to harm you.
I will leave as I came, of my own will.
No... it takes ten men
to open that gate.
Sir, no! You'll die!
It's moving...
Out of the way!
Wolves!
Flint! Flint!
Stop. Your princess is safe!
We're coming.
Yakul, let's go.
Thank you.
He's gone.
Wait!
He's mine.
Did they shoot you?
Are you going to die?
Why did you stop me?
Speak while you still live!
I didn't want you to die.
I'm not afraid to die if it will drive away the humans!
I knew that when I first saw you.
You've wasted your life by getting in my way!
I'll cut your throat!
That'll shut you up.
Live...
I don't listen to humans!
You're beautiful...
What's wrong, San?
Shall I tear him apart?
It's the apes.
Apes! Do you insult
the tribe of Moro?
This forest ours.
Give us man.
Give us man and go.
Be gone before my fangs find you.
Go.
We eat man.
We eat him.
Let us eat man.
Why would the tribe of the apes...
...want to eat a man?
We eat man. We get his strength.
We get strength to drive humans away.
You won't get that power by eating a man.
All that will do is defile you
and turn you into something else!
We plant trees. Humans kill them.
Forest not come back.
We kill humans.
The Deer God is with us.
Don't give up. Plant your trees.
Moro's tribe is fighting for you!
Deer God not fight. We die.
Wolf girl not care. Wolf girl human.
Monkey! I'll break your neck!
Stop it!
It's all right.
You go ahead.
I'll deal with the human.
What about him?
Can we eat him?
No, you can't. Now go on.
Come here. Let's be friends.
Help me carry your master.
You're smart. You know
not to set foot on this island.
That human stench.
Go where you will. You're free.
There he is!
At last, the Nightwalker!
Quick, come and look.
That's why we've been sitting
in these stinking bearskins.
Don't look, you'll go blind!
And you call yourselves hunters?
This decree from the Emperor...
...allows us to subdue the Deer God!
Now he's the Nightwalker.
When day begins, he becomes a deer again.
He's going in. There!
- Jiko!
- I saw them.
Over there.
There must be hundreds of them.
They're not from these woods.
They're lords of some other forest.
It's Okkoto!
He swam across the straits?
No other boar has those tusks.
He brought his whole tribe.
He knows we're here. Run!
Come on, jump!
There's no wound.
Yakul...
If you're awake, thank Yakul.
He never left your side.
You know his name?
He told me all about you,
about your village and its forest.
I'll help you, because the Deer God saved your life.
I had a dream... a golden deer...
Eat this.
Chew.
We're here to kill humans and save the forest.
Why are humans here?
She is San, my daughter.
There are humans everywhere.
Go back to your homeland and kill them there.
We kill for the forest of the Deer God.
Why is the man here?
The Deer God healed him.
He should leave here alive.
The Deer God saved him?
The Deer God healed a human?
Why did he not save Nago?
Does the Deer God not protect all in the forest?
The Deer God gives life and takes it away.
Have you boars forgotten that?
You begrudge us the Deer God's favor.
You did nothing to help Nago!
He feared death, as do I.
I also carry within me a poisoned human stone.
Nago fled. I will stay
here and face my death.
Ask the Deer God for help.
I have lived long enough, San.
The Deer God would probably take my life.
No, Mother!
You protect the Deer God.
You lie!
Nago was beautiful and strong.
Our brother would never run.
You wolves ate him!
Silence! You slander my mother!
Hear me, all of you.
It was I who killed Nago.
He became a demon and attacked our village.
A huge boar. Here is my proof.
I came to this land to ask
the Deer God to lift this curse.
He healed my wound, but Nago's curse remains.
I must suffer until his curse destroys me.
Ah, it's Okkoto.
Finally, someone with some sense.
Okkoto, wait!
You mustn't eat him.
You are Moro's daughter.
I have heard of you.
Your eyes...
Stand back. I will not eat him.
Wolf Princess...
Fear not. I tell of Nago's end.
My thanks to you, young one.
It grieves us that our tribe spawned a demon.
Lord Okkoto, how I may lift the curse?
Leave this forest.
If we meet again, I must kill you.
You cannot win against the fire stones of the humans.
Look on my tribe, Moro.
We grow small and stupid.
Soon we will be nothing more...
...than game
for the humans to hunt.
If you stake everything on one battle,
you'll play into their hands.
I seek no help from wolves.
Even if we all fall in battle,
we will leave the humans in awe.
The Deer God...
Keep the oxen together!
Hold your fire. Let them come.
Fire!
Reload! Quick!
That damned Eboshi's fighting the wrong enemy.
Go on ahead and hide.
It's them! They've returned.
- Jiko!
- Well done.
We're moving out. Tell the others.
Hello, Jiko.
His Majesty is impatient.
This is no time for sport with country samurai.
Lord Asano sends them against me.
Asano? He's a powerful man.
He wants half my iron.
How greedy of him.
This is no time to fight men.
The boars are gathering in the forest.
Give Asano all your iron.
Keep your promise to His Majesty, then smash Asano.
Quick, Lady Eboshi!
Asano's men are coming.
Speak of the devil. A messenger.
An envoy approaches.
Remember your manners.
Welcome home!
Aren't you going to receive him?
Mistress Eboshi of the Ironworks, you fight well!
I bring a message from my lord.
Open the gate!
We can hear you from there.
Our lady took this mountain from the boars.
Now it's worth something and you want it.
On your way!
You are impudent, woman!
Impudent?
We've been impudent since the day we were born!
You want iron? Take some!
Eboshi's women are quite impressive!
Samurai or monsters, they don't care.
They certainly don't lack for courage.
What good is this paper?
It's helped me get the best hunters and trackers.
We're after a god, not just beasts.
Yes, my lady?
Do you know who this comes from?
- The Son of Heaven.
- The what?
The Emperor.
Oh, it's nothing special.
Off you go.
The more we make iron, the weaker the forest becomes.
We lose fewer lives.
We've spent too much time and money.
We didn't send 40 sharpshooters just for the iron.
At least that's what His Majesty would say.
Surely he doesn't believe that the
head of a god confers immortality?
I'm not privy to his thoughts.
I prefer it that way.
I'll keep my promise.
Boars are easier to deal with than Moro and her tribe.
You can summon that shady bunch hidden under the cliff.
You saw them, did you?
One more thing...
Did a young man pass through here?
A strange youth, riding a red elk.
He left.
They look frightening.
They're not ordinary hunters.
They're special scouts.
Let us go with you.
Don't trust those men!
We can't help you from here if anything happens!
We know how to shoot.
That's why I need you here.
I fear humans more than monsters.
With the Deer God dead, things will become clear.
Is the Deer God's head all the Emperor really wants?
We may have to fight men with muskets, too.
Men can't be trusted.
Stay on your toes.
Don't worry about Lady Eboshi.
I'll protect her with my life.
- I wonder.
- What!
I'd believe that coming from a woman!
Are you suffering?
You could simply jump and end the pain, you know.
When your strength returns, the curse will torment you.
I feel like I've slept for days.
I dreamed San was watching over me.
I hoped you would cry out in your
sleep, so I could bite off your head.
These woods are beautiful.
Are the boars moving yet?
Go back into the cave, boy.
You can't hear it...
The forest crying out as the boars move forward.
I hear the forest crying and
feel the wasting of my body...
and I wait for that woman.
I dream of crushing her head in my jaws.
Can't humans and the forest live in peace?
Can't this be stopped?
The humans are gathering.
We're not safe, even here.
And San? Will you force her
to die with you?
How like a human.
You think only of yourself.
She is a daughter of our tribe.
If the woods die, so will she.
Set her free! She's human.
Silence, boy!
What can you do for her?
The humans who violated the forest
threw her in my path as they ran from me.
Now she is neither human nor wolf.
My poor, ugly, lovely daughter.
Can you save her?
I don't know, but together we can live.
How? Will you join San
and fight the humans?
No. That will only
breed more hatred.
There is nothing you can do.
Soon Nago's curse will kill you.
Leave this place at sunrise.
Can you walk?
Yes, thanks to you and the Deer God.
Yakul! Did you worry?
My legs are still weak.
It's too quiet.
Where are the kodama?
I can smell the ironworks.
Thank you for guiding me.
I have a favor to ask.
Give this to San.
Let's go.
What a stench! I can't breathe.
That's tracker's smoke.
It will blunt our sense of smell.
It's her.
- She knows we're here.
- It's a trap.
Trap?
They want to lure the boars out of the woods.
Everything has been planned.
We've got to warn them.
They'll die!
Okkoto is no fool.
The boars know it's a trap, but still they'll charge.
They are a proud race.
The last one alive will keep charging forward.
They're cutting trees.
Another provocation.
Mother, this is farewell.
The smoke will blind Okkoto.
I'll be his eyes.
As you like, San.
But there is a life for you with that boy.
I hate humans!
From Ashitaka... for me?
It's beautiful.
You two go with San.
I will stay with the Deer God.
Let's go.
The tribe of Moro fights with you!
Where is Okkoto?
Thank you!
It's coming from the ironworks.
Let's go.
Halt!
Samurai!
Let me pass!
I don't believe it.
He's fending them off.
Don't waste your arrows.
Quick!
- You're right, it is him.
- It's not a ghost.
Ashitaka!
Toki! Are you all right?
Of course!
They thought they'd catch us while the men were away.
We showed 'em!
- They thought we'd be easy.
- Where's Lady Eboshi?
She took every man and went after the Deer God.
We're trapped here and can't reach her.
The Deer God?
So that's what I heard.
Sir, I've still got your bow.
What about his saddle and cloak?
- I forgot.
- You're useless!
Koroku, thanks!
I'll bring help. Can you hold on?
We'll pour hot iron on them if we have to!
- Hurry, Ashitaka!
- Bring Lady Eboshi.
Missed!
They're bringing boats. Hurry!
Summon Lady Eboshi. We'll fight, too!
I'll be back. Keep fighting!
We'll be here!
Kill that man!
They're after us, Yakul!
Burning flesh...
Yakul!
Stay back!
Show me the wound.
Wait here. I'll be back.
Stay, I said!
We're almost there.
Who goes there?
You're not allowed here.
I'm indebted to these men.
I have a message for Lady Eboshi.
She's not here.
I'll see that she gets it.
I will speak to her.
Where is she?
Ashitaka, you made it after all!
You've suffered badly.
Some men are still buried.
It was horrible.
The ironworks are under attack.
There's still time. The women are
holding the inner stockade.
This cannot stand!
Asano waited until we left.
Where's Lady Eboshi?
She went after the Deer God.
Call her back. There's no time!
If you're finished, get moving.
Get back to work!
And the ironworks?
Now wait a minute!
They're ready to sacrifice us all.
- There's no time to lose.
- Send Eboshi a message!
She's deep in the woods.
We'll never find her.
Send one of your trackers, then.
They're using Lady Eboshi.
Were there any wolves with the boars?
Have you seen Princess Mononoke?
It was pitch black when they came at us.
She was there.
We were on the front line...
And?
I don't know. All of a sudden,
the world turned upside down...
The scouts put us there to lure the boars in.
There were mines underneath us...
and grenades from above.
Where's San?
Be still, I want to help you.
A wolf! There's a wolf
still alive over here.
Sir, what are you...
Sir!
What are you doing, boy?
He'll take me to Eboshi.
So you're with them, are you?
Step aside.
Would you sacrifice these men and their families?
Poison darts!
Stop!
Give me a hand!
He's free!
Go through the swamp and hide near the lake.
They have sharpshooters.
Be careful.
Take this. My last arrow broke.
Go with them.
Look after him!
Find San. That's where Eboshi is.
Keep up with the scouts.
We finish this today!
Jiko!
Well? How does it look?
Okkoto's hurt. He and the girl
are going to the Deer God.
So they're going to ask him
for help. Stay with them.
Keep out of sight or he won't appear.
Of course.
Was that boar blood on his face?
It's a scout trick.
Revolting, isn't it?
We're almost at the Deer God's pond.
Something's coming!
Something's wrong, Okkoto!
We have to keep moving.
Something bad is coming.
I can't smell it.
There's too much blood.
Apes!
You did this.
Your fault. Forest die.
Is this how you thank those who fought for your forest?
You bring monsters.
Not animal! Not human!
Neither animal nor human?
- They're here!
- Doom! Doom!
Scouts?
They're here!
My warriors have returned from the land of the dead.
Forward, my warriors!
To the Deer God!
Okkoto, no! Your warriors
haven't come back to life.
The boar skins hide their scent.
Humans!
Stop! They want us to
lead them to the Deer God!
Come out, Deer God!
If you are lord of this forest,
revive my warriors to slay the humans.
Okkoto! Still your heart!
We're surrounded! He's done for.
Leave him!
No! He'll become a demon!
Tell Mother it's the Deer God the humans want.
She'll know what to do.
We can't let our kind die out!
Go!
I'll kill the first one who moves,
and tell the forest what you are.
Ashitaka?
Get back!
I burn! A flame bursts from within me.
No!
No, Okkoto! Don't turn into a demon!
Okkoto!
An answer!
- What is it?
- San's in danger!
Let's go!
It's hot!
No! I don't want
to be a demon!
Okkoto!
Too slow. Get on.
A wolf!
Eboshi...
Go on ahead!
Eboshi, listen to me!
- Cease fire!
- Ashitaka?
The ironworks are under attack.
Forget the Deer God and go back!
The women need help.
Your men are on their way.
They're waiting for you.
What proof do you have?
None! I would have stayed
and fought if I could!
You want me to kill samurai instead of the Deer God?
No! Can't the forest
and the ironworks live in peace?
- Whose side is he on?
- Let's go back!
The women can hold their own.
They have weapons and supplies.
There's the pond. He's close!
It's now or never. Stay alert.
Do we need her?
We're hunting a god.
Let her do the dirty work.
Moro! Are you dead?
San!
Where are you?
Ashitaka!
Okkoto...
Leave, boy.
If we fight, the god won't come.
Okkoto! Be still!
Give me Princess Mononoke.
Where is San?
San, can you hear me?
It's me, Ashitaka!
San!
Silence him!
Shoot him down!
San!
Ashitaka!
And here I was saving my last strength for that woman.
Close up!
Stay away from him.
The curse will fall on you.
Have you lost even the power of speech?
Well done. Fall back
and tend to the wounded.
A horrible sight.
There he is.
Give me back my daughter!
Ashitaka...
Can you save San?
The Deer God...
Don't shoot!
Eboshi! Your enemy is not
the Deer God!
Guns can't hurt him...
Only through the head...
San!
Don't die!
They wanted life, but it gave them death.
- It's the Nightwalker!
- Watch closely, all of you.
This is how you kill a god.
This is also the god of death.
Stay close behind me.
Stop!
Eboshi!
Damn you!
Got him! Get the head!
Jiko! Bring the box!
The porters are dead! Quick!
Don't touch the body!
It'll suck the life out of you.
Take it! The head is yours.
Lady Eboshi!
Moro's head... it moved by itself!
Come on, hurry! Run!
Run!
To the island!
- I can't swim!
- It's shallow.
Bring her here. I'll kill her!
Moro's had her revenge.
- Lady Eboshi!
- Help me.
Don't waste your sympathy.
I promised Toki I'd bring you back.
It's searching for its head.
We can't stay here.
San!
Help me.
No! You're on their side!
Take her and go away!
Keep away! I hate humans!
I am human. So are you.
Shut up!
I'm a wolf!
Don't touch me!
I'm sorry. I tried to stop it.
Everything is finished.
The forest is dead.
No it's not.
We're still alive. Help me.
Wait! Help us!
A little danger and they're useless.
Don't stop!
The head's moving!
It's calling him!
That will fix it.
Thanks.
- It's too quiet.
- They're waiting for dawn.
I wonder if that young man found Eboshi.
I'm sure he did.
She should be here soon.
Look at that face. Hey, Koroku!
Let him sleep for now.
What is it? It sounds unearthly.
The Nightwalker!
Hold your positions!
- It's coming this way.
- We've got to run.
We guard the ironworks!
We promised Lady Eboshi.
It's him! Ashitaka!
Everyone, escape!
The Deer God is coming for his head!
Touch that muck and you're dead!
Go to the lake.
The water will protect you.
Lady Eboshi and the men are coming from the other side.
We must return the head!
Hurry!
It's here.
What do we do?
Don't panic.
To the lake!
Stay calm! Help the injured.
Not that way!
There goes the roof...
Once the forge starts to burn, it's all over.
No, it isn't. We're still alive.
Farther... quickly!
There they are!
Go!
Wait!
You're still alive? That's good.
I'll return the head.
Leave it and go.
Give it back now? It's too late.
The sun's coming up.
Look! A brainless,
life-sucking god of death.
He'll vanish with the sun.
He's coming, Jiko. Quick!
The thirst to possess heaven and earth
is what makes us human.
I don't want to kill you.
Oh, dear.
Don't look so serious.
Get going!
Ashitaka!
Trapped.
We're surrounded!
- Sun, come quickly!
- Open it!
Don't you understand? It's too late.
Ashitaka, talking with humans is useless.
Human hands must return it.
I warned you.
O Deer God...
We return your head!
Be at peace!
Here it comes!
- It stopped.
- There they are!
Lady Eboshi!
Careful, she's hurt.
It's falling!
Hang on tight!
I didn't know the Deer God made flowers bloom.
San, look!
Even restored, these are not the Deer God's woods.
The Deer God is dead.
He can't die.
He is life itself.
He is both life and death.
He is telling us we should live.
I love you, Ashitaka.
But I'll never forgive the human race.
Then live in the forest, and I'll live at the ironworks.
Together, we'll live.
Yakul and I will visit you.
Can you believe it?
Carried to safety by a wolf.
Someone bring Ashitaka.
I want to thank him.
We'll start over.
We'll build a good village here.
I give up.
You can't win against fools.
VOICES
Yoji Matsuda
Yuriko Ishida
Yuko Tanaka
Kaoru Kobayashi
Masahiko Nishimura
Tsunehiko Kamijo
Akihiro Miwa
Mitsuko Mori
Hisaya Morishige
Chief Executive Producer
Yasuyoshi Tokuma
Executive Producers
Seiichiro Ujiie Yutaka Narita
Original Story and Screenplay by
Hayao Miyazaki
Music by Joe Hisaishi
Theme Song "Mononoke Hime"
Lyrics by Hayao Miyazaki
Music by Joe Hisaishi
Performed by
Yoshikazu Mera
Dialogue adaptation by
Jim Hubbert and Studio Ghibli
Subtitles by Aura
A Studio Ghibli Film
Producer
Toshio Suzuki
Directed by
Hayao Miyazaki
The End