Distributed by TOHO CO., LTD.
And NIPPON HERALD FILMS, INC.
The hero of today's hunt
is Lord Ichimonji.
His was the arrow
that felled the boar.
Let us drink to him.
The infernal beast
charged right in front of me.
My horse reared, and down I went
before I could even draw my bow.
Father,
shall we have the boar roasted?
He was old.
His flesh would be tough and gamy.
Not fit to eat.
Just like me.
Think you could eat me?
You'd stick in our throats.
No, our purpose in joining your hunt
was to deepen our friendship.
Indeed.
And it is to cement the bonds
between our two houses
that I would have my daughter
marry your third son, Saburo.
Now wait a moment.
That's my wish as well.
Lord Ichimonji,
this is an excellent opportunity.
Give us your answer.
Whom would you choose
for your son, Saburo -
my daughter or Lord Ayabe's?
What a quandary.
Two daughters
but only one son.
A pity my second son, Jiro,
already has a wife.
Kyoami.
Come entertain us.
From the far mountain
From the near mountain
Who comes hippety-hopping
With two tall blades
pointing out of his head
A hare
Just one hare, Kyoami?
I think I see two.
They've come hopping through
the mountains to be eaten up by Father.
Hold your tongue, Saburo!
Don't be an ass!
It appears Lord Ichimonji is tired.
Let us withdraw until he awakens.
It's not like Father
to nod off in front of guests.
He's just feigning sleep.
After Saburo's insult,
how else could he save face?
He's never done this before.
It was only a boar hunt.
He used to rout an entire army
and be none the worse for wear.
It's impolite
to Lords Ayabe and Fujimaki.
Kyoami, wake Lord Ichimonji.
I'm more worried about Father.
He's not snoring
as he usually does.
- Father! Is something wrong?
- Are you ill?
So it was a dream.
I had a dream.
I was walking
through a desolate field...
never encountering another soul
no matter how far I went,
hearing no reply
no matter how loudly I shouted.
I was alone.
All alone in the whole wide world.
I was terrified.
How silly of me.
Taro's voice
brought me back,
and there you all were,
my beloved sons.
Taro...
Jiro...
and Saburo.
I've never seen you
like this, Father.
You make me uneasy.
Watch your tongue, Saburo!
Have you no gratitude
for your father's affection?
Actually, I too have difficulty
believing what Father just said.
We're utterly helpless
without Father's guidance.
Are you implying instead
that he relies on us?
Patience, now.
I've been thinking about that,
and I've come to a decision.
I want to tell you about it now.
This is as good a time as any -
especially with Lord Fujimaki
and Lord Ayabe in our company.
Ask them to join us.
I, Hidetora Ichimonji...
was born in a small castle
on the far side of that mountain.
In those days, this region
was in constant upheaval.
Lords great and small
vied for power.
As a lad of 17...
I rode forth from that small castle
with my banner raised.
For 50 years I waged war...
and at last made
the entire region my domain.
I hoisted the Ichimonji colors
atop that great castle.
Even after that,
I crossed lances a time or two
with Lords Fujimaki and Ayabe here,
but we have now set aside
our differences,
stabling the steeds of war
and cultivating
bonds of friendship.
But 70 years
have quickly come upon me.
As of this day,
I cede authority
over the house of Ichimonji
to my eldest son, Taro.
My lord!
- This is too sudden!
- My lord!
Not at all.
I've been planning this
for quite some time.
The day has
long been approaching
for me to step aside
and lay the mantle
on younger shoulders.
I tell you now:
That day has come.
I repeat.
From this moment forth,
Taro is head of the house of Ichimonji,
and lord of this domain.
I will yield the keep
of the First Castle to him
and move to the outer tower.
With me will come
30 of my close attendants,
and I shall retain the formal title
and privileges of Great Lord.
But all actual authority
shall rest with Taro.
This is my decree!
We bow to your will, Father.
But what of myself and Saburo?
What do you intend for us?
Jiro and Saburo,
I bestow upon you the Second
and Third Castles and their lands.
You will strengthen your fortifications
and aid Taro in defending the First Castle.
I shall divide my time
among the three castles,
and thus enjoy
my remaining years.
Alas, the ravages of age.
If I may, Father.
It is a tremendous honor
to be named
the head of our house,
but I must beg you to reconsider.
Why?
Though I am indeed
your eldest son and heir,
to rule in your place
is far beyond my abilities.
I have long prayed
to the god of war
that you might live
to be a hundred,
even if it means taking
from my own allotment of years.
My brother certainly has
a way with words.
I'd never have the nerve
to speak such honeyed phrases.
Makes me itch just to hear them.
Don't be so contrary.
Are you implying
Taro's words were mere flattery?
Father, pay no attention
to Saburo.
I share Taro's sentiment.
I would far prefer
to remain behind your shield,
but it's now our turn
to shield you from life's arrows
so that your remaining years
may be filled with ease.
Reassuring words, Jiro.
Bring me that quiver!
Break this in two.
Can you break this?
Now...
break these three arrows
together.
A single arrow is easily broken.
Not so three bundled together.
Even should a great catastrophe
threaten to overwhelm Taro,
if the three of you join forces
to meet the challenge,
the house of Ichimonji
and its domains will be safe.
Father, there are ways to break
even three arrows together.
More of your contrariness.
Stop playing the fool!
You're the one playing the fool -
talking nonsense all of a sudden.
- Nonsense?
- Yes! You've either gone senile or mad.
Silence!
You dare to insult your father?
What madness have I spoken?
What senile nonsense?
Very well, since you ask.
Consider the times
in which we live.
To survive, one must discard
loyalty and affection.
- I know that all too well.
- As well you should,
since the blood you've spilled
is beyond reckoning.
Your lifelong code has been
no pity, no mercy.
But remember, Father,
we too are children of this age,
weaned on chaos and strife.
Yet, because we are your blood,
you trust in our undying fidelity
as you dream of peaceful retirement.
To me, that is nothing
but madness and senility.
Very well. I see.
You're saying that someday
you might forget I am your father
and turn against me?
More nonsense still! What fool
announces his intent to betray?
Then will Taro or Jiro
turn against me?
You resent the fact
Father chose Taro to succeed him.
Saburo, is that why
you slander us this way?
You may be my brother,
but I'll only stand for so much.
Father, see what's happened
to your three arrows already?
Can a blood feud be far behind?
How dare you?
Would you trample
on your father's wishes?
Very well! If you insist these times allow
no bonds between parent and child,
then consider our bonds severed!
You are now a stranger to me!
Out of my sight!
You mustn't, my lord!
Silence, Tango.
My mistake was to dote on him
over the others.
I coddled him too much.
This swollen head, this insolence -
these are my own creation.
But it's too late for regrets.
When flesh is rotten,
it must be cut away,
even if it's your own!
Wait, my lord!
Master Saburo minces no words,
and what he says may seem
disrespectful and even brutal.
But it is his upright heart that leads him
to speak with unadorned candor.
If you consider
his words carefully,
you will find truth in them.
- Silence!
- No!
Desist!
I will not!
You...
No, my lord!
Have you lost your head,
my lord?
As your advisor,
it is my duty to speak frankly.
Brandishing your sword
will not make me budge!
- Insolence!
- I beg you, revoke your rash decision!
Your impudence matches Saburo's!
I won't have it!
I banish you both!
Father!
A terrible predicament.
What do you intend to do,
Master Saburo?
It's Father I'm worried about,
not myself.
It tears at my heart
to think what lies ahead for him.
You're a fool, Tango.
Why?
Defending me
only got you banished.
It's a mistake for you
to be separated from Father...
no matter
what the circumstances.
I think they may be after us.
Wait a moment, will you?
Why do you flee, son-in-law?
- Son-in-law?
Let me explain.
You incurred your father's wrath
and were exiled.
Lord Ayabe and I both
witnessed it all.
Now that you've been cast out
and are little more than a beggar -
Oh, forgive me!
How should I put it?
This is awkward -
It's all right. Now that I'm
little more than a beggar -
- The offer of marriage is off.
- Naturally.
No, you misunderstand!
Those were Lord Ayabe's words
when he withdrew his proposal.
But as I set out
on my way home,
I began thinking.
Your conduct showed
great strength of character.
You're a most interesting fellow.
Was I to let a man like you
slip through my fingers?
And so I turned back to find you,
only to have you flee.
Is my proposal
disagreeable to you?
I don't know what to say.
Then come stay with me
while you think it over.
You too, Tango.
I admire a man
with your backbone.
I want you to come as well.
It's most kind of you,
but I must decline your invitation.
No matter what lowly disguise
I must adopt,
I will remain near Lord Hidetora.
If you'll excuse me.
What is it?
Lord Hidetora's ladies
are moving to the outer tower.
They refuse to yield
to your retinue.
This is a blatant affront!
I am now the mistress
of this castle.
Etiquette demands
that they make way.
Why are my women kneeling
to Taro's wife?
It's outrageous!
I beg to differ.
Now that you've yielded
the throne to Taro,
it's only proper.
He gives away his house
and gives away his lands
A generous man,
the village head
Now he's but a scarecrow
Standing out in the field
Are you calling me a fool?
No, sire!
The fool kneels here before you.
Enduring ridicule,
I seek to entertain.
But you, my lord -
you've squandered your domain.
You know, Kaede...
now that it all belongs to me,
the view
is even more magnificent.
As I recall,
a battle standard
used to be kept there.
Yes, my father kept his standard
and suit of armor there.
What happened to them?
I gave them to Father's men
just now.
The armor is of no importance,
but the standard -
My lord,
that standard represents
the head of the house of Ichimonji.
But Father said he would retain
the title and privileges of Great Lord.
Are you then to be
merely a shadow?
What are you saying?
He made it clear
I am now lord of this domain.
In that case,
I suggest you act like a lord.
Attendants!
What?
You want the standard back?
- That's right.
What? One minute you give,
and the next you take back?
Silence!
We have orders from Lord Taro!
The new lord
is a gourd in the wind
Swinging this way
Swinging that way
Spinning in the breeze
on its spindly vine
High in the keep
Dangles an empty gourd
Isn't it hilarious
Insolent fool!
I'll teach you!
The new lord
is a gourd in the wind
Swinging this way
Swinging that way
Spinning in the breeze
on its spindly vine
High in the keep
dangles an empty gourd
Isn't it hilarious
Who is it?
Ogura, from the keep.
I bring a message, sire.
To celebrate
the transfer of power,
Lord Taro wishes to hold
a family gathering in the keep tonight.
He requests the honor
of your presence.
Lord Ikoma is invited as well.
You call this a family gathering?
Father,
won't you be seated?
You expect me to sit below you?
Who do you think I am?
My husband's
most honorable father.
Is that all?
What happened to the Great Lord?
Is he dead?
- Don't be silly.
- I'm not being silly!
I retain the title and standing
of Great Lord. Have you forgotten that?
Of course not.
But it seems you've forgotten, Father,
that you made me head of the house.
What are you talking about?
I've yielded the keep to you,
moved to the outer tower,
and reduced my retinue.
Their number may be few,
but their conduct is intolerable.
What am I to make of that song?
Swinging this way
Swinging that way
Spinning in the breeze
on its spindly vine
With such goings-on,
how am I to establish my authority?
They're brutish warriors
with no use for niceties.
You can't keep them
from enjoying a comic song.
There's such a thing
as going too far.
The fool's song
blatantly mocks me.
It was only natural
for my guard to defend my honor.
Yet you loosed your arrow
and killed my man.
I cannot let such things pass.
Just this once
I will overlook it,
but I must have your bond
that it will not happen again.
You will sign that statement
and seal it with your blood.
"Covenant"?
I'm astounded
you'd even suggest this.
Read it!
"Covenant.
Item:
I cede control over all Ichimonji lands
to my first son, Taro.
Item:
I declare my first son, Taro,
head of the house of Ichimonji.
Item:
Although I am his father,
I shall hereafter submit
to Taro's authority
and not act against his will.
I attest to the above
in the name of all the deities
and hereby affirm this covenant."
You expect me to sign and seal
this nonsense with my blood?
The items listed here
are nothing more
than what you yourself proclaimed
before Lord Ayabe
and Lord Fujimaki.
What does it change
to set it in writing?
Are you really my son?
- What a question!
- Is this how a son treats his father?
The hen pecks the cock
and makes him crow.
I cannot stay here!
Fortunately,
I have another son.
Thank you for your cooperation.
I was born and raised here
in this, my father's castle...
and sent forth from here
to marry you.
After our marriage,
my father and brothers
let down their guard...
and fell to your father's sword.
How I've longed for this day...
ever since
I returned to this castle.
It was in this very room
that my mother took her life.
My father plans to come here.
Taro has driven him
from the First Castle.
My brother's letter says
Father has become so willful and erratic,
it would be unwise to let him stay.
He adds that Father's counselor, Ikoma,
has secretly shifted his allegiance.
It's quite unlike Lord Taro
to use such harsh language.
If I may, my lord,
why do you just sit quietly by?
My question exactly.
You're the one who should
succeed Lord Hidetora.
Taro is no match for the task.
If we were you, we'd stake
our lives on a chance like this.
Are you saying
you'd stake your lives on me?
Exactly.
But dogs will abandon a master
who abandons the chase.
Shrink from this
and you become our quarry.
How the dogs howl!
I have given the situation
much thought.
Just because
I was born a year after Taro,
am I to grovel all my life
at his feet?
I will throw off these shackles!
Just what we wanted to hear.
Control your impudence.
Now listen.
Taro will be easy to handle,
but his wife, Lady Kaede,
is a different matter.
True.
Actually, she'd be
a perfect match for you.
Perhaps you should steal her.
- Don't be impertinent.
Our first concern is Father.
Though officially retired,
he still has 30 retainers -
seasoned warriors,
each worth a thousand men.
He'll soon arrive at my gate
in their company.
We need a plan.
Open the gates!
It's Hidetora!
The Great Lord is here!
I will see Sué first.
Tell Jiro I'll see him later.
Sué.
Praise be
To the eternal Western Paradise
Praise be to the eternal Buddha
In 36 trillion manifestations
Praise be to Amida Buddha
I thought I'd find you here.
Father!
Never mind the formalities.
It's been a long time.
Let me look at you.
Always that same sad face.
Every time I see you,
it tears at my heart.
It's worse
when you smile like that.
I burned down
your father's castle.
Your parents and family
all perished.
How can you smile at me?
You should be glaring at me
with hatred.
That would be easier to bear.
Go on, let your hatred show!
I do not hate you.
Everything is determined
by our karma from previous lives.
In all things I take comfort
in the Buddha's heart.
The Buddha again!
There is no Buddha in our world.
We live in a dark age
from which the Buddha's guardians
have been routed by the Asuras.
The Buddha's great mercy
can no longer help us.
Ah, Jiro!
I've come to be your guest.
I'm disappointed in Taro.
Let me tell you -
There's no need, Father.
Taro explained everything in his letter.
Taro wrote to you?
He says your guards
were vulgar and unruly.
I am to receive you
with the courtesy due my father,
but he orders me not to allow
your men inside the castle walls.
That's absurd!
How can I leave my men
to rot outside
while I alone enter the castle?
My brother is now
head of the clan.
I have no choice
but to obey him.
If you cannot abide
by his conditions,
then perhaps your best course
is to return to the First Castle
and apologize.
Apologize to Taro?
Return to the First Castle?
What's the meaning of this?
This is outrageous!
Stop!
Lord Kurogane!
Lord Shirane!
Why are we being
treated this way?
Lord Ikoma!
These are
Lord Hidetora's instructions.
This sudden visit
has caught
the castle unprepared.
Wait outside the walls
until the castle is ready.
I've heard enough.
Now I see.
You're no different...
from Taro.
You just want me out of the way.
That's not true.
Come alone and I'll welcome you
with open arms.
You only say that
because you know I can't.
You have stepped down.
Under your own son's protection,
what need can you have of retainers?
Only the wild beasts...
can live without
the company of their own.
I've heard enough excuses.
Open the gates!
What are you waiting for?
Don't worry.
My men aren't coming in.
I'm leaving!
Open the gates!
Close the gates!
I never want to see you again!
The villages are all deserted.
There's not a grain of rice
to be had anywhere.
The peasants must have taken it all
and fled to the hills.
My lord.
The Third Castle
is our only choice.
That was the first castle
you conquered.
We can go there
and make a fresh -
Fool!
If I could do that,
I wouldn't be wandering
the wilderness without food.
Think a moment.
Would the protectors
of the Third Castle
welcome the man who banished
their lord and master?
By order of Lord Taro,
head of the Ichimonji clan,
I have come to take possession
of this castle.
Open the gates!
Without Lord Saburo,
this castle means nothing to us.
Our sole desire
is to follow Lord Saburo
and die protecting him.
Word has come that he is
in Lord Fujimaki's domain.
We go now to join him.
By your leave.
Lord Tango!
I've brought rice,
miso and salted plums.
I, Tango Hirayama,
though banished,
have followed my lord in disguise.
Seeing how you suffer,
I beg to offer you these provisions.
Is that really you, Tango?
Wait!
Circumstances prevent us
from accepting these provisions.
No matter how hungry, we will not
take charity from the peasants.
That's right.
The peasants' conduct
is unforgivable.
Burn down all their villages!
One moment, my lord!
You mustn't blame the peasants.
Lord Taro forced them to flee
their villages and hide from you.
What exactly did he do?
He issued a decree
banishing you
and declaring
that anyone who helps you...
must die.
You tried to warn me of this.
I should have taken it to heart.
I remain your humble servant,
my lord.
Go ahead and laugh, Tango.
Laugh at Hidetora's
wretched plight.
Betrayed by my own sons
and turned out of my castles,
I have no place to go.
That's not true, my lord.
You do have a place to go.
Master Saburo
has found refuge with Lord Fujimaki,
who wants him for a son-in-law.
Go to him.
No! Speak no more of that!
How could I ever face Saburo now?
My lord,
you must listen to me.
Saburo's only thought
is for your welfare.
It was at his bidding
that I followed you
disguised as I am.
It was he who insisted
that I stay close by
and see to your safety.
I bring news, sire.
Saburo's men have turned over
the Third Castle to Lord Ogura
and departed
for Lord Fujimaki's domain.
What?
Now we see
Lord Fujimaki's scheme.
First he makes Master Saburo
his son-in-law,
then he takes in
Saburo's warriors,
and finally your lordship himself.
Then he foments war
among your divided clan
and walks off with your domain
while you battle it out.
That's absurd!
Lord Fujimaki is not that kind of man!
We must go
to the Third Castle at once.
But the castle
is in Lord Ogura's hands.
What of it?
Ogura's a reasonable man.
What's that I smell?
Something stinks.
A very rotten stench.
My lord, Ogura has
only a handful of men.
We can easily overwhelm them
if necessary.
Bring my horse!
By all means hurry,
what with hell so near
and heaven so far!
Insolent brat!
If you don't like it, begone!
All we did...
was speak the truth.
My lord!
- My lord, the attackers are -
- I know!
Find Ikoma and Ogura for me!
But it's they
who've betrayed us!
The enemy is everywhere,
inside and out.
Hell is upon us!
Lord Taro is slain!
- What?
- A terrible shame!
It was a stray shot
from the tower!
Such are the vagaries of war.
The fates are kinder
to you than to Taro.
What about Father?
Harakiri, most likely.
- My lord, we're doomed!
- Prepare yourself!
Farewell, my lord!
Withdraw!
My lord!
The die is cast!
You must not falter!
You have but one path to follow.
It leads to absolute rule
of the house of Ichimonji.
There's no turning back.
Lord Hidetora!
My lord!
Has he gone mad?
He's better off for it!
What are you saying?
Please, my lord!
You must reclaim your wits!
In a world gone mad,
it's madness to be sane.
What on earth do you see?
Forgive me!
Ah, excellent!
Your madness finally shows you
the true nature of your sins!
Oh, the unspeakable horror
On a withered plain I see
All those I destroyed
In all the many clans
Phantom armies rise up
One by one before me
Who's there?
Travelers stranded by the storm.
We beg shelter for the night.
My hovel is much too humble
for visitors.
We ask nothing special.
I have reasons
for wishing to be alone.
Why? A contagious malady?
No.
Then, please!
I'm sorry.
Listen.
The one who seeks shelter
is Lord Ichimonji himself.
We're coming in!
Our lord has taken ill.
He's soaked to the bone.
Have you anything to cover him with?
I'm cold.
My lord.
Is that you, Tango?
Rejoice, Kyoami!
He's himself again.
More's the pity.
He was better off mad.
Listen to me.
I was attacked...
by my own sons,
Taro and Jiro.
And I was betrayed by Ikoma.
Worse yet...
I myself stood by and watched
as my loyal followers
died in vain.
By some twist of fate...
I came out of it alive.
I should have died!
You there! Woman!
I am not a woman.
I'm sorry. It's so dark.
We need a light.
I have no light...
and no use for one.
What?
Are you without sight?
Are you not Lady Sué's brother,
young Lord Tsurumaru?
Tsurumaru?
It's been a very long time...
Lord Hidetora.
You remember me?
How could I forget?
I may have been only a boy,
but never could I forget
the man
who burned down
my father's castle
and gouged out my eyes...
as the price
for letting me live.
My sister taught me
to pray to the Buddha
and banish hatred from my heart,
but try as I might...
not for one day
have I forgotten...
not one night
have I slept in peace.
Now then,
I regret I cannot show you
the hospitality
befitting a great lord.
But I have a flute
my sister gave me.
Perhaps I might play
a tune for you
in place of the hospitality
I'm unable to offer.
This is the only pleasure
that remains for me now.
My lord!
Lady Kaede,
I bring a lock
of your husband's hair.
Unhappily it falls to me
to inform you
of his death in battle.
I curse the fates that made it so.
Lord Ogura...
where are
my husband's remains?
In this fierce heat,
the body would have become
too unsightly for you to view.
We cremated it
at the Third Castle
and held funeral rites
at a nearby temple.
Lord Ogura,
where are his armor and helmet?
Do you mock me?
I'm now wearing
the armor he wore.
Surely you recognize it.
Of course.
I just couldn't believe
you'd so quickly claim
these mementos of my husband...
for yourself to wear.
I'm stung by your words.
I thought my brother would be pleased
to see me return to his castle
wearing his armor.
But I see it was
a rash decision.
Forgive me.
Help me remove this armor!
Lady Kaede,
forgive my disrobing before you.
Lords Ikoma and Ogura,
you've been of great service to us
during these upheavals
in the house of Ichimonji.
Please accept these humble tokens
as an expression of our gratitude.
These are
my parting gifts to you.
Farewell.
After careful consideration,
Lord Jiro feels it unwise
to take into his service
men who betrayed their masters
while serving as their counselors.
His reasoning is unassailable.
We are helpless to intervene.
Please do not be offended.
You do understand?
I'm so glad.
If you'll excuse us, my lord.
Lady Kaede is here, sire.
Ask her to ascend.
I'm afraid I was upset before
and spoke indiscreetly.
I must apologize.
Please think nothing of it.
They say your father
has gone mad.
That must please you.
Why would you say
such a thing?
Lady Kaede,
I merely spoke what I felt
was the ungilded truth.
Forgive me
if I've caused offense.
But you must hate
my father fiercely
for what he did to your family.
Or am I mistaken?
I could say much the same:
Lord Jiro too must be
most pleased.
After all, you are now head
of the Ichimonji clan.
This helmet is rightfully yours.
I'm not blind, Lord Jiro!
You drove your father mad, murdered
your brother and stole his lands!
This is for my husband!
You're wrong!
You deny it even now?
It wasn't me!
I didn't kill my brother!
Then who did?
Speak! Who was it?
- Who was it?
- It wasn't me.
Kurogane shot him.
Hypocrite!
Would you give the order,
then deny the blame?
A fine leader you are!
You contemptible weakling.
Now it's my turn to speak
the ungilded truth.
Lord Jiro,
I couldn't care less
about my husband's death.
All I care about
is myself!
I refuse to live as a widow,
with my hair cut short,
or as a nun,
with my head shaved.
This castle was my father's.
I will not be driven from it!
Lord Jiro,
if you'll grant my request,
I will say nothing.
I'll tell no one
of your abominable crimes.
I'll not speak out
in bitter reproach against you.
If I did, I could throw
this land into turmoil!
It's in my power...
to tear this domain to shreds!
What do you say, Lord Jiro?
My... lord?
Yes, Lady Kaede?
I didn't hear that.
How can you still be
so formal with me?
After what we've done,
I really should be...
your wife.
But I already have Sué.
Then am I to be
merely your concubine?
No!
You must belong to me alone.
No one else can have you!
You needn't cry, Kaede.
I'd never make you
a mere concubine.
But as long
as Lady Sué remains -
I'll think of something.
What can you do?
I'll divorce her.
That will not do!
I can't bear to think
that another woman
has known your touch.
She can't be allowed to live!
Do you know where we are?
In more peaceful times, this would
have been Tsurumaru's castle.
You now take shelter
in the ruins of a castle
that you yourself burned down.
Must be nice
having no idea what's happening.
Your helmet, my lord.
And those are your crest.
Now you look even more grand.
Look who's coming -
those demons!
Two demons approaching!
Dirty traitors!
You'll pay for your treason!
No, wait!
Let us explain!
Excuses won't save you!
Lord Hidetora told me
all about your treachery.
My lord!
Die, traitor!
Jiro killed Taro!
If Hidetora hadn't gone mad,
he'd have been next!
If he recovers his wits,
he'll be killed too!
Jiro killed Taro!
We must take Lord Hidetora
to Saburo at once!
If only we could.
Mention Saburo
and he runs away.
He can't bring himself
to face Saburo after what happened.
On that point he's sane.
My lord.
Why do you shrink
from Master Saburo?
Let us go to him.
No, our only choice
is to bring Saburo here.
I'll go get him.
I'll return as soon as I can.
I leave our lord in your hands.
My lord,
you're allowing Lady Kaede
to lead you by the nose.
If you wish to marry her, fine.
But to kill Lady Sué?
Sometimes it is necessary
to take a life,
but to kill one
who needn't be killed -
I'll have nothing to do
with such lunacy!
Lord Kurogane.
I trust the Second Castle
has ample stores of salt?
Yes. Why?
You'll need to bring
the head back wrapped in salt.
Otherwise, in this heat,
it'll be in such a frightful state,
we'll have to cover our eyes.
For a woman
of Lady Sué's beauty,
that would be too cruel.
Since you will see to it personally,
I'm sure there will be no mishaps.
I leave it
in your capable hands.
Why do I stay
with this crazy old man?
If the boulder you're sitting on
begins to roll,
you'd best jump clear.
Otherwise you'll be crushed.
Only a fool refuses to jump.
This place -
Where are we?
We're in paradise!
Damn it all!
Ever since I was a child,
I've been tending to him.
Now be a good boy.
Time for beddy-bye.
I have returned, my lord!
Approach!
You have been most diligent.
At your service, my lady.
In accordance
with your careful instructions,
I have brought
the item you requested.
Be so kind as to examine it.
With your permission,
I will inspect it first.
What is this?
Is this some kind of a joke?
- Is something wrong?
- I'll not have it!
What in the world?
Lady Sué must have been
a fox in disguise.
Enough of your pranks!
This is a statue from a shrine!
A clever fox indeed!
Now she's turned herself
to stone!
Kurogane!
Would you make a fool of me?
Heavens, no.
We have a great many foxes
in these parts,
and it's said
they often play tricks on humans.
You must be very careful,
my lord.
Foxes often work their evil
in the shape of a woman.
In Central Asia,
a she-fox seduced King Pan Tsu
and persuaded him
to kill a thousand men.
In China, a she-fox became King Yu's
queen and brought down his kingdom.
Here in Japan,
a white fox with nine tails
caused great havoc in court
as Princess Tamamo,
before reverting back
to her true form.
They lost track of the white fox
after that,
but it's been suggested
she may have settled
in this area.
So beware, my lord, beware.
With your permission.
I make one small request,
and this is how you respond?
How could you do this?
You conspired with Kurogane
to humiliate me!
No, you're mistaken!
I won't hear it!
Stop, Kaede!
This was all Kurogane's doing!
It's always Kurogane.
Is that man your only vassal?
First he plays the villain
by killing Taro,
then he plays the hero
by saving Sué.
And to think
this two-headed monster
is your right-hand man!
Until I have Sué's head,
you'll not see me again!
Sister, I forgot my flute.
There's no time now.
But I've treasured it
since I was little.
What can we do?
Lord Kurogane said
your pursuers would be close behind.
I'll go back for it.
Your legs are weak.
I should be the one.
No, we're almost to the ruins
of your family's castle.
This is your only chance
to pray for your dead.
Once you escape from here,
you might never return.
Come, Tsurumaru.
Let us hurry.
There it is, Tsurumaru!
Our castle... what's left of it.
Where, Sué?
Over there.
Where is it?
Heaven and earth
have gone topsy-turvy.
I was once the fool
who made him laugh.
Now he's the fool,
and I'm the one laughing.
Don't just stand there.
Say something.
Blabber your nonsense
and I'll speak my truth...
and we'll have a good laugh
comparing the two.
Come on, old man!
A serpent once had an egg
pure and white,
while that of a bird
was speckled and dirty.
This must be a castle.
This is a stone wall.
The bird gave up the speckled egg
to lay on the white one.
This is strange.
The egg cracked open
and out came a snake.
Nothing but empty space
above the walls.
Why is that?
The bird was eaten
by the snake it hatched.
What is this place?
Who am I?
You're a stupid bird!
Saburo.
The pain!
I'm a worm.
Don't crush me.
Crush you? Who'd bother
to crush a worm like you?
Who are you?
Someone's crying.
Who could it be?
Damn it!
Man is born crying.
He cries and cries,
and then he dies!
My lord,
Saburo has crossed the river
and taken up a position
in Hachiman Field.
That's odd. What does he hope
to do with so few men?
- A messenger has come from Saburo.
- What?
His message?
Saburo has come
for your father.
He will withdraw
as soon as he has him.
My lord!
Lord Fujimaki is at the border.
I don't like this.
I told Lord Fujimaki
I didn't want him here.
There's nothing to fear.
With him up there, the enemy
will be pinned down once they arrive.
Meanwhile, we can safely fetch
your father from Azusano.
But it's such
a massive show of force.
One false move could mean war.
Was it hasty of me to come?
I came because I couldn't
just sit by and watch,
though Saburo will surely
be angry with me.
As long as we stay right here,
he shouldn't object.
Prepare to march!
My lord, this is not
the time to fight.
Tell Saburo
he can have your father.
Don't start a war.
I can't let him have Father.
Together they will accuse me
of treason and attack me.
Even if we wanted to turn over
your father, we don't know where he is.
Recent events have thrown
the whole domain into turmoil,
and Fujimaki and Ayabe
are looking for an opening.
We should be securing our bulwarks,
not marching into battle.
My lord,
I bring a message
from Lady Kaede.
She awaits you with sake
to celebrate your departure for battle.
A warrior riding into battle
mustn't leave his heart with a woman.
You must refrain.
The enemy approaches.
As soon as they're here,
we'll slip through those woods
to find his lordship.
Be patient.
Koyata, rest the horses.
Dismount!
Fool!
You're letting Kurogane
sway you again.
You're wrong!
To fight now
is not in our favor.
The leader's prowess
determines victory or defeat.
You have nothing to fear
from Fujimaki or Ayabe.
Your mistake
was sparing your father
just because he went mad.
But how can I kill him
if I don't know where he is?
I'm sure Saburo
knows where to find him.
Why else would he have come?
All you need do
is send a messenger to Saburo
saying he can take your father,
then dispatch your assassins
to follow him.
I've lost my way.
All men lose their way.
This path...
Looks familiar.
I've come this way before.
Men have been wandering
the same paths forever.
If you don't like it, then jump!
My lord!
Up there.
Who is that?
Sué!
Sister, whose voice was that?
This was her father's castle.
These are the ruins of the castle
that I burned down.
Why am I here?
Why is Sué here?
And Tsurumaru too!
Is this a dream?
No, this must be hell!
I'm in hell!
I'm in the depths of hell!
Mount!
A message from Lord Jiro!
Agreed.
He says they won't stand
in our way.
We're to take Father
and leave promptly.
Let us go at once.
No. We mustn't
reveal his whereabouts.
We'll wait until dark.
- My lord.
Ayabe's forces are massing
on that ridge.
The vulture!
He smells blood.
Remain calm, my lord.
On that ridge we have Ayabe.
On the other,
Fujimaki awaits his chance.
This is the moment of truth.
We must stand firm
and give them no excuse to attack.
He came to take Father,
yet he makes no move.
What's his plan?
Why is she taking so long?
I'll see what's keeping her.
No.
No, I don't need the flute.
You're acting like a child.
Sister, I don't ever want
to be alone again.
You won't be alone.
On this scroll is an image
of Amida Buddha.
It will protect you in my absence.
Sister!
I won't be gone long.
My lord!
I found Kyoami
in tears at Azusano.
Kyoami,
where's Lord Hidetora?
Forgive me!
I lost him.
You last saw my father
at Azusano?
We can no longer wait for dark.
Koyata!
Tango and I are going to Azusano.
Keep the enemy engaged here.
Ten of you
go with Lord Saburo!
They're on the move.
A detachment headed for Azusano,
with Saburo in the lead.
Gunnery captain!
Take your men to Azusano
and lay an ambush.
Whoever kills Saburo
will be the hero of this battle!
This is insanity!
Break your word
and it will mean war!
So be it.
It has to happen sometime.
- We'll have to fight the others too.
- What of it?
If Ayabe and Fujimaki
violate our borders,
we'll rout their forces
and make their lands our own!
Brave words,
but words don't win wars.
What happened to the man
who rebuked me for timidity?
Kaede was right.
You play the villain, but you're gutless!
Under her spell yet again?
Silence!
If you're opposed,
stay behind!
If you fear the fight,
then begone!
My lord!
How could I leave you, my lord?
Where would I go?
You have your orders, Captain!
Go!
Runner!
Take this message to Lord Saburo:
"Enemy gunners are on the way.
Be on guard."
Infantry...
forward!
He thinks he's clever.
All forces...
move into the woods!
Right face!
Forward!
Lord Saburo!
- Father!
- Lord Hidetora!
Father!
My lord!
Look at that sky!
Is this the other world?
Am I in paradise?
Father!
How can you be so cruel?
Why do you drag me
from my grave?
Father!
Don't you know me, Father?
Father?
Who are you calling father?
Wait. I remember now.
I had three sons.
Are you one of them?
Yes. I am Saburo.
- Saburo! Is it really you?
- Father!
I have no face to show you,
no words to excuse myself.
If you have poison for me,
I will drink it.
You mustn't talk like that.
I bear you no grudge.
Don't lie to me!
I've had my fill of honeyed words!
My lord, has Master Saburo
ever been one to lie?
False words roll freely
off many tongues,
but look at him, my lord.
These tears do not deceive.
Father,
come with me.
Come live with me
and forget this frightful dream.
Please forget what I did.
Forgive me.
I was a senile old fool.
Father!
All forces...
attack!
The enemy has taken cover
in the woods.
Our superior strength
is useless there.
Then we'll burn them out!
Charge!
Press the attack!
Pull back!
We should be crushing them!
Forward!
My lord!
Ayabe's army has crossed the border.
He's marching on your castle!
What?
Ayabe is on that ridge!
Damn it!
Those troops are decoys!
Pull back!
After them!
Cease pursuit!
Again!
I have so much to tell you.
Saburo,
you and I will talk quietly alone,
just father and son.
That's all I want.
Nothing else.
He's dead.
I've got wits enough to see that!
Saburo's dead.
You and I live...
but Saburo is -
You can't die.
I have things to tell you...
forgiveness to beg.
How can this be?
Are you really gone forever?
Don't touch me!
It grows dark.
Wretched old age!
This is the end.
My lord!
No, my lord!
Kyoami, do not call
his spirit back.
Would you have him suffer
still more?
Lord Saburo!
A surprise attack
by Ayabe's forces
has sent the enemy in retreat
to the First Castle!
Victory is ours!
How can this be?
Of all things, at this moment,
why did Master Saburo
have to die?
Why did Lord Hidetora
have to go?
Are there no gods,
no buddhas?
If you exist, hear my words:
You're all cruel
and fickle pranksters!
You ease your boredom
in the heavens
by crushing us like worms!
Damn you!
Is it such sport
to see us weep and howl?
Stop it!
Do not curse the gods!
It is they who weep.
In every age they've watched us
tread the path of evil,
unable to live
without killing each other.
They can't save us
from ourselves.
Stop your crying!
Such is the way of the world.
Men live not for joy
but for sorrow,
not for peace
but for suffering.
Look at those
in the First Castle.
Even now they vie for the greater
share of sorrow and suffering
and revel
in their mutual slaughter.
My lord!
We will defend this position.
You must go to the keep.
Inside!
Hurry up!
Close the gate!
Where's Lord Jiro?
Whose head is that,
Saburo's or Hidetora's?
Neither. It is another's,
on order of his lordship.
What?
Stop, Kurogane!
Who rules this domain,
you or Lady Kaede?
I pledged fealty to you,
but never to her!
She-fox!
Your vain schemes have destroyed
the house of Ichimonji!
Do you see now
how foolish you were?
On the contrary.
My sole desire
was to avenge my family
by watching
the house of Ichimonji fall
and seeing this castle burn.
Silence!
My lord,
we are undone.
Prepare to die.
I will follow you directly.
Directed by
AKIRA KUROSAWA
THE END