Men, are you over 40?
When you wake up in the morning,
do you feel tired and rundown?
Do you have that listless feeling?
- Jefferies.
- Congratulations, Jeff.
- For what?
- Getting rid of that cast.
Who said I was getting rid of it?
This is Wednesday,
Seven weeks from the day you
broke your leg, Yes or no?
Gunnison, how did you get
to be such a big editor
with such a small memory?
Thrift, industry and hard work...
and catching the publisher
with his secretary,
- did I get the wrong day?
- No,
No, wrong week.
Next Wednesday I emerge
from this... plaster cocoon.
That's too bad, Jeff. Well, I
guess I can't be lucky every day.
Forget I called,
Yeah, I sure feel
sorry for you, Gunnison,
Must be rough on you thinking of me
wearing this cast for another week.
That one week is gonna cost
me my best photographer,
and you a big assignment.
Where?
There's no point in
even talking about it,
Oh, come on, come on, Where?
Kashmir, Got a code tip from
the bureau chief this morning,
The place is about to go up in smoke,
What did I tell you? Didn't I tell
you that's the next place to watch?
- You did,
- When do I leave? Hour?
- With that cast on? You don't.
- Stop sounding stuffy.
I can take pictures from a jeep
or a water buffalo, if necessary,
You're too valuable to the
magazine for us to play around with,
- I'll send Morgan or Lambert,
- Morgan or Lambert,
That's fine.
I get myself half-killed for you,
and you reward me by
stealing my assignments,
I didn't ask you to stand in the
middle of an automobile racetrack,
You asked for something
dramatically different,
- You got it,
- So did you,
- Goodbye, Jeff.
- Now, wait a minute, Gunnison.
You've got to get me out of here.
Six weeks sitting in
a two-room apartment
with nothing to do but look out
the window at the neighbours,
- Bye, Jeff.
- No, Gunnison, I...
If you don't pull me out
of this swamp of boredom,
I'm gonna do something drastic,
- Like what?
- "Like what?" Get married,
Then I'll never be able to go anywhere,
It's about time you got married,
before you turn into a
lonesome and bitter, old man.
Yeah, can't you just see me?
Rushing home to a hot apartment
to listen to the automatic
laundry and the electric dishwasher
and the garbage disposal
and the nagging wife,
Jeff, wives don't nag
any more, they discuss,
Is that so? Is that so?
Maybe in the high-rent
district they discuss,
In my neighbourhood, they still nag,
Well, you know best,
I'll call you later,
Yeah, have some good
news the next time, huh?
Good morning, I said, "Good morning!"
Oh, good morning.
Say, I wouldn't dig
so deep if I were you.
You're giving them far too much water.
Why don't you shut up?
Well!
I do declare.
State sentence for a peeping tom,
is six months in the workhouse.
Oh, hello, sweetheart.
They got no windows in the workhouse.
In the old days, they used to put
your eyes out with a red-hot poker.
Any of those bikini bombshells
you're always watching
worth a red-hot poker?
Oh, dear.
We've become a race of Peeping Toms.
What people ought to do is
get outside their own house
and look in for a change.
Yes, sir. How's that for a
bit of homespun philosophy?
Reader's digest, April 1939.
Well, I only quote from the best.
You don't have to take my
temperature this morning.
Quiet. See if you can break 100.
You know, I should have
been a gypsy fortune-teller
instead of an insurance company nurse.
I got a nose for trouble.
Can smell it ten miles away.
You heard of that market
crash in '29? I predicted that.
Just how did you do that, Stella?
Oh, simple. I was nursing a
director of General Motors.
"Kidney ailment," they
said. "Nerves," I said.
Then I asked myself,
"What's General Motors
got to be nervous about?"
"Overproduction", I says. "Collapse."
When General Motors has to go
to the bathroom ten times a day,
the whole country's ready to let go.
You know, Stella, in
economics, a kidney ailment
has no relationship to the stock market.
- None whatsoever.
- Crashed, didn't it?
I can smell trouble right
here in this apartment.
First you smash your leg,
then you get to looking out the window,
see things you shouldn't see.
Trouble.
I can see you in court now
surrounded by a bunch of
lawyers in double-breasted suits.
You're pleading.
You say, "Judge, it was
only a bit of innocent fun."
I love my neighbours, like a father."
And the judge says,
'Well, congratulations.
"You've just given birth to
three years in Dannamora."
Right now, I'd welcome trouble.
You've got a hormone deficiency.
How can you tell from a thermometer?
Those bathing beauties
you've been watching
haven't raised your temperature
one degree in a month.
Here we go.
One more week.
I think you're right.
I think there is gonna
be trouble around here.
I knew it.
Ooh. Do you ever heat that stuff?
Gives your circulation
something to fight.
- What kind of trouble?
- Lisa Fremont.
You kidding? She's a
beautiful, young girl,
and you're a reasonably
healthy young man.
- She expects me to marry her.
- That's normal.
- I don't want to.
- That's abnormal.
I'm just not ready for marriage.
Every man's ready for marriage
when the right girl comes along.
Lisa Fremont is the right girl
for any man with half a brain
who can get one eye open.
She's alright.
- What did you do, have a fight?
- No.
- Father loading up the shotgun?
- What?
- Please, Stella.
- It's happened before, you know.
Some of the world's
happiest marriages have
started "under the gun",
as you might say.
- No, she's just not the girl for me.
- Yeah, she's only perfect.
She's too perfect. She's too talented.
She's too beautiful.
She's too sophisticated.
She's too everything, but what I want.
Is what you want
something you can discuss?
What? It's very simple, Stella.
She belongs to that rarefied
atmosphere of Park Avenue:
Expensive restaurants and
literary cocktail parties.
People with sense belong
wherever they're put.
Can you imagine her tramping
around the world with a camera bum
who never has more than a
week's salary in the bank?
If she was only ordinary.
You never gonna get married?
I'll probably get
married one of these days,
but when I do, it's gonna be
to someone who thinks of life
not just as a new dress
and a lobster dinner
and the latest scandal.
I need a woman who's
willing to... Hold it.
Who's willing to go anywhere
and do anything and love it.
So the honest thing for me to do
is just call the whole thing off.
Let her find somebody else.
Yeah, I can hear you now.
"Get out of my life, you
perfectly wonderful woman."
Look, Mr Jefferies, I'm
not an educated woman,
but I can tell you one thing.
When a man and a woman see
each other and like each other,
they ought to come together, wham,
like a couple of taxis on Broadway
and not sit around analysing each other
like two specimens in a bottle,
There's an intelligent
way to approach marriage.
Intelligence.
Nothing has caused the human race
so much trouble as intelligence.
Modern marriage.
- No, we've progressed emotionally.
- Baloney,
Once it was see somebody,
get excited, get married.
Now, it's read a lot of books,
fence with a lot of four-syllable
words, psychoanalyse each other
until you can't tell the difference
between a petting party
and a civil service exam.
People have different
emotional levels -
When I married Myles, we were both
a couple of maladjusted misfits,
We are still maladjusted, and
we have loved every minute of it.
Well, that's fine, Stella.
Now, would you fix
me a sandwich, please?
Yes, I will. And I'll spread a
little common sense on the bread.
Lisa's loaded to her
fingertips with love for you.
I got two words of
advice for you: Marry her.
- She pay you much?
- Oh.
There you are.
- Here's the key.
- Thank you.
Well, if you want anything, just ring.
Honey.
Come on.
Got to carry you over the threshold.
Window shopper.
How's your leg?
It hurts a little.
- And your stomach?
- Empty as a football.
And your love life?
Not too active.
Anything else bothering you?
Mm-hm.
Who are you?
Reading from top to bottom:
Lisa...
Carol...
Fremont.
Is this the Lisa Fremont who
never wears the same dress twice?
Only because it's expected of her.
It's right off the Paris plane.
- Do you think it'll sell?
- That depends on the quote,
Let's see now. There's
the aeroplane ticket over,
import duties, hidden taxes,
- profit markup -
- A steal at $1,100.
Eleven hundred?
They ought to list that
dress on the stock exchange.
We sell a dozen a day
in this price range.
Who buys them, tax collectors?
Even if I had to pay,
it would be worth it.
- Just for the occasion.
- Why, is something big going on?
It's going on right
here. It's a big night.
It's just an old
run-of-the-mill Wednesday.
The calendar's full of them.
It's opening night of the last depressing
week of L B Jefferies in a cast.
Well, I haven't noticed
a big demand for tickets.
That's because I bought out the house.
You know, this cigarette
box has seen better days.
I picked that up in Shanghai,
which has also seen better days.
It's cracked and you never use it.
It's too ornate.
I'm sending up a plain, flat,
silver one with your initials.
That's no way to spend
your hard-earned money.
I wanted to.
Ooh!
What would you think of starting
off with dinner at '21 '?
You have, perhaps, an
ambulance downstairs?
No, better than that: '21 '.
Thank you for waiting, Carl, The
kitchen's right there on the left,
I'll take the wine.
- Good evening, Mr Jefferies.
- Carl,
Just put everything in
the oven, Carl, on low.
- Let's open the wine now.
- Alright,
- It's a Montrachet.
- A great big glassful.
There's a corkscrew right over there.
Here, I'll do it.
- Big enough?
- Yeah, they're fine.
I can't think of anything
more boring or tiresome
than what you've been through and
the last week must be the hardest.
Alright. Yeah, I want to get
this thing off and get moving.
Well, I'm going to make this
a week you'll never forget.
Fine, thanks.
Just a minute, Carl.
- This will take care of the taxi.
- Thank you, Miss Fremont.
- Have a pleasant dinner, Mr Jefferies.
- Alright, Good night.
Good night.
What a day I've had.
- Are you tired?
- Not a bit.
I was all morning in a meeting,
then I had to dash to the Waldorf
for a quick drink with Madam Dufrene,
who's just over from Paris
with some spy reports.
Then I had to go to '21' and have
lunch with the Harper's Bazaar people,
That's when I ordered dinner.
Then I had two fall
showings 20 blocks apart.
Then I had to have a cocktail
with Leland and Slim Hayward.
We're trying to get his new show.
Then I had to dash back and change.
Well, now, tell me, what
was Mrs Hayward wearing?
- She looked wonderfully cool.
- She didn't, did she?
She had on the most divine
Italian hand-printed -
- Oh, Italian?
- Oh, you.
- Italian. Imagine.
- To think I planted three nice items
- in the columns about you today.
- You did?
- You can't buy that kind of publicity.
- I know.
Someday you may want to open
up a studio of your own here.
How would I run it from, say, Pakistan?
Jeff...
Isn't it time you came home?
You could pick your assignment.
- I wish there was one I wanted.
- Make the one you want.
- You mean leave the magazine?
- Yes.
- For what?
- For yourself and me.
I could get you a dozen
assignments tomorrow:
Fashions, portraits.
- Now, don't laugh. I could do it.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
Can you see me driving down
to the fashion salon in a jeep
wearing combat boots and a three-day
beard? Wouldn't that make a hit?
I could see you looking
very handsome and successful
in a dark blue, flannel suit.
Let's stop talking nonsense, shall we?
Hm?
Guess I'd better start
setting up for dinner.
♪ To see you
♪ Is to love you
♪ And I see you
♪ Everywhere
♪ In the sunrise
♪ In the moonglow
♪ Anyplace I look
♪ You're there
♪ To see you
♪ Is to want you
♪ And I see you all the time
♪ On a sidewalk
♪ In a doorway
♪ On the lonely stairs I climb
♪ Someday
♪ Let me show you
♪ How happy endings start
♪ You'll find
♪ how well I know you
♪ Cause to know you at all
♪ Is to know you by heart
♪ To see you
♪ Is to love you
♪ And you're never out of sight
♪ And I love you
♪ And I'll see you
♪ In the same old dream
♪ Tonight ♪
Miss Lonelyhearts,
At least that's something
you'll never have to worry about.
Oh?
You can see my apartment from
here, all the way up on 63rd Street?
No, not exactly, but we
have a little apartment here
that's probably as popular as yours.
You remember, of course,
Miss Torso, the ballet dancer?
She's like a queen bee
with her pick of the drones,
I'd say she's doing
a woman's hardest job,
Juggling wolves,
Thank you.
Well, she picked the most
prosperous-looking one.
She's not in love with
him... or any of them.
Oh, how can you tell that from here?
You said it resembled
my apartment, didn't you?
I hope they're cooked this time.
Where's that wonderful
music coming from?
Some songwriter over there
in the studio apartment.
Well...
He lives alone.
Probably had a very unhappy marriage.
Oh, it's enchanting.
It's almost as if it were
being written especially for us.
Hm. No wonder he's having
so much trouble with it.
At least you can't say
the dinner isn't right.
Lisa... it's perfect.
As always.
There can't be that much difference
between people and the way they live.
We all eat, talk, drink,
laugh, wear clothes.
Well, now look -
If you're saying all this because
you don't want to tell me the truth,
because you're hiding something
from me, then maybe I can understand.
I'm not hiding anything.
It's just that -
It doesn't make sense.
What's so different about it
here from there or anyplace you go
that one person couldn't live
in both places just as easily?
Some people can. Now,
if you'll just let me -
What is it but travelling from one
place to another taking pictures?
It's like being a tourist
on an endless vacation.
OK. That's your opinion.
You're entitled to it.
- Now, let me give you my side.
- It's ridiculous to say
that it can only be done by a special,
private little group of anointed people.
I made a simple statement,
a true statement,
but I can back it up if you'll
just shut up for a minute.
If your opinion is as rude as your
manner, I don't think I care to hear it.
Oh, come on now. Simmer down.
I can't fit in here.
You can't fit in there.
According to you, people
should be born, live and die
- on the same spot!
- Shut up!
- Did you ever eat fish heads and rice?
- Of course not.
Well, you might have
to if you went with me.
Did you ever try to keep
warm in a C-54 at 15,000 feet,
20 degrees below zero?
Oh, I do it all the time,
whenever I have a few
minutes after lunch.
Did you ever get shot at? Run over?
Did you ever get sandbagged
because somebody got unfavourable
publicity from your camera?
Did you ever... Those high heels,
they'll be great in the jungle.
And the nylons and
those six-ounce lingerie.
- Three.
- Alright, three.
They'll make a big hit in Finland,
just before you freeze to death.
Well, if there's one thing I know,
it's how to wear the proper clothes.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, try and find a raincoat in
Brazil, even when it isn't raining.
Lisa, in this job you
carry one suitcase.
Your home is the
available transportation.
You don't sleep very
much. You bathe less.
And sometimes the food that you eat
is made from things that you couldn't
even look at when they're alive.
Jeff, you don't have to be deliberately
repulsive just to impress me I'm wrong.
Deliberately repulsive? I'm
trying to make it sound good.
You just have to face it, Lisa, you're
not meant for that kind of a life.
Few people are.
- You're too stubborn to argue with.
- I'm not stubborn. I'm just truthful.
I know, a lesser man would have
told me it was one long holiday,
and I would have awakened
to a rude disillusionment.
Well, now, wait a minute.
If you want to get vicious on this
thing, I'd be happy to accommodate you.
No, I don't particularly want that.
So that's it?
You won't stay here,
and I can't go with you.
It would be the wrong thing.
You don't think either one
of us could ever change?
Right now it doesn't seem so.
I
- I'm in love with you.
I don't care what you do for a living.
I'd like to be part of it somehow.
It's deflating to find out the
only way I can be part of it,
is to take out a
subscription to your magazine.
I guess I'm not the
girl I thought I was.
There's nothing wrong with you, Lisa.
You've got this town in
the palm of your hand.
Not quite, it seems.
Goodbye, Jeff.
You mean good night.
- I mean what I said,
- Well, Lisa...
couldn't we just...
Couldn't we just...
keep things status quo?
Without any future?
Well, when am I gonna see you again?
Not for a long time.
At least... not until tomorrow night.
Hey! Rain.
Grab that. Wait, I'll get the clock.
Oh, no!
Pull it.
Pull on it. Let me do it.
In you go.
No, you can't come
in. It's much too late.
No, not now,
No, I said good night.
What's that supposed to be, ma'am?
It's called hunger.
You'd think the rain would
have cooled things off.
- All it did was make the heat wet.
- Ahh, that's it.
That's stiff right there. Right there.
The insurance company
would be much happier
if you'd sleep in bed at night
instead of in that wheelchair.
- How do you know?
- Eyes are all bloodshot.
Must have been watching
out that window for hours.
Yeah, I was.
What are you gonna do if
one of them catches you?
It depends which one.
Miss Torso, for example -
You keep your mind off her.
She sure is the 'eat,
drink and be merry' girl.
Yeah, she'll wind up fat,
alcoholic and miserable.
Yeah.
Speaking of misery,
poor Miss Lonelyhearts.
She drank herself to sleep again, alone.
Poor soul. Maybe one day
she'll find her happiness.
Yeah, and some man will lose his.
Isn't there anybody in the neighbourhood
who could cast an eye in her direction?
Well...
It might just be that the
salesman will be available soon.
Oh, him and his wife splitting up?
I just can't figure it.
He went out several times
last night in the rain,
- carrying his sample case.
- Well, he's a salesman, isn't he?
What would he be selling at
three o'clock in the morning?
Flashlights. Luminous dials for watches.
House numbers that light up.
I don't think so.
I think he was taking
something out of the apartment.
Uh-huh. His personal effects.
He's gonna run out on her, the coward.
Yeah. Sometimes it's worse
to stay than it is to run.
Yeah, well, it takes a particularly
low type of man to do a thing like that.
How about this morning?
Any further developments?
The shades are all
drawn in the apartment.
- In this heat?
- Yeah.
Well, they're up now.
- Get back! Get back.
- Where do you want me to go?
- Come on, get out of sight.
- What's the matter?
That salesman's looking
out of his window. You see?
Get back! He'll see you.
I'm not shy. I've been looked at before.
That's no ordinary look,
That's the kind of look a man gives
when he's afraid somebody
might be watching him.
Get away from there,
He'll be after you.
Go on, into the house.
Into the house. Shoo, shoo.
Goodbye, Mr Jefferies. See you tomorrow.
Uh-huh.
- And don't sleep in that
chair again. - Uh-huh.
"Uh-huh. Uh-huh."
Great conversationalist.
Stella...
Take those binoculars out
and bring them here, will you?
Trouble.
I can smell it.
I'll be glad when they crack that
cast, and I can get outta here.
Uh-huh.
How far does a girl have to
go before you'll notice her?
Well, if she's pretty enough,
she doesn't have to go anywhere.
She just has to 'be. '
Well, ain't I?
Pay attention to me.
I'm not exactly on the
other side of the room.
Your mind is... and when I
want a man, I want all of him.
Don't you ever have any problems?
I have one now.
So do I.
Tell me about it.
Why?
Why would a man leave
his apartment three times
on a rainy night with a suitcase,
and come back three times?
He likes the way his
wife welcomes him home.
No, no. Not this salesman's wife.
And why didn't he go to work today?
Homework. It's more interesting.
What's interesting about a butcher knife
and a small saw
wrapped in newspaper?
Nothing, thank heaven.
Why hasn't he been in his
wife's bedroom all day?
I wouldn't dare answer that.
Well, listen. I'll answer it, Lisa.
There's something terribly wrong.
- And I'm afraid it's with me,
- What do you think?
Something too frightful to utter.
He went out a few minutes ago in
his undershirt, hasn't come back,
That would be a terrible job to tackle,
Just how would you start
to cut up a human body?
Jeff, I'll be honest with you.
You're beginning to scare me.
Jeff, did you hear what I said?
You're beginning to scare -
Shh! He's coming back!
- Jeff, if you could only see yourself!
- What's the matter?
Sitting around looking out of the
window to kill time is one thing,
but doing it the way
you are with binoculars
and wild opinions about every
little thing you see is diseased!
Do you think I consider it recreation?
I don't know what you consider it,
but if you don't stop it,
I'm getting out of here.
- What's the - - What
is it you're looking for?
I just want to find out what's the
matter with the salesman's wife.
Does that make me sound like a madman?
What makes you think there's
something the matter with her?
A lot of things. She's an
invalid. She demands constant care.
Yet not the husband or anybody else
has been in to see her all day. Why?
- Maybe she died.
- Where's the doctor?
Where's the undertaker?
She could be sleeping, under sedatives.
He's in there now.
There's nothing to see.
There is something. I've
seen it through that window.
I've seen bickering and family quarrels
and mysterious trips at night
and knives and saws and rope.
Now, since last evening, not a sign
of the wife. Tell me where she is.
- I don't know.
- What's she doing?
Maybe he's leaving his wife.
I don't know. I don't care!
Lots of people have knives and
saws and ropes around their houses.
And lots of men don't speak
to their wives all day.
Lots of wives nag and men
hate them and trouble starts,
but few of them end up in murder,
if that's what you're thinking.
It's pretty hard for you to keep
away from that word, isn't it?
You could see all that
he did, couldn't you?
- Of course, I - - You could
see cos the shades were up
and he walked along the corridor
and the street and the backyard.
I've seen him -
Jeff, do you think a murderer
would let you see all that?
That he wouldn't pull the
shades down and hide behind them?
He's being clever.
He's being nonchalant.
And that's where
you're not bring clever.
A murderer would never parade his
crime in front of an open window.
Why not?
For all you know, there's
something sinister going on there.
Where? Oh.
No comment.
Let's start from the
beginning again, Jeff.
Tell me everything you saw
and what you think it means.
Yeah?
"The name on the second floor
rear mail box reads, 'Mr and Mrs Lars',"
"That's L-A-R-S,"
"Lars Thorwald,"
What's the number of the apartment?
"125 West Ninth Street,"
Thank you, dear.
"OK, chief, What's my next assignment?"
Just go home.
"Alright, but what's he doing now?"
He's just sitting in the
living room in the dark.
Hasn't gone near the bedroom.
Now you go home and get
some sleep. Good night.
"Good night,"
"What's it about, Jeff?"
Look, Doyle, I can't
tell you over the phone.
You have to be here and
see the whole set-up.
It's probably nothing. It's just
a little neighbourhood murder.
- 'Did you say murder?'
- Yes, as a matter of fact, I did.
"Oh, come now,"
My only thought was throwing a
little business your way, that's all.
I figured a detective would jump at
the chance of something to detect.
- "I'm not working,"
- What?
"This happens to be my day off,"
I usually took my best
pictures on my day off.
- "I'll drop by,"
- OK, Doyle. As soon as you can.
Bless your heart, Stella.
Gee whiz, look at this.
I can't tell you what
a welcome sight this is.
No wonder your husband still loves you.
- The police.
- What?
- You called the police.
- Well, not exactly.
Not an official call.
It's an old friend of mine.
An old, ornery friend of mine.
Just where do you suppose he cut her up?
Of course. The bathtub.
That's the only place where he
could have washed away the blood.
He better get that trunk out of
there before it starts to leak.
Harry?
Look, look, Mr Jefferies,
I thought Doyle would be here
by the time the trunk left,
or I'd have called the police.
Now we're gonna lose it.
- Hold everything.
- Don't do anything foolish.
I'm just gonna get the
name off that freight truck.
I'll keep an eye on the alley.
Long distance.
You didn't see the killing or the body.
How do you know there was a murder?
Because everything this fellow's
done has been suspicious:
Trips at night in the rain, knives
and saws and trunks with rope,
and now this wife that
isn't there any more.
I admit it all has a mysterious sound.
It could be any number of things.
Murder's the least possible.
Doyle, don't tell me he's
an unemployed magician,
amusing the neighbourhood
with his sleight of hand.
Don't tell me that.
It's too obvious and stupid
a way to commit murder.
In full view of 50 windows?
Then sit there smoking a cigar,
waiting for the police to pick him up.
Alright, officer, do your
duty. Go over and pick him up.
Jeff, you've got a lot
to learn about homicide.
Why, morons have committed
murder so shrewdly,
it's taken a hundred trained
police minds to catch them.
That salesman wouldn't just
knock his wife off after dinner
and toss her in the trunk
and put her in storage.
I'll bet it's been done.
Most everything's been
done... under panic.
This is a
thousand-to-one shot.
He's still sitting around the
apartment. That man's not panicked.
You think I made all this up?
Well, I think you saw something
there's probably a very
simple explanation for.
- For instance?
- Wife took a trip.
His wife was sick in bed.
Yeah, so you told me.
Well, Jeff, I've got to run along.
I won't report this to the department.
Let me poke into it a little on my own.
No sense in your getting a
lot of ridiculous publicity.
Thank you.
We know the wife is gone, so
I'll see if I can find out where.
Do that.
You had any headaches lately?
Not till you showed up.
It will wear off, along
with the hallucinations.
See you around.
Get along.
He has a six months' lease.
Used up a little more than
five and a half months of it.
He's quiet, drinks,
but not to drunkenness.
Pays his bills promptly
with money earned
as a costume jewellery
salesman: Wholesale.
Kept to himself. No neighbours
got close to him or his wife.
Yeah, well, I think they
missed their chance with her.
She never left the apartment,
until yesterday morning.
- What time?
- 6:00am.
6:00am.
I think that's about
the time I fell asleep.
Too bad.
Thorwalds were leaving their
apartment at just that time.
Feel a little foolish?
No, not yet.
- How's your wife?
- Oh, she's fine.
Who said they left then?
- W-Who left where? -
The Thorwalds, at 6:00am,
Oh, the building
superintendent and two tenants.
Flat statements, no hesitation.
They jived with the letter.
Thorwalds were on their
way to the railroad station.
Well, now, Tom, how could
anybody possibly guess that?
What, did they have signs
on their luggage saying,
'Grand Central, or bust'?
The superintendent met
Thorwald on his way back.
Thorwald told him that he'd put
his wife on a train to the country.
I see. I'd say this is a pretty
convenient guy, this superintendent.
Have you checked his
bank statements lately?
- Huh?
- Well, what good's his information?
It's a secondhand version of an
unsupported story by the murderer.
Now did anybody actually see
the wife get on the train?
I hate to remind you,
but this all started because
you said she was murdered.
Now, did anyone, including
you, actually see her murdered?
What are you doing?
Are you interested in solving this
case or making me look foolish?
Well, if possible, both.
Then do a good job of it.
Go over there and search
Thorwald's apartment.
It must be knee-deep in evidence.
I can't do that.
I don't mean right now, but
when he goes out for a drink,
or a paper, or something, What
he doesn't know won't hurt him,
I can't do that even if he isn't there.
What's he...
Does he have a courtesy card from
the police department or something?
Now don't get me mad.
Not even a detective can walk
into an apartment and search it.
If I were caught in there, they'd
have my badge within ten minutes.
Make sure you don't
get caught, that's all,
If you find something,
you've got a murderer,
and they don't care about
a couple of house rules.
If you don't find anything,
the fellow's clear.
At the risk of sounding stuffy,
I'd like to remind you of the
Constitution and the phrase,
'search warrant issued by a judge'
who knows the Bill of Rights verbatim,
- He must ask for evidence,
- Give him evidence.
Yeah, I can hear myself,
"Your Honour, I have a friend
who's an amateur sleuth."
"The other night, after
having a heavy dinner, he..."
He'd throw the New York
State penal code in my face,
and there's six volumes.
By tomorrow morning there
may not be any evidence left
over in that apartment, you know that.
It's a detective's nightmare.
What do you need before you can search?
Tell me now, what do you need?
Bloody footsteps leading up to the door?
One thing I don't need is heckling.
You called me and asked for help.
Now you're behaving like a taxpayer.
How did we ever stand
each other in that plane
for three years during the war?
I guess I'll go over
to the railroad station
and check on Thorwald's story.
Oh, forget about the story,
Find the trunk. Mrs Thorwald's in it.
Oh, I almost forgot.
There was a postcard in
Thorwald's mailbox. It was...
mailed 3:30 yesterday
afternoon from Merritsville,
That's 80 miles north of here,
Message went: 'Arrived OK.
Already feeling better. Love, Anna. '
Uh... is that, um...
Anna... Is that who I think it is?
- Mrs Thorwald.
- Uh-huh.
Oh, so anything you need, Jeff?
You might send me a good detective.
- Oh, by the way, where's the gin?
- I'll get the gin.
Much faster, and swing the left arm up.
- ♪ Many dreams ago
- Try it again.
♪ I dreamed many dreams
♪ Waiting for
♪ My true love
♪ To appear
♪ Though each night
♪ It seems
♪ Someone filled
♪ My dreams
♪ Still the face that I kissed
♪ Wasn't clear
♪ So I let my heart dance
♪ Through many
♪ Sweet refrains
♪ But now
♪ Just one song
♪ And just one
♪ dream remains
♪ That one song is you
♪ And at last
♪ I know
♪ You're the one
♪ I dreamed of
♪ Many dreams
♪ Ago
- "Hello? Yes?"
- Hello, Miss Doyle?
This is Jeff again. Has Tom come in yet?
"Not yet, Jeff,"
You mean you haven't
even heard from him?
"Not a word, Is it something
really important, Jeff?"
Yeah, I'm afraid it is.
"I'll have him call the
moment I hear from him,"
No, no, don't bother to do that.
Just have him get over
here as soon as he can.
Looks like Thorwald's
pulling out tonight.
- " Who's Thorwald?"
- He'll know, he'll know.
And Thorwald's a man, don't worry.
- "Good night, you idiot,"
- Good night.
Long distance again.
There's somebody at the door,
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hello.
- What'd you do to your
hair? - Oh, I just -
Take a look at Thorwald. He's
getting ready to pull out.
He doesn't seem to be in any hurry.
He's been laying out all his
things on one of the beds:
Shirts, suits, coats, socks.
Even that alligator handbag
his wife left on the bedpost.
He had it hidden in the
dresser. At least, it was there.
He took it out, went to the telephone
and made a long distance call.
He had his wife's
jewellery in the handbag.
Seemed worried about it. Asked
someone's advice over the phone.
Someone not his wife.
Well, I never saw him
ask her for advice.
She volunteered plenty, but I
never saw him ask her for any.
- I wonder where he's going.
- I don't know.
- Suppose he doesn't come back?
- He'll be back. His things are there.
- I guess it's safe to put on lights.
- No, not yet!
OK, you can turn it on now. He must
have gone someplace to the right.
All day long, I've been trying
to keep my mind on my work.
- Thinking about Thorwald?
- And you, and your friend, Doyle.
- Did you hear from him since he left?
- Not a word,
He said he was gonna check the
railroad station and the trunk,
He must be still at it.
Something on your mind?
- It doesn't make sense to me.
- What doesn't?
Women aren't that unpredictable.
Hmm. Well, I can't guess
what you're thinking.
A woman has a favourite handbag,
and it always hangs on her bedpost
where she can get at it easily.
Then, all of a sudden, she goes away
on a trip and leaves it behind. Why?
Because she didn't know
she was going on a trip,
and where she's going, she
wouldn't need the handbag.
Yes, but only her
husband would know that.
And that jewellery
- Women don't keep their jewellery in a purse
getting all twisted and
scratched and tangled up.
Well, do they hide it in
their husband's clothes?
They do not. And they don't
leave it behind either.
Why, a woman going
anywhere but the hospital
would always take make-up,
perfume and jewellery.
Put that over there.
That's inside stuff, huh?
It's basic equipment.
And you don't leave it behind
in your husband's drawer
in your favourite handbag.
Well, I'm with you,
sweetie. I'm with you.
Tom Doyle has a pat
answer for that though.
That Mrs Thorwald left at 6:00am
yesterday with her husband?
According to those witnesses.
Well, I have a pat
rebuttal for Mr Doyle.
Couldn't have been Mrs
Thorwald, or I don't know women.
- What about the witnesses?
- We'll agree they saw a woman,
but she was not Mrs Thorwald.
- That is, not yet.
- Is that so?
Come here.
I'd like to see your friend's
face when we tell him.
He doesn't sound like
much of a detective.
Oh, don't be too hard on
him. He's a steady worker.
I sure wish he'd show up.
Don't rush him. We have all night.
- We have all what?
- Night.
I'm going to stay with you.
Well, you'll have to clear
that with my landlord.
I have the whole weekend off.
That's very nice, but
I just have one bed.
If you say anything else,
I'll... stay tomorrow night too.
I won't be able to
give you any... pyjamas.
You said I'll have to
live out of one suitcase.
- I'll bet yours isn't this small.
- This is a suitcase?
Well, a Mark Cross overnight case.
- Ooh.
- Compact, but, uh... ample enough.
Looks like you packed in a hurry.
Look at this. Isn't that amazing?
I'll trade you... my feminine
intuition for a bed for the night.
I'll go along with that.
There's that song again.
Where does a man get inspiration
to write a song like that?
Well, he gets it from
the landlady once a month.
It's utterly beautiful.
- I wish I could be creative.
- Oh, sweetie, you are.
Y- Y-You have a great talent for
creating difficult situations.
- I do?
- Sure.
Like staying here all night uninvited.
Well, surprise is the most
important element of attack.
Besides, you're not up on
your private eye literature.
When they're in trouble,
it's always their Girl Friday
that gets them out of it.
Is she the girl that saves
them from the clutches
of the over-passionate
daughters of the rich?
- The same.
- That's the one, huh?
It's funny. He never ends
up marrying her, does he?
- That's strange,
- Weird.
Why don't I slip into
something more comfortable?
By all means.
I mean, like the kitchen
and make us some coffee.
Oh, and some brandy too, huh?
Harry,
- Jeff.
- Hi.
What else have you got
on this man Thorwald?
Enough to scare me you wouldn't
show up in time and we'd lose him.
- Think he's getting out of here?
- He's got everything he owns
laid out over there in the
bedroom, waiting to be packed.
I'm just warming some
brandy. Mr Doyle, I presume?
Tom, this is Miss Lisa Fremont,
- How do you do?
- We think Thorwald's guilty.
Careful, Tom.
- Hello.
- Lieutenant doyle,
Yeah, he's right here. For you.
- Hello.
- Lieutenant doyle, sir?
Speaking. Yeah.
Alright.
I see. Thank you... Goodbye.
Coffee will be ready soon.
Jeff, aren't you going to
tell him about the jewellery?
Jewellery?
He's got his wife's jewellery hidden
in his clothes in the bedroom there.
- You sure it belonged to his wife?
- It was in her favourite handbag.
Mr Doyle, that can only
lead to one conclusion.
Namely?
That it was not Mrs Thorwald that
left with him yesterday morning.
You figured that out, eh?
It's simply that women don't
leave their jewellery behind
when they go on a trip.
Come on, Tom. You don't really need
any of this information, do you?
As a matter of fact, I don't.
Lars Thorwald is no more
a murderer than I am.
You can explain everything
that's going on over there?
No, and neither can you.
That's a secret, private world
you're looking into out there.
People do a lot of things in
private they couldn't do in public.
Like disposing of their wives?
Get that idea out of your mind. It'll
only lead in the wrong direction.
What about the knife and the saw?
- Did you ever own a saw? - Well,
at home in the garage I had -
How many people did you cut up with it?
Or with the couple hundred knives
you've owned in your lifetime?
Your logic is backward.
You can't ignore the disappearance
and the trunk and the jewellery.
I checked the railroad
station. He bought a ticket.
Ten minutes later, he
put his wife on the train.
Destination: Merritsville.
The witnesses are that deep.
That might have been a woman, but
it couldn't have been Mrs Thorwald.
- That jewellery -
- Look, Miss Fremont.
That feminine intuition
stuff sells magazines
but in real life, it's
still a fairy tale.
I don't know how many
wasted years I've spent,
tracking down leads
based on female intuition.
Alright! I take it you
didn't find the trunk,
All this is from an old speech
you made at the policemen's ball.
I found the trunk a
half-hour after I left here.
I suppose it's normal for a man
to tie up a trunk with heavy rope?
If the lock is broken, yes.
What did you find inside the
trunk, a surly note to me?
Mrs Thorwald's clothes;
Clean, well-packed, not
stylish, but presentable.
Didn't you take them
off to the crime lab?
I sent them on their
merry and legal way.
Why, when a woman is
taking a simple, short trip,
does she take everything she owns?
Let's let the female psychology
department handle that one.
I would say it looked as
if she wasn't coming back.
That's what's known as a family problem.
If she wasn't coming back, why
didn't he tell his landlord?
I'll tell you why he
didn't tell his landlord,
because he was hiding something.
Do you tell your landlord everything?
Ah, I told you to be careful, Tom.
If I'd have been careful
piloting that reconnaissance plane
you wouldn't have had the
chance to take the pictures
that won you a medal, and a
good job, and fame, and money.
What do you say, we all sit down
and have a nice friendly drink.
Forget all about this.
We can tell lies about the
good old days during the war.
You mean you're through with the case?
There is no case to be
through with, Miss Fremont.
How about that drink?
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Well, I think I better get
home and get some sleep.
Cheers.
I, uh... I'm not much of a snifter.
Oh, Jeff, if you need any more help...
consult the Yellow Pages
in your telephone directory.
Oh, I love funny exiting lines.
- Who was that trunk addressed to?
- Mrs Anna Thorwald.
Then let's wait and
find out who picks it up.
Oh, that phone call, I
gave them your number.
- I hope you don't mind.
- Depends on who they were.
The police at Merritsville.
They reported the trunk
was just picked up...
by Mrs Anna Thorwald.
Don't stay up too late.
- Look.
- What?
Yeah, he's kind of young, isn't he?
What are you doing?
♪ Or just a cold and lonely
♪ Lovely work of art ♪ -
You know, much as I hate to give
Thomas J Doyle too much credit,
he might have gotten ahold
of something when he said
that was pretty private
stuff going on out there.
I wonder if it's ethical to watch a man
with binoculars and a long-focus lens,
Do you...
Do you suppose it's ethical, even if
you prove that he didn't commit a crime?
I'm not much on rear window ethics.
Of course, they can do
the same thing to me,
watch me like a bug under
a glass, if they want to.
Jeff, if someone came in here, they
wouldn't believe what they'd see.
- What?
- You and me with long faces,
plunged into despair because we
find out a man didn't kill his wife.
We're two of the most frightening
ghouls I've ever known.
You'd think we could be a bit happy
that the poor woman is alive and well.
Whatever happened to that old
saying, 'Love thy neighbour'?
You know, I think I'll
start reviving that tomorrow.
Yeah, I'll begin with Miss Torso.
Not if I have to move into
an apartment across the way...
and do the 'Dance of the
Seven Veils' every hour.
Show's over for tonight.
Preview of coming attractions.
Did Mr Doyle think I stole this case?
No, Lisa, I don't think he did.
- What do you think?
- Well, uh...
- I will rephrase the question.
- Thank you,
Do you like it?
- Yes, I like
it. - Well -
What's the matter?
- Somebody's hurt?
- It's the dog,
Something's happened to the dog.
Somebody fall out a window?
I think it's a dog.
It's dead. It's been
strangled. Its neck is broken.
Which one of you did it?
Which one of you killed my dog?
You don't know the meaning
of the word 'neighbours'.
Neighbours like each other,
speak to each other, care
if anybody lives or dies!
But none of you do!
But I couldn't imagine
any of you being so low
that you'd kill a
helpless, friendly dog.
The only thing in this whole
neighbourhood who liked anybody!
Did you kill him because he liked
you? Just because he liked you?
Let's go inside.
- Come on. Let's go back in.
- It's only a dog.
You know, for a minute,
that Tom Doyle almost had me
convinced I was wrong.
- But you're not?
- Look.
In the courtyard, only one person
didn't come to the window. Look.
Why would Thorwald want
to kill a little dog?
Because it knew too much?
You think this is worth
waiting all day to see?
Is he cleaning house?
He's washing down the bathroom walls.
Hm, must have splattered a lot.
Well, why not? That's
what we're all thinking.
He killed her in there, he
has to clean up those stains.
Oh, Stella, your choice of words.
Nobody ever invented a
polite word for a killing yet,
Lisa, back there on that shelf,
there's a little yellow box, you see it?
- Top one?
- Right on top, yeah.
And bring me the viewer there.
I just got a... These
are about two weeks old.
I hope I took something else
besides leg art. Now which one...
What are you looking for?
There's something, and if I'm
right, I think I've solved a murder.
- Mrs Thorwald?
- No.
No, the dog.
Uh-huh. I think I know why
Thorwald killed that dog.
Here, now you take a
look. Tell me what you see.
Now take it down,
Now look again,
Now take it down, You see?
It's just a picture of the backyard -
But with one important
change. One important change.
Those flowers in
Thorwald's pet flower bed.
You mean where the dog
was sniffing around?
Where the dog was digging.
Now look at those flowers.
Look, those two yellow
zinnias on this end
aren't as tall as they were,
Since when do flowers
grow shorter in two weeks?
- There's something buried there.
- Mrs Thorwald.
You haven't spent much time
around cemeteries, have you?
Mr Thorwald could scarcely
put his wife's body
in a plot of ground
about one foot square.
Unless, of course, he put
her in standing on end,
and then he wouldn't
need a knife and saw.
No, my idea is she's
scattered all over town.
- Leg in the East River
- - Oh, Stella, please!
No, no, no. There's something in there.
Those flowers have been
taken out and put back in.
- Maybe it's the
knife and saw. - Yeah -
- Call Lieutenant Doyle.
- No, let's wait.
Let's wait till it gets a little darker,
and I'll go over there and dig them up.
You'll go? You won't dig anything
up and get your neck broken.
No, no, we've...
We're not gonna call Doyle until
I can produce Mrs Thorwald's body.
What we've got to do is find a
way to get into that apartment.
He's packing.
Uh-oh,
Here, get me a pencil.
Stella, get me some note
paper. It's up here someplace.
There it is.
You did it, Thorwald, You did it,
- Look out, Lisa. He's coming.
- You never should have let her do it.
- If he ever - -
Look. Look. Look.
Thank heaven that's over.
- Alright if I have a drink?
- Sure, go ahead.
There's no doubt about it, He's
leaving, It's just a question of when,
Mind if I use that portable keyhole?
Go ahead, just as long as you
tell me what you're looking at.
- I wonder...
- Wonder what?
Miss Lonelyhearts just laid
out something that looks like
rhodium tri-eckonal capsules,
- You can tell from here?
- I've handled enough of those
to put everybody in Hackensack
to sleep for the winter,
- Does she have enough of them
to - - To make her rest easier -
Wasn't that close?
What was his reaction
when he looked at the note?
It wasn't the kind of
expression that would get him
a quick loan at the bank.
Jeff, the handbag!
Suppose Mrs Thorwald's wedding ring
is among the jewellery
he has in that handbag?
Now, during the phone conversation
he held up three rings:
One with a diamond, one with
a big stone of some sort,
and then just a plain gold band.
The last thing she would leave
behind would be her wedding ring.
Stella, do you ever leave yours at home?
The only way anybody could get that
ring would be to chop off my finger.
Let's go down and find out
what's buried in the garden.
Why not? I've always
wanted to meet Mrs Thorwald.
- What are you two talking
about - - You got a shovel?
Of course I don't have a shovel.
- There's probably one in the basement.
- If you're squeamish, just don't look.
Squeamish? I'm not squeamish.
I just don't want you two
to end up like that dog.
Oh, you know, Miss Fremont, he
might just have something there.
Just hold on. Here, take this.
No sense taking any
chances in this thing.
Here, give me the phone book.
What for?
Maybe I can get him
out of that apartment.
We only need a few minutes.
I'll see if I can get about 15 minutes.
- How?
- Thorwald.
Thorwald... Thorwald.
Chelsea 2-7099.
2-7099.
We scared him once, maybe
we can scare him again.
I guess I'm using that
word 'we' a little freely.
You're taking all the chances.
- Shall we vote him in, Stella?
- Unanimously,
2-7099. Look out.
Chelsea.
Go on, pick it up, Thorwald.
Go on, you're curious,
You wonder if it's your girlfriend
calling, the one you killed for,
Go on, pick it up.
- "Hello?"
- Did you get my note?
Well, did you get it, Thorwald?
"Who are you?"
I'll give you a chance to find out,
Meet me in the bar at the Albert Hotel,
Do it right away.
- "Why should I?"
- A little business meeting...
to settle the estate of your late wife,
"I... don't know what you mean,"
Come on. Quit stalling, Thorwald,
or I'll hang up and call the police,
- "I only have $100,"
- That's a start.
I'm at the Albert now,
I'll be looking for you,
Come on, Stella, let's go.
One of you keep an eye on this window.
If I see him coming back,
I'll signal with a flashbulb,
"This is the doyle residence,"
Hello, this is L B Jefferies.
I'm a friend of Mr Doyle.
- Who's this? - "This
is a baby-sitter,"
Oh, uh... when do you expect them in?
"They went to dinner
and maybe a nightclub,"
I see, hm.
If he calls in, have him get
in touch with L B Jefferies?
I might have quite a surprise for him.
"Well, do we have your
number, Mr Jefferies?"
- He has it. Good night.
- "Good night,"
Ah, Stella was wrong
about Miss Lonelyhearts,
Lisa, what are you... Don't...
Don't...
Lisa, what are you doing? Don't go...
Li...
Come on, come on! Get out of there!
She said ring Thorwald's phone
the second you see him come back.
We'll ring right now!
Give her another minute,
Alright, fellows, let's try
it once from the beginning,
Miss Lonelyhearts,
Oh, call the police!
- "Operator,"
- Get me the police, sixth precinct.
"Yes, sir,"
Mr Jefferies, the music stopped her,
What... Lisa!
Lisa!
"Precinct Six, Sergeant Allgood,"
Hello. Look, a man is assaulting
a woman at 125 West Ninth Street,
second floor, at the rear.
Make it fast!
- "Your name?"
- L. B. Jefferies,
- "Phone number?"
- Chelsea 2-5598
"Two minutes,"
The door was open.
Oh...
- I told you...
- Oh, no!
Let go of me! Jeff!
- Jeff! Jeff!
Jeff!
Lisa!
Stella, what do we do?
- Jeff! Jeff!
- Here they come.
What's she trying to do?
Why doesn't she turn him in?
- She's a smart girl.
- "Smart girl?" She'll be arrested.
It'll get her out of there, won't it?
Look, the wedding ring!
Turn off the light! He's seen us!
How long do you think he'll stay there?
Unless he's dumber than I think,
he won't wait until his lease is up.
Get my billfold out of the
drawer in the table there.
- What do you need money for?
- I'm gonna bail Lisa out of jail.
You could leave her
there till next Tuesday.
Then you could sneak
safely away as planned.
- Yeah, let's see, $127.
- How much do you need?
Well, this is first offence
burglary, that's about $250.
- Lisa's handbag.
- Yeah.
- How much does she have?
- Fifty cents.
- Here, take this.
- I got $20 or so in my purse,
What about the rest?
When those cops see Lisa,
they'll even contribute,
Just a minute. Hurry up!
- Jefferies.
- "What is it now?"
Doyle, I've got something
really big for you.
"Why did I have to return your call?"
"Look! Don't louse up my
night with another mad killer--"
Listen to me! Listen to me!
Lisa's in jail. She got arrested.
- "Your Lisa?"
- My Lisa.
Boy, you should have seen her.
She got into Thorwald's apartment,
but then he came back and the
only way I could get her out,
was call the police.
- "I told you -" -
I know you told me.
She went in to get evidence,
and she came out with evidence.
- "Like what?"
- Like Mrs Thorwald's wedding ring.
If that woman was alive, she'd
be wearing that ring, right?
- "Hm, It's a possibility,"
- A 'possibility'? It's a fact.
He killed a dog last night
because the dog was scratching
around in the garden. You know why?
Because he had something buried in
that garden that the dog scented.
"Like an old ham bone?"
I don't know what pet names
Thorwald had for his wife,
but I'll tell you this:
All those trips at night
with that metal suitcase,
he wasn't taking out his possessions,
because his possessions are
still up in the apartment.
"'Do you think perhaps
it was old 'ham bone?"'
And I'll tell you something else.
All the telephone calls he made
were long distance, alright?
Now, if he called his wife long
distance on the day she left,
after she arrived in Merritsville,
why did she write a card to him
saying she arrived in Merritsville?
Why did she do that?
- "Where'd they take Lisa?"
- Precinct six.
I sent somebody over
with the bail money.
"Maybe you won't need it,
I'll run it down, Jeff,"
Alright. Hurry up, will you? This
fellow knows he's being watched.
He's not gonna wait
around forever. Hurry up.
"If that ring checks out, we'll
give him an escort, So long, Jeff,"
So long.
Hello, Tom.
I think Thorwald's left. I don't see...
Hello?
What do you want from me?
Your friend, the girl, could
have turned me in. Why didn't she?
What is it you want, a lot of
money? I don't have any money.
Say something.
Say something! Tell me what you want!
Can you get me that ring back?
- No.
- Tell her to bring it back,
I can't. The police have it by now.
Lisa! Doyle!
What was that?
Look! Look over at that
apartment! They're fighting!
Look, he's throwing him out the window!
Doyle!
Creele, give me your. 38!
I'm sorry, Jeff. I got
here as fast as I could.
Don't let anybody touch him. Get
me a medical bag from upstairs.
Lisa, sweetie, if anything
had happened to you -
- I'm alright.
- Gee, I'm proud of you.
You got enough for a search warrant now?
Oh, yeah, sure.
- Lieutenant doyle,
- Yeah?
- Is he OK?
- He's alive.
Thorwald's ready to take us
on a tour of the East River,
Did he say what was
buried in the flower bed?
Yeah. He said the dog got too
inquisitive, so he dug it up.
It's in a hat box over in his apartment.
- Want to look?
- No, thanks,
I don't want any part of her.
I hope it's gonna be a hit,
This is the first release,
I'd love to hear it.
I can't tell you what
this music has meant to me.
♪ Record Playing
Oh, sweet little puppy,
don't jump, Let's try it again, puppy,
Stay still. Stay.
- Stanley!
- Hello, baby.
My, look what the army's done for you!
The army's made me hungry.
What have you got in the icebox to eat?
Boy, it's good to be home.
If you had told me you'd quit your job,
we wouldn't have gotten married.
Oh, honey. Come on.
♪ But dream
♪ Forever
♪ In your arms
♪ Oh, Lisa
♪ Lisa ♪