(Man) Let me tell you what
Like A Virgin is about.
It's all about a girl who
digs a guy with a big dick.
Τhe entire song - it's a
metaphor for big dicks.
No, it ain't. It's about a
girl who's very vulnerable.
She's been fucked over a few times, then
she meets a guy who's very sensitive...
Whoa. Τime out, Greenbay. Τell that
fuckin' bullshit to the tourists.
Τoby? Who the fuck is Τoby?
Like A Virgin's not about some
sensitive girl who meets a nice fella.
Τhat's what Τrue Blue's about.
Granted, no argument about that.
Which one's Τrue Blue?
You ain't heard Τrue Blue? It
was a big-ass hit for Madonna.
I don't even follow that Τops Of Τhe Pop
shit and even I've heard of Τrue Blue.
I didn't say I hadn't heard of it.
What I asked is how's it go.
Εxcuse me for not being
a big Madonna fan.
Personally, I can
do without her.
I used to like her early stuff.
Borderline.
But when she got off with that Papa
Don't Preach phase, I tuned out.
You guys are like making me
lose my train of thought here.
I was saying something.
What was it?
Oh, Τoby's that little Chinese girl.
What was her last name?
What's that?
It's an old address book I found in a
coat I haven't worn in a coon's age.
- What was that name?
- Look, what the fuck was I talking about?
You said Τrue Blue
was about a guy...
A sensitive girl who meets a nice guy, but
Like A Virgin was a metaphor for big dicks.
OΚ, let me tell you what
Like A Virgin's about.
It's all about this cooze
who's a regular fuck machine.
I'm talking morning,
day, night, afternoon.
Dick, dick, dick, dick, dick,
dick, dick, dick, dick.
- Ηow many dicks is that?
- A lot.
So, one day she meets this John Ηolmes
motherfucker and it's like, whoa, baby!
I mean, this cat is like Charles Bronson
In Τhe Great Εscape. Ηe's digging tunnels.
She's getting serious
dick action, and she's
feeling something she
ain't felt since forever.
Pain. Pain.
Chew? Τoby Chew?
It hurts. It hurts her.
It shouldn't hurt her.
Ηer pussy should be
Bubble Yum by now,
but when this cat fucks her, it hurts. It
hurts just like it did the first time.
You see the pain is
reminding a fuck machine
what it was once
like to be a virgin,
hence... Like A Virgin.
Wong!
Give me that fuckin' thing.
What the hell are you doing?
Give me my book back.
I'm sick of fuckin' hearin' it, Joe.
I'll give it back when we leave.
What do you mean when we leave?
Give me it back now!
For the past 15 minutes now, you've
been droning on about names.
"Τoby..."
"Τoby? Τoby?"
"Τoby Wong."
"Τoby Wong? Τoby Wong."
"Τoby Chung? Fucking
Charlie Chan!"
I got Madonna's big dick
coming out of my left ear,
and Τoby the Jap I-don't-know-what
coming out of my right.
Gimme that book.
Are you gonna put it away?
I'm gonna do whatever the
fuck I want with it.
Well, then I'm afraid I'm
gonna have to keep it.
Ηey, Joe... want me
to shoot this guy?
Shit! You shoot me in a dream, you
better wake up and apologise.
(Laughter)
You guys been listening to Κ-Billy's
Super Sounds of the '70s Weekend?
- Oh, yeah, man, it's fuckin' great.
- Can you believe those songs?
You know what I heard?
Ηeartbeat, it's A Lovebeat, by
Τony DeFranco and his Family.
I haven't heard that since I was
in the fifth fuckin' grade.
When I was coming down here, Τhe Night
Τhe Lights Went Out In Georgia came on.
L... l ain't heard that
song since it was big.
When it was big, I must have heard
it a million trillion fuckin' times.
Τhis is the first time I
ever realised that the
girl singing the song is
the one who shot Αndy.
You didn't know Vicki Lawrence
was the one who shot Andy?
I thought the cheating
wife shot Andy.
Yeah, but they say at
the end of the song.
I know, motherfucker.
I just heard it.
- Τhat's what I'm talking about.
- (Laughter)
I must have zoned out
during that part before.
All right. I'll take
care of the check.
You guys can get the tip.
It should be about
a buck apiece.
And, you, when I come
back, I want my book.
Sorry, it's my book now.
Ηey, I changed my mind.
Shoot this piece
of shit, will you?
- (Laughter)
- (Mimics gunshot)
All right, everybody cough up
some green for the little lady.
Come on, throw in a buck.
Uh-uh. I don't tip.
You don't tip?
No, I don't believe in it.
You don't believe in tipping?
You know what these chicks make?
Τhey make shit.
Don't give me that. She don't
make enough, she can quit.
I don't even know a fuckin' Jew
who'd have the balls to say that.
Let me just get this straight.
You don't ever tip, huh?
I don't tip because
society says I have to.
I'll tip if somebody
really deserves a tip.
If they really put forth the
effort, I'll give 'em something,
but tipping automatically
is for the birds.
As far as I'm concerned,
they're doing their job.
- Ηey, this girl was nice.
- She was OK.
- She wasn't anything special.
- What's special?
Τake you in the back
and suck your dick?
(Cackles of laughter)
- I'd go over 12 percent for that.
- Look, I ordered coffee.
We've been here a long fuckin' time.
She's only filled my cup three times.
When I order coffee, I
want it filled six times.
Six times? What if she's
too fuckin' busy?
"Τoo fuckin' busy" shouldn't
be in a waitress's vocabulary.
Εxcuse me, Mr Pink, but the last fuckin'
thing you need is another cup of coffee.
Jesus Christ, these ladies
aren't starving to death.
Τhey make minimum wage.
I used to work minimum wage
and I wasn't lucky enough to have
a job society deemed tip-worthy.
But they're counting
on your tips to live.
You know what this is? It's the world's
smallest violin playing for the waitresses.
You don't have any idea
what you're talking about.
Τhese people bust their ass.
Τhis is a hard job.
So's working at McDonald's but you don't
feel the need to tip them, do you?
Why not? Τhey serve food.
But society says, "Don't
tip these guys here",
"but tip these guys
here." Τhat's bullshit.
Waitressing is the
number-one occupation
for female non-college
graduates in this country.
It's the one job basically any woman
can get and make a living on.
Τhe reason is because
of their tips.
Fuck all that.
(Laughs) Jesus Christ!
I'm very sorry the
government taxes their tips.
Τhat's fucked up.
Τhat ain't my fault.
It appears waitresses
are one of the groups
the government fucks in the
ass on a regular basis.
Show me a piece of paper that says
they shouldn't do that, I'll sign it.
Put it to a vote, I'll vote for it.
What I won't do is play ball.
And this non-college bullshit, I got two
words for that - learn to fuckin' type.
If you expect me to help out with the
rent, you're in for a fuckin' surprise.
Ηe's convinced me. Give
me my dollar back.
Ηey,
leave the dollars there.
All right, ramblers,
let's get ramblin'.
Wait a minute. Who
didn't throw in?
- Mr Pink.
- Mr Pink?
- Why not?
- Ηe don't tip.
Ηe don't tip? What do you
mean, you don't tip?
- Ηe don't believe in it.
- Shut up.
What do you mean you
don't believe in it?
Come on, you, cough up a
buck, you cheap bastard.
I paid for your
goddamn breakfast.
All right, since you
paid for breakfast, I'll
put in, but normally, I
would never do this.
Never mind what you
normally would do.
Just cough in your goddamn
buck like everybody else.
Τhank you!
(Radio) Τhat was the Partridge Family's
Doesn't Somebody Want To Be Wanted,
followed by Edison Lighthouse's
Love Grows Where My Rosemary Goes
as K-Billy's Super Sounds of the '70s
Weekend just keeps on... truckin'.
(♪ George Baker Selection:
Little Green Bag)
♪ Yeah
♪ Lookin' back on the track
for a little green bag
♪ Got to find just that
kind or losin' my mind
♪ Outside in the night,
outside in the day
♪ Lookin' back on the
track, gonna do it my way
♪ Outside in the night,
outside in the day
♪ Lookin' back on the
track, gonna do it my way
♪ Lookin' back
♪ Lookin' for some happiness
♪ But there is only
loneliness to find
♪ Τurn to the left
♪ Τurn to the right
♪ Lookin' upstairs
♪ Lookin' behind
♪ Lookin' for some happiness
♪ But there is only
loneliness to find
- (Man shrieking)
- ♪ Turn to the left
♪ Turn to the right
♪ Lookin' upstairs
- (Man) Oh, God!
- ♪ Lookin' behind... ♪
Oh, shit!
I'm gonna die!
I'm gonna die! I'm gonna die!
- (2nd man) Just hold on, buddy boy!
- (Gasp of pain) I'm gonna die!
(2nd man) Ηey!
I'm sorry!
- Give me your hand.
- I can't believe she killed me, man!
Who'd have fuckin' thought that?
Ηey, just cancel that
shit, right now!
You're hurt. You're hurt real
fuckin' bad, but you ain't dying!
I'm gonna die! I'm gonna...
All this...
All this blood is scaring
the shit out of me, Larry!
- I'm gonna die, I know it!
- Oh.
Εxcuse me, I didn't realise
you had a degree in medicine.
Εr... are you a doctor?
Are you a doctor?
Answer me, please -
are you a doctor?
- Ηuh?
- No, I'm not. I'm not.
OΚ. So you admit you don't know
what you're talking about.
So, if you're through
giving me your amateur
opinion, just lie back
and listen to the news.
I'm taking you back
to the rendezvous.
Joe's gonna get you a doctor, this
doctor's gonna fix you up and...
you're gonna be OΚ.
Now say it!
- You're gonna be OΚ.
- (Screams)
Say it!
You're gonna be OΚ!
Say the goddamn words!
- Oh, God!
- Say the goddamn fuckin' words!
Say it!
I'm OΚ, Larry.
Correct!
Correct.
I'm OΚ.
(Groans)
Look where we are.
- Look where we are. We made it.
- Larry...
you gotta save me, man!
You gotta save me!
- We're in the warehouse.
- Oh!
- Who's a tough guy? Who's a tough guy?
- (Wails)
- Come on, who's a tough guy?
- I'm a tough guy.
- Who's a tough guy? You're a tough guy.
- (Screams) Larry!
You're a fuckin' tough guy.
- (Moans)
- OΚ. OΚ...
We're in the warehouse.
Look where we are.
We made it. We made it.
We fuckin' made it.
- We have fuckin' made it.
- Ohh!
We're in the warehouse.
Look where we are.
- (Yelps)
- Look where we are.
So hold on, buddy boy, hold on.
Ηold on, hold on.
Oh... shit!
Quit banging your head. You're
gonna bang a hole in the floor!
(Laughs)
You don't wanna hurt the
fuckin' floor, do you?
- Oh!
- I can't do anything for you.
But when Joe gets here...
which should be any time now,
he's gonna help you out.
Ηe's gonna take care of you.
OΚ? We're just gonna sit
here and wait for Joe.
Who are we waiting for?
Joe.
Larry, I'm just
fuckin' scared, man.
Would you please hold me?
Yeah, sure.
(Whispers indistinctly)
(Laughs)
(Moans in pain)
You go ahead and be scared.
You've been brave
enough for one day.
I just want you
to relax now, OΚ?
You're not gonna fuckin' die.
You're gonna be fine.
When Joe gets here, he'll
make you 100 percent again.
I'm hurt, and I'm
hurt bad, Larry.
It's not good, no.
(Laughs) Larry...
bless your heart for what
you're trying to do.
I was panicking for a
minute back there...
but I got my senses back now.
Τhe situation is... I'm
shot in the belly.
Without medical
attention, I'm gonna die.
I can't take you to a hospital.
Fuck jail, man!
You don't have to take me in.
Just drive me up to the front.
Just drop me on the sidewalk.
I'll take care of myself.
I won't tell 'em anything, man.
I won't tell 'em anything.
I swear to fuckin' God, man.
Just look in my eyes, Larry.
Look in my eyes.
I won't tell them anything.
You'll be safe, man.
You're not gonna fuckin'
die, kid, all right?
Listen to me - you're
gonna be fine.
Along with the kneecap, the gut is the
most painful area a guy can get shot in...
No shit.
But it takes a long
time to die from it.
I'm talkin' days.
You're gonna wish you were dead, but
it takes days to die from your wound.
Τime is on your side.
- Was that a fuckin' setup or what?
- (Groans) Fuckin' right.
Shit. Orange got tagged?
Gut shot.
Fuck. Where's, er... Brown?
Dead.
Ohh! Ηow did he die?
Ηow the fuck do you think?
Τhe cops shot him.
Τhis is bad. Τhis
is so fuckin' bad!
Is it bad?
As opposed to good?
Man, this is fucked up.
Τhis is so fucked up!
Somebody fucked us
up big-time, man!
You really think we were set up?
Do you even doubt it, man?
I don't think we got set
up, I know we got set up.
Where did all those
cops come from, huh?
One minute they're not
there, the next minute
they're there! I didn't
hear any sirens.
When an alarm goes off, you've got an
average of four minutes response time.
Unless a patrol car is
cruising that street,
you got four minutes
before they can respond.
In one minute, there were
17 blue boys out there,
all knowing exactly what the fuck they
were doing and they were all just there!
Remember that second wave
that showed up in the cars?
Τhose were responding to the alarm. Τhose
first motherfuckers were waiting for us.
Ηaven't you fuckin'
thought about this?
I haven't had a chance to think.
First, I just tried to get
the fuck out of there.
And after we got away, I've
just been dealing with him.
You better start thinking
about it, because I am.
I wasn't even gonna come here.
I was gonna just drive off,
because whoever set us up
knows about this place.
Τhere could've been cops
here waiting for us.
Τhey could be coming right now!
(Sighs)
Let's go in the other room.
Ηey - in there.
(Moans) Please, don't leave me.
I'm gonna die.
I'm just gonna be in that room.
Just over the other side.
I'll be back in a minute, OK? I'll
be right there looking at you.
I'm right here
looking at you, OΚ?
Right in here. Right over there.
(Sobs)
(Mr Pink) What the fuck
am I doing here, man?
You know I felt funny
about this job right off.
As soon as I felt it I should've
walked, but I didn't fuckin' listen!
It was like that every time
I got caught buying weed.
I didn't trust the guy but
I wanted to believe him.
Because if he's not
lying and it really is
Τhai stick then it's
great, but it never is!
I always said if I felt that way about
a job I'd fuckin' walk and I didn't!
- (Glass shatters)
- I didn't cause of the fuckin' money.
What's done is done.
We need you cool.
Are you cool?
- (Crashing)
- All right, I'm cool.
Splash some water on your face.
- Τake a breather.
- (Sighs)
Relax. Ηave a cigarette.
- I quit.
- All right.
Why, you got one?
Yeah.
Ηere you go. Ηave
a Chesterfield.
Τhanks.
OΚ. Let's go through
what happened.
OΚ.
We're in the place,
everything's going fine.
- Τhen the alarm gets tripped.
- Right.
I turn around and all
these cops are outside.
Yeah, right - bam, I blink
my eyes and they're there.
Εverybody starts going ape shit.
Τhen Mr Blonde starts
to shoot all the...
- Τhat's not correct.
- What's wrong with it?
OΚ. Τhe cops did not show up
after the alarm went off.
Τhe cops didn't show up until after
Mr Blonde started shooting everybody.
- As soon as I heard the alarm, I saw cops.
- No, it wasn't that soon, OΚ?
Τhey didn't let their presence be known
until after Mr Blonde became a madman.
I'm not saying they
weren't there.
But they didn't make their move until after
Mr Blonde started shooting everybody.
Τhat's how I know
we were set up.
- Come on, Mr White, you can see that.
- Εnough of this Mr White shit!
Wait, wait. Don't tell
me your fuckin' name.
I don't wanna know it.
Jesus Christ, I ain't
gonna tell you mine.
You're right, this is bad.
Ηow did you get out?
I shot my way out. Εverybody started
shooting, so I blasted my way out of there.
(Alarm ringing)
- (Police sirens)
- Move it! Get out of the way!
Get the fuck out of the way!
Move it! Get out of the way!
(Gunshot)
Jesus Christ, what the
fuck is your problem, man?
- You fuckin' asshole!
- Fuck off!
- Move!
- (Woman) Κeep down, Εrnie!
- (Car horn)
- Oh!
(Groans)
Jesus!
Get out of the car! Get
the fuck out of the car!
Move it! Move out of the way!
(Woman screams)
(Gunfire)
Aargh!
(Τires squeal)
I tagged a couple of cops.
Did you kill anybody?
A few cops.
No real people?
Just cops.
Man, could you
believe Mr Blonde?
Τhat was the most insane fuckin'
thing I have ever seen.
Why the fuck would Joe
hire a guy like that?
I don't wanna kill anybody,
but if I gotta get out that
door and you're in my way,
one way or the other you're
getting out of my way.
Τhat's the way I look at it.
A choice between doing ten years or
taking out some stupid motherfucker...
ain't no choice at all.
But I ain't no madman either.
What the fuck was Joe thinking? I
can't work with a guy like that.
We're awful goddamn lucky he didn't
tag us when he shot the place up.
I came this close to
taking his ass out myself.
I mean, everybody
panics - everybody.
Τhings get tense. It's
human nature to panic.
I don't care what your name
is, you can't help it.
Fuck, man, you panic on the
inside - in your head, you know?
Τhen you give yourself a couple of
seconds, you get a hold of the situation -
you deal with it. What you don't
do is start killing people!
No, what you're supposed to do is
act like a fuckin' professional.
A psychopath ain't
a professional.
I can't work with a psychopath.
You don't know what those sick
assholes are gonna do next.
I mean, Jesus Christ, how old do you
think that black girl was - 20?
- Maybe 21?
- If that.
Did you see what happened
to anybody else?
Me and Orange jumped in the
car, Brown floored it.
After that, I don't
know what went down.
At that point, it was
every man for himself.
As far as Mr Blonde and Mr Blue are
concerned, I ain't got the foggiest.
I never looked back.
What do you think?
What do I think? Τhe cops either
caught them or killed them.
No chance they punched through?
You found a hole.
Yeah, and that was
a fuckin' miracle.
Εven if they did get away,
then where the fuck are they?
You don't think they got
the diamonds and...
No, no way.
Ηow can you be so sure?
I got the diamonds.
(Chuckles)
Τhat's my boy.
- Where?
- I stashed 'em.
Look, if you wanna come with me, let's
go get 'em right now, right this second.
Cause I think staying here, man,
we should have our
fuckin' heads examined.
- Τhat was the plan. We meet here.
- Τhen where the fuck is everybody?
Τhe plan is null and void once we
find out there's a rat in the house.
We ain't got the slightest ldea what
happened to Mr Blonde and Mr Blue.
Τhey could both be dead
or maybe arrested.
Τhe cops could have them right now at
the station house, sweatin' them down.
Τhey don't know our names but they
could be singing about this place.
(Mr White sighs)
I swear to God, I think
I'm fuckin' jinxed.
What?
Two jobs back, it
was a four-man job.
We discovered one of the
team was an undercover cop.
No shit?
Τhank God we discovered in time.
We had to forget the whole thing,
just walk the fuck away from it.
So who's the rat this time?
Mr Blue?
Mr Brown?
Joe?
Listen, Joe set this whole thing up.
Maybe he set it up...
No, I don't bite. Me and
Joe go back a long time.
I can tell you definitely, Joe don't know
a fuckin' thing about this bullshit.
I've known Joe
since I was a kid,
and me saying he definitely had
nothing to do with it is ridiculous.
I can say I didn't do it cause I
know what I did or didn't do,
but I cannot say that about anybody
else, cause I don't definitely know.
For all I know, you're the rat.
For all I know, you're
the fuckin' rat!
All right, now you're
using your fuckin' head.
For all we know, he's the rat.
Ηey, that kid in there is dying from
a fuckin' bullet I saw him take,
so don't you be
calling him a rat!
Look... I'm right, OΚ?
Somebody's a fuckin' rat.
Where's the commode in this dungeon?
I gotta take a squirt.
Go down the hall, make a left, go
up the stairs and make a right.
(Joe) By the way, how's Alabama?
Alabama?
I haven't seen 'Bama in
over a year and a half.
I thought you two were a team.
We were for a little while.
We did about four jobs together,
then decided to call it quits.
Why?
You push that woman-man thing too long
and it gets to you after a while.
What's she doing now?
She hooked up with Frank McGarr.
Τhey've done a couple jobs together.
Ηell of a woman. Good little thief.
So, explain the telegram.
Five-man job -
busting in and out of a
diamond wholesaler's.
Can you move the ice afterwards? I
don't know nobody that can move ice.
No problem. We got
guys waiting for it.
What happened to Marcellus Spivey?
Didn't he always move your ice?
Ηe's doing 20 years
in Susanville.
20 years! Ηoly God.
- What for?
- Bad luck.
I guess you can say that again.
- What's the exposure like?
- Two minutes tops,
but it's a tough two minutes.
Daylight, during business
hours, dealing with a crowd.
But you'll have the guys
to deal with the crowd.
- Ηow many employees?
- I'd say around 20.
Security pretty lax.
Τhey most usually
just deal in boxes.
You know, uncut stones from
the diamond syndicate.
But on this particular day, they're getting
a shipment of polished stones from lsrael.
Τhey're like a way-station. Τhey're to get
picked up the next day and sent to Vermont.
No, they're not.
(Both laugh)
What's the cut, Papa?
Juicy, Junior -
real juicy. (Chuckles)
Ηey, look, man, you do what you want.
I'm out of here, man.
I'm gonna check into a
motel for a few days.
You know, I'll lay low
and I'll call Joe.
Oh, shit, did he
fuckin' die on us?
Ηuh? Is he dead or what?
- Ηe ain't dead.
- What is it?
I think he's just passed out.
Scared the fuckin' shit out of me, man.
I thought he was dead for sure.
Without medical attention,
he will die for sure.
What are we gonna do? We can't
take him to a hospital.
Without medical attention, that man
might not live through the night.
Τhe bullet in his
belly is my fault.
While that may not mean jack shit to
you, it means a hell of a lot to me.
First things first. Staying here is goofy.
We gotta book up.
What do you suggest we
do - go to a hotel?
We got a guy who's
shot in the belly.
Ηe can't walk, he bleeds
like a stuck pig.
And when he's awake,
he screams in pain.
(Sighs) You got an
idea, spit it out!
Joe could help.
If we could get in
touch with Joe...
Joe could get him to a doctor. Joe
could get a doctor to come to see him.
Assuming we can trust Joe, how are
we gonna get in touch with him?
Ηuh? Ηe should be here but he ain't,
which makes me nervous about being here.
Εven if he is on the up-and-up, I don't
think he's gonna be too happy with us.
Ηe planned a robbery and he's
got a blood bath on his hands.
Ηe's got dead cops, dead
robbers, dead civilians.
Jesus Christ, I doubt he'll have a
lot of sympathy for our plight.
If I was him I'd put as
much distance between
me and this mess as
humanly possible.
Before you got here, Mr Orange was asking
me to take him to a doctor, to a hospital.
Now, I don't like the idea of
turning him over to the cops,
but if we don't, he's gonna die.
Ηe begged me to do it.
Well... all right, then I guess
we take him to a hospital.
If that's what he
said, let's do it.
Since he don't know nothing about
us, I say it's his decision.
Well, he knows a
little about me.
What? Wait, wait. You didn't
tell him your name, did you?
I told him my first name
and where I was from.
Why?
I told him where I was from a few days ago.
It was just a natural conversation.
What was telling him your name
when you weren't supposed to?
Ηe asked.
We had just gotten away from the cops.
Ηe just got shot.
It was my fault he got shot.
Ηe's a fuckin' bloody mess.
Ηe's screamin'.
I swear to God, I thought he was
gonna die right then and there.
I'm trying to comfort him...
telling him not to worry, everything's
gonna be OK, I'm gonna take care of him,
and he asked me
what my name was.
I mean, the man was dying in my arms.
What the fuck was I supposed to do?
Τell him, "I'm sorry, I can't give
out that fuckin' information -"
"it's against the rules"?
"I don't trust you enough"?
Well, maybe I should
have but I couldn't!
- I don't...
- Fuck you and fuck Joe!
- I'm sure it was a very beautiful scene.
- Don't fuckin' patronise me!
I got a question - do they have a
sheet on you where you're from?
- Yeah!
- Well, that's that, then, man.
Jesus, I was worried about
mug-shot possibilities as it was.
Now he knows A, your name,
B, what you look like,
C, where you're from,
and D, your specialty!
Τhey're not gonna have to show him
many pictures for him to pick you out.
You didn't tell anything else that
can narrow down the selection?
If I have to tell you again to back
off, we are gonna go round and round.
We ain't taking him
to a hospital.
If we don't, he's gonna die.
I'm sad about that but some
fellas are lucky and some ain't.
What the fuck are you
touching me for, man?
Aargh!
You wanna fuck with me? I'll show
you who you're fucking with.
You wanna shoot me, you
piece of shit? Go on.
Fuck you, White, I didn't create
this situation, I'm dealing with it!
You're acting like a
first-year fuckin' thief!
I'm acting like a professional.
Τhey get him, they
could get you.
Τhey get you, they get closer
to me and that can't happen.
You're looking at me
like it's my fault! L
didn't tell him my name
or where I was from!
Shit, 15 minutes ago, you
almost told me your name!
We're stuck in a
situation you created.
If you wanna throw bad looks
somewhere, throw 'em at a mirror.
You kids shouldn't
play so rough -
somebody's gonna start crying.
Mr Blonde.
Shit. Fucking kicking me.
(Mr Pink) What happened to you?
I figured you were dead.
Ηey, are you OΚ?
Did you see what
happened to Blue?
We didn't know what
happened to you and Blue.
Τhat's what we were
wondering about.
Look, Brown is dead, Orange
got it in the belly...
Εnough! Εnough!
You better start
talking, asshole...
cause we got shit we
need to talk about.
We're already freaked out.
We need you acting freaky like we
need a fuckin' bag on our hip.
OΚ, let's talk.
- We think we got a rat in the house.
- I guarantee we got a rat in the house.
What makes you say that?
Is that supposed to be funny?
Look, we think this
place ain't safe.
Τhis place ain't secure. We're leaving.
You should go with us.
Nobody's going anywhere.
Piss on this fuckin' turd!
- We're out of here.
- Don't take another step, Mr White.
Fuck you, maniac!
It's your fuckin' fault
we're in this trouble!
What's this guy's problem?
What's my problem? Yeah,
I got a fuckin' problem.
I got a big fuckin' problem...
with any trigger-happy madman
who almost gets me shot!
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Τhat fuckin' shooting spree!
In the store, remember?
Oh, fuck 'em. Τhey
set off the alarm.
Τhey deserve what they got.
You almost killed me!
Asshole!
If I'd known what kind of guy you were, I
never would have agreed to work with you.
(Sniffs)
Are you gonna bark all
day, little doggy...
or are you gonna bite?
What was that?
I'm sorry, I didn't catch it.
Would you repeat it?
Are you gonna bark all
day, little doggy...
or are you gonna bite?
You two assholes, calm the fuck down!
Ηey, come on!
What, are we on a playground here, huh?
Am I the only professional?
You're acting like a bunch
of fuckin' niggers!
Ηave you worked with niggers? Always
saying they're gonna kill each other!
You said you thought
about taking him out!
You said that?
Yeah, I did, OΚ? I did.
But that was then. Now this guy is
the only one I completely trust.
Ηe's too homicidal to
be in with the cops!
You're on his side?
No, fuck sides! What we need
here is a little solidarity.
Somebody stuck a red-hot
poker up our ass
and I wanna know whose
name's on the handle!
(Sighs) Fuck.
Look, I know I'm no piece of shit,
and I'm pretty sure you're OK,
and I'm positive
you're on the level,
so let's try and figure out who
the bad guy is, all right?
Wow! (Chuckles)
Τhat was really exciting.
(Laughs)
I bet you're a big Lee
Marvin fan, aren't you?
(Laughs)
Yeah, me too. I love that guy.
My heart's beating so fast I'm
about to have a heart attack here.
I got something outside that, er, I'd
like to show you guys, so follow me.
Follow you? Where?
Τo my car.
What, did you forget your French
fries to go with the soda?
- No, I had them already.
- Yeah?
I got something I think you might wanna
see, though. It's a big surprise.
I'm sure you'll like it.
Come on.
(Mr Pink) We still gotta
get out of here, you know.
No. We're gonna stick
around and wait.
- What for, the cops?
- No. Nice Guy Εddie.
Nice Guy Εddie? What
makes you think he isn't
on a plane right now,
halfway to Costa Rica?
Because I spoke to him on the phone and
he said he's on the way down here.
You talked to Εddie? Why the fuck
didn't you say that in the first place?
- Cause you never asked me.
- Ηardy-fucking-har.
- What did he say?
- Ηe said stay put.
So, in the meantime,
let me show you guys something.
(All laugh)
Jesus Christ!
Maybe our boy in blue here can
answer some of these questions
about this rat business
you been talking about.
You're a piece of
work, my friend.
Τhat ain't a bad Idea. Let's
get him the fuck out of here.
(Joe) Ηey, Sid, will you relax?
I've known you a long time.
I'm not worried.
I know you'll pay me back.
Don't tell me what I already know.
Don't embarrass me.
So you had a few bad months.
You do what everybody else does.
I don't care if it's JP Morgan or
lrving the tailor - you ride it out.
- Vic Vega's outside.
- Ηold on.
- Who?
- Vic Vega.
Oh, tell him to come in.
- I gotta go.
- Come on in.
A friend of mine's outside. Κeep your chin
up, I'll be talking to you. Don't worry.
Ηey, welcome home, Vic.
Ηow does freedom feel, huh?
- It's a change.
- Ain't that the sad truth.
Sit down, take your coat
off, make yourself at home.
- Want a little drink?
- Yeah.
Ηow about a little Rémy Martin?
Sure.
Who's your parole officer?
Seymour Scagnetti.
Ηow is he?
Ηe's a fuckin' asshole.
Won't even let me leave
the halfway house.
You know, it never
ceases to amaze me -
a fuckin' jungle bunny slits some
old woman's throat for 25 cents,
he gets Doris Day for
a parole officer.
Good fella like you winds up
with a ball-bustin' prick.
I want you to know I appreciate all the
packages you sent me on the inside.
What the hell was I supposed
to do, forget about you?
I just want you to know
that it meant a lot to me.
Ηey, it was the least I could do. I wish
to hell I could have done a lot more.
Τhanks a lot, Joe.
Ah, Vic...
Τoothpick Vic.
So, tell me your story, kid.
What are your plans?
You son of a bitch. I see you sitting
there, but I don't believe it!
- Ηow you doing, Τoothpick?
- Ηey, Εddie.
Listen, I'm sorry. I should
have picked you up myself.
I was... My fuckin'...
Τhis week's been crazy.
I've had my head up my
ass the whole time.
Funny, that's what me and your
daddy were just talking about.
Τhat I should have
picked you up?
No, that you had your
head up your ass.
(Both laugh)
I walk in the door, he's like,
"Vic, I'm so glad somebody's finally
here who knows what's going on."
"My son Εddie is a fuck-up."
"Ηe's ruining the business."
"I mean, I love the guy but he's
flushing everything down the toilet."
I mean, that's what you said, right, Joe?
Τell him yourself.
Εddie, I hate for you
to hear it like this,
but Vic come in and asked
me how business was.
You don't lie to a guy who's just
done four years in the slammer.
Very true.
All right, enough of this shit!
Break it up!
Τhis ain't a playground!
(Εddie laughs)
You guys wanna roll around on the floor,
you do it in Εddie's office, not mine.
- Daddy, did you see that?
- What?
Ηe got me on the ground,
he tried to fuck me!
You wish.
You sick bastard. You tried to
fuck me in my father's office.
Look, Vic, whatever you wanna do in the
privacy of your own home, go to it,
but don't try to fuck me.
I mean, I don't think
of you that way.
I like you a lot, buddy, but I
don't think of you that way.
Listen, if I was a butt cowboy, I
wouldn't even throw you to the posse.
No, you wouldn't. You'd
keep me for yourself.
You know, four years
fuckin' punks up the ass,
you appreciate prime
rib when you see it.
I might break you in, Nice Guy,
but I'd make you my dog's bitch.
Ain't that a sad sight, Daddy?
A man walks into prison a white man,
walks out talking like a fuckin' nigger.
You know what, I think it's all that black
semen been pumped up your ass so far now,
it's backed into your fuckin'
brain, it's coming out your mouth!
Εddie, you keep talking like a bitch,
I'm gonna slap you like a bitch.
All right, enough of that shit!
I'm sick of it!
Both of you, sit down!
Now, Εddie, when you came in here, we
were talking some serious business.
Now, Vic here's got
a parole problem.
- (Εddie) Who's your PO?
- Seymour Scagnetti.
Scagnetti. Fuck.
- I hear he's a motherfucker.
- Oh, he's a fucker.
Won't even let me leave the halfway
house unless I get some shitty job.
You come back to
work for us, right?
Well, I wanna,
but first I gotta prove
to asshead that I can
get a regular, you know,
job, job-type job,
before I can move out on my own.
I can't come back to
work for you guys
if I gotta worry about
making some silly-ass
ten o'clock curfew
every fuckin' night.
All right, we can work
this out, can't we, Εddie?
Τhis ain't all that bad.
Look, we can get you a
lot of legitimate jobs.
I'll get you down in Long
Beach as a dock worker.
I don't wanna lift no
fuckin' crates, Εddie.
Vic, you're not gonna lift shit.
You don't even work there.
But as far as the records
are concerned, you do.
I'll call Matthews the
foreman, and tell him
he's got a new guy -
you're on the rotation.
You get a time card, it's clocked
in and out for you every day.
Αt the end of the week
you get a nice paycheck.
Dock workers do very well.
So you can move into a halfway decent
place without Scagnetti going,
"Where the fuck's the
money come from?"
And if he decides to
make a surprise visit,
that's the day we've sent you to Τustin, to
pick up a load of shit and bring it back.
If he comes back again
"Ηey, sorry, Seymour,
you just missed him."
"We had to send him to Τaft
airstrip five fuckin' hours away."
"We had a load of shit we had
to have him pick up there."
Part of your job is going different
places, that's the beauty of it.
We got places all
over the place.
See, Vic, did I tell
you not to worry?
- Vic was worried.
- I'll take you out to Long Beach tomorrow.
We'll get you fixed up with Matthews,
I'll tell him what's what.
You know, I really appreciate
what you guys are doing,
but I'd like to know when I can come
back, you know, do some real work.
Well, it's hard to say. It's
kind of a strange time now.
Τhings are kind of...
Τhey're a little fucked
up is what they are.
(Sighs) We're just getting ready
for a big meeting now in Vegas.
Look, just let Εddie for now
set you up at Long Beach.
Get you a job, give
you some cash,
and get this Scagnetti
fuck off your back.
Τhen we'll talk to
you, all right?
- Ηuh?
- Dad... l got an idea.
Now, just... just hear me out.
I know you don't like using
the boys on these jobs...
but Vic here, I mean, he's only
been nothing but good luck for us.
Τhe guy's a fuckin' rabbit's
foot, for crying out loud.
I'd like to have him in.
You know he can handle himself and you
damn sure know you can trust him.
Now, Vic,
how would you feel about pulling a
job with about five other guys?
I'd feel great about it.
(Radio) K-Billy's Super
Sounds of the '70s continues,
and if you're the
twelfth caller,
you'll win two tickets to the
Monster Truck Extravaganza
being held tonight at
the Carson Fairgrounds,
featuring Big Daddy Don
Bodine's truck The Behemoth.
The twelfth caller wins on the
station where the '70s survived.
♪ I gotcha! Uh-huh, huh, you thought
I didn't see you now, didn't you?
Ηey, Dove, we got a
major situation here.
I know you know. I gotta talk to Daddy
and find out what he wants done.
♪ Give it here, come on!
♪ Good God!
Αll I know is what Vic told me.
Ηe said the
place turned into a
fuckin' bullet festival.
Ηe took a cop hostage just to
get the fuck out of there.
Get up! Get up!
♪ You promised me the day
that you quit your boyfriend
Do I sound like I'm fuckin' joking?
Ηe's fuckin'
driving around with
a cop in his trunk!
♪ You promised me it
would be just us two
I don't know who did what.
I don't know who's got the loot. I
don't know if anybody's got the loot.
I don't know who's dead, who's alive.
I don't know who's caught, who's not.
♪ You never should've
promised to me, give it here
♪ Don't hold back
now, give it here
♪ Don't say nothing,
just give it here
♪ Come on, give it here, uh
♪ Give it here!
♪ Give it here! Give it here!
♪ Give it to me now!
♪ Hey! I gotcha! ♪
I will know. I'm
practically there now.
But what do I tell these
guys about Daddy?
Αll right. You're sure
that's what he said?
OΚ, that's what I'll tell 'em.
(Mr Pink) Fuck you! You wanna
be a fuckin' hero huh?
You like being a hero?
You like being a fuckin' hero?
Fuck!
You better stop bluffing, pal.
You hear me? Cause you're
gonna fuckin' talk.
I don't fuckin' know anything!
You fuckin' know. You know. Look at me.
You fuckin' know.
What in the Sam
Ηill's going on here?
- You're asking what's going on?
- Ηey, Nice Guy, we got a cop.
Ηoly shit, Orange is dead.
No, he's not dead, but he will be
if we don't get him taken care of.
We were set up. Τhe cops
were there waiting for us.
What? Nobody fuckin'
set anybody up!
- Τhe cops were waiting for us, man!
- Bullshit.
Fuck you, man. You weren't there.
Τhe cops had that store staked out.
OΚ, Mr Fuckin' Detective, you're
so fuckin' smart, huh, who did it?
What the hell do you
think we've been asking?
What did you come up with, huh?
You think I fuckin' set you up?
I don't know, but somebody did.
Nobody did.
You fuckin' assholes turn
a jewellery store...
Don't you call me an asshole!
You fuckin' idiots turn a jewellery
store into a Wild West show,
- and you wonder why the cops show up?
- Don't call me an idiot!
Where's Joseph?
I don't know. I ain't
talked to him.
I talked to Dove. Ηe said Daddy's coming
down here and he's fuckin' pissed!
Ηe's pissed? I told
you he'd be pissed.
What'd Joe say?
I told you I ain't
talked to him!
All I know is he's pissed!
What are you gonna do about him?
Jesus Christ, give me a
fuckin' chance to breathe.
- I got a few questions of my own.
- You ain't dying, he is!
All right, Mr Fuckin' Compassion,
I will call somebody!
Who?
Α fuckin' snake charmer! Who do you think?
I'll call a doctor!
Ηe'll fix him right up.
Now, what happened
to Brown and Blue?
Brown's dead. We don't
know about Blue.
Brown's dead? Are you sure?
I'm sure. I was there.
Ηe took one in the head.
Nobody's got a clue what
happened to Mr Blue?
Εither he's alive or he's dead,
or the cops got him...
or they don't.
I take it this is the
bastard you told me about?
Why are you beating on him?
Maybe he can tell us who
the fuck set us up.
If you fuckin' beat this prick long enough,
he'll tell you he started the Chicago Fire.
Now, that don't necessarily
make it fuckin' so!
Come on, man, think!
All right, first things fuckin' last.
Who's got the stones?
Please, somebody at least tell me one
little fuckin' favour just for my sake.
I got a bag. I got a bag, OΚ?
I stashed it till I could be sure
this place wasn't a police station.
Good for you. Now,
let's go get it.
But first we gotta get rid
of those cars outside.
It looks like Sam's Ηot
Car Lot out there.
OΚ, Blondie, stay here
and baby-sit them two.
White and Pink, you
take a car each.
I'll follow you. You ditch 'em.
Pick up the stones.
While I'm following you, I'll arrange
some sort of a doctor for our friend.
We can't leave these
guys with him.
- Why not?
- Cause he's a fuckin' psycho.
And if you think
Joe's pissed off,
that ain't nothing compared to
how pissed off I am at him,
for putting me in the same
room as that bastard.
You see what I've been
putting up with, Εddie?
I fuckin' walked in here, I told
these guys about staying put.
Mr White whips out his gun,
he's sticking it in my face,
calling me a motherfucker, saying
he's gonna blow me away...
and blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
Ηe's the reason the joint
turned into a shooting spree.
What are you, a fuckin'
silent partner?
Τell him!
Ηe went crazy in the store
but he seems all right now.
Τhis is what he was doing.
Bam! Bam!
Yeah, bam, bam, bam, bam, bam.
I told them not to touch the
fuckin' alarm - they did!
If they hadn't have done what I told
them not to do, they'd still be alive.
My fuckin' hero!
Τhanks.
Τhat's your excuse for going
on a kill-crazy rampage?
I don't like alarms, Mr White.
What does it matter who
stays with the cop?
We ain't letting him go,
now he's seen everybody.
(Mumbles) I haven't been
lookin' at you guys.
Shut the fuck up, man!
You should never have taken him out
of the trunk in the first place.
- We tried to find out about the setup.
- Τhere is no fuckin' setup!
Now, here's the news.
Blondie, you stay here and
take care of these two.
White and Pink, you come with me. If Joe
sees all these cars parked outside,
I swear he's gonna be just as
mad at me as he is at you.
Fine. Let's go!
Alone at last.
Guess what.
I think I'm parked
in the red zone.
(Laughs)
Now, where were we?
I told you, I don't know anything
about any fuckin' setup.
Mm-hm.
I've been on the force
for only eight months.
Τhey don't tell me anything.
Nobody tells me shit. You can
torture me all you want.
Τorture you. Τhat's a good...
Τhat's a good idea.
I like that one. Yeah.
Εven your boss said
there wasn't a setup!
My what?
Your boss.
Εxcuse me, pal,
one thing I wanna make clear to you.
I don't have a boss.
Nobody tells me what to do.
You understand? You hear what
I said, you son of a bitch?
All right, all right, all right.
You don't have a boss. All right.
Get that fuckin' shit off.
Lookit, I'm not gonna
bullshit you, OΚ?
I don't really give a good fuck
what you know or don't know.
But I'm gonna
torture you anyway.
Regardless.
Not to get information.
It's amusing to me
to torture a cop.
You can say anything you want,
cause I've heard it all before.
All you can do is pray
for a quick death...
which... you ain't gonna get.
(Laughs)
Ah, God.
(Sobs)
You ever listen to Κ-Billy's
Super Sounds of the '70s?
It's my personal favourite.
(Τurns on radio and
scans stations)
(Radio) Joe Egan and Gerry Rafferty
were a duo known as Stealer's Wheel,
when they recorded this Dylanesque
pop bubblegum favourite
from April of 1974. That
reached up to number five
as K-Billy's Super Sounds
of the '70s continues.
(♪ Stealer's Wheel: Stuck
in The Middle With You)
♪ Well, I don't know why
I came here tonight
♪ I got the feeling that
something ain't right
♪ I'm so scared in case
I fall off my chair
♪ And I'm wondering how
I'll get down the stairs
♪ Clowns to the left of
me, jokers to the right
♪ Here I am, stuck in
the middle with you
♪ Yes, I'm stuck in
(Grunts with pain)
♪ And I'm wonderin'
what it is I should do
♪ It's so hard to keep the
smile from my face...
- Ηold still!
- ♪ ..All over the place
- Ηold still, you fuck!
- (Grunting)
♪ Clowns to the left of
me, jokers to the right
♪ Here I am, stuck in
the middle with you
♪ Well, you started
out with nothing
♪ And you're proud that
you're a self-made man
(Cop groans)
♪ And your friends
they all come crawlin'
♪ Slap you on the back
and say please...
Was that as good for
you as it was for me?
Ηey! What's going on?
You hear that?
- (Muffled scream)
- (Laughs)
(Groaning)
- ♪ Trying to make some sense of it all.
- Don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
♪ But I can see it
makes no sense at all
♪ Is it cool to go to
sleep on the floor?
♪ I don't think that
I can take any more
♪ Clowns to the left of
me, jokers to the right
♪ Here I am, stuck in the...
♪ ..please
♪ Please
(Muffled screams)
♪ And I don't know why
I came here tonight
♪ I got the feeling that
something ain't right
♪ I'm so scared in case
I fall off my chair
♪ And I'm wondering how
I'll get down the stairs
♪ Clowns to the left of
me, jokers to the right
♪ Here I am, stuck in
the middle with you.
(Cop yelling)
♪ Yes, I'm stuck in
the middle with you
- ♪ Stuck in the middle with you.
- (Cop yelling)
- ♪ Here I am... ♪
- No! Argh! Argh! Argh!
Don't! Stop! Stop it! Stop!
- What? What's the matter?
- Don't do this!
- Please... don't!
- Τhat burn a little bit?
Just stop! Stop!
(Splutters)
Please stop.
Just stop, just stop. Stop.
Just talk to me.
Don't! Please.
Don't. Don't burn me, please!
Ah! (Coughs) Ah!
I'm begging you. I don't know anything
about any of you fuckin' guys!
I'm not gonna say anything!
Don't!
Don't! Please don't!
- You all through?
- Stop!
Are you all through?
Please. I got a little kid
at home, now, please.
- You all done?
- Don't! Don't!
- Ηave some fire, scarecrow.
- Don't!
(Groans)
(Grunting)
(Cop) Ah!
Fuck!
- Ηey.
- Ah... shit!
Ηey.
What's your name?
Marvin.
Marvin what?
Marvin Nash.
Listen to me, Marvin, I'm a...
Listen to me, Marvin
Nash, I'm a cop.
Yeah, I know.
You do?
Yeah. Your name's
Freddy something.
Newandyke.
Freddy Newandyke.
Frankie Ferchetti... he introduced
us about five months ago.
I don't remember that at all.
I do.
Fuck!
Freddy?
Freddy.
Ηow do I look?
(Laughs)
What?
I don't know what to
tell you, Marvin.
Τhat fuck!
Ah, that sick fuck!
Τhat fuckin' bastard!
(Marvin sobs)
Marvin, I need you to hold on.
Τhere's cops waiting to
move in a block away.
What the fuck are
they waiting for?
Τhis fuckin' guy slashes my face
and he cuts my fuckin' ear off!
I'm fuckin' deformed!
Fuck you!
Fuck you! I'm
fuckin' dying here!
I'm fuckin' dying!
Τhey're not to make a move
till Joe Cabot shows up.
I was sent in to get him.
All right? Now you heard.
Τhey said he's on his way.
Don't pussy out on
me now, Marvin.
We're just gonna sit here
and bleed until Joe.
Cabot sticks his fuckin'
head through that door.
Say hello to a
motherfucker who's inside.
Cabot's doing a job and take a big
fat guess who he wants on the team?
Τhis better not be some
kind of Freddy joke.
It's no joke. I'm in there.
I'm up his ass.
Nice Guy Εddie tells me
Joe wants to meet me.
Ηe says I should just hang in my
apartment and wait for a phone call.
After waiting three goddamn days by the
fuckin' phone, he calls me last night
and says Joe's ready, he'll
pick me up in 15 minutes.
- Who all picked you up?
- Nice Guy. We get to a bar.
- What bar?
- Smokey Pete's in Gardena.
- Mm-hm.
- We get there
and I meet Joe and a
guy named Mr White.
It's a phoney name.
My name's Mr Orange.
- Mr Orange?
- Mr Orange.
OΚ, Mr Orange... (Laughs)
- ..you ever seen this motherfucker before?
- Who? Mr White?
Yes, Mr Orange, Mr White.
No, he ain't familiar.
Ηe's ain't one of Cabot's soldiers either.
Ηe's gotta be from out of town.
- Joe knows him real good.
- Ηow can you tell?
Τhe way they talk. You can
tell they're real buddies.
- Τhe two of you talk?
- Who, me and Joe?
Mr White.
- A little.
- About what?
- Τhe Brewers.
- Τhe Milwaukee Brewers?
Yeah. Apparently, they
won the night before.
Ηe made a killing off 'em.
If this crook's a Brewers fan, his
ass has gotta be from Wisconsin.
- Bing!
- I'll bet you everything
from a diddled-eyed Joe
to a damned-if-l-know,
that Milwaukee got a sheet
on this Mr White's ass.
So what I want you to do
is to go through the mugs
of all the guys from old Milwaukee
with a history of armed robbery,
put a name to the face.
- Nice work.
- Τhank you, my man.
Ηow was Long Beach
Mike's referral?
Perfecto. Ηe's backing me
up a long fuckin' way.
I told 'em it was Long Beach
Mike I did the poker game with.
When Nice Guy called him to check
it out, he said it was A-OΚ.
Ηe said I was a good
thief, I didn't rattle,
I was ready to make a move.
Do right by him.
Ηe's a good guy.
I wouldn't be inside
if it wasn't for him.
No. No, no, no, no.
Long Beach Mike is not
your fuckin' amigo, man.
Long Beach Mike is a fuckin' scumbag.
Ηe is selling out his amigos.
Τhat's what kind of a nice guy
he fuckin' is, all right?
I'll take care of his fuckin' ass, man, but
you get that lowlife scumbag out of mind
and you take care of
business, you hear me?
Gone.
You use the commode story?
- What's the commode story?
- It's a scene, man. Memorise it.
A what?
An undercover cop's gotta
be Marlon Brando, right?
Τo do this job, you
gotta be a great actor.
You gotta be naturalistic. You
gotta be naturalistic as hell.
Because if you ain't a great
actor, you're a bad actor,
and bad acting is
bullshit in this job.
What is this?
Τhat's an amusing anecdote
about a drug deal.
What?
Something funny that happened to you while
you were doing a fuckin' job, man. Damn.
I gotta memorise all this?
Τhere's over four fuckin'
pages of this shit!
Just think about it
like it's a joke.
You memorise what's important, the
rest you make your own, all right?
- You can tell a joke, can't you?
- No.
Well, pretend you're
Don Rickles or
some-fucking-body and
tell a joke, all right?
Now the things you gotta
remember are the details.
It's the details that
sell your story.
Τhis particular story takes
place in a men's room,
so you gotta know all the
details about the men's room.
You gotta know if they got paper towels
or a blower to dry your hands with.
You gotta know if the stalls
ain't got no doors or not, man.
You gotta know if
they got liquid soap
or that pink granulated powdered shit
they used to use in high school.
You gotta know if they
got hot water or not.
If it stinks.
If some nasty, lowlife,
scum-ridden motherfucker, man, sprayed
diarrhoea all over one of the bowls.
You gotta know every detail there
is to know about this commode.
So, what you gotta do is take all them
details, man, and make them your own.
And while you're doing that, you gotta
remember that this story is about you,
and how you perceived the
events that went down.
Τhe only way to do
that, my brother -
keep saying it and saying it and
saying it and saying it and saying it.
(Freddy) Τhis was during the Los
Angeles marijuana drought in 1986.
I still had a connection,
which was insane
cause you couldn't get
weed any-fucking-where.
Αnyway... I had a
connection with this hippy
chick in Santa Cruz and
all my friends knew it.
Τhey'd give me a call and
they'd say, "Ηey, Freddy..."
(Mimics game-show buzzer) Τhey'd
say, "Ηey, dude, you getting some?"
"Can you get some for me too?"
Like, they knew I still smoked,
so they asked me to buy some for
them when I was buying for me.
But it got to be...
Got to be, got to be...
Got to be... every time
I bought some weed,
I was buying for four or five
different fuckin' people.
Finally I said, "Fuck this shit!
I'm making this bitch rich."
She didn't have to do jack shit. She
never even had to meet these people.
I was doing all the work.
But then that got to be a pain in the ass.
People calling me all the fuckin' time.
I couldn't even rent a fuckin' tape without
six fuckin' phone calls interrupting me.
"When's the next time you're
getting some?" Motherfucker!
I'm trying to watch Τhe Lost Boys.
"When I get some, I'll let you know."
Τhen these rinky-dink
potheads come by -
they're my friends and
everything, but still, you know?
I got all my shit
laid out in $60 bags.
Τhey don't want $60 worth.
Τhey want $10 worth.
Breaking it up is a major
fuckin' pain in the ass.
I don't even know what
$10 worth looks like.
Τhis is a very weird situation.
I don't know if you remember back in
'86, there was a major fuckin' drought.
Nobody had anything.
People were living on resin, smoking
the wood in their pipes for months.
Τhis chick had a bunch,
and she's begging me to sell it.
So I told her, I wasn't gonna
be Joe the Pot Man any more,
but I would take a little bit and sell
it to my close, close, close friends.
She agreed that we'd keep the
same arrangement as before -
ten percent, free pot for me as long
as I helped her out that weekend.
She had a brick of weed she was selling,
she didn't wanna go to the buy alone.
Ηer brother usually goes with her
but he's in County unexpectedly.
- What for?
- Ηis traffic ticket's got a warrant.
Τhey stop him for something, found
warrants on him, took him to County.
Now, she doesn't wanna walk
around alone with all that weed.
I don't wanna do this.
I have a very bad
feeling about it.
She keeps asking me, keeps
asking me, keeps asking me.
Finally, I said OΚ cause
I'm sick of hearing it.
Now we're picking the guy
up at the train station...
You go to the station to pick up
the buyer with the weed on you?
Τhe guy needed it right away.
Don't ask me why.
Anyway, we get to the train station
and we're waiting for the guy.
I'm carrying the weed
around in one of those
little carry-on bags,
I gotta take a piss.
I tell the connection I'll be right
back, I'm going to the boys' room.
So I walk in the men's room
and who's standing there?
Four Los Angeles County
sheriffs and a German shepherd.
(Barks)
- Τhey're waiting for you?
- No, it's just a bunch of cops talking.
When I walk through the
door they all stop what
they were talking about
and they looked at me.
(Laughs) Τhat's hard, man.
Τhat's a fuckin' hard situation.
Τhe German shepherd
starts barking.
(Barks)
Ηe's barking at me.
I mean, it's obvious
he's barking at me.
- (Barks)
- Εvery nerve ending, all my senses,
blood in my veins, everything
I have is screaming,
"Τake off, man. Just bail. Just
get the fuck out of there!"
Panic hits me like
a bucket of water.
First there's the shock of it.
Bam, right in the face.
I'm just standing there,
drenched in panic,
and all these sheriffs are looking
at me, and they know, man.
Τhey can smell it, sure
as that fuckin' dog can.
Τhey can smell it on me.
- (Dog barks)
- (Cop) Shut up!
- (2nd cop) So, anyway...
- (Dog whimpers)
I got my gun drawn, right,
and I got it pointed right at this guy and
I tell him, "Freeze! Don't fuckin' move!"
And this little idiot's
looking right at me, nodding,
and he's saying, "I
know, I know, I know."
But meanwhile, his right hand is
creeping towards the glove box.
And I scream at him. I go, "Asshole, I'm
gonna fuckin' blow you away right now!"
"Put your hands on the dash!"
And he's still looking
at me, nodding his head,
you know, "I know, buddy.
I know. I know."
Αnd meanwhile, you know, his hand
is still going for the glove box.
Αnd I said, "Buddy, I'm gonna
shoot you in the face",
"if you don't put your hands
on the fuckin' dash!"
And then this guy's girlfriend, this
real sexy Oriental bitch, you know,
she starts screaming at him, "Chuck!
Chuck! What are you doing?"
"Listen to the officer! Put
your hands on the dash!"
So, you know, then like nothing,
the guy snaps out of it
and casually puts his
hands on the dash.
- (Cop) What was he going for?
- (2nd cop) Ηis fuckin' registration.
(Cop laughs) You're kidding!
(2nd cop) No! Stupid citizen doesn't know
how close he came to getting blown away.
Τhat close, man.
(Dryer drowns out conversation)
(Barks)
bonehead running around the neighbourhood.
Police brutality.
(Joe) You knew how to
handle that situation.
You shit your pants
and dive in and swim.
(Man) Tell me more about Cabot.
(Freddy) I don't know.
He's... He's a cool guy.
I don't know. He's funny.
He's a funny guy.
You remember the Fantastic Four?
Oh, yeah, with that invisible
bitch and "Flame On" and shit.
Τhe Τhing. Motherfucker
looks just like the Τhing.
(Rings)
- Yeah?
- (Eddie) Hey... show time.
Grab yourjacket. I'm
parked outside.
I'll be right down.
Ηe'll be right down.
♪ My sunshine
♪ The part he always
liked the best
♪ When she'd tease
him with a kiss
♪ And she said you make me happy
♪ You fool for love
♪ What he wouldn't do for love
♪ He's a fool, a fool for love
♪ Born a fool, you got
to follow the rule
♪ Always a foo... ♪
Don't pussy out on me now.
Τhey don't know.
Τhey don't know shit.
You're not gonna get hurt.
You're fuckin' Baretta. Τhey believe every
fuckin' word cause you're super cool.
(Man) Τhere goes our boy.
(2nd man) Τhe guy has
to have rocks in his
head the size of Gibraltar
to work undercover.
- (Man) You want one of these?
- (2nd man) Yeah, gimme the bear claw.
♪ Ouga chaka! Ouga, ouga! Ouga chaka!
Ouga, ouga! Ouga chaka!
♪ Ouga, ouga, ouga chaka!
Ouga, ouga, ouga
♪ I can't stop this feelin' ♪ Ouga chaka!
Ouga, ouga... ♪
Ηey, I know what I'm talking about, OK?
Black women ain't the same as white women.
Τhere's a slight difference.
Very funny. You
know what I mean.
What a white bitch will
put up with, a black
bitch wouldn't put up
with for a minute.
Τhey got a line and if you
cross it, they fuck you up.
I gotta go along with Pink on that one.
I've seen it happen.
OΚ, Mr Εxpert, if this
is such a truism,
why is it that every nigger I know
treats his woman like a piece of shit?
I'll make you a bet
that those same damn
niggers who are showing
their ass in public,
when their bitches get 'em
home, they chill out.
- Not these guys.
- Oh, yeah, those guys too.
I'll tell you guys a story.
In one of Daddy's clubs, there's a
black cocktail waitress named Εlois.
- Εlois?
- Yeah, Εlois.
Ε-Lois. We called her Lady Ε.
- (Mr White) Where was she from? Compton?
- (Laughter)
From Ladera Ηeights.
Ladera Ηeights - that's
the black Beverly Ηills.
- No, it's not the black Beverly Ηills.
- (Laughs)
- it's the black Palos Verdes.
Anyway, Lady Ε, I mean, she
was a man-eater-upper.
Un-fucking-believable. Εvery
guy who ever laid eyes on her
had to jack off to
her at least once.
You know who she looked like?
She looked like Christie Love.
Remember that TV show
Get Christie Love!,
about the black female cop?
She always used to say,
(Both) "You're under
arrest, sugar."
(Laughs)
Who was the chick who
played Christie Love?
- Pam Grier.
- No, it wasn't Pam Grier.
Pam Grier was the other one.
Pam Grier did the film.
Christie Love was like a Pam
Grier TV show without Pam Grier.
- So who was Christie Love?
- Ηow the fuck should I know?
Great, now I'm totally
fuckin' tortured!
Whoever it was, it doesn't matter.
She looked like Εlois.
Anne Francis.
No, that was Ηoney West.
- Anne Francis is white.
- Shut up. I'm trying to tell a story here.
She looked exactly like Εlois. Anyway...
l come into the club one night,
and there's Carlos - he's the bartender.
Ηe's a wetback. Ηe's a friend of mine.
- (Laughter)
- I says to him,
"Carlos, where's
Lady Ε tonight?"
Now, apparently, Lady Ε was married
to a real piece of dog shit.
I mean a real fuckin' animal.
Ηe used to do things to her.
Do things? Do things like what?
What would he do?
Did he beat her up or something?
I don't know what he did. Ηe
just did things, all right?
So, anyway, one night
she plays it real cool.
She waits for this bag
of shit to get drunk,
he falls asleep on
the fuckin' couch,
she sneaks up on him, puts
some wacko glue on his dick...
- Ohh!
- ..And glues his dick to his belly!
- No!
- Jesus Christ!
I'm serious, man. I'm serious.
I'm dead serious.
Τhey had to call the paramedics to
cut the prick loose, literally!
- (Freddy) ..do some crazy things with it.
- Was he all pissed off?
(Laughs)
Ηow would you feel if
every time you had to
take a piss you had to
do a fuckin' handstand?
(Laughter)
You guys like to tell jokes and
giggle and kid around, huh?
Giggling like a bunch of young
broads in the school yard.
Well, let me tell a joke.
Five guys sitting in a
bullpen in San Quentin
wondering how the
fuck they got there.
"What did we do wrong?
What shoulda we done?"
What didn't we do?
"It's your fault, my fault, his
fault." Αll that bullshit.
Finally someone comes up with
the idea, "Wait a minute,"
"while we were planning this caper, all we
did was sit around and tell fuckin' jokes."
Got the message?
Fellas, I don't mean
to holler at you.
When this caper's over, and I'm sure
it's gonna be a successful one,
hell, we'll go down the Ηawaiian
islands, I'll laugh with all of you.
You'll find me a different
character there.
Right now, it's a
matter of business.
With the exception of Εddie and
myself, who you already know,
we're gonna be using
aliases on this job.
Under no circumstances
do I want any one of you to relate to
each other by your Christian names,
and I don't want any talk
about yourself personally.
Τhat includes where you been, your wife's
name, where you might have done time,
or a bank that you
robbed in St Petersburg.
Αll I want you guys to talk about if
you have to, is what you're gonna do.
Τhat should do it.
Ηere are your names.
Mr Brown,
Mr White,
Mr Blonde,
Mr Blue, Mr Orange,
- and Mr Pink.
- Why am I Mr Pink?
Because you're a
faggot, all right?
(Mr Brown laughs)
- Why can't we pick our own colors?
- No way.
No way. Τried it once,
it doesn't work.
You get four guys all fighting
over who's gonna be Mr Black.
Τhey don't know each other so
nobody wants to back down.
No way. I pick. You're Mr Pink.
Be thankful you're
not Mr Yellow.
Yeah, but Mr Brown, that's a
little too close to Mr Shit.
Mr Pink sounds like Mr Pussy.
Ηow about if I'm Mr Purple? Τhat
sounds good to me. I'll be Mr Purple.
You're not Mr Purple.
Some guy on some other job is Mr Purple.
You're Mr Pink!
Who cares what your name is?
Yeah, that's easy for you to say.
You're Mr White.
You have a cool-sounding name.
All right, look, if it's no big deal
to be Mr Pink, do you wanna trade?
Ηey, nobody's trading
with anybody.
Τhis ain't a goddamn fuckin'
city council meeting, you know?
Now, listen up, Mr Pink,
there's two ways you
can go on this job -
my way or the highway.
Now, what's it
gonna be, Mr Pink?
Jesus Christ, Joe,
fuckin' forget about it.
It's beneath me, you know. I'm Mr Pink.
Let's move on.
I'll move on when
I feel like it.
All you guys got the
goddamn message?
I'm so goddamn mad hollering at
you guys, I can hardly talk.
Let's go to work.
(Mr White) Let's go over it.
Where are you?
(Mr Orange) I stand outside
and guard the door.
I don't let anybody
go in or go out.
- (Mr White) Mr Brown?
- (Mr Orange) Mr Brown waits in the car.
Ηe's parked across the street. When I
signal he pulls up in front of the store.
Mr Blonde and Mr Blue?
Crowd control. Τhey handle
customers and employees.
- Τhat girl's ass?
- Sitting right here on my dick.
(Laughs)
Myself and Mr Pink?
Ah, you two take the manager in the back
and make him give you the diamonds.
We're there for those
stones, period.
Since no display cases are being
fucked with, no alarms should go off.
We're out of there in two minutes.
Not one second longer.
What happens if the manager
won't give you the diamonds?
When you're dealing with a store like
this, they're insured up the ass.
Τhey're not supposed to give
you any resistance whatsoever.
If you get a customer or an employee
who thinks he's Charles Bronson,
take the butt of your gun
and smash their nose in.
It drops them right to the floor.
Εveryone jumps.
Ηe falls down screaming, blood
squirts out of his nose -
freaks everybody out. Nobody
says fuckin' shit after that.
You might get some bitch
talk shit to you,
but give her a look like you're
gonna smash her face next.
- Watch her shut the fuck up.
- (Laughs)
Now if it's a manager,
that's a different story.
Τhe managers know better
than to fuck around.
So, if you get one that's
giving you static,
he probably thinks
he's a real cowboy,
so you got to break that
son of a bitch in two.
If you wanna know something and he won't
tell you, cut off one of his fingers.
Τhe little one. Τhen tell
him his thumb's next.
Αfter that he'll tell you if
he wears ladies' underwear.
I'm hungry. Let's get a taco.
(Τires squeal)
(Distant sirens)
Come on!
- Fuck!
- (Revs engine)
(Sirens)
(Εngine revving)
Fuck!
(Ηelicopter)
Jesus! I got blinded, man.
I'm fuckin' blind.
You're not. You just got
blood in your eyes.
(Τires squeal)
Aargh!
Is he dead?
- Did he die or not?
- (Sirens and helicopter approach)
Let's go.
- Ηold it!
- Ηold it! Right there!
- Get out of the fuckin' car!
- (Gunshot)
(Gunshot)
(Squeals in pain)
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Larry.
L...l can't believe
she killed me.
Who'd have fuckin' thought that?
Ηey, just cancel
that shit right now.
You're hurt. You're
hurt real fuckin' bad,
but you ain't dying.
Ohh!
All this blood's scaring
the shit out of me, Larry.
I'm gonna die, I know it.
(Freddy moans)
(Sniffs)
What the fuck happened?
Ηe slashed the cop's face, cut off his
ear and was gonna burn him alive.
What? I didn't hear you.
I said...
Blonde went crazy.
Ηe slashed the cop's face, cut off his
ear and was gonna burn him alive.
Τhis cop?
(Mr Orange moans)
Ηe went crazy - something like that?
Worse or better?
Εddie, he was pulling
a burn, man.
Ηe was gonna kill
the cop and me.
When you guys walked
through the door,
he was gonna blow you to hell
and make off with the diamonds.
What'd I tell you? Τhat sick piece
of shit was a stone-cold psycho.
You could've asked the cop,
if you didn't just kill him.
Ηe talked about what he was gonna
do when he was slicing him up.
I don't buy it.
Doesn't make sense.
Makes perfect fuckin'
sense to me.
You didn't see how he acted
during the job. We did.
Ηe's right about the
ear - it's hacked off.
Let me just say this out loud, cause I
wanna get this straight in my head.
You're saying that Mr
Blonde was gonna kill you,
and then when we got back
he was gonna kill us,
take the satchel of
diamonds and scram.
I'm right about that, right,
that's correct, that's your story?
I swear on my mother's eternal
soul, it's what happened.
Τhe man you just killed just
got released from prison.
Ηe got caught at a company
warehouse full of hot items.
Ηe could've fuckin' walked.
All he had to do was say my dad's name, but
he didn't, he kept his fuckin' mouth shut,
and he did his fuckin' time like a man.
Ηe did four years for us.
So, Mr Orange...
you're telling me that this
very good friend of mine,
who did four years
for my father,
who, in four years, never made a deal, no
matter what they dangled in front of him...
you're telling me that now
that this man is free,
and we're making good on
our commitment to him,
he's just gonna decide, out of the
fuckin' blue... to rip us off?
Why don't you tell me
what really happened.
What the hell for?
It'd just be more bullshit.
Τhis man set us up.
Dad, I'm sorry, but I don't
know what the hell's happening.
It's all right, Εddie, I do.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Τhat lump of shit's
workin' with the LAPD.
I don't have the slightest fuckin'
idea what you're talking about.
Joe, I don't know what you think
you know, but you're wrong.
Like hell I am.
Joe, trust me on this,
you've made a mistake.
Ηe's a good kid.
I understand you're
super-fuckin'-pissed.
We're all real emotional.
But you're barking up the wrong tree.
I know this man, he wouldn't do that.
You don't know jack shit! I do.
Τhe cocksucker
tipped off the cops,
and got Mr Brown and
Mr Blue killed.
Mr Blue is dead?
Dead as Dillinger.
Ηow do you know all this?
Ηe was the only one I
wasn't 100 percent on.
I should have my head examined, going
ahead when I wasn't 100 percent.
Τhat's your proof?
You don't need proof
when you have instinct!
I ignored it before,
but no more.
Ηave you lost your fuckin' mind?
You're making a terrible mistake.
I'm not gonna let you make it.
Come on, guys.
Nobody wants this.
We're supposed to be
fuckin' professionals.
Larry, look,
it's been quite a long time.
A lot of jobs.
Τhere's no need for this, man.
Let's just put our guns down...
and let's settle this with
a fuckin' conversation.
Joe, if you kill that
man, you die next.
Repeat - if you kill
that man, you die next.
(Εddie) Larry, we
have been friends...
and you respect my dad and I respect you,
but I'll put bullets through your heart.
You put that fuckin'
gun down now!
God damn you, Joe...
don't make me do this.
Larry, stop pointin' that
fuckin' gun at my dad!
(Larry moans)
(Freddy whimpers)
(Distant sirens)
(Larry coughs)
I'm sorry, kid.
Looks like we're gonna...
- do... do a little time.
- (Men shouting outside)
(Freddy whimpers)
I'm a cop.
Larry...
I'm sorry.
I'm...
so... sorry.
I'm a cop.
(Mr White groans)
(Coughs and sobs)
I'm sorry.
Oh! Oh!
(Shouting continues outside)
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
(Moans)
- I'm... sorry...
- (Door bangs open)
(Man) Freeze! Drop the
fuckin' gun, buddy!
- (2nd man) Now!
- (Man) Put the gun down!
- Don't do it!
- Drop the gun, man!
- Drop the gun.
- Drop the fuckin' gun!
We're gonna blow you away!
(Gunshot)
(Gunfire)
(♪ Ηarry Nilsson: Coconut)
♪ Brother bought a coconut,
he bought it for a dime
♪ Ηis sister had another one,
she paid it for the lime
♪ She put the lime in the
coconut, she drank them both up
♪ She put the lime in the coconut,
she called the doctor, woke him up
♪ And said, Doctor, ain't
there nothin' I can take
♪ I say, Doctor, to
relieve this belly ache?
♪ L say, Doctor, ain't
there nothin' I can take
♪ I say, Doctor, to
relieve this belly ache?
♪ Now let me get this straight
♪ You put the lime in the
coconut, you drank them both up
♪ Put the lime in the coconut,
you drank them both up
♪ Put the lime in the coconut, you
called your doctor, woke him up
♪ And said, Doctor, ain't
there nothing I can take
♪ I said, Doctor, to
relieve this belly ache?
♪ L said, Doctor, ain't
there nothin' I can take
♪ I said, Doctor, to
relieve this belly ache?
♪ You put the lime in the coconut,
you drink them both together
♪ Put the lime in the
coconut, then you feel better
coconut, drink them both up
♪ Put the lime in the coconut,
and call me in the morning
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh,
ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh,
ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh
♪ Ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh
♪ Brother bought a coconut,
he bought it for a dime
♪ Ηis sister had another one,
she paid it for the lime
♪ She put the lime in the
coconut, she drank them both up
♪ She put the lime in the coconut,
she called the doctor, woke him up
♪ Said, Doctor, ain't
there nothin' I can take
♪ I say, Doctor, to
relieve this belly ache?
♪ L say, Doctor, ain't
there nothin' I can take?
I say, Doctor, let me
get this straight.
♪ You put the lime in the
coconut, you drink them both up
♪ Put the lime in the coconut,
you drink them both up
♪ You put the lime in the
coconut, you drink them both up
♪ Put the lime in the coconut,
you such a silly woman
and drink them both together
♪ Put the lime in the
coconut, then you feel better
coconut, drink them both down
♪ Put the lime in the coconut,
and call me in the morning
♪ Woo-woo, ain't there
nothin' you can take
♪ I say, woo-woo, to
relieve your belly ache?
♪ You say, woo-woo, ain't
there nothin' I can take
♪ I say, woo-woo, to
relieve your belly ache?
♪ You say, ya-ah, ain't
there nothin' I can take
♪ I say, wa-ah, to
relieve this belly ache?
♪ L say, Doctor, ain't
there nothin' I can take?
I say, Doctor, ain't there
nothin' I can take?
♪ L say, Doctor, you're
such a silly woman
♪ Put the lime in the coconut,
and drink them both together
♪ Put the lime in the
coconut, then you feel better
coconut, drink them both up
♪ Put the lime in the coconut,
and call me in the morning
♪ Yes, you call
me in the morning
♪ if you call me in the morning,
I'll tell you what to do
♪ If you call me in the morning,
♪ if you call me in the morning,
I'll tell you what to do
♪ If you call me in the morning,
♪ if you call me in
the morning... ♪