(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
OFFICER 1: What do you
call yourself, huh?
(REPEATS QUESTION IN SPANISH)
Antonio Montana.
And you, what you
call yourself?
OFFICER 2: Where'd you
learn English, Tony?
In school.
And my father, he was
from the United States.
Just like you, you know?
He was a Yankee.
He used to take me a
lot to the movies.
I learned.
I watch the guys like Humphrey
Bogart, James Cagney.
They teach me to talk.
I like those guys.
I always know one day I'm
coming here, United States.
OFFICER 2: So where's
your old man now?
He dead. He die.
Sometime. Somewhere.
OFFICER 2: Mother?
She dead, too.
OFFICER 1: What kind of
work you do in Cuba?
You know, things.
I was this, that.
Construction business.
I work a lot with my hands.
I was in the Army.
OFFICER 1: Any family
in the States?
Cousins, brother-in-law,
anybody?
Nobody. Everybody's dead.
OFFICER 2: You ever
been to jail, Tony?
Me? Jail? No way, no.
OFFICER 2: Been in
a mental hospital?
Oh, yeah. On the
boat coming over.
OFFICER 2: What about homosexuality,
Tony? You like men, huh?
You like to dress
up like a woman?
What is wrong with this guy?
He kidding me or what?
OFFICER 1: Just answer
the questions, Tony.
Okay. No.
Fuck, no.
OFFICER 2: Arrested for
vagrancy? Marijuana?
Never, man.OFFICER 2: Heroin?
Cocaine?
No.
OFFICER 3: Where'd you get the beauty
scar, tough guy? Eating pussy?
How am I gonna get a scar
like that eating pussy?
This was when I was
a kid, you know?
OFFICER 3: Mmm-hmm.
You should see the other kid.
You can't recognize him.
And this?
What? That's nothing.
That's from my sweetheart.
Sweetheart, my ass!
We've been seeing more
and more of these.
Some kind of code these
guys used in the can.
Pitchfork means an
assassin or something.
You want to tell us about it,
or you want to take a trip
to the detention center?
Okay, you got me.
I was in the can one time.
For buying dollars. Big deal.
That's pretty funny, Tony.
That's true.
It was a Canadian tourist.
Did you mug him first?
Get him out of here!
OFFICER 2: Come on!
So I fuck up!
Let me talk to this guy.
Please! Let me talk
to him a minute.
You a Communist?
Huh?
How'd you like it?
They tell you
always what to do,
what to think, what to feel.
Do you want to
be like a sheep?
Like all those other people?
(MIMICKING SHEEP BLEATING)
I don't have to
listen to this!
You wanna work 8,
10 fucking hours?
You own nothing,
you got nothing!
Do you want a chivato
on every corner,
watching everything you do?
Everything you say, man?
You know I eat octopus
three times a day?
I got fucking octopus
coming out of my ears.
I got fucking Russian shoes,
my feet's coming through.
How'd you like that?
You want me to stay
there and do nothing?
I'm no fucking criminal, man.
I'm no puta or thief.
I'm Tony Montana, a political
prisoner from Cuba.
I want my fucking
human rights, now!
Like President Jimmy
Carter says. Okay?
Carter should see this human
right. He's really good.
What do you say?
I don't believe
any of this shit!
They all sound alike to me.
That Castro is
shitting all over us.
Send the bastard to Freedom
Town. Let them see him.
Get him out of here.
You know something?
You can send me anywhere.
Here, there, this, that.
It don't matter.
There's nothing
you can do to me
that Castro hasn't done...
OFFICER 3: Get
him out of here!
MANNY: So?TONY: So?
What'd you tell them?
What you told me to tell them.
That we... I was
in sanitation.
They didn't go for it.
Sanitation?
Yeah.
I told you to tell them
you was in a sanitarium,
not sanitation.
Sanitarium. Yeah.
You didn't tell me that.
No, I told you to say you had
TB and you was in a sanitarium.
You was cured.
When did you tell me that?
You should've kept
your mouth shut.
They'd think you was a
horse and let you out.
(CUBAN MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Tony! Montana!
Tony Montana! Come here.
Come here, man. I
gotta talk to you.
Come on, man. It's important.
So close, man. Come on.
I gotta talk to you.
Where are you going?
Leave him alone.
I got better things to do.
You're chicken, man.
You almost made it.
Are you ready for
some good news?
Sure. What you got, man?
We can be outta this
place in 30 days.
Not only that, but we got a
green card and a job in Miami.
Now are we made or
are we made, man?
What do we gotta do? Go to
Cuba and hit the Beard?
No, man, somebody else.
You're kidding.
No.
You're not kidding?
Guy named Rebenga, man.
Emilio Rebenga.
Rebenga?
I know that name.
Yeah?
He's political. Yeah.
MANNY: Well, he's coming in here
today. Castro just sprung him.
This guy was one of the top dogs
for Fidel in the early days.
Castro felt he couldn't trust
him and threw him in jail.
But while he was on top, he
tortured a few guys to death.
One of the guy's brothers
is a rich guy in Miami now.
He wants the favor repaid.
That's where we come in.
It's ugly, man.
(LAUGHS)
Yeah.
You tell your guys in
Miami, your friend,
it'd be a pleasure.
I'd kill a Communist for fun,
but for a green card, I gonna
carve him up real nice.
(RIOTERS YELLING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(YELLING)
(CHANTING IN SPANISH)
Rebenga!
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
From a friend you fucked!
That face. That's nice.
That doesn't look like me.
(EXCLAIMS)
That looks pretty, man.
(LAUGHING) Whoo!
TONY: Fuck!
What's wrong, man?
(REPEATS QUESTION IN SPANISH)
Your big shot friend better
come up with something soon.
I didn't come to the U.S.
to break my fucking back.
He's coming! What do
you want from me?
Fucking thing!
I told you.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
What's wrong?
(CONTINUES SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXCLAIMING IN SPANISH)
Look at that one.
That one in the pink.
She's beautiful.
Look at those titties.
TONY: Look at that
punk with her.
What's he got that
I don't have?
Well, he's very handsome,
for one thing, you know?
(CHUCKLING)
I mean, look at the
way he dresses.
Come on. That's style,
flash, pizzazz.
And a little coke money
doesn't hurt nobody.
Look at this.
Fucking onions.
They ought to be picking
gold from the street.
Oh, God, I can feel it.
There's two guys looking
for you out there.
That's him, man. That's El mono.
I told you.
OWNER: Don't stay
too fucking long.
We've got a lot of work to do.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON CAR STEREO)
(LAUGHING)
(MANNY SPEAKING SPANISH)
Waldo! Good to see you, man.
This is my friend Tony Montana
I've been telling you about.
Tony, that's Omar Suarez, and
that's Waldo Rojas over there.
I got something for you.
Yeah? What do we gotta do?
Gotta unload a boat.
Marijuana. 45 tons.
You get 500 each.
500? That's great.
You gotta be kidding.
500?
Who do you think we
are, baggage handlers?
The going rate on a
boat is 1,000 a night.
You know that.
First you gotta work
your way up to 500.
What I did for you in Freedom
Town, what was that?
That Rebenga hit was
a game of dominoes?
That was something else.
TONY: Shut up! Take it easy.
What's with this
dishwasher, chico?
Don't he know we could've got
any space cadet to
hit Rebenga cheaper?
50 bucks!
Then why didn't you?
Don't call me no
fucking dishwasher,
or I'll kick your monkey ass.
Who the fuck are you?
You can't do that, man!
The Colombians!
Okay, all right, big man!
You want to make
some big bucks?
Let's see how tough you are.
You know something
about cocaine?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You kidding me or what?
There's a bunch of
Colombians coming in Friday.
New guys.
They say they got two
keys for us, for openers.
Pure coke. Hotel
in Miami Beach.
I want you to go over there.
If it's what they say, pay
them and bring it back.
Do that, you got 5 grand.
Go, pay them, bring
it back, yeah?
You know how to
handle a machine gun?
Yeah, man. We
were in the Army.
You gonna need a
couple other guys.
That's no problem.
Be at Hector's bodega
at noon, Friday.
You get the buy money then.
If anything happens
to that buy money,
my boss will stick your
heads up your asses
faster than a
rabbit gets fucked!
I'm scared.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
You're pushing your luck.
Don't worry.
That was dumb.
You worry too much.
You'll have a heart attack.
You act like that guy's doing
you a favor or something.
What's this with
the Colombians?
What does it matter?
He says "Colombians," and
you make these eyes...
I don't like fucking
Colombians, okay?
What you guys doing?
There's a lot of
dishes to be washed.
Wash them yourself.
I retire!
What the fuck you
gonna do now?
Don't come back here!
I gotta look after
my investment!
Fuck you guys!
Close the shop!
MANNY: Look at those tits.
She's begging for it.
CHI CHI: Are you
fucking crazy?
She's 103 years old.
Not that one. Man! That one!
CHI CHI: Which one?
MANNY: The young one.
Move the fucking car.
We're at a stop sign.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
We're just staying loose up
here. You gotta stay loose.
You can't worry. You'll
have a heart attack.
CHI CHI: Just play it cool.
Miami Beach.
MANNY: Miami Beach, man!
The money stays in the
trunk till I come out.
You got it? Me, nobody else.
Okay.
I'm not out in 15 minutes,
something's wrong. Okay?
Room 9. You ready?
ANGEL: Sure thing.
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Okay. You mind leaving
the door open?
So my brother-in-law
sees everything's okay.
Sure. No problem.
No problem.
Hello. This is Marta.
Marta, hello.
I am Hector.
And I am Tony.
So, Omar says you're okay.
Yeah? Good. Omar's okay.
Okay.
So, you got the money?
You got the stuff?
Sure I have the stuff, but
not right here with me now.
I got it close by.
I don't have the
money either, man.
I have it close by, too.
Where?
In the car?
No, not in the car, man.
HECTOR: No?
How about you? Where
you have your stuff?
Not far.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
Okay. You want me to come in?
We start over again?
(LAUGHS)
Where you from, Tony?
What the fuck difference
does it make where I'm from?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Take it easy, man.
I just want to get to know
who I do business with.
You'll know me once you do business
with me and stop fucking around.
Okay?
TONY: What's the story? Tony!
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
You know, Frog Face, you
just fucked yourself.
You steal from
me, you're dead.
Yeah?
You want to give me the cash,
or do I kill your
brother first
before I kill you?
Why don't you try sticking
your head up your ass?
See if it fits.
Yeah? Okay.
(CHATTERING ON TV)
(VOLUME INCREASING)
MAN 1 ON TV: Yeah,
it's very important.
WOMAN ON TV: I understand
it's important.
MAN 1: Thank you.
WOMAN: You're welcome.
MAN 2: You forecasted
an earthquake
in the 3-to-4-point
range this morning.
MAN 3: We had an earthquake
in the 3-to-4-point range.
MAN 2: I'm impressed.
MAN 3: Thank you, sir.
MAN 2: However, isn't it
rather slender evidence...
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON CAR STEREO)
You have such beautiful skin.
I like the way you...
I don't know what I'm
supposed to do today, but...
(CHAINSAW WHIRRING)
Antonio, mira!
Watch what happens
to your friend.
If you don't want this
to happen to you,
give me the money.
(ANGEL SCREAMING)
Come on, come on.
(EXCLAIMING IN SPANISH)
Now the leg, huh.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Let's do it, man. Come on.
We're all gonna be all right.
Okay, cara cicatriz.
You can die, too. It makes
no difference to me.
Last chance, pendejo!
Fuck you!
(WHIRRING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
You Okay?
Yeah, man. It went in and out.
TONY: Okay, take him
out of here, quick!
Chi Chi! Get the yeyo.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Your turn.
I kill you!
Die!
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Hurry up! Get in! Come on.
Let's go!
Close the door!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Bunch of cowboys.
Somebody fucked up.
OMAR OVER PHONE: Yeah, well,
I'll check it out right away.
You do that, Omar.
You do that.
You still got the money?
Yeah.
And I got the yeyo.
You got the yeyo?
Yeah, right.
Bring it here.
Fuck you.
I'm taking it to Lopez myself.
Not you, me.
Nice fucking guy.
Frank Lopez. Tony Montana.
Tony Montana.
Mr. Lopez. It's a
real pleasure.
You can call me Frank.
Everybody calls me Frank.
My Little League team,
even the fucking
prosecutors around town,
they all call me Frank.
Okay, Frank. How are you?
Manny Ribera.
He caught one on the job.
Went right through.
We heard about that.
Omar, he tells me great
things about you guys.
Well, Omar's okay.
Not to mention, of course,
the nice job you did for me.
That Commie son of a bitch...
You don't have to mention that.
That was fun.
That was fun?
Damn right.
(LAUGHING)
That was fun.
Sometimes it's fun.
What do you want to drink?
Scotch, gin, rum?
What do you like?
Gin is fine. Want some?
Two gins.
I need a guy with steel
in his balls, Tony.
A guy like you. And I need
him around me all the time.
You, Tony, and your
compadre here.
Here's the stuff.
Two keys.
It cost my friend Angel his
life. Here's the money.
My gift to you.
I'm sorry about
your friend, Tony.
If people would do
business the right way,
there'd be no
fuck-ups like this.
Don't think I don't
appreciate the gesture.
You're gonna find, you stay
loyal in this business,
you're gonna move up.
You're gonna move up fast.
And you'll find out
your biggest problem
is not bringing in the stuff,
but what to do with
all the fucking cash!
(LAUGHING)
I hope I have that
problem someday.
You'll have that
problem, don't worry.
Sit down over here.
Where the hell's Elvira?
It's late. Go find
her, will you?
Jesus! Fucking broad.
She spends half her life dressing,
the other half undressing.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Gotta get her in between.
ERNIE: She's coming.
Yeah.
You gotta jump on her
when she's not looking.
That's the best time.
What are you guys
doing tonight?
You wanna go to a nice
restaurant with me? You hungry?
I could eat a horse.
Okay, they'll
cook you a horse.
I'll eat it.
Tell me, where'd they get you?
Right there in the side?
It's nothing. It went
right through me.
It hit the wall.
I ran out of bullets,
like an asshole.
When I changed the clip, a
guy who I thought I killed
wasn't dead and shot me.
The guy was behind me.
I killed him.
How many bullets you catch?
Bullets? One bullet.
9mm.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
FRANK: Elvira, where
the hell you been?
It's 10:00. I'm starving.
You're always hungry. You
should try starving.
Where you going? Come on.
Come over here! I want you
to meet a friend of mine.
Tony Montana. Elvira.
Hello.
Manny Ribera. Elvira.
So, there are five of us.
Where are we having dinner?
I thought we'd go to
the Babylon Club.
Again? Again.
You know, Frank, if anyone
wanted to assassinate you,
you wouldn't be
too hard to find.
Assassinate me? Who the
hell would want to kill me?
(FRANK LAUGHS)
I got nothing but friends!
You never know.
Maybe the catcher on
your Little League team.
The catcher? That
son of a bitch,
he didn't get a base
hit all season.
I should kill him!
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
You know who that is? Luis
and Miguel Echevierra.
They got the biggest distribution
setup from here to Houston,
Tucson, all down that way.
What do you think
of that, huh?
Look.
You see that fat bastard?
That's Nacho Contreras.
El Gordo!
He's got more cash than
anybody in this place.
He's a real chazer!
(LAUGHING)
You know what a chazer is?
No, Frank, you tell me.
What is a chazer?
It's the Yiddish
word for "pig."
A guy who wants
more than he needs.
He don't fly straight no more.
So, it comes down
to one thing,
Tony boy, and you
never forget it.
Lesson Number 1.
Don't underestimate
the other guy's greed!
ELVIRA: Lesson Number 2.
Don't get high on
your own supply.
That's right. Lesson Number 2.
Don't get high on
your own supply.
Course, not everybody
follows the rules.
Your champagne, Mr. Lopez.
That is '64?
The best, Mr. Lopez.
Omar, you pour it,
and you bring
another bottle right
away, will you?
Pleasure, Mr. Lopez.
$550 for this bottle, Tony.
What do you think of that?
That's pretty good.
For a bunch of fucking grapes.
So, here's to old friends
and to new friends.
How you like it, Tony?
That's good, Frank.
That's good?
Like you say, man.
That's good!
I'm gonna get you
new clothes, too.
I'm gonna get you $550 suits,
so you look real sharp.
'Cause I want you
to work for me.
I want you and your boys
to work with Omar here.
We are going to do
something big next month.
We are running a string
of mules from Colombia.
You do good on that, there'll
be some other things.
That sounds like
fun to me, Frank.
You want a cigar?
You wanna dance, Frank,
or sit here and have
a heart attack?
Who? Me, dance? I want a
heart attack instead.
Don't foam into the Dommie P.
How about you?
What? You want me to dance?
Yeah, sure. Go on, Tony.
You dance.
Go on. Have some fun.
What do you think of him?
I think he's a
fucking peasant!
But you get a guy like
that on your side,
he breaks his back for you.
What's your name?
What?
What's your name? Elvira what?
Hancock.
What?
Hancock!
Hancock?
Sounds like a bird. Hancock.
Flying around.
Where you from?
Baltimore.
What?
Baltimore! Baltimore?
Where's that?
It doesn't really matter, okay?
I'm just trying
to be friendly.
I don't need another friend,
especially one who just
got off a banana boat.
Banana boat?
Hold it. You got
the wrong guy.
I don't come off
no banana boat.
You're thinking of
someone else, maybe.
Aren't you part of the
Cuban crime wave?
What you talking crazy for?
I'm a political refugee here.
So take it easy.
Don't talk crazy.
Sorry.
I didn't know you were so sensitive
about your diplomatic status.
What is your problem, baby?
You're good-looking.
You got a beautiful
body, beautiful legs,
a beautiful face, all these
guys in love with you.
Only you got a
look in your eye
like you haven't been
fucked in a year!
Hey, José.
Who, why, when and how I fuck
is none of your business, okay?
Now you're talking
to me, baby.
That I like. Keep it coming.
Don't call me "baby"!
I'm not your baby.
Not yet, but you gotta
give me some time.
Even if I were
blind, desperate,
starved and begging for
it on a desert island,
you'd be the last
thing I'd ever fuck.
That chick he's with...
MANNY: Yeah? ...She likes me.
She likes you?
How do you know?
I know.
The eyes, chico.
They never lie.
Are you serious?
Serious? What do you think?
That's the boss' lady, okay?
You're gonna get us killed.
Fuck you, man. The boss' lady.
That guy's soft.
Look in his face.
The booze and the concha
tell him what to do.
Don't fucking go
crazy on me, okay?
Just remember last
year at this time
we were in a fucking
cage, okay?
You remember.
I'd like to forget that.
I say be happy
with what you got.
You be happy.
Me, I want what's
coming to me.
What's coming to you?
The world, chico,
and everything in it.
Oh, man.
This is paradise.
This is paradise,
I'm telling you.
This town's like a great big pussy
just waiting to get fucked.
I should've come
here 10 years ago.
I'd have been a
millionaire by this time.
By this time, I'd
have had my own boat,
my own car, my
own golf course.
You know what I want? I thought
of this the other day.
A line of blue jeans.
With my name written on the
back of chicks' asses.
How's that?
That sounds completely
crazy to me.
Look at that. Look.
You're missing the sights.
That's what you're doing.
We're missing the action.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Want to have some ice cream
with my friend and me?
Get lost, greaseball!
Look at that. Ice cream?
That's right. You
said "ice cream"?
Girls like ice cream.
Oh, come on. That won't work.
You can't do it that way.
You know how you pick up
chicks in this country?
What was that?
What you just did?
That's what you do.
That's disgusting.
Watch.
Look at that fucking thing.
You look like a lizard.
Like a bug coming
out of your mouth.
Figures you wouldn't
understand.
But the women in this country,
when you do that, they know.
They know what?
They understand.
They go crazy.
It'll take practice,
but you gotta learn.
'Cause women love when
you suck the pussy.
Look at that.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
She's looking at us.
You think you can
do it with her?
I think I can.
TONY: You want to
try it with her?
MANNY: Why not?
You gonna watch me?
I'm looking at you. Go ahead.
You won't do it. Watch this.
I'm with you, man.
I'm gonna get her.
Go ahead, Romeo!
Do your thing.
Just be quiet. Just hang back.
Romeo!
You're looking
very pretty today.
Yes, you. I've
been watching you.
You want to see
something funny?
Take a look over there.
See that man?
Watch that guy. I
gotta sit down here.
I gotta watch my friend.
He gonna stick his
tongue out to that girl.
Oh, look at that.
You're sick!
You see what happened to him?
If I wasn't a nice guy...
She's too big for you.
Causing trouble
like that, come on.
Bitch! Lesbian! What
I try to tell you?
What I try to tell you?
This country, you gotta
make the money first.
Then when you get the
money, you get the power.
Then when you get the power,
then you get the women.
That's why you gotta
make your own moves.
MANNY: That's the
one I rented.
No. That's her, man.
There she is.
About time.
Frank got held up
at the golf course.
He told me to pick you up.
He said he'd meet us
at the track later.
He said to bet on Ice Cream
in the first, by the way.
In that thing? You
must be kidding.
What you talking about?
That's a Cadillac.
I wouldn't be caught
dead in that.
Oh, come on.
It's got a few years,
but it's a cream puff.
It looks like
somebody's nightmare.
So, you like this better?
Yeah.
It's like one of them
tigers from India.
Tigers, huh? Tigers, no?
Crazy guy. Know what
he's been doing?
Dragging me to the zoo
to look at tigers.
He says he's gonna buy one.
You do that and you won't
have any friends left.
Not that you have any now.
You're gonna like
that tiger, man.
You gonna drive around with a
tiger in your passenger seat?
Maybe. Some lady tiger.
How much?
43,000, fully equipped.
That all?
Machine-gun turrets are extra.
He's a funny guy.
Come here, Manny.
Bulletproof this, okay?
And this here and here.
MANNY: Okay.TONY:
And the windows.
Get me a phone
with a scrambler.
A scrambler.
And a radio with scanners
to pick up flying
saucers, stuff like that.
Don't forget the fog lights.
Oh. In case I get caught in a
swamp. That's a good idea.
(HORN HONKING)
Get out of the way, lady!
I'm trying to drive here!
I thought you were
taking me to Frank.
We got an hour. You hungry?
No, but I'm bored.
Well, that figures.
Check it out, Manny, okay?
And pay the guy.
And you take a taxi. Meet
me at the track, okay?
Good doing business with you.
Mr. Montana.
Oh, God, man!
I wouldn't buy the car
if you didn't like it.
Planning on driving the girls
crazy, aren't you, Tony?
Oh, yeah. You know who?
What would Frank say?
I like Frank, you know?
Only I like you better.
(SNIFFS)
You got some for me?
Sure.
Okay.
(SNIFFS)
Don't get confused, Tony.
I don't fuck around
with the help.
You wanna play that way
with me, I play with you.
Shit.
Would you kiss me
if I wear the hat?
No!
Playtime is over, okay?
(LAUGHS)
Okay.
Mama?
Antonio.
Long time.
No postcards from jail, huh?
Gina.
Tony?
Look at you.
You're beautiful.
I didn't...
Mama, look at those eyes, huh.
Look at that. She
looks like me.
(LAUGHS)
You know the last time I saw
you, you was like that.
You looked like a little boy.
Now look at you.
I got something for you.
It's no big deal.
Oh, Tony!
(SOBBING)
I never thought I'd see
you again you know?
You think they'd keep
a guy like me down?
Well, no.
You look so good.
Look, open that up. Open it.
For me?
I think so.
It's nothing much,
you know, nothing.
(EXCLAIMING)
See what's written
on the back?
GINA: On the back? Aw.
Always.
"Always." It's
beautiful, Tony!
Mama is still working
in the factory,
and I work part-time
in a beauty parlor.
I'm doing hair, Tony. Do you
remember Hiram Gonzalez?
His father owned that
barbershop. It's his place.
Plus I go to junior college.
Miami Dade.
In two more years, I get
my cosmetology license.
Then I'll be making
enough money...
Surprise!
All that's over,
starting today.
Why?
My kid sister don't
have to work
in no beauty parlor, and Mama,
she don't have to
sew in no factory.
Your son made it, Mama.
He's a success.
That's why I didn't
come around before.
I want you to see what
a good boy I've been.
Here's $1,000.
For you, Mama.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Who did you kill
for this, Antonio?
Mama.
I didn't kill nobody, Mama.
MAMA: No? No.
What are you doing now?
Banks, or is it still
bodegas, you and the others?
No! Things are different now.
I'm working with an
anti-Castro group.
I'm an organizer now.
I get a lot of political
contributions.
Sure you do.
A gun sticking in
somebody's face is how.
You know, all we hear
about in the papers
is animals like you
and the killings.
It's Cubans like you who are
giving a bad name to our people,
people who come
here, work hard
and make a good name
for themselves.
People who send their
children to school.
What are you saying?
That's your son...
Son? I wish I had one.
He's a bum. No.
He was a bum then
and he's a bum now.
Who do you think you are?
Mmm?
We haven't heard a word
from you in five years.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You suddenly show up here,
throw some money around
and think you can
get my respect.
You think you can buy
me with jewelry?
You think you can come into my
house with your hotshot clothes
and your jail manners
and make fun of us?
You don't know what
you're saying.
That's not the way
I am, Antonio!
That is not the way I
raised Gina to be!
You are not going
to destroy her.
I don't need your money.
(THANKING IN SPANISH)
I work for my living.
I don't want you in
this house anymore!
I don't want you around Gina.
So come on. Get out!
Okay.
Mama...
And take this lousy money
with you. It stinks.
Tony.
Why do you have to spoil
it for everybody, huh?
I'm sorry, Tony.
Okay, Mama.
No. Tony, wait a minute!
Don't go, please!
Gina, stay here!
No, Mama.
He's no good. Gina!
Tony, wait, please!
I'm sorry. I don't know.
Mama, ever since
Papa left, she's...
Forget Papa. We never had one.
I know you did some
bad things back then.
In the Army, I know you
got into some trouble.
The Communists,
they're always trying
to tell you what to do.
Mama doesn't understand that.
I know.
I just... I don't know.
I just want you to know
that I don't care.
It doesn't matter
to me how long
you've been away,
five or ten years.
You're my blood, always.
I know.
Come on. I want
you to take this.
I gotta go back in.
No, Tony. Please.
You need this.
What will I tell her?
Take that. You don't
tell her anything.
Don't tell her I
gave it to you,
but give her some
from time to time.
And listen, you
go out yourself.
Go ahead. Go out, do some
things. Have some fun.
You gotta get some
fun out of life.
You gonna beat yourself
to death at 19?
A pussycat like you?
Come here.
I'll talk to you again. Okay.
Put that money away.
Don't let her see it.
I'll talk to her.
I'll talk to you. Okay.
Let's go.
She's beautiful.
How come you...
Hey!
Stay away from her. You hear?
She's not for you.
Okay.
(ENGINE STARTING)
So, this and my other factory,
I can guarantee production
of 200 kilos refined
every month of the year.
The problem is, I have
no steady market.
Basically, what I'm looking
for is somebody in the States
who can share the
risk with me,
somebody who can guarantee
to buy from me, say,
150 kilos a month.
Oh, that's a big commitment,
Mr. Sosa. Something like that...
Too bad Frank's not here.
You should talk to him.
It would've been
nice if he'd come.
He would like to come,
but with his trial coming up,
it's hard to leave
the country.
So he sent you instead?
Something like that.
We'll talk at my
house, shall we?
You got good stuff here.
Class-A shit.
This Lopez guarantees to
buy 150 kilos from me
every month of the year.
He picks it up here.
I can sell it to him
for as little as
7,000 a key. You can't
do better than that.
But then we got to take
the risk of moving it.
We'll be cutting out the
Colombians. Know what that means?
That means we have to
go to war with them.
We cut out the Colombians,
we take risks on both sides.
TONY: Why don't we
split the risk?
You guarantee your delivery,
say, as far as Panama,
we take it from there.
Panama is risky.
It costs me more.
Panama I can sell
for 13.5 a key.
13.5? What, are you nuts?
13.5? We still got to take
that shit to Florida.
Do you know what that's
like these days?
You got the Navy everywhere.
You got frogmen.
You got EC2s with the
satellite-tracking shit.
You got the fucking Bell 209
assault choppers up the ass.
We're losing one out
of every nine loads.
That's no duckwalk
anymore, let me tell you.
Forget about 13.5.
(PHONE RINGING)
What do you suggest
that is reasonable?
Excuse me. One moment.
What the fuck's the
matter with you?
Are you negotiating
for Frank Lopez?
Don't worry about it.
Take it easy.
I'm not worried about it.
You should worry about it.
If he wants to make a deal,
it's up to him, not you.
We're doing this one deal.
That's it.
Fuck you. How's that?
Fuck you. Fuck you.
OMAR: You need to open your
eyes and keep your mouth shut.
That's it. Let it go at that.
TONY: Don't worry about it.
Your head's in
the wrong place.
You must watch out
for yourself.
Why not talk to him?
You think he wants to
give you the money?
Shut the fuck up.
I'm doing the talking
here, not you.
You're here to watch my back.
Watch my back.
Better than your front,
let me tell you.
That's easier to watch.
(INAUDIBLE)
Close your mouth.
I can't wait to see what Frank's
gonna react to this one.
Just shut up. I'm doing
the talking here.
SOSA: Now where were we?
Panama.
You're looking for
a partner, right?
Something like that.
Look, Mr. Sosa, we're
getting ahead of ourselves.
I am down on Frank's authority
to buy 200 keys, that's it.
That's my limit.
I got no right.
Nobody got no right
to negotiate...
Let the man finish, okay?
Let him propose a proposition,
then we can talk more.
You got no authority here.
I started you in this business,
so shut the fuck up.
Frank is gonna love it.
That's up to Frank, not you!
I'm sorry about
this, Mr. Sosa.
No, it is all right.
You're right. Maybe you
should talk to Frank.
Well, good.
I don't think it's something I
want to do on an overseas phone.
But as soon as I
get back to Miami,
I will talk to
Frank personally.
Good.
My associates can escort
you to my chopper
to take you to Santa Cruz.
I have a jet there. You'll
be in Miami in five hours.
You'll be back here
tomorrow in time for lunch.
Good.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Good talking to you.
Why not leave
your friend here?
While you're gone, he can tell
me how to run my business.
I think Frank
wants to see him.
No, that's okay.
You tell Frank I'm keeping
this guy on ice for him.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I guess so.
Let's finish our lunch.
I have to hand it
to you, Mr. Sosa.
You got everything
a man could want.
I like you, Tony. There
is no lying in you.
Unfortunately, I
don't feel the same
about the rest of
your organization.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
What do you mean
by that, Mr. Sosa?
I'm talking about Omar Suarez.
This garbage was recognized
by my associate at lunch
from several years
ago in New York.
He was an informer
for the police.
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
He put Vito Duval and Nello
and Gino Ramos away for life.
So how do I know you're
not a chivato, too, Tony?
Hey, Sosa.
Let's get this straight now.
I've never fucked anybody over
who didn't have it coming.
You got that?
All I have in this world
is my balls and my word.
I don't break them for
no one, you understand?
That piece of shit up
there, I never liked him,
I never trusted him.
For all I know,
he had me set up
and had my friend Angel
Fernandez killed.
But that's history.
I'm here, he's not.
You want to go on
with me, say it.
You don't, then
you make a move.
I think you speak from
the heart, Montana.
But I say to myself,
"This Lopez, your boss,"
"he had chivatos like
that working for him."
His judgment stinks.
So I think to myself,
"How many other mistakes
has this Lopez guy made?"
"How can I trust his
organization?" You tell me, Tony.
Frank is smart, you know?
You can't blame him
for that animal.
It's a crazy business
we're in, you know?
That could happen to
anyone, even you.
Why don't I go back
and talk to Frank
and work it out?
I'll fix things between us.
You got my word on that.
I think you and me, we
can work this thing out,
we do business
together a long time.
Just remember,
I'll only tell you one time,
don't fuck me, Tony.
Don't you ever try to fuck me.
FRANK: You what?
You made a deal for
fucking $18 million
without even checking with me?
Are you crazy, Montana?
Are you crazy?
Coño. Take it easy.
Coño, my ass!
At 10.5 a key, it's puro.
You can't lose money. No way.
We make 75 million
on this deal.
75 million.
That is serious money.
What is Sosa going to do
when I don't come up with
the first 5 million?
What is he going to do?
Will he send me a bill?
He'll send a hit
squad up here!
There'll be a war
in the street.
Relax! Take it easy. I'm
in tight with Sosa.
You short a couple of mil, I
go on the street for you.
I make a couple of moves,
a mil here, a mil
there, you got it.
Okay?
You've been making
moves on your own?
I got ears, you know.
I hear things.
What do you hear about Echevierra
and the Diaz brothers?
What about Gomez?
What'll he do when you
start moving 2,000 keys...
Fuck Gaspar Gomez and
fuck the Diaz brothers!
Fuck them all!
I'll bury those cockroaches!
What they ever do for us?
Look, Frank, the
time has come.
We gotta expand.
The whole operation.
Distribution.
New York, Chicago, LA.
We gotta set our own
mark and enforce it.
We gotta think big now.
Think big.
Like your friend Sosa.
Let me tell you something about
that greaseball cocksucker.
He is a snake,
that's what he is.
You turn your back on
him, he'll stick it in.
You don't trust a
guy like that.
You want me to believe
Omar was a stoolie
because Sosa said so?
You bought that line?
Maybe I made a mistake
sending you down there.
Maybe you and Sosa know
something I don't know.
Like what?
You tell me, "Like what."
You calling me a liar, Frank?
That what you're calling me?
Let's just say I want things
to stay the way
they are for now.
You stall your deal with Sosa.
Stall it?
Okay, boss.
Come on.
I am the boss.
Sure, you're the boss.
Hey, Tony.
Remember I told you
when you started,
the guys who last
in this business
are the guys who fly straight,
low-key, quiet.
And the guys who want it all,
chicas, champagne, flash,
they don't last.
You finished?
Can I go now?
Hi, there.
You just missed Frank.
Too bad.
Only I didn't come
to see Frank.
This is not the time
or the place, Tony.
Next time, make
an appointment.
That's okay.
I got something important I
want to talk to you about.
So why don't we have
a couple of drinks,
act normal,
and just take it easy?
Come on. I like Scotch.
Sure. Why not?
Okay. I won't bite you.
We're all normal here.
I heard you and Frank aren't
working together anymore.
That's right.
I think it's
easier, don't you?
Makes things easier.
Thank you.
Here's to the land
of opportunity.
For you, maybe.
You like kids?
Kids?
Kids. You know, kids.
Little kids.
Sure. Why not?
As long as there's a nurse.
Good, 'cause I like kids, too.
I like them. Boys, girls.
Don't matter to me.
Frank's gonna be
back any minute.
Come here.
Sit here.
I want to talk to you.
Sit down.
I'm not gonna bite you.
Okay, here's the story.
I come from the gutter.
I know that.
I got no education,
but that's okay.
I know the street,
and I'm making all the
right connections.
With the right woman,
there's no stopping me.
I could go right to the top.
Anyway, what I got
to tell you is this,
I like you.
I liked you the first
time I laid eyes on you.
I said, "She's a tiger."
"She'll belong to me."
Anyway,
I want you to marry me.
I want you to be the
mother of my children.
Me? Marry you?
That's right.
(SIGHS)
What about Frank, Tony?
What will you do about Frank?
Frank is not gonna last, okay?
He's finished.
Just think about it, okay?
I want you to really
think about it.
I'll go now. Take care.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
All your enemies are gone.
Mr. Montana. How are you?
Hello.
What the fuck she doing here?
MANNY: Come on, man.
She's just dancing.
Come on. Take it easy.
It's just a disco.
Who's that guy she's with?
MANNY: He's some guy who
works for Luco. He's nobody.
He's harmless. Works for Luco?
Yeah. Forget him.
(EXCLAIMS)
Hello, Tony. You remember me?
Bernstein. Mel
Bernstein, right?
Chief Detective, Narcotics.
That's right, yeah. I
think we should talk.
Talk? What are we
going to talk about?
I ain't killed
nobody, not lately.
No, not lately.
What about ancient history,
like Emilio Rebenga?
Or a bunch of whacked-out
Indians at the Sun Ray Motel?
Whoever's giving you
your information
is taking you for a long ride.
Oh, yeah? Yeah.
Tony, baby, we gonna talk,
or am I gonna bust your
wiseass spic balls
here and now?
Keep your eye on her.
MANNY: I'll do that.
TONY: Okay.
My office. Good.
The word on the street is you're
bringing in a lot of yeyo.
That means you're not a
small-time punk anymore,
you're public property now.
Supreme Court says that your
privacy can be invaded.
Okay. How much?
How much?
There's an answer
to that, too.
Here's how much.
Can you see it?
Big number. Yeah!
That's on a monthly basis,
same thing every month.
You know how this works?
No. You tell me.
We tell you who's
moving against you,
and we shake down who
you want shaken down.
Let's say that you got a real
problem making a collection.
And then we step in for you.
Got eight killers with
badges working for me.
When they hit, it hurts.
Same thing works
the other way.
You feed me a bust
now and then.
Some cowboy setting
himself up in business.
Small fry, you know?
We like snacks.
How do I know you're the last
cop I'm gonna have to grease?
What about Fort Lauderdale?
Metro? DEA?
How do I know what rock they're
gonna crawl out from under?
Well, that's not
my business, Tony.
We don't cross no lines.
You think I want
this conversation
going any farther
than this table?
My guys' got families.
They're legitimate cops.
I don't want to see
them embarrassed.
If they're embarrassed,
they'll suffer.
If they suffer, they'll
make you suffer.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You understand what
I'm talking about?
Huh?
Thanks for the drink.
By the way,
I got a vacation coming up.
I'm gonna take the wife
to London, England.
We've never been there.
So throw in a couple of
round-trip tickets, first class.
You gotta smile more, Tony.
You gotta enjoy yourself.
Every day above
ground is a good day.
Hello.
Yeah. Now that's the idea.
Okay, Mel.
You think about what I said?
About the kids?
You know, you are really nuts.
I'm nuts about you.
Why don't you find
your own girl?
My own girl? Yeah.
That's what I'm doing.
Go do it somewhere else.
Get lost.
Maybe I don't hear
so good sometimes.
You won't hear anything
if you go on like this.
Will you do something?
You're fucking right I'm
going to do something!
I'm giving you orders. Blow!
Orders? You giving me orders?
The only thing in this world
that gives orders is balls.
You got that?
Balls.
Let's go.
Elvira.
When you gonna learn? Huh?
Looking good, honey.
Keep up the bad work.
That cocksucker.
What happened?
He put that prick
Bernstein on me.
Who? Lopez did?
How do you know?
Who else knew about Rebenga?
Omar?
He's fertilizer.
He's letting me know
he's got weight on me.
I'll tell you what, man.
You know our little trip we've
been planning to New York?
It might be a good time.
Wait. Where you going?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Welcome to my private room.
Your private room.
This is my private room.
I got a beautiful, nice,
white lounge chair for you.
Gina, you taste so muy bueno.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Tony!
What are you doing? Shut up!
What? We wasn't doing nothing!
GINA: Fernando, wait!
Get out!
Damn you!
You think he's cute?
I saw him putting his
hand all over your ass.
My kid sister in a toilet.
It's none of your business.
None of my business?
The fuck it ain't!
You can't tell me what to do!
I am telling you!
Listen to me. Come here.
I catch you here again,
I'm gonna wipe you all
over the fucking place.
Yeah? Go ahead! Do it now.
I want to see it.
I want to see it
now, big shot.
Don't push me.
I want to see it now!
Don't push me! Get outta here!
Go outside.
You got some nerve, Tony!
You think you can
tell me what to do?
You can't tell me what to do.
I'm not a baby anymore.
I'll do what I want to do,
see whoever I want to see.
And if I want to fuck them,
then I'll fuck them!
Fucking, man! Come on, man.
What the fuck you want?
You want something? Huh?
No. Don't touch me.
No. We've got to
get out of here.
Not there. I don't
want to go out there.
Another great night here
at the Babylon, right?
(DRUMS BEATING)
Okay. All right!
Do another gram, you'll
all be babbling on.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
Is that coke in your bra, or
are you just glad to see me?
A little bit of hope,
I'm sure, yes.
I'm in a good mood. I was depressed
when I got up this morning.
I had a dry dream,
but I'm better now.
I do Laurel and Hardy
in Spanish, too.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
That's the height of
culture, I assure you.
But my favorite Cuban of all
time has to be Ricky Ricardo.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Mr. Babalu himself.
He had the same
problem for 10 years.
"Lucy, don't come
down to the club."
He's your brother. He loves you.
That's why he did it.
All right? He cares about you.
To him, you're still
his little sister.
That's the problem. He still
treats me like I'm a baby.
I'm 20 years old now.
I'm not anybody's baby.
You're so grown-up.
Come on, Gina. Put yourself
in his place, okay?
Right now, you happen to be
the best thing in his life,
the only thing that's
any good, that's pure.
Of course he doesn't want you
mixing with those people,
growing up to be like him.
He has this father
thing for you.
Feels like he has
to protect you.
Protect me against what?
Against guys like that asshole
you were dancing with tonight.
I like Fernando. He's a
fun guy and he's nice.
And he knows how to treat
a woman. All right?
He knows how to treat a woman?
Yes.
By taking her to the
toilet to make out?
MC: You've been a
great audience.
I got a special treat for you.
Here's a guy I found
in the jungle
from Caracas, Venezuela.
He's unlike anything
you've seen.
Give a warm Babylon welcome
to the one and only Octavio!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(INSTRUMENTAL BALLAD PLAYING)
Look around. Go
out with someone
who has something on the ball,
who's going somewhere in life.
Like who?
For instance, someone who's got
a real job, like a banker.
Or... Or a doctor, a lawyer...
What about you?
What are you talking about?
Why don't you take me out?
Are you crazy?
I see the way you
look at me, Manolo.
Do you think I'm blind? I see.
Come on.
What? Look, Gina,
Tony and I are like
brothers, all right?
You're his kid sister.
So what? That's where it ends.
That's where it stays.
Are you afraid of Tony, huh?
You afraid of
Tony's kid sister?
I'm not afraid of anybody!
That's not the point here!
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(PHONE RINGING)
MANNY: Oh, fuck.
(MIRIAM LAUGHS)
It's not for me.
Don't look at me.
How do you know?
'Cause I'm not here.
Oh, really? Then
where are you?
Shit, you're weird.
I'm weird?
Hello?
TONY: Hello, Miriam?
Tony!
Put Manny on, okay?
Okay. Just a second.
It's Tony.
What are you doing,
checking up on me?
Get your clothes
on and meet me
in front of Lopez
Motors in 45 minutes.
What? What happened?
Nothing we can't fix.
All right. I'll be there.
You're still on the phone.
Let's go.
Take it easy, okay?
I'm leaving now. Fuck.
Nick? Yeah, Tony.
This is what I want
you to do for me,
you call Lopez.
Call him at his
office at 3:00 sharp.
And you tell him,
"We fucked up, he got away."
Okay. Yeah.
Got it? What are
you going to say?
"We fucked up. He got away."
What time? 3:00 sharp.
FRANK: So when are we gonna
make some money on this thing?
Six months to start
don't mean shit, Larry.
I'm not a Rockefeller, you know.
Not yet, anyway.
(FRANK LAUGHING)
So you owe me.
Listen, go down to the
ball game tonight?
I couldn't make it.
I got things.
I'll tell you about them.
You're kidding. What was
the score? Three to two?
Mel, guess what.
My Little League team,
the Little Lopezers,
they won the division tonight.
That's great. Congratulations.
What'd you do, fix the umpire?
Jesus Christ.
Tony, what happened to you?
They wanted to spoil
my $800 suit.
Who the fuck did this?
Hitters. I don't know.
Somebody must've
brought them in.
I've never seen them before.
Hello, Mel.
Got an answer to this, too?
There always is, Tony.
I'll bet it was the
Diaz brothers.
They got a beef going back
to the Sun Ray thing.
Maybe you're right, you know?
Anyway, I'm glad
you made it, Tony.
We'll return the favor
for you in spades.
I'll take care of this myself.
What is the gun for, Tony?
What, this? It's nothing.
I'm... How do you say?
Paranoid.
(PHONE RINGING)
You gonna answer, Frank?
It must be Elvira. She got
mad after we left the club.
I'll tell her you're
not here, okay?
No, it's all right.
I'll talk to her.
Hello.
It's all right. I'm gonna be
home in an hour. Don't worry.
Frank, you're a piece of shit.
What are you talking about?
You know what I'm
talking about,
you fucking cockroach.
What are you talking about?
Listen to me, huh.
You know what a
chazeris, Frank?
That's a pig that
don't fly straight.
Neither do you, Frank.
Tony, why the fuck
would I hurt you?
I brought you in.
So we had a few
differences, no big deal.
I gave you your start. I was
the one who believed in you.
I stayed loyal to you.
I made what I could
on the side,
but I never turned
on you, Frank!
Never!
But you,
a man who ain't got his
word is a cockroach.
Mel. Do something, will you?
It's your tree, Frank.
You're sitting in it.
All right, Tony.
I was the one.
Please, give me a
second chance.
Will you do that? Please?
Give me a second chance.
I'll give you $10 million.
Okay? $10 million.
I got it in a vault over
there in Spain, Tony.
We go over there, we get on
a plane, and it's yours.
Okay? All of it. $10 million.
Okay, Tony?
Huh?
Please, Tony?
Elvira? You want Elvira?
You can have her. I'll go away.
I'm gonna disappear.
You'll never see me again.
Please, Tony, I
don't want to die.
I never did nothing to nobody.
No, you never did
nothing to nobody.
You had somebody
else do it for you.
Oh, Tony, I'm begging you.
Get up! Get up now!
(SOBBING) Jesus!
No! God!
Look. Tony, no! Don't
kill me, please.
I won't kill you.
Oh, Christ, thank you.
Get off my foot.
Thank you.
Manolo, shoot that
piece of shit!
No, no!
No!
Every dog has his
day, huh, Mel?
I told him
it didn't make any sense
clipping you when we had you working
for us. He wouldn't listen.
He got hot tonight
about the broad.
He fucked up.
You, too, Mel. You fucked up.
Don't go too far, Tony.
I'm not, Mel. You are.
(GROANING)
Fuck. You can't shoot a cop!
Whoever says you was one?
Wait a minute!
You let me go.
I'll fix this up.
Sure, Mel. Maybe you
can handle yourself
one of them first-class
tickets to the Resurrection.
Fucking punk! Son of a bitch!
So long, Mel.
Have a good trip.
Fuck you!
Okay, come on.
What about Ernie?
You want a job, Ernie?
Sure, Tony.
Okay, then you
call me tomorrow.
Man, you got a job!
Tony! Thanks.
Tony.
God, what's happened?
Where's Frank?
Where do you think?
Come on. Get your stuff.
You're coming with me.
(RHYTHMIC POP MUSIC)
(INAUDIBLE)
(ROARING)
TONY: So you come to me with
some kind of thing. Okay.
You propose it, I talk to you.
But we got a problem.
I can't pay more.
I'm bringing in twice as
much as I ever did before.
We're doing 10 million, 15
million a month. Come on.
That's serious money.
You bank boys gotta
come down a bit.
No way.
That's crazy. We
can't do that.
Then that's too bad.
What am I gonna do?
We're not a wholesale
operation.
We're a legitimate bank.
The more cash you give me,
the harder it is
for me to rinse.
That's a problem.
I didn't know.
The fact is, I can't take
any more of your money
unless I raise the
rates on you.
You gonna raise the...
I gotta do it.
The IRS is coming...
Don't give me that shit!
Let's talk.
I'm talking.
I go low, you go high.
I know the game.
This is business talk.
Let me explain something.
The IRS is coming down
heavy on South Florida.
There was a TIME magazine
story that didn't help.
There's a recession.
I got stockholders I got
to be responsible for.
I got to do it, Tony.
You'll learn from him.
I got to go 10% on the first 12
million in denominations of 20.
I'll go 8% on your $10 bills,
6% on your fives.
We'll go somewhere else.
That's it.
There's no place else to go.
Fuck you, man! Fuck you!
I'll fly the cash
myself to the Bahamas.
Once, maybe. Then what?
You'll trust some monkey
in a Bahamian bank
with 20 million of your
hard-earned dollars?
Come on, Tony. Don't
be a schmuck.
Who else can you trust?
That's why you pay us so much.
You trust us.
Huh?
Did you hear that guy?
You got to listen to him.
You'll learn something.
Stay with us.
You're a well-liked customer.
You're in good hands with us.
And I got to run.
I'm safe but poor.
How's married life
treating you?
Better than you are.
(LAUGHS)
Say hello to the princess
for me. She's beautiful.
I'll see you. Take care.
You, too.
That prick!
Fucking WASP whore.
Talking to me like I'm some
maricón who came over on a boat.
(SNIFFS)
I tell you what. We don't need
that smiling motherfucker.
We should talk to this Jewish
guy, Seidelbaum, okay?
He's got his own exchange.
He charges 4% at the most.
And he's connected.
Fuck them. Mob guys. Guineas.
I don't trust them.
Did you sweep the house
this month? The cars?
Yeah, I told you about it.
The $5,000?
Look at that.
What?
That cable truck there.
Since when does it take
three days to rig a cable?
What? You been watching
it for three days?
The thing has been
there for three days.
What am I gonna do,
not look at it?
What, you think
it's cops, right?
I don't know.
Could be the Diaz brothers,
coming to get me.
Maybe. I'll check
it out, okay?
You check it out.
Then we're gonna blow that
fucking truck back to Colombia!
Come on. We're not the only
dopers living on the block.
Okay? Remember that.
That truck could be
anybody and anything.
It could be a cable company...
You know something? You got
some fucking attitude.
For someone who's in
charge of my security...
Here are the keys
to the front door.
Go down there. Give
them the keys!
I'm just trying
to say something.
You're spending a lot of money
on this counter-surveillance.
I don't give a fuck.
It's 12% of our
adjusted gross.
12% isn't peanuts.
I don't give a fuck!
It makes me sleep good at night.
That's what counts.
Okay? You worry about it.
I am worried about it.
I'm telling you. We're
getting sloppy.
Our thinking, our fucking
attitude, you know?
We're not fucking
hungry anymore.
Miami's changing. You
can see it everywhere.
New construction. New jobs.
Growth that's financed by
Florida Security Trust.
We've put your money
to work for 75 years,
building a more
prosperous Miami.
Count on us being
here tomorrow.
TONY: That's because for 75 years,
you been fucking everybody.
Somebody should do something
about those whores.
I mean, charging me 10
points on my money.
They're getting away with it.
Fuck, there's no laws anymore.
Forget it. Anything goes.
They been around 1,000 years.
They got all the
angles figured out.
You know what capitalism is?
Getting fucked.
ELVIRA: True capitalist
if ever I met one.
Uh-oh.
Did you hear that?
How would you
know, bubblehead?
You ever do nothing besides
get your hair fixed
and powder your nose?
Look at you. You do too
much of that shit.
Nothing exceeds like excess.
You should know that, Tony.
I should know what?
What should I know?
Why do you have to talk to
me like that all the time,
like I got to know something?
Let me talk to you.
Listen. What time is it?
This Seidelbaum...
6:55.
Okay.
I met with this
guy Seidelbaum...
The drug-related violence
that's plagued South Florida...
He's good for a
laugh, this guy.
With a small law-enforcement
budget, how can you put a dent
on an estimated
$100-billion-a-year business?
It seems at times
all you can do
is put your finger in
the dike and pray.
Put your fingers in a dyke?
The only place you
can get your fingers
is in some dyke.
Not by outlawing
the substances,
but by legalizing
and taxing them.
These voices say that will drive
out the organized crime element.
I am not one of those voices.
I know that. But you know why?
'Cause you got your head
up your culo, that's why.
That fucking guy, he
never tells the truth.
Splendor of our
city at its best.
TONY: It's those guys, man!
It's the fucking bankers,
the politicians,
they're the ones that
wanna make coke illegal
so they can make
the fucking money
and then get the
fucking votes!
They fighting the bad guys.
They're the bad guys!
They fuck anything and anyone.
Can't you stop saying
"fuck" all the time?
Can't you stop talking about
money? It's boring, Tony.
Where's this coming from?
Boring? What's boring?
You're boring. Oh.
"Money." That's all I
hear in this house.
Look at these pelicans fly.
Come on, pelicans!
Here it is.
Frank never talked
about money.
That's 'cause he was so smart.
(BOTH SPEAKING SPANISH)
You know what you're becoming?
You're an immigrant spic millionaire
who can't stop talking...
Who the fuck you calling a "spic,"
you white piece of bread?
Get out of the way of the TV!
Dig a hole in the garden,
bury it, and forget about it.
I work hard for this! I
want you to know that.
Somebody should've
given it to you.
You would've been
a nicer person.
Know what your problem
is, pussycat?
What is my problem?
You got nothing to
do with your life.
Why don't you get a
job or something?
Do something. Be a nurse.
Work with blind kids, lepers.
That kind of thing.
Anything beats lying
around all day
waiting for me to fuck you!
Don't toot your horn, honey.
You're not that good.
No? Frank was better?
You're an asshole!
Where you going? Come here!
Elvie!
I was kidding!
I was only kidding!
I guess sometimes married life
is not all it's
cracked up to be.
Where you going?
I got a date.
You got a date? Come here.
Yeah.
What?
This Seidelbaum thing.
Yeah, it's all set up.
Yeah, well, you forget it.
Stay out of it. I'll
take care of it.
Stay out of it? It's my deal.
I set it up.
You're not a negotiator,
Manny, you know that.
You like the ladies
more than the money.
That's your problem.
What the fuck are you talking
about? I'm your partner, okay?
If you don't trust me
with that kind of thing,
who're you gonna trust?
Junior partner.
Bullshit, man.
Don't talk to me about
trust, I don't like it.
You should listen to your wife.
She's right.
You are an asshole, man!
Come here. Give me a kiss.
Come here.
Fuck you, man!
Who put this thing together?
Me! That's who!
Who do I trust? Me!
Fuck him. "Trust."
(SWITCHING CHANNELS)
Asshole. Fuck called
me an asshole.
I need that shit.
I don't need him.
I don't need her. Fuck them.
I don't need nobody.
Back then I worked ¡n
pictures down in Colombia.
I was in that movie Burn.
You ever see it?
You saw me with Marlon Brando?
You know, we're good friends.
I was his driver.
No shit?
Brando.
They shot it there. Cartagena.
Gillo Pontecorvo. He
was the director.
Italian guy.
Tell me about him.
I also know Paul Newman.
I worked with him in Tucson.
No kidding?
Do you know Benny Alvarez?
In Tucson. Benny Alvarez?
Subtotal.
No?
He's a nice guy.
$283,107.65.
You want a company check here?
I got 284.6.
That's just not possible.
The machine don't
make mistakes.
Let's count it again.
No. Come on.
Business is business. Come on.
You're talking $1,500 here.
Okay, you keep the change. Okay?
I don't give a shit.
I'll count it again for you.
No, come on.
This check here, where
does this check go?
Montana Realty Company.
Montana what?
That's 284.
284,600.
LUIS: How come you don't
know Benny Alvarez?
Me and Benny have
lunch together.
NICK: He probably knows me.
You ask him.
We're up to what?
Seven checks. $1,325,623.
200,000 more.
We ought to take a leak.
(THUD)
Freeze!
Get your hands up!
Go against the
wall, turn around.
You're not kidding.
You're under arrest for
violation of the RICO Statute.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and
will be taken against you.
How do I know you
guys are cops?
What's that say, asshole?
That's pretty good, man.
Where'd you get that?
You call yourself a Cuban?
You make a real Cuban throw up!
Call your dog off
me, Seidelbaum.
I want to call my lawyer.
SEIDELBAUM: Lot of good
he's gonna do you.
You see that eye
there in the clock?
Say, "Hi, honey."
That's pretty cute.
Look at that.
You jerk off in front
of us, Seidelbaum?
NICK: I was supposed to
meet this chick at 3:00.
You're a fucking
pain in the ass.
All right, Benny, kill it.
You understand the
rights I've given you?
I know all that
bullshit, Seidelbaum!
Save your breath.
You got nothing on me.
You know it. I know it.
I'm changing dollar
bills, that's all.
You want to waste my time?
Okay. I call my lawyer.
He's the best lawyer in Miami.
He's such a good lawyer
that by tomorrow morning, you
gonna be working in Alaska.
So dress warm.
SHEFFIELD: Give me a check for
100 grand, plus 300 in cash.
I guarantee you walk on
the conspiracy charge.
They're gonna come back
at us on a tax evasion,
and they'll get it.
So, what am I looking at here?
Five years. You'll
be out in three.
Maybe less, if I
can make a deal.
Three fucking years!
For what?
Washing money?
The fucking country was
built on washed money.
Can't be that bad.
It's not like Cuba.
What the fuck you talking?
The jails are like hotels.
You kidding me or what?
You fucking high or what?
I'll delay the trial.
A year and a half, two years.
You won't even start...
Fuck you, man!
I'm not going back
in any cage, okay?
No way. I been there.
Okay, look.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I give you $400,000 more.
Okay, now that's $800,000.
With that kind of money, you
can buy the Supreme Court.
Tony, the law has to prove
beyond a reasonable doubt.
I'm an expert at
raising that doubt.
But when you got 1.3 million
undeclared staring into
a videotape camera,
honey baby, it's hard
to convince a jury
you found it in a taxicab.
I'm so glad you could come
on such short notice.
I really appreciate it.
It's okay. How's Elvira?
Oh, great. How's your wife?
Three more months.
Oh, yeah? Congratulations.
How about you?
When you gonna have another
Tony to take your place?
I'm working on it.
You have to work harder. Come.
I want you to meet
some of my friends.
This is Pedro Quinn,
chairman of the Andes
Sugar Corporation.
Pleasure meeting you.
Nice to meet you.
General Edward Strasser, Commander
of the First Army Corps.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Pleasure.
This is Ariel Bleyer,
with the Ministry of the
Interior. Tony Montana.
And here is our friend Charles
Goodson from Washington.
Nice to meet you.
How do you do, Mr. Montana?
SOSA: Sit here, Tony.
Gentlemen.
I would like to
discuss something
that is of interest
to all of us here.
You have a problem, Tony.
We have a problem.
I think together we can
solve all our problems.
We all know you have tax
troubles in your country
and that you may have
to do a little time.
We have friends in Washington
that assure us these troubles
can be taken care of.
You may have to pay some
back taxes, a big fine,
but there will be no prison.
Okay.
So what's your problem, Alex?
I'll show you my problem.
INTERVIEWER: I've heard about financial
support your government receives
from the drug
industry in Bolivia.
Well, the irony of this
is that this money,
which is in the billions,
is coming from your country.
You are the major purchaser
of our national product,
which is cocaine.
INTERVIEWER: On one hand, you're
saying the U. S. government
is spending millions
to eliminate
the flow of drugs
onto our streets.
At the same time,
we are doing business
with the same government
that is flooding our
streets with cocaine.
Let me show you a few
of the other characters
that are involved in
this tragic comedy.
My organization just
recently traced
a large purchase by this man.
This charming face here
belongs to General Cucombre.
He is the Minister of the
Defense of Bolivia, my country.
And General Cucombre
just a couple months ago
bought a $12 million villa on
Lake Lucerne in Switzerland.
Now, if Cucombre
is supposed to be
the Bolivian Defense Minister,
what is he doing
living in Switzerland?
Guarding cash registers?
This man here, Alejandro Sosa,
a very interesting character.
He's a wealthy landowner,
educated in England,
very good family.
But this man is the business
brain and drug overlord
of an empire that stretches
across the Andes.
He's not your
ordinary drug dealer.
INTERVIEWER: Well,
discussing it openly...
(SWITCHES OFF TV)
He's scheduled for
60 Minutes next.
He is going on French, British,
Italian, Japanese television.
People everywhere are
starting to listen to him.
It's embarrassing, Tony.
That is our problem.
You remember
Alberto, don't you?
How could I forget him?
Alberto is an expert in
the disposal business.
He's going to help
us fix our problem.
But he doesn't speak English.
He doesn't know his way
around the States too well.
He needs a little help.
Is that a problem, Tony?
No problem.
Good.
So what's the big mystery
with the Bolivian situation?
You gonna tell me what
happened with Sosa, or what?
A lot of bullshit,
that's what happened.
Politics.
I want you to stay
down here for a while.
Run things for me.
I gotta go to New
York next week.
Fuck this, man.
I don't like it, man. I
don't like this at all.
You don't like it?
You got me into this
mess in the first place.
With that fucking
Seidelbaum, that right?
With Seidelbaum?
What does Seidelbaum
have to do with Sosa?
How do you connect those two?
Why don't you eat your food?
What's wrong with it?
I'm not hungry.
You're not hungry?
Do you even know
about the trial?
What did you order
it for, then?
I lost my appetite.
Do you even know
that Sheffield said
he can get you a postponement?
(SNIFFING)
Is this it? That's
what it's all about?
Eating, drinking,
fucking, sucking...
Come on, man.
Snorting?
Then what?
Tell me. Then what?
You're 50. You got
a bag for a belly.
You got tits, you need a bra.
They got hair on them.
You got a liver, and
they got spots on it
and you're eating
this fucking shit
and you're looking like these
rich fucking mummies in here.
Come on. It's not so bad.
It could be worse.
Is this what it's all about?
Forget it.
This what I work for? Tell me.
Look at that.
A junkie
I got a fucking junkie for a
wife. She don't eat nothing.
Sleeps all day with
them black shades on.
Wakes up with a Quaalude...
Don't pick on her, man.
And who won't fuck me
'cause she's in a coma.
I can't even have
a kid with her.
Her womb is so polluted,
I can't even have a fucking
little baby with her!
You son of a bitch!
You fuck!
You shouldn't talk like that.
How dare you talk
to me like that!
What makes you so
much better than me?
What do you do? Don't worry.
You deal drugs and
you kill people.
Oh, that's wonderful, Tony.
Real contribution
to human history.
Go ahead. Tell everybody.
You want a kid?
TONY: Tell the world.
What kind of a father
would you make?
(YELLING)
Gonna drive him to
school in the mornings?
Are you even gonna be alive by
the time the kid goes to school?
You don't know how
to be a husband!
Sit down before I...
Do we ever go anywhere
without having 600 thugs
hanging around all the time?
I have Nick "The
Pig" as a friend.
What kind of life is that?
Can't you see
what we're becoming, Tony?
We're losers.
We're not winners,
we're losers.
Go home. You're stoned.
I'm not stoned, you're stoned.
Get her out of here.
Come on.
I'm not going home with you.
I'm not going home
with anybody.
I'm going home alone.
I'm leaving you.
I don't need this
shit anymore.
Okay, but I'll walk you out.
I'll take her home in a cab.
Let her go.
Another Quaalude, she
gonna love me again.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
What're you looking at?
You're all a bunch
of fucking assholes.
You know why?
You don't have the guts to
be what you want to be.
You need people like me.
You need people like me
so you can point
your fucking fingers
and say, "That's the bad guy."
So, what does that make you?
Good?
You're not good.
You just know how to hide,
how to lie.
Me, I don't have that problem.
Me, I always tell the truth.
Even when I lie.
So say good night
to the bad guy!
Come on.
The last time you gonna see
a bad guy like this again,
let me tell you.
Come on. Make way
for the bad guy.
There's a bad guy
coming through!
Better get out of his way!
TONY OVER PHONE: No. You tell
Sheffield to keep his nose out of it.
There's gonna be no trial.
I got it all under
control now.
Just tell him to
stay out of it!
Okay, what about Elvira?
Did she call?
Yeah, all right.
Tony, everything go okay?
Yeah, everything is roses.
Ernie, what time do you got?
Ten to.
Where is this guy, man?
I gotta call Manny again.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You don't tell me
what to do here!
He's coming out.
ERNIE: He's coming.
I don't give a fuck.
It's him, man.
(ALBERTO SPEAKING SPANISH)
I don't care where
you blow him up.
Tell me when, okay?
You just tell me when.
That's all I care about.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING SPANISH)
I heard you the first time.
One time. That's all
you gotta tell me.
This fucking guy,
I'm telling you.
ERNIE: Look. Here he comes.
Where's he going?
What's he doing that way?
What the fuck he doing?
What the fuck is that?
Come here.
You said she took the
kids in the other car!
She did, every fucking day.
I don't know what's going on.
No fucking way. No fucking way.
That's it!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
This fucking guy.
Fuck you, you fucking vulture.
(ALBERTO SPEAKING SPANISH)
Two little kids in the car.
This is so fucking bad.
I see them, all right?
I see them!
Shut the fuck up, okay?
You don't have the guts to look
them in the eye when you kill them.
You gotta hide
with that shit...
ERNIE: He's getting up.
Let's do it.
Make you feel good?
Make you feel good to
kill a mama and her kids?
Make you feel big.
TONY: Like you, big man!
Fuck you!
What do you think I am?
You think I kill two
kids and a woman?
Fuck that! I don't need
that shit in my life!
You die, motherfucker!
(HORNS BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
What do you think I am, huh?
You think I'm a fucking
worm like you?
I told you, man! I told
you, don't fuck with me!
I told you, no fucking kids!
No, but you wouldn't listen!
You stupid fuck!
Look at you now.
TONY: Nick, where
the fuck you been?
On a delivery?
Where the hell is Manny?
I been calling all over.
Where is he?
(STUTTERING)
I don't know, Tony.
He's been gone the
last couple of days.
He didn't say nothing.
He's gone? What? Where?
I left him in fucking charge,
man! Where the fuck is he?
You can't trust
nobody anymore!
I don't know, Tony.
He just took off.
He didn't say nothing.
He took off?
Are you all right?
No, I'm not all right!
I'm pissed!
When I get back there,
I'll kick some ass
all over the place!
When you coming back?
I'm coming back tonight!
This fucking cocksucker.
Tony, your mama called.
Gina's gone.
Gone? Where?
She got to see you right away.
Tell her I'll
call her tonight.
Listen to me. What about Elvie?
She call?
No.
Okay, listen to me.
If she calls, just
tell her I love her.
Okay? Just tell her that.
TONY: You hear from Manny? No.
Your mama called,
she gotta see you.
Sosa's been ringing every
half hour. He sounds pissed.
Get him on the phone.
Elvie call?
No.
You keep trying Manny. I
want that cocksucker here.
I want him here now! Okay?
Okay.
Come on. Go ahead, get him!
Let's go. Come on!
(CHI CHI SPEAKING SPANISH)
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah? Mama. Yeah, I know.
They told me.
Okay. I'm coming over.
I'll be over to see you.
I'll be over, yeah.
Put it on the speaker.
(SNIFFING)
SOSA OVER PHONE:
What happened, Tony?
Alex, how you doing?
What happened?
Oh, we had some problems.
Alex?
Tony, what happened?
We had a little problem.
I heard.
How you hear that?
Our friend gave a
speech at the UN.
He was not supposed
to give that speech.
Well, your guy, Alberto,
he's a piece of shit.
I told him to do something,
he didn't listen,
so I canceled his contract.
My partners and I
are pissed off.
That's okay. No big deal.
There's other Albertos.
We'll do it next month.
No, Tony, you can't do that.
They found what was
under the car.
Now our friend has got
security up the ass.
The heat will come down
hard on my partners and me.
There's not gonna
be a next time,
you dumb cocksucker!
You blew it!
Take it easy when
you talk to me.
I told you a long time ago, you
fucking monkey, not to fuck me!
Who the fuck you think
you're talking to, huh?
You want to fuck with...
Who the fuck you think I
am, your fucking bellboy?
You want to go to war? We
take you to war, okay?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Alex, you there? Hey!
He's not there. Cálmate, man.
She got a place of her own.
She don't tell me where.
One night, I follow
her in a taxi.
She goes to a fancy
house in Coconut Grove.
Where'd she get the money?
You!
You were giving her the money!
You see what you do to her?
I don't give her
that much money.
You did!
One time, $1,000 you gave her.
Was a guy with her?
I don't know.
There was this car
in the driveway.
I know if I go there,
she'll kill me.
She's like you.
Where's the place?
Where is it?
400 something...
Citrus Drive.
400 what? 409, I think.
You gotta talk to her, Antonio.
She don't listen to me.
She says to me,
"Mira, shut up!"
"Mind your own business."
Exactly like you do to me.
Ever since you came back,
she's been getting this way.
I gotta go.
Why do you have to
hurt everything?
Why do you have to destroy
everything that
comes your way?
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
409 Citrus Drive.
Okay.
Tony, I can't find
Manny anywhere.
Fuck!
Okay. Listen, boss,
I'll try again.
You stay here. Keep
trying Manny, okay?
(DOOR BELL BUZZING)
Tony.
(GUN FIRING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(SOBBING)
We got married just yesterday.
We were gonna surprise you.
ERNIE: Jesus, Tony.
Tony, we gotta get
outta here, man.
We gotta get outta here.
Go get Gina.
No!
No, Gina. Come on, Gina. No!
God!
Tony, we can't stay here.
We gotta go.
We gotta get out of here.
(GINA SOBBING)
Come on, Gina.
Here we go. It's
gonna be okay.
You got her? I got her.
No! This is Tony's place!
Let me go!
(SCREAMING)
We put some pills into her.
She's gonna be
all right, Tony.
She's cooling down. Right?
She's gonna be fine.
Just fine.
Right.
What are we gonna do now?
Do?
We're going to war.
That's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna eat that
Sosa for breakfast!
Close that fucker down.
(SNIFFING)
Tony, take it easy.
All right, Ernie. Let's go.
We'll take care of the house.
Come on.
This cocksucker's gonna
run all over you.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Come on. I'll bury
these cocksuckers.
(CLEARS THROAT)
We gotta get organized here.
Fuck! Manny.
How the fuck I do that?
How the fuck I do that, Manny?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
GINA: Tony.
Gina.
Is this what you want, Tony?
You can't stand for another
man to be touching me.
So you want me, Tony, huh?
Huh?
What are you talking about?
Ah.
Is that it?
Here I am, Tony.
I am all yours now,
Tony, you see?
(CHUCKLING)
I'm all yours now.
Gina.
You better come
and get me now.
All right. Come on.
Come and get me.
You do it now before
it's too late.
(GROANING)
Oh, come on, Tony.
Fuck me.
Fuck me. Come on
and just fuck me!
(SCREAMING)
Die!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
They're all over the place!
Get out of here!
Gina.
Come on. Look at your face.
It's all dirty.
(SOBBING)
Please talk to me.
Don't be mad at me.
Please. Gina, come on.
I love Manny, you know?
I love him.
And I love you, too, you know?
Give me a smile.
They're coming
from everywhere!
Tony, open up! Open
the fucking door!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Please! Tony!
Let me in, boss! Please!
Tony, open the fucking door!
(GROANING)
You wait here, okay? I'll
be with you. I'll be back.
You wait for me.
I'm coming back.
Okay, Sosa. You want
to fuck with me?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
You're fucking with the best!
You want to fuck with me?
You cockroaches.
You want to play games?
Okay, I play with you.
You wanna play rough?
Say hello to my little friend!
(SCREAMING)
You want to play rough?
There! You like that?
You want more?
You whores!
Cowards!
(SCREAMING)
Want to fuck with me?
Go ahead!
Come on!
How do you like that, huh?
You fucking maricón!
You think you can take me?
You need a fucking army
if you gonna take me!
You hear? Come on! I take
you all to fucking hell!
Who you think you fucking with?
I'm Tony Montana!
You fuck with me, you
fucking with the best!
I'm still standing.
Come on! I take your
fucking bullet!
You think you kill
me with bullets?
I take your fucking bullets!
Go ahead!
(GROANS)