[ © anoXmous https://thepiratebay.se/user/Zen_Bud/]
- Name?
- Horowitz, Salomon.
- Schneider, Sarah.
- Birnbaum, Olga?
- Over there. Over there!
- Come here!
- Isak Hudes.
- Hudes, Isak.
Zucker, Helena.
Zucker, Helena!
- Hirsch, Salomon?
- Mandel, Maria.
- Hauptman, Chaim!
- Weisman! Weisman, Marcus!
- Feber, Ludwig!
- Feber, Ludwig.
Elsa Bauman.
-Josef Klein.
- Klein.
- Davidowich, Ignacy.
- Paula Biffer. - Nadel, Rachela.
- Steiner, Gertruda.
- Steiner, Hilda.
- Jerzy, you know who that man is?
- I don't know.
Let's get together, please.
Smile. Good!
Yes, sir.
Bring them over
a round of drinks.
Very good, sir.
And who shall I say they are from?
You can say
they are from me.
- From the gentleman.
- Where?
Do you know him?
-Find out who he is.
-Yes, sir!
Agnieszka, I would give anything
to hear you sing tonight...
...but I know you won't.
You embarrass me.
What's he doing?
Stay here.
How are you doing?
You'd leave a woman
alone at the table in a place like this?
Sweetheart, you're the picture
of loneliness.
What a lovely fragrance.
You are breaking my heart.
An extra chair, please.
Vodka for my friend.
- And for the lady?
- Pernod!
"There's a wood sale
in Green Forest... "
"... a wood sale!"
"Wood is being sold in the Green Forest. "
Come to the table, girls!
Drink with us!
"Left around the corner,
right around the corner... "
"... there is wood sale everywhere. "
Come to us!
Merry us!
"The whole trunk costs only one taler.
one taler. "
"The whole trunk costs only one taler,
- Thank you.
- I'll tell you what I mean by cooperative.
Two days after the law is passed
that all Jews have to wear the star...
...the Jewish tailors are
turning them out by the gross in a variety...
...of fabrics
at three zloty each.
Tell me about
your cellar wines.
- I have an excellent German Riesling, 1937.
- French!
- A Bordeaux. Chateau Latour, '28, '29?
- No, I'm sorry.
It's as if they have no idea
what kind of law it is.
As if it's the emblem
of a riding club.
- A Margaux, '29?
- No, no, we don't have that.
- Burgundy then? A Romanee-Conti, '37?
- Yes.
It's human nature.
"We'll do this to avoid that. "
That's what they have done
since thousands of years.
It's what they do.
They weather the storm.
But this storm is different. This is not
the Romans. This storm is the SS.
"If God wants to honor you... "
"... then he'll send you world wide. "
"If god wants to honor you
then he'll send you world wide. "
"Faleri, Falera... "
"... Faleri
Falera-ha ha ha!"
"Faleri, Falera!"
"He sends you away world wide"
-Martin?
-Yes, sir!
Who is that man?
That's Oskar Schindler!
"Faleri, Falera
ha ha ha!"
"He sends you away world wide. "
"Faleri, Falera!"
To Krakow!
Attention, all Jews!
From now on, Jewish art...
...meat preparing is forbidden.
Announcement for all Jews!
From now on...
- Rabbi...
- Private property cannot be confiscated.
- How long are the schools going to be closed?
- I do not know the answer..
- Article 47: Pillage is formally prohibited.
- You don't know anything!
- I am familiar with the Hague Convention.
- Religious...
They come into our house
and tell us we don't live there any more.
It now belongs
to a certain SS officer.
Please!
I only know what they tell me.
And what they tell me
changes from day to day!
Aren't you supposed
to be able to help?
I mean, what if I just
took this thing off?
- What are they going to do about it?
- They will shoot you.
- Why don't you stop this silly talk?
- Itzhak Stern!
I'm looking
for Itzhak Stern.
Are you Itzhak Stern or not?
- I am.
- Where can we talk?
There's a company
you did the books for, on Lipowa Street.
Made what?
Pots and pans?
By law, I have to tell you, sir,
I'm a Jew.
Well, I'm a German.
So there we are.
- A good company, you think?
- Modestly successful.
I know nothing about enamelware.
Do you?
I was just
the accountant.
Simple engineering though,
wouldn't you think?
Change the machines around,
whatever you do...
...you could make other
things, couldn't you?
Field kits, mess kits.
Army contracts.
Once the war ends,
forget it, but for now it's great.
You can make a fortune,
don't you think?
I think most people right now
have other priorities.
Like what?
I'm sure you'll do just fine,
once you get the contracts.
In fact, the worse things get,
the better you'll do.
Oh, well, I can get the signatures
I need. That's the easy part.
Finding the money
to buy the company, that's hard.
You don't have any money?
Not that kind of money.
You know anybody?
Jews, yeah.
Investors.
You must have contacts...
...in the Jewish business community
working here.
What community?
Jews can no longer own businesses.
- That's why this one's in receivership.
- But they wouldn't own it.
I'd own it. I'd pay them
back in product- pots and pans.
- Pots and pans!
- Something they can use.
Something they can
feel in their hands.
They can trade it on the black market,
do whatever they want.
Everybody's happy!
If you want, you could
run the company for me.
Let me understand.
They'd put up all the money,
I'd do all the work.
What, if you don't mind
my asking, would you do?
I'd make sure it's known
the company's in business.
I'd see that it had
a certain panache.
That's what I'm good at.
Not the work, not the work.
The presentation!
I'm sure I don't know anybody
who'll be interested in this.
Well, they should be,
Itzhak Stern.
Tell them they should be.
Attention, attention!
All Jews!
From now on, it's forbidden...
I've got a client who'll sell marks
for zloty at 2.45 to 1.
Wool, mink collar.
It's a nice coat.
She'll trade it
for ration coupons.
- Wicks, for lamps.
- You have a truckload of wicks?
What am I going to do
with a truckload of wicks?
9 by 12, 9 by 14.
I don't know.
Big, beautiful, Persian.
-What?
- You don't recognize this?
-It's shoe polish.
-In metal containers?
You asked for shoe polish.
In metal containers.
This is glass, it's not what I asked for.
What's the difference?
- What's the difference?
My client sold it to his client,
who sold it to the German Army.
Only by the time it got there, because
of the freezing cold, it broke. All 10,000 units.
This is not my problem.
- This is not his problem.
- This is not your problem?
- This is not my problem.
- All right!
The German Army wants
to find out where it came from.
- I am going to make sure they find out.
- Now it's your problem.
You be quiet!
Metal containers.
Hello!
Pardon me for interfering,
but that's a nice shirt.
Nice shirt.
Do you know
where I can find a nice shirt like that?
Like this?
It's illegal to buy or sell
anything on the street.
We don't do that.
We're here to pray.
Do you have any idea
how much a shirt like this costs?
Nice things cost money.
How many?
I'm going to need some other
things, too, as things come up.
- This won't be a problem.
- From time to time.
Attention! Attention!
- Name? Address?
- Fill in the forms!
Go on, go on!
Don't push each other!
- You come here!
- Stay there!
Attention! Attention!
All Jews are enforced...
...to live in the Jewish district.
Not getting the residence
from the registry office...
...will be against decree 44/91
and judged through the military court.
This is obviously the right place.
How are you doing?
Goodbye, Jews!
Goodbye,Jews!
Oh, my God!
Oy, God!
It could not be better.
- It could be worse.
- How? Tell me.
How on earth
could it possibly be worse?
Good morning!
- Hey, Goldberg.
- Poldek.
- What's this?
- Uh, the Jewis assembly has its own police now.
- You don't say.
- Coordination service!
I'm a policeman now,
could you believe it? It's hard to believe.
Oh, no, it's not hard to believe.
It's a good racket, Poldek.
The only racket here.
Look, maybe I could put in
a good word for you with my superiors.
- Your superiors?
- Come on, they're not as bad as everyone says.
Well, they're worse than everyone says,
but it's a lot of money.
A lot of money!
Give me my housing assignment.
- Come on.
- You look funny in that hat, Goldberg.
You look like a clown, you know?
He's a very important man.
Just give him
two minutes of your time.
Since when did time cost money?
Just sit down and listen...
...please!
Sir?
For each thousand you invest,
I will repay you with...
- Two hundred.
- ... 200 kilos of enamelware a month...
...to begin in July
and to continue for one year.
After which time, we're even.
That's it. It's very simple.
- Not good enough.
- It's not good enough!
Not good enough?
Look where you're living. Look where
you've been put. "Not good enough! "
A couple of months ago
you'd be right, not anymore.
Money's still money.
No, it is not!
That's why we are here.
Trade goods...
...that's the only currency
that'll be worth anything in the ghetto.
Things have changed, my friend.
Did I call this meeting?
You told Mr Stern
you wanted to speak to me.
I'm here.
I've made you a fair offer.
Fair would be
a percentage in the company.
Forget the whole thing.
Get out!
How do we know
that you will do what you say?
Because I said I would.
You want a contract?
To be upheld by what court?
I said what I'll do.
That's our contract.
Five, six, seven...
...eight, nine...
The standard SS rate for Jewish
skilled labourers is seven marks a day...
...five for unskilled and women.
This is what you pay
the Reich Economic Office.
The Jews themselves
receive nothing.
Poles you pay wages.
Generally, they get a little more.
- Are you listening?
- What was that about the SS?
The rate? The what?
The Jewish worker's salary,
you pay it directly to the SS, not to the worker.
- He gets nothing.
- But it's less.
- It's less than what I would pay a Pole.
- It's less?
That's the point
I'm trying to make.
Poles cost more.
Why should I hire Poles?
An enamelware factory,
over at, Lipowa Street.
It, uh, it, um...
It's owned by a German.
But it's outside the ghetto,
so you can barter for extra goods...
...for eggs, I don't know
what you need...
...with the Polish workers.
You can't get it here.
Also, he's asking for ten
healthy women for the...
I'm healthy!
Bring your sister, okay?
You need to convince them you have
a trade, something valuable to the war effort.
- Like what?
-I'm a musician. - What if you don't?
- Your name goes on a list.
- Your name is on the list, they put you on trucks...
- No, no, no, that's not true.
- You're a musician?
- Yeah.
- I'd find a good hiding place if I were you.
- I'm not going to hide like some animal.
- There are places to hide.
The next!
I'm a graduate
of the University of Lwow.
I used to work at the
hydroelectric station in Roznow...
Blue card!
I'm gonna get the necessary papers
because this card is no good any more.
You can stay in this line all day,
you'll still get one of these.
They are no good.
You'll have to leave the line now...
...then you'll get a blue card, a Blauschein,
to say that you are an essential worker.
I'll get these papers
for you at Pankiewicz.
Pharmacist.
Just there, look!
Guess who is here?
Poldek!
Enjoying the weather, Poldek?
- Enjoying the lines?
- Need some shoe polish?
In metal container maybe!
Not essential? I think you misunderstand
the meaning of the word.
No blue card, sir.
Stand over there.
Move. Next!
What do you mean,
"Not essential"?
I teach history and literature.
Since when it's not essential?
He's metal polisher.
- It was not right?
- It's very good. He's 53 years old.
- It's too new.
-Thank you.
You're crazy.
You left it in your drawer.
How many times
have I told you?
Your work certificate,
you keep in your pocket at all times.
And you leave everything
in your drawer.
How many times I've told you?
I'm a metal polisher!
Take the round sheet of tin...
...dip it in soap emulsion.
Then place it centrally in the press.
We obtain the soup pot.
The soup pot!
Soup pot!
Grosz, Mrs Grosz, stay together.
Look, sir, I have ten work permits here
for the German enamel factory...
...and signed by Mr Bankier
and myself.
If it's carbonized,
clean it with a file.
But don't touch both the electrodes
at the same time.
You'll get electrocuted.
Here, have a try.
Roll the metal
under the press...
...but be very careful
unless you want your fingers...
...to become part of the teapot!
- Occupation?
- I'm a writer. I play the flute.
But Moses is a skilled metalworker.
He can make tin pots.
He can make tanks.
He can make whatever
Mr Schindler asks.
He's highly skilled.
Give him your card.
Moses, give him your card.
Now, dip the basin with the tongs
into the enamel solution.
And after swiveling it around,
carefully place it aside to drip-dry.
And whatever he asks you, allow me
just to represent you and speak for you.
Don't say a word!
Filing, billing, keeping
track of my appointments, shorthand.
- Typing, obviously. How is your typing?
- Uh, all right.
Please!
You need a secretary.
Pick one.
I don't know how.
They're all so... qualified.
You have to choose.
Big smile, big smile!
If you would,
look after my guest.
Um, boxed teas are good.
Coffee, pâté, um...
...kielbasa sausage,
cheeses, Beluga caviar...
...and, of course, who could live
without German cigarettes?
Get me as many
as you can find.
And some more fresh fruit.
The real rarities,
oranges, lemons, pineapples.
I need several boxes of Cuban cigars.
The best.
And dark unsweetened chocolate...
...not in the shape of ladyfingers,
the chunk chocolate.
Big as my hand,
you sample at wine tastings.
We're going to need lots of cognac.
The best, Hennessy.
Dom Perignon champagne.
Um, get L 'espadon sardines...
...and, oh,
try to find nylon stockings.
It is my distinct pleasure
to announce...
...the fully operational status
of German enamel factory...
...manufacturers of superior
enamelware crockery...
...expressly designed
and crafted for military use.
Utilizing only
the most modern equipment...
...D.E.F.'s staff of highly skilled and
experienced artisans and journeymen...
...deliver a product
of unparalleled quality...
...enabling me to proffer,
with absolute confidence and pride...
...a full line
of field and kitchenware...
...unsurpassable in all respects
by my competitors.
See attached list
and available colours.
Anticipating the enclosed bids
will meet with your approval...
...looking forward to a long and
mutually prosperous association...
...I extend to you in advance
my sincerest gratitude...
...and very best regards.
Oskar Schindler.
Yeah, I need 700 gross
from here for next Thursday.
Nine hundred,
no, make it ten for Wednesday.
All this stuff here goes to Madritsch's
factory on Tuesday of next week.
My father was fond of saying,
"You need three things in life... "
"... a good doctor,
a forgiving priest... "
"... and a clever accountant. "
The first two,
I've never had much use for.
But the third!
Just pretend, for Christ's sake!
Is that all?
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm saying I couldn't
have done this without you.
The usual thing would be
to acknowledge my gratitude.
It would also, by the way,
be the courteous thing.
You're welcome.
Get out of here!
Klonowska, who is it?
She's so embarrassed.
Look at her.
You know something?
You would like her.
- Oskar, please!
- What?
I don't have to like her...
just because you do.
It doesn't work that way.
You've done well here.
You look wonderful.
- Be careful of the step, miss.
- Mrs Schindler, Marek.
- It's not a charade, all this?
- Charade? How could it be a charade?
- The clothes, the car, the apartment.
- Wait a minute.
Take a guess how many
people are on my payroll.
Oskar!
My father, at the height of his success,
had 50. I've got 350.
350 workers on the factory floor,
with one purpose.
To make pots and pans?
To make money.
For me!
Does anyone ask about me?
Back home?
Everybody. All the time.
They won't soon forget the name
Schindler here, I can tell you that.
"Oskar Schindler"
they'll say.
"Everybody remembers him. "
"He did something extraordinary. "
"He did something
no one else did. "
"He came here with nothing,
a suitcase...
"... and built a bankrupt
company into a major manufactory. "
"And left with
a steamer trunk... "
"... two steamer trunks
full of money. "
"All the riches of the world. "
It's comforting to see
that nothing's changed.
You're wrong, Emilie.
There's no way I could have
known this before but...
...there was always
something missing.
In every business I tried,
I can see now, it wasn't me that failed.
Something was missing.
Even if I'd known what it was,
there's nothing I could have done about it...
...because you can't
create this thing.
And it makes all the difference
in the world between success and failure.
Luck?
War!
Should I stay?
It's a beautiful city.
I asked you if I should stay.
It's up to you.
Promise me, Oskar.
No doorman or maitre d' will ever presume...
...I'm anyone other
than Mrs. Schindler, and I'll stay.
Goodbye, darling.
I could try to read this
or I could eat my lunch while it's still hot.
We're doing well?
- Yes.
- Better this month than last?
- Any reason to think next month will be worse?
The war could end.
- What?
- There is a machinist outside...
...who'd like to thank you
personally for giving him a job.
Every day he comes. He's very grateful.
It'll just take a minute.
Mr Lowenstein!
I want to thank you, sir...
...for giving me
the opportunity to work.
You're welcome.
I'm sure you're doing a great job.
The SS beat me up.
They would have killed me...
...but I am essential
to the war effort, thanks to you.
That's great.
I work hard for you.
- I'm sure you do.
- I'll continue to work hard for you.
That's great. Thanks.
- God bless you, sir.
- All right.
You are a good man.
- He saved my life.
- Yes, he did.
- God bless him.
- Yeah. Come on.
God bless you!
I'm sorry, Herr Direktor,
but you're running very late.
This is for the major, sir.
And this is for his niece, Greta.
It's her birthday.
- Greta as in Garbo.
- Don't ever do that to me again.
Go. Go, go, drive!
Don't bow.
- Did you notice that man had one arm?
- Did he?
- What's his use?
- Very useful.
- How?
- Very useful! Success!
You'll be given brooms and shovels...
...each of you will grab one
and start cleaning the street.
We'll be late for work.
You shouldn't
think of them as yours, Oskar.
You need to understand that
some of the officers here...
...don't give a damn
about production.
To them, it's a matter of,
um, national priority...
...that Jews
be made to shovel snow.
It's got nothing to do
with reality, Oskar.
You know it and I know it.
Jews shoveling snow!
It's got a, um,
ritual significance.
- Come with me.
- I am an essential worker.
- Essential worker?
- Yes.
- I work for Oskar Schindler.
- Essential worker for Oskar Schindler.
- A one-armed Jew? Twice as useless!
- Yes, yes.
I lost a day
of production, Rolf.
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Danka, look at the snow.
Look at the snow. Look at the snow!
I lost a worker.
I expect to be compensated.
File a grievance with the
Economic Office. It's your right.
- Would it do any good?
- Of course not!
A big shot from the SS Budget
and Construction Office came to lunch...
...and he told us that to believe
the Jewish skilled worker had a place...
...in Reich economics
was a treasonable idea.
A one-armed machinist, Oskar?
He was a metal press operator.
Quite skilled.
Mr. Director!
Shit. I don't believe it.
Stern, is that you?
No, it's Poldek.
It's about Stern.
Leave your luggage
on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Given name first,
then your surname.
Do not bring
your baggage with you.
It will follow you later.
Leave your luggage
on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Leave your luggage
on the platform.
Stern?
- He's on the list.
- He is?
- Well, let's find him.
- I'm sorry. You can't have him.
He's on the list. If he were an essential
worker, he would not be on the list.
I'm talking to a clerk.
What is your name?
- Sir, the list is correct.
- I didn't ask you about the list.
- I asked you your name.
- Klaus Tauber.
Tauber!
Squad leader, this gentleman
thinks a mistake's been made.
My plant manager is
somewhere on this train.
If it leaves with him on it,
it'll disrupt production...
...and the Armaments Board
will want to know why.
-Attention! The train is about to leave.
-Is he on the list?
Yes, sir. Itzhak Stern.
Well, the list is correct, sir.
There is nothing I can do.
- What is your name?
-Close and secure all doors.
- My name? My name is Kunder.
- This train is now leaving.
- Kunder.
- Hauptscharführer Kunder.
- K-U-N-D-E-R.
- And what's yours?
Schindler.
S-C-H-I-N-D-L-E-R.
Gentlemen, thank you very much.
I think I can guarantee you
you'll both be in...
...Southern Russia
before the end of the month. Good day.
Stern!
- Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
Stern!
- Stern! Stern!
- Itzhak Stern!
-Stern!
-Sir!
- Stern!
- Herr Direktor!
My apologies.
- Stop the train! He's here!
- I apologize.
- Stop the train!
- Stop the train! Stop it!
Sign here. Initial there.
Makes no difference to us,
you understand. This one, that one.
It's the inconvenience to the list.
- It's the paperwork.
- I somehow left my work card at home.
I tried to explain them
it was a mistake, but...
- ... I'm sorry, it was stupid!
- What if I got here five minutes later?
Then where would I be?
I woke up from a dream
this morning.
I was broke and sharing a room
with 12 people I didn't know...
...only to discover I was broke and
sharing a room with 12 people I didn't know.
- You laugh about it?
- I have to laugh.
You are living behind walls.
The walls I can deal with.
It's the restrictions to my life I'm tired of.
Those walls keep them out.
That's all I care about.
I like it here.
There's a kind of, I don't know...
...ancestral squalor to it all.
- You are a slave to these people.
- No one envies us any more.
- I'm smart!
- Oh, yes, you're smart!
- You're a real genius.
- You had your chance.
Today, today I actually found time
to organize a thought.
I can't remember
the last time I did that.
When's the last time
we did this?
we stood around and talked?
No one ordered me
onto a truck today.
No one took my business
away from me.
You don't really have
a business to take.
There's nowhere down from here.
This is it.
This is the bottom.
The ghetto is,
liberty!
This street divides the ghetto
just about in half.
Right side, Ghetto A:
Civil employees...
...industrial workers and so on.
Left side, Ghetto B:
Surplus labour...
...the elderly and infirm mostly.
Which is where you'll
want to start, huh?
Do you have any questions, sir?
Ja, why is the top down?
I'm fucking freezing.
We expect a labor force of
25.000 to 30.000.
Segregated of course.
The men in the barracks near the guarry...
-... the women on the other side of the wire.
-My place is where?
-There, sir.
-There?
-Yes, the villa.
-You call that a villa?
- Their synagogue, can you see it?
- That's not a villa!
- We' to turn it into the camp stables.
- It's a house!
What's that over there?
Playground.
Fifty-one.
And we have a dentist,
shoemaker, practical physicians.
There they are, sir.
One of you is, uh,
a very lucky girl.
There is an opening for a job...
...away from all this,
backbreaking work...
...at my new villa.
Uh...
...which of you has
domestic experience?
Yeah, on second thought,
I don't really want someone else's maid.
All those annoying habits
I have to undo.
I don't want
to give you my cold.
Uh, what's your name?
- Helen Hirsch.
- What?
Helen Hirsch.
- What? I can't hear.
- Helen Hirsch.
- Yes!
- Take it all down!
-Back to your work!
-To work!
Take it down! It is not safe!
She says the foundation was
poured wrong. She's got to take it down.
I told her it's the barracks,
not the fucking Hotel Europa.
Fucking Jew bitch engineer.
You fucking bitch!
Herr Kommandant.
The entire foundation...
...has to be torn down
and repoured.
If not, there will be
at least a subsidence...
...at the southern end
of the barracks.
Subsidence, and then collapse.
- And you are an engineer?
- Yes!
My name is Diana Reiter.
I'm a graduate...
...of Civil Engineering
from the University of Milan.
Ah, an educated Jew,
like Karl Marx himself.
- Sergeant!
- Yes, sir!
- Shoot her.
- What?
Commander!
I'm only trying to do my job.
Yeah, I'm doing mine.
Sir, she's foreman
of construction.
We are not going to have arguments
with these people.
Okay!
No!
Shoot her here, on my authority!
-It will take more than that.
-I'm sure, you are right!
Take it down, repour it,
rebuild it. Like she said.
We have more to see, but we have
only one more hour of light.
Today is history.
Today will be remembered.
Years from now, the young
will ask with wonder about this day.
Today is history,
and you are part of it.
Six hundred years ago...
...when elsewhere they were putting
the blame for the Black Death...
...Kazimiers The Great,
so called...
...told the Jews
they could come to Krakow.
- Chaja, bread.
- They came.
- Not that fat. No, less.
- They trundled their belongings into the city.
- Yes, a bit less.
- They settled...
...they took hold.
They prospered...
...in business, science,
education, the arts.
They came here with nothing.
Nothing!
And they flourished.
For six centuries
there has been a Jewish Krakow.
Think about that.
By this evening...
...those six centuries
are a rumour.
They never happened.
Today is history!
Get off and line up
in a two row!
Come on, quicker!
I think we will start,
with Ghetto B.
- All right?
- Start from both sides?
- No, no! I would like you to start there.
- The right side?
-And then move around.
- All right!
Label them clearly.
They will follow you later on.
Leave your luggage!
Label them clearly.
They'll follow you later on.
- Open up!
- Lakoom.
Come down!
Jews, all out!
Put on something warm
and come out.
To Chodi Square!
Gold, Chaim!
Go to Chodi Square.
- Gold, Chaim!
- Yes, Chaim Gold.
Shoot him!
Put on something warm
and go to Chodi Square.
No baggage!
-Go through.
-No baggage! No baggage!
Hey, little boy.
How old are you, huh?
Huh, what's your name?
What's your name, huh?
I said, no luggage!
Don't pack, no luggage!
Go to Chodi Square!
Leave your luggage here!
- Blue card!
- Chodi Square!
What's this bag doing here?
Everybody to Chodi Square!
We're getting out through the sewers.
I have to check if they're clear.
- Mila, pack some things. Nothing bigger...
- I can't go in the sewers.
I told you
I won't go in the sewers.
You can go. Yes, you can.
-Move!
-Over there! Over there! Move!
Your card, Jew?
Your papers, Jew?
Your papers, Jew!
That line!
Your papers?
I'm not going up
because of your goddamn papers!
Your goddamn papers!
Why are you shooting?
Are you crazy?
In this traffic,
you could have shot me!
The bullet passed me by so close!
-Sorry!
-Now you say sorry? You're crazy!
Stay away! Stay away!
Don't talk, don't talk!
Just go to the trucks!
Keep on walking, keep on walking!
Don't talk!
Come here, you fuckin' Jew!
Stand still!
I said, stand still!
She's good as dead.
Leave her.
Give me a moment.
Just let me bring her inside.
You can join her,
or join the line.
- Women to the left!
- Wilhelm! - Rose!
-Men to right.
-Women to the left!
- Women to the left.
- Let me go! I won't leave my husband!
Women to the left,
and men to the right.
Your government
is in the wrong country!
Mama! Mama!
Mila!
Oh, God, Danka!
- You have a blue card.
- Blue card doesn't matter any more.
- They are cleaning out the ghetto.
- There's not enough room for you.
What are you talking about? We tried it
before. There's more than enough room.
- I changed my mind!
- Mama!
Look at the space in there.
Now look at me. You are just scared.
I can fit the girl, but not you.
- Mama, I'm coming out!
- Stay where you are.
I'd rather you be here
than who knows where.
Mama!
Commander!
Very good saluting.
I respectfully report I've been given orders
to clear the bundles from the road.
So there will be no obstructions
to the thoroughfare.
Finish and join the lines,
little Polish clicking soldier.
Mrs. Dresner?
Yes.
Oh, you are a friend
of my son's.
Don't worry, I'll go quietly.
I'll be no trouble.
No, get under the stairs. They'll be done
searching soon. You'll be safe there.
- Please hide! Please!
- Warmed by the sun.
Hide under the stairs!
I've searched the building.
There's no one here.
- Okay, then we're going to the next block.
-Understood!
- Danka!
- Mama!
Hello, Adam.
Hello, Danka.
Come with me.
I will put you in the good line.
Do you know the saying,
"An hour of life is still life"?
You are not a boy any more.
I'm saying a blessing for you.
Oh, please, let's go.
Let's go, please!
Come on!
Mark it...
...mark it!
- What is it? Is it Bach?
- No, no. It's Mozart.
- Mozart?
- Yes!
- Can we still manage today?
- No way!
We can't manage it.
I wish this fucking
night were over.
Appeal!
Line up! In rows of five!
Line up!
Come on, in rows of five!
Caps off!
Sort the names!
Those who're announced will raise
their hands and shout a clear "Yes"!
Yes!
- Keller, Fanni!
- Yes!
- Adalbert, Hermann!
- Faber, Dorothea!
- Yes!
- Goldstein, Pola!
-Warmberger, Markus!
-Yes!
Edelstein, Max!
Disband!
The worst is over.
We are workers now.
No excuses!
Oh, God, Amon!
Go to your barracks immediately!
Come here, come here!
Come on, come here!
Amon, you're
such a damned fuckin' child!
Wakey, wakey.
- Make coffee.
- Make it yourself.
The SS will manage
certain industries itself inside Plaszow.
A metalworks, brush factory...
...another for reprocessing
jewish clothing from the ghettos...
...for use by
bombed-out families back home.
But it's private industry like yours
that stands to benefit most...
...by moving inside the wire of
Commandant Amon Goeth's camp...
No, no, no. Sit, sit.
Julian, how are you?
Good to see you, my friend.
- Oskar Schindler.
- Leo John.
- Franz, good to see you.
- Hello, Oskar. Glad you could join us.
- My pleasure. Julius.
- How are you? You lost weight.
Only in the shoulders.
Please, everybody, sit down.
How are you doing?
Oskar Schindler.
- We started without you.
- Fine. I miss anything good?
I was explaining to Herr Bosch
and Herr Madritsch...
...some of the benefits of moving
their factories into Plaszow.
I meant the food.
Since your labour is housed on-site,
it's available to you at all times.
You can work them
all night if you want.
Your factory policies, whatever they've
been in the past, they'll continue to be.
They'll be respected.
I have to know, where do you get a suit
like that? What is that? Is that silk?
Of course!
Yeah, it's, it has a nice sheen
about it.
- Thank you.
- Very nice.
I'd say I'd get you one, but the man
who made it is probably dead.
I don't know.
I go to work the other day.
Nobody's there.
Nobody tells me about this.
I have to find out. I have to go in.
Everybody's gone.
No!
They're not gone.
They're here.
They're mine!
Every day that goes by, I'm losing money.
Every worker that is shot costs me money.
I have to find somebody else.
I have to trade them!
We are going to be making so much
money that none of this is going to matter.
It's bad business.
Thank you.
Leave the bottle.
Take that.
Lena, thank you.
Scherner told me
something else about you.
Yeah? What's that?
That you know the meaning
of the word "gratitude. "
That it's not some vague thing with you...
...like it is with others.
You want to stay where you are.
You've got things
going on the side.
Things are good.
You don't want anybody
telling you what to do.
I can understand all that,
you know? I know you.
What you want...
is your own sub-camp.
Do you have any idea what is involved?
The paperwork alone?
You've got to build the fucking thing. Getting
the fucking permits is enough to drive you crazy.
Then the engineers show up, they stand
around, they argue about drainage, foundations...
...codes, exact specifications, fences 4
kilometres long, 1,200 kilograms of barbed wire...
...6,000 kilograms of electrified
fences, ceramic insulators...
...three cubic metres
of air space per prisoner.
I'm telling you, you want to shoot
somebody. I've been through it. I know.
Well, you know.
You've been through it.
You could make things
easier for me.
I'd be grateful.
Clear the road!
Keep moving!
-Keep moving!
-Turn left!
Where's Stern?
Goldberg and Chilowicz,
make sure I see my cut...
...from the, uh,
factory owners in this camp...
...leaving you to take care
of my main account...
...the Schindler account.
He wants his independence.
I gave it to him.
But independence costs money.
This you understand?
Look at me!
Don't forget
who you are working for now.
- Yes!
- Make sure he stays. He's a slippery bastard!
Yes!
Now, girls, everyone.
- We need more wine.
- More wine!
Stand on my friend.
Don't let him leave.
- What happens in life...
-Cheers, cheers!
Thank you, Mr. Director.
Cheers, Mr. Director!
- What are you doing?
- What? Scratching my head.
Makes them think we have lice.
Helps make them keep their distance.
- Do you have lice?
- Do you have your notebook?
The calendar on my desk has the birthdays
of our SS friends' wives and children.
Don't forget to send something.
Record pay-offs to the Main Administration
and Economics Office, the Armaments...
- Slowly, Stern, slowly.
- The Armaments Board...
...Governor General's Division of the
Interior and Chief of Police as "fees"...
...and make them
on the first of each month...
...as opposed to individual pay-offs
to our SS contacts.
The list is
in the lower drawer of my desk...
-... which you...
-"First of month... "
SS contacts: List, lower drawer
of my desk, which you handle...
...as cash contributions to legitimate
charities sent to each official's office.
Dealings with our black market contacts,
listed as suppliers...
-... in the legitimate ledger, are more complicated.
- Forget it!
- What do you mean, you can't forget it!
- It gives me a headache!
- I couldn't get you out of here.
- I'll be all right.
Anyway, I'm here almost every week.
Wednesdays, usually.
I'll look in on you,
see how you're doing.
Here,
put these in your pocket.
Come on!
Mr. Director, don't let things fall apart.
I've worked too hard.
Thanks for...
Good luck!
Attention! Caps off!
-Work!
-Back to work!
-What are you making?
-Hinges, sir!
Yeah, I've got some workers coming in
tomorrow. Where are they from again?
Yugoslavia, Mr. Commander!
I've got to make room.
- Make me a hinge.
- Yes, sir!
Keep going, you're doing well.
Says he's doing well.
Oh, that's very good.
But I'm a bit confused,
and perhaps you can help me.
What I don't understand
is that you've been working...
.. since I think, what,
about 6.00 this morning?
Yet such a small pile of hinges.
- Oh, Christ.
- May I try that, sir?
Check the angle lever.
Maybe it's bent.
No, no. You wouldn't hear a click
if it was the angle lever.
- Maybe the pin shaft is greasy.
- Yeah, come on.
What did I just say?
Here.
Mr. Commander!
I beg to report that my heap
of hinges was so unsatisfactory...
...because the machines
were being recalibrated this morning.
I was put on to shoveling coal.
Strange, huh?
Yeah!
Thank you, Muek.
Ah, Lisiek. Don't touch the leather,
it's just been oiled.
- Squad leader!
- Oh, for me?
-Oh, thank you very much, Mr Director.
-Mr. Director!
Mr. Director!
He was making hinges slowly.
So the man can turn out a hinge in
less than a minute. Why the long story?
- Thank you, sir.
- You're welcome!
- Nobody knows who stole the chicken?
- Tell him about the chicken.
A man walks around with a chicken
and nobody notices this.
Save yourselves.
Tell him about the chicken.
Still nobody knows?
It was you!
You committed this crime!
- No, sir.
- But you know who, though.
- Yes.
- Who?
Him!
- He's very gifted.
- Yeah, sure. Bring him over.
Sir, thank you.
- Thank you again, Mr. Director!
- You're welcome again.
It's an honour to work
for such a great company.
It's great to have you!
I promise to learn everything there's
to know about enamelware production.
That's great!
- Hello? Miss Elsa Krause is here.
- I only need five minutes.
She wants to speak
to Mr. Director.
Yes.
He won't see you.
Please, sit down.
- Pernod? Cognac?
- Uh, no. No, thank you.
So, what can I do for you?
They say that no one dies here.
They say your factory is a haven.
They say you are good.
Who says that?
Everyone.
My name is Regina Perlman,
not Elsa Krause.
I've been living in Krakow
on false papers since the ghetto massacre.
My parents are in Plaszow.
Their names are
Chana and Jakob Perlman.
They are older people. They are killing
older people now in Plaszow.
They bury them
up in the forest. Look...
...I don't have any money.
I, I borrowed these clothes.
I'm begging you.
Please, please
bring them here.
I don't do that.
You've been misled.
I ask one thing:
Whether or not a worker
has certain skills.
My father is an importer,
not a metalworker.
Such activities are illegal.
You will not entrap me!
Cry, and I will have you arrested.
I swear to God!
People die.
It's a fact of life.
He wants to kill everybody? Great!
What am I supposed to do about it?
Bring everybody over?
Is that what you think?
Send them over to Schindler.
Send them all!
His place is a haven,
didn't you know? It's not a factory.
It's not an enterprise
of any kind.
It's a haven for rabbis
and orphans...
...and people with
no skills whatsoever!
You think
I don't know what you're doing?
You're so quiet all the time.
I know, I know!
- Are you losing money?
- That's not the point!
- What other point is...
- It's dangerous! It's dangerous to me!
You have to understand.
Goeth is under enormous pressure.
You have to think of it
in his situation.
He's got this
whole place to run.
He's responsible
for everything here, all these people.
He's got a lot of things
to worry about.
And he's got the war
which brings out the worst in people.
Never the good, always the bad.
Always the bad.
But in normal circumstances he
wouldn't be like this. He'd be all right.
There'd just be the good
aspects of him which...
He's a wonderful crook.
A man who loves good food,
good wine, the ladies, making money...
Killing!
He can't enjoy it.
Bejski told me the other day,
somebody escaped...
...from a work detail
outside the wire.
Goeth lined up everybody
from the missing man's barracks.
He shot the man to the left of Bejski,
the man to the right of him.
He walked down the line shooting
every other man with a pistol.
Twenty-five!
- What do you want me to do about it?
- Nothing, nothing.
We're just talking.
"Perlman. "
Perlman!
Husband and wife.
Jakob and Chana Perlman!
Have Goldberg bring them over.
Caps off!
Ready for inspection!
I'm sure this will be better
than those rags, Lisiek.
Mr. Director, I was just
helping Lisiek to find something...
...to clean the stains
from the Commander's bathtub.
- Go clean it.
- Pardon me, Sir!
You don't have to report to me, Helen.
You know who I am?
I'm Schindler.
Of course. I, I have heard and...
...you have been here before.
Here, why don't you
keep this someplace?
- Go on, take it.
- I get extra food here.
Well, if you don't want to eat it,
trade it. Or give it to Lisiek.
Why not build yourself up?
My first day here, he beat me...
...because I threw out
the bones from dinner.
He came down to the basement
at midnight, and he...
...he asked me where they were.
For his dogs, you understand?
I said to him, I,
I don't know how I say this.
I never could say it now,
I said to him...
..."Why are you beating me?"
He said, "The reason
I beat you now...
...is because you ask
why I beat you. "
I know your sufferings, Helen.
It doesn't matter.
I have accepted them.
Accepted them?
One day he will shoot me.
No, no, no, no,
he won't shoot you.
I know. I see things.
We were on the roof on Monday,
young Lisiek and I...
and we saw the Commander
come out of the front door and...
...and down the steps by the patio
right there below us and...
...and there on the steps
he drew his gun and he...
...shot a woman
who was passing by.
A woman carrying a bundle.
Through the throat.
Just-Just a woman
on her way somewhere, you know.
She was no fatter or thinner...
...or slower or faster
than anyone else...
...and I couldn't guess
what had she done.
The more you see
of the Commander...
...the more you see there is
no set rules that you can live by.
You can't say to yourself,
"If I follow these rules, I will be safe. "
He won't shoot you
because he enjoys you too much.
He enjoys you so much
he won't even let you wear the star.
He doesn't want anyone else
to know, it's a Jew he's enjoying.
He shot the woman from the steps
because she meant nothing to him.
She was one of a series
neither offending or pleasing him.
But you, Helen!
It's all right.
It's not that kind of a kiss.
Thank you!
Here!
Right, the wine!
Wonderful party, Amon.
Thank you.
Why do you drink that motor oil?
I send you
good stuff all the time.
Your liver's going to explode
like a hand grenade.
You know, I look at you...
...I watch you!
You're never drunk.
Oh, that's...
...that's real control.
Control is power.
That's power.
Is that why they fear us?
We have the fucking power to kill,
that's why they fear us.
They fear us because
we have the power to kill arbitrarily.
A man commits a crime,
he should know better.
We have him killed,
and we feel pretty good about it.
Or we kill him ourselves
and we feel even better.
That's not power, though.
That's justice.
It's different than power.
Power is when we have
every justification to kill...
...and we don't.
You think that's power?
That's what the emperors had.
A man stole something...
...he's brought in
before the emperor...
...he throws himself
down on the ground, he begs for mercy.
He knows he's going to die.
And the emperor, pardons him.
This worthless man.
He lets him go.
I think you are drunk.
That's power, Amon.
That, is power!
Amon the good!
I pardon you!
What do they want?
I don't know, but they're in my office
right now reviewing our books.
As my accountant, tell me,
should I be alarmed...
...that the auditors
are reviewing my books?
- Or have you done your job properly?
- You needn't be alarmed.
I needn't be alarmed!
-I'm sorry, sir.
-Do you know how much this saddle is worth?
Do you know how much it costs?
All right!
Stern, what the hell are you
doing following me around?
Barracks one, eleven...
...fifteen and thirty-two...
...apply to inspection area.
She was smoking on the job.
Tell her not to do it again.
I have to report, sir...
...I've been unable to remove
the stains from your bathtub.
- What are you using, Lisiek?
- Soap, Commander.
Soap? Not lye?
Go ahead, go on, leave.
Leave, I pardon you.
I pardon you!
Although I am not a rabbi,
in these circumstances...
...I pray to the Almighty
that he will forgive me...
...if I intone the blessings.
So...
...this is where you come
to hide from me.
I came to tell you...
...that you, um, you really are
a wonderful cook and a well-trained servant.
I mean it. If you need a reference
after the war...
...I'd be, I'd be happy
to give you one.
It must get lonely down here
when you're..
...listening to everyone upstairs
having such a good time.
Does it?
You can answer.
But what's the right answer?
That's what you're thinking:
"What does he want to hear?"
The truth, Helen,
is always the right answer.
Yes, you're right.
Sometimes
we're both lonely.
Yes. I...
...I mean...
...I would like so much to...
...reach out and touch you
in your loneliness.
Wh- what would that be like,
I wonder? I mean...
...what would be wrong with that?
I realize that you're not
a-a person in the...
...the strictest sense
of the word, but...
No, maybe you're right
about that too, you know, maybe what's...
...what's wrong isn't...
...it's not us!
It's, no, it's this!
I mean, when they
compare you to...
...to, uh, vermin
and to rodents and to lice...
...I just, uh...
No, no, you,
you make a good point.
You make a very good point.
Is this the face of a rat?
Are these the eyes of a rat?
Hath not a Jew eyes?
I feel for you, Helen.
No, I don't think so.
You're a Jewish bitch!
You nearly talked me into it,
didn't you?
Bravo!
-Bravo!
- Cheers! Cheers!
On behalf of the, of the workers, sir,
I, I wish for you a happy birthday.
Happy birthday!
Well, the staff, please.
Thank you very much
for the lovely cake.
Thank you very much.
Tell them "Thank you" from me.
The trains arrived and the people
were driven out with clubs.
They were lined up in front
of two big warehouses.
One was marked "Cloak Room"
and the other "Valuables. "
And there they
were made to undress.
A Jewish boy handed them pieces
of string to tie their shoes together.
They shaved their hair.
They told them it was needed to make
something special for U-boat crews.
And then they were herded
down a big corridor...
...to bunkers with
Stars of David on the doors...
...and signs that said
"Bath and Inhalation Room"
SS gave them soap.
They told them to breathe all the time
because it's good for disinfecting.
And then they gassed them.
Mila, why soaps?
So that they would agree
to go in, I think.
Come on, Mila, stop it.
Your bedtime stories are scaring everyone.
- I just don't believe it.
-Ja. You know it's ridiculous.
- I don't believe it either.
- I cannot believe it.
-I didn't say I believed it. I said I heard it.
-From who?
From somebody who heard it
from someone who was there.
You know, if they were there,
they would have been gassed.
- Yes!
- It doesn't make any sense.
We're their workforce.
What sense does it make
to kill your own workforce?
To go to all this trouble
of assembling a workforce only to...
No, it can't be true.
We are very, very
important for them.
Yes, we do now!
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight. Sweet dreams.
Attention, attention!
Everyone who is alive...
...is to come to the roll-call area!
- Attention, attention!
- We have to go to the roll-call area!
- Everyone who is alive...
The list makers are here.
- ... is to come to the roll-call area.
- There is going to be a selection.
Attention, attention.
Everyone who is alive...
...is to come to the roll-call area!
-Gentlemen!
100.000 Hungarian is coming.
All stand in a single row!
You could afford
to lose some weight, Amon.
And you've got to
cut down on the cognac.
Morning.
What's going on?
It's another
semi-annual physical.
- There!
-I've got another shipment coming in of...
What are they this time?
- Hungarians.
- Oh, yeah, Hungarians!
We've got to separate the sick
from the healthy to make room.
Look alive, Rebeka.
Quicker!
That's my mechanic.
Whose bright idea was it
to get rid of him?
No, no, no!
Wait, go away. She can work.
Come here. Look,
separate the sick from the healthy.
Those who can work
and those who can't. She can work.
You can work, you can come.
On your feet!
Those not selected for transport,
put your clothes back on.
- Go back to the barracks.
- Return to the barracks.
Go back to the barracks!
Oh, my God!
- Olek? Olek?
- Danka?
Olek? Olek?
Olek! Olek!
- Olek?
- Danka?
Back to the barracks!
Go back to your barracks!
- I didn't see him!
- They're hiding. I'm telling you, they're hiding.
I know Danka. She knows a good place.
She took all of them together.
Back to the barracks!
Find your own hiding place. There's
no room for you here. Go away, quick!
Get out. This is our place.
Get out!
- Oskar!
- Amon! Gentlemen!
- Why didn't you call me?
- I tried to call you. Here, Hujar, move.
- Quite a picnic, huh? Madritsch!
- Oskar!
They're running a little late.
It's taking longer than I thought.
- A drink?
- Something cold. Bowle.
The Bowle!
Oh, another beautiful day.
The loading of the
transport wagons is finished.
We can start!
Water! Water!
Water, water!
- To your health!
- Oh, thank you.
What do you say we get your fire hoses out
here and hose down the cars? Thank you.
Indulge me!
- Hujar!
- Yes, sir!
- Go bring the fire hoses.
- Where's the fire?
In the windows.
That's it, that's it.
On the roof. That's it, good, good.
In the window, in the window.
Come on. Come on.
That's it, more, more!
That's it, that's it.
More, more!
This is really cruel, Oskar.
You are giving them hope.
You shouldn't do that.
That's cruel!
Come on, try and
reach the far end. Look out!
Water!- More water!
I've got some 200 metre
hoses back in Emalia.
I have 20 metres
at home in my garden.
We can reach the cars at the end.
What? What?
- Hujar!
- Yeah, sure.
Don't forget the roof!
On the roof
on the other side.
Water!
Lieutenant,
every time the train stops...
...you open the doors,
you give them water, yeah?
- Okay!
- Okay!. This car! This car!
I'm not saying you'll
regret it, but you might.
- You should be aware of that.
- We will have to risk regret.
All right, sure. It's a nice day.
I'll go for a drive with you.
What about you?
I violated
the Race and Resettlement Act.
Though I doubt anyone can point out
the actual provision to me.
I kissed a Jewish girl.
Did your prick fall off?
He likes women.
He likes good-looking women.
He sees a beautiful woman,
he doesn't think.
I mean,
he has so many women.
And they love him.
Yeah, they love him.
I mean, he is married, yeah, but he's...
All right, no. She was Jewish.
He shouldn't have done it.
But you didn't see this girl.
I saw this girl.
This girl was, woof...
...she was very good-looking.
They cast a spell on you,
you know, the Jews.
When you work closely with them,
like I do, you see this.
They have this power. It's like a virus.
Some of my men are infected with this virus.
They should be pitied, not punished.
They should receive treatment.
This is as real as typhus.
I see this all the time.
It's a matter of money?
You're offering me a bribe?
A bribe? No. No, please.
It's a gratuity.
Heil Hitler!
Hello, Amon!
Sit down!
We give you Jewish girls
at five marks a day, Oskar.
You should kiss us, not them.
God forbid you ever get
a real taste for Jewish skirt.
There's no future in it.
They don't have a future.
That's not just good,
old-fashioned, Jew-hating talk.
It's policy now.
Yeah, beautiful, good!
-Again, yes!
-Good!
Come on faster!
Be quick!
Move your ass!
It could be done quicker!
Hurry up, don't sleep!
Only the whole pieces,
leave the small parts!
What's going on here?
You can do it with your hands,
quick!
Come here!
Only the whole pieces,
leave the fucking small parts!
Now you better make it quick,
get rid of this shit!
That's it! Immortals!
Immortals are all around!
Can you believe this?
As if I don't have enough to do,
they come up with this?
I have to find every rag
buried up here and burn it.
The party's over, Oskar. They're closing
us down, sending everybody to Auschwitz.
-When?
-I don't know.
As soon as
I can arrange the shipments.
Maybe 30, 40 days.
That ought to be fun.
- I've been talking to Goeth.
- I know the destination.
These are the evacuation orders.
I'm to help organize the shipments,
put myself on the last train.
That's not what
I was going to say.
I made Goeth promise me
he'll put in a good word for you.
Nothing bad is going to happen to you
there. You'll receive special treatment.
The directives coming in from Berlin
mention "Special Treatment" more and more often.
- I'd like to think that's not what you mean.
- Preferential treatment, alright?
- Should we invent a whole new language?
- I think so.
You're staying, I take it.
- In Krakow? What on earth for?
- What for? You have a business to run.
Of course, you'll have
to hire new workers. Poles, I guess.
They cost a little more, but...
What are you going to do?
You ran my business.
No, I'm going home.
I've done what I came here for. I've got
more money than any man can spend in a lifetime.
Some day, this is all
going to end, you know.
I was going to say
we'll have a drink then.
I think I better have it now.
I don't understand.
I mean, you want these people?
"These people"?
My people, I want my people.
Who are you, Moses?
Come on, what is this?
Where's the money in this?
Where's the scam?
It's good business.
It's good business
in your opinion.
Look, you've got to move them,
the equipment, everything to Czechoslovakia.
Pay for all that and build another camp.
Doesn't make any sense.
- Look, Amon, it's good for me...
- You're not telling me something.
I know them. I'm familiar with them.
I don't have to train them.
- You're not telling me something.
- It's good for you. I'll compensate you.
- That's right.
- It's good for the army.
- You know what I'm going to make?
- What?
- Artillery shells.
- Everyone is making artillery shells.
- Tank shells, they need that.
- Tanks shells, yeah!
- Everybody's happy.
- Everyone's happy, except me.
You're probably
scamming me somehow.
If I'm making a hundred,
you've got to be making three.
And if you admit to making three,
then it's four actually. But how?
- I just told you.
- You did, but you didn't.
Yeah, all right, don't tell me.
I'll go along with it.
It's just irritating I can't work it out.
Look, all you have to do
is tell me what it's worth to you.
- What's a person worth to you?
- No, no, no, no.
What's one worth to you?
Poldek Pfefferberg,
Mila Pfefferberg...
...and uh...
...uh, Stagel, Stagel...
- Paul.
- Paul! Paul Stagel.
Doctor...
- The investors. I want all of them.
- Yes, sir.
Uh, Fischer. Ismail Fischer.
Fischer, Ismail.
- Josef Scharf.
- One moment, sir. I'm sorry, sir.
Come on, Stern.
Scharf, Scharf.
The children,
all the children!
- Herbert Stier.
- Thank you.
- How many?
- 400, 450.
More, more!
Good morning.
- Feigenbaum, Jakob.
- Wolf. Wolf Wein.
Feigenbaum: Lutek, Jakob, Nacha.
Yes? Nacha.
Nacha, that's right.
And Wolf.
How many?
- 600.
- More!
You can do
the same thing I'm doing.
- You might even make money at it.
- I don't know.
Come on, Julius, I know about
the extra food and clothes you give them.
Paid for out of your own pocket.
If we make a combined approach...
...we could get more than
4,000 out, mine and yours.
-Oskar!
-We could relocate them...
...in something like safety,
in Moravia.
I don't know.
How many cigarettes
have you smoked tonight?
Too many!
For every one you smoke,
I smoke half.
- I've done all I can.
- I will not accept that.
- No, Oskar, I can't do any more.
No!
- How many? How many?
- 850, give or take.
Give or take what, Stern?
Count them. How many?
That's it.
You can finish that page.
What... did... Goeth...
say about this?
You just told him how
many people you needed and...
You're not buying them?
You're buying them? You're
paying him for each of these names?
If you were still working for me,
I'd expect you to talk me out of it.
It's costing me a fortune.
Finish the page and leave
one space at the bottom.
You...
The list is an absolute good.
The list... is life.
All around its margins
lies the gulf.
Oskar, there's a clerical error here
at the bottom of the last page.
No, there's one more name
I want to put there.
I'll never find a maid as well trained as her
at Brinnlitz. They are all country girls.
No!
- One hand of twenty-one.
- No!
- If you win, I pay you 7,400 reichsmarks.
- Hit a natural, I make it 14,800.
- No!
If I win,
the girl goes on my list.
- I can't wager Helen in a card game.
- Why not?
Wouldn't be right.
She's just going to
Auschwitz Number Two, anyway.
- What difference does it make?
- She's not going to Auschwitz.
I'd never do that to her. No, I want her
to come back to Vienna with me.
I want her to come
to work for me there.
- I want to grow old with her.
- Are you mad?
- Amon, you can't take her to Vienna with you.
- No, of course I can't.
That's what I'd like to do.
What I can do, if I'm any sort of a man,
is the next most merciful thing.
I shall take her into the woods and shoot
her painlessly in the back of the head.
What was it you said
for a natural 21?
Was it 14,800?
Jews of Schindler, to these tables!
Say your names clearly.
- We are the family Dresner.
-Juda, Jonas...
...Donata and Chaja.
- We are Rosners. Henry, Manci...
- And Leo.
- And our son.
- I am Olek.
Maria Mischel.
Chaim Nowak.
Wulkan, Markus.
Michael Lemper.
Itzhak Stern.
Rebeka and Joseph Bau.
- Rosalia Nussbaum.
- Wilhelm Nussbaum.
Jakob Levartov.
- Farber, Rosa.
- Farber, Andrzej.
- Sara.
- Friehof, Fischel.
Mietek Pemper.
Poldek and Mila Pfefferberg.
Horowitz, Dolek.
Adam Levy.
Marcel Goldberg.
Klipstein, Isak David.
Altmann, Eduard.
Grunberg, Miriam.
Luftig, Eliasz.
Hilmann, Eduard.
Erna Rothberg.
Zuckermann, Jetti.
Helen Hirsch.
The worst is over.
Men to this transport
and women to this transport.
Be careful! Men to this transport
Watch your step! Men to this transport
and women to this transport.
Wonderful Olek, wonderful.
You know how we make
ice into water?
Olek, get another one!
Position yourselves
all in a single row!
You'll be pleased with the level
of efficiency I get from these workers.
Budzyn, under my command...
...was the envy of every other commandant
in the labour camp system.
- The prisoners, however...
- Excuse me!
...they would have rather been
somewhere else.
The train with the women
has already left Plaszow...
...and will be arriving
here very shortly.
I know you've had
a long journey.
But it's only a short walk
further to the factory...
...where hot soup and bread
is waiting for you.
Welcome to Brinnlitz!
- Beans in chunt?
- Beans are the best part.
I don't like beans.
Beans and meat
and potatoes and bread.
That's not the way
you make chunt.
- Eggs in chunt?
- Yes!
- I don't like chunt.
- No, you don't.
- What do you like?
- I like caviar!
One day on the fire...
-Oh, yes!
-One day...
Position yourselves
in front of the wagons!
You've got to stay together.
Leave the wagons!
I said, leave the wagons!
Bagaze zostawic!
Faster! Quick! Quick!
What's going on back there?
Move it!
Come on, out!
Hurry up, out!
Thirty, thirty-five,
forty, forty-five...
Out!
Get out!
Quicker, get out!
All of you, out!
- Where are the list makers?
- Where are the tables?
Move the line!
Get out!
- Quick! Get out!
- Faster!
Quicker!
Come on, be quick!
Mama, where are we?
- 17, 18, 20-
- They're in Auschwitz.
The train was never routed here.
A paperwork mistake.
Take off your shoes!
Quicker, quicker!
Take off your clothes!
Hurry up!
Hurry up! Stay in a row
and take off your clothes!
Quicker!
Take off your clothes quickly!
Hurry up!
SHOWERS AND DISINFECTION
Go in, hurry up!
Quicker!
Go to the showers, quickly!
Quicker! Quicker!
Eyes on the necks!
Hands on the shoulders!
- How old are you, mother?
- Sixty-eight.
- Cough for me, mother.
- They say to fall against the fence is a kindness.
Don't kill yourself
against the fence, Clara.
If you do, you'll never
know what happened to you.
- How old are you, mother?
- Sixty-six, sir.
- Sir?
- Good morning.
A mistake has been made.
We are not supposed to be here.
We work for Oskar Schindler.
We are Schindler Jews.
- Who is Oskar Schindler?
- He had a factory in Krakow.
- Enamelware.
- A pot maker.
How old are you, mother?
You are not the only industrialist
who needs labour...
...Mr. Schindler.
I remember earlier this year,
IG-Color ordered...
...a trainload of Hungarians
for its chemical factory.
The train came in
through the archway...
...and the officer in charge
of the selection went immediately to work...
...and sent 2,000 of them...
...straight away
to "special treatment".
It is not my task to interfere with
the processes that take place down here.
Why do you think I can help you
if I can't help IG-Color?
Allow me to express the reason.
I'm not making
any judgement about you.
It's just that I know
that in the coming months...
...we're all going
to need portable wealth.
I could have you arrested.
I'm protected by powerful friends.
You should know that.
I do not say
I am accepting them.
All I say is, I'm not comfortable
with them on the table.
I have a shipment
coming in tomorrow.
I'll cut you 300 units from it.
New ones.
These are fresh.
- The train comes, we turn it around.
- Yes, yes, yes!
- It's yours.
- I understand.
I want these.
You shouldn't
get stuck on names.
That's right.
It creates a lot of paperwork.
Zoldinger, Ernestina!
Waldergrun, Hilda!
Waldergrun, Leonora!
Laast, Anna!
Pfefferberg, Mila!
Dresner, Ruth!
Dresner, Danka!
Nussbaum, Sidonia!
Rosner, Manci!
Hirsch, Helen! Grosz, Chaja Sara!
Seelenfreund, Estella!
Move it!
Move it, quick!
- Faster! Faster!
-Come on!
Quick, quick!
Faster!
- Faster!
-Hurry up!
No! No! No!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
What are you doing?
These are mine! These are my workers!
They should be on my train!
They're skilled munitions workers!
They're essential!
Essential girls!
Their fingers polish the insides
of shell metal casings.
How else am I to polish the inside of
a 45 millimetre shell casing?
You tell me.
You tell me!
Back on the train!
Under Department "W" provisions...
...it is unlawful
to kill a worker without just cause.
Under the Businesses
Compensation Fund...
...I am entitled to file
damage claims for such deaths.
If you shoot without thinking...
...you go to prison, I get paid.
That's how it works.
So, there will be no
summary executions here.
There will be no interference
of any kind with production.
In hopes of ensuring that, guards will
no longer be allowed on the factory floor...
...without my authorization.
For your cooperation,
you have my gratitude.
Come on, come!
Oh, boy! I haven't seen
something like that since years.
Come on, boys, come!
No doorman or maitre d'
will ever mistake you again...
...I promise.
- This is Itzhak Stern, my accountant.
- You must be Mrs. Schindler.
- It's a pleasure to meet you.
- Emilie has volunteered to work in the clinic.
- Very generous of you.
- I know.
We need to talk
when you have a moment.
This is my wife, Stern.
I don't keep any secrets from my spouse.
Oskar, please, attend to business.
It's much more attractive.
- Madam.
- Hello!
What is it?
We've received an angry complaint
from the Armaments Board.
The artillery shells,
tank shells, rocket casings!
Apparently all of them
have failed quality control tests.
That's to be expected!
Start-up problems. This isn't pots
and pans. This is a precise business.
- I'll write them a letter.
- They're withholding payment.
Sure, so would I, so would you. I wouldn't
worry. We'll get it right one of these days.
There's a rumour you've been going
around miscalibrating the machines.
They could shut us down,
send us back to Auschwitz.
I'll call around, find out
where we can buy shells.
- Pass them off as ours.
- I don't see the difference...
...whether they're made here
or somewhere else.
You don't see a difference?
I see a difference.
You'll lose a lot of money.
Fewer shells will be made.
Stern, if this factory ever produces...
...a shell that can actually be fired,
I'll be very unhappy.
- Hello, madam.
- How do you do?
How are you doing, Rabbi?
Rabbi!
Good, Mr. Director.
Sun's going down.
Yes, it is.
What day is this? Friday?
It is Friday, isn't it?
Is it?
What's the matter with you?
You should be preparing for the Sabbath.
Shouldn't you?
I've got some wine.
In my office. Come!
What?
Do you have any money,
uh, hidden away someplace...
...that I don't know about?
No!
Why?
Am I broke?
Well...
Yesterday morning, at 2:41 a. m...
...at General Eisenhower's
headquarters...
...General Jodl...
...signed the Act
of Unconditional Surrender...
...of all German land,
sea and air forces in Europe...
...to the Allied
Expeditionary Force.
And simultaneously
to the Soviet High Command.
The German war is,
therefore, at an end.
But let us not forget for a moment...
I think it's time the guards
came into the factory.
...Japan, with all
her treachery and greed...
The unconditional surrender
of Germany has just been announced.
At midnight tonight,
the war is over.
Tomorrow you'll
begin the process...
...of looking for survivors
of your families.
In most cases,
you won't find them.
After six long years
of murder...
...victims are being mourned
throughout the world.
We've survived.
Many of you have come up
to me and thanked me.
Thank yourselves.
Thank your fearless Stern...
...and others among you
who worried about you...
...and faced death
at every moment.
I'm a member of the Nazi party.
I'm a munitions manufacturer.
I'm a profiteer of slave labour.
I am a criminal.
At midnight you'll be free,
and I'll be hunted.
I shall remain with you until
five minutes after midnight...
...after which time,
and I hope you'll forgive me I have to flee.
I know you have received orders
from our commandant...
...which he has received from his superiors
to dispose of the population of this camp.
Now would be
the time to do it.
Here they are, they're all here.
This is your opportunity.
Or you could leave...
...and return
to your families as men...
...instead of murderers.
In memory of the countless
victims among your people...
...I ask us to observe
three minutes of silence.
- Thank you, Mr. Jereth.
Open wide.
Thank you, Mr. Jereth.
Thank you, Mr. Jereth!
As soon as peace occurs,
I want...
...um, I want that cloth
distributed to the workers.
Two and a half metres each.
Also, each person is
to get a bottle of vodka.
They won't drink it.
They know its value.
Likewise those Egipshi cigarettes
we organized.
It'll be done.
Everything you ask.
We've written a letter,
trying to explain things...
...in case you are captured.
Every worker has signed it.
Thank you!
It is Hebrew, from the Talmud.
It says:
"Whoever saves one life, saves the world entire. "
I could have got more out.
I could have got more.
I don't know.
If I just...
I could have got more.
Oskar, there are 1,100 people who are
alive because of you. Look at them.
If I'd made more money...
I threw away so much money.
You have no idea.
If I had just...
There will be generations
because of what you did.
I didn't do enough.
You did so much.
This car...
...Goeth would've bought this car.
Why did I keep the car?
Ten people right there.
Ten people.
Ten more people.
This pin...
...two people.
This is gold.
Two more people.
He would have given me
two for it, at least one.
He would have given me one,
one more.
One more person.
A person, Stern,
for this!
I could have gotten...
...one more person and I didn't.
And I, I didn't!
You have been liberated...
...by the Soviet Army!
Have you been in Poland?
I just came from Poland.
Are there any Jews left?
Where should we go?
Don't go east, that's for sure.
They hate you there.
I wouldn't go west either,
if I were you.
We could use some food.
Isn't there a town over there?
[ © anoXmous https://thepiratebay.se/user/Zen_Bud/]