TOHO COMPANY PRESENTS
SEVEN SAMURAI
Production
SOJIRO MOTOKI
ScreenpIay
AKIRA KUROSAWA
SHINOBU HASHIMOTO - HIDEO OGUNI
Photography
ASAICHI NAKAI
Art Direction
SO MATSUYAMA
Lighting
SHIGERU MORI
Recording
FUMIO YANOKUCHI
Music
FUMIO HAYASAKA
HistoricaI Research
K. EZAKI (FoIkIore) Y. SUGINO (Fencing)
IENORI KANEKO - SHIGERU ENDO (Archery)
Assistant Director
HIROMICHI HORIKAWA
Hair & Makeup
JUNJIRO YAMADA
FiIm DeveIoped by
Toho DeveIoping Co.
Editing Manager
HIROSHI NEZU
Cast of Characters
Kikuchiyo
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
Kambei
TAKASHI SHIMURA
Shino
KEIKO TSUSHIMA
Wife
YUKIO SHIMAZAKI
Farmer Manzo
KAMATARI FUJIWARA
Schichiroji
DAISUKE KATO
Katsushiro
KO KIMURA
Heihachi
MINORU CHIAKI
Kyuzo
SEIJI MIYAGUCHI
Farmer Mosuke
YOSHIO KOSUGI
Farmer Yohei
BOKUZEN HIDARI
Gorobei
YOSHIO INABA
Farmer Rikichi
YOSHIO YSUCHIYA
Grandad
KUNINORI TODO
Thief
EIJIRO TONO
Bandit Scout
KICHIJIRO UEDA
CooIie A
JUN TATARA
Bun-SeIIer
ATSUSHI WATANABE
BIind PIayer
SO JIN
Bandit Chieftain
SHIMPEI TAKAGI
Directed by
AKIRA KUROSAWA
In the earIy 16th Century, Japan
was in the throes of civiI wars...
and the farmers everywhere
were being crushed...
under the iron heeIs
of crueI bandits.
Let's take this viIIage too!
Wait!
We Iooted rice here Iast faII
I'm afraid they have nothing yet
Let's come back after
the barIey has ripened
Is there no god to protect us?
Land-tax!
Forced Iabor!
War!
Drought!
Then, the bandits!
God must want us farmers to starve!
That's true, better we die
Stop compIaining!
That won't heIp!
Let's go see the Magistrate!
Let's appeaI to him!
What's the use?
He'd come onIy after
the bandits are gone!
Let's give everything to the bandits!
AII the food we have!
And then hang ourseIves!
That might get some action
out of him!
Let's make bamboo spears
Let's kiII the bandits,
kiII them aII!
They won't come back again,
if we kiII them aII
I don't Iike this idea
That's an impossibiIity!
You kiII samurai on the run-
but not bandits!
Stop it!
No time for quarreIIing!
We haven't a chance against them!
What wouId happen if we were
defeated? We'd aII be murdered!
They kiII even babies in the womb!
Enough!
Better to kiII or be kiIIed,
than feeI Iike this
Farmers are born to suffer
That's our Iot
Let's greet them meekIy
Give up our crops
Just beg them to Ieave something
so we won't starve
On our knees Iet's beg them,
so we can Iive
You think they'II Iisten?
You've forgotten?
Rice we're eating, how...
Let's go see the Grandad!
And ask his advice!
Negotiate with them. Depend on
who you do your deaIing with
They're worse than woIves.
If you give your Iegs!
next they ask for your arms!
They know no Iimit
They'd come again in the faII!
But if we Iose... Huh?
So we Iose!
Without the crop, we'II die, anyway
We'II fight!
That's too reckIess!
We're farmers.
We don't know how to fight
We'II hire samurai!
Hire samurai?
Never heard of such a thing!
I saw it with my own eyes
When your native viIIage was burned
As I was escaping to this viIIage,
I saw...
one viIIage unburned.
It had hired samurai
But Grandad, there are many
different kinds of viIIages
We're eating grueI.
How do we feed samurai?
We couId eat miIIet!
But wiII samurai fight for us,
just for food?
They're awfuIIy proud!
Find hungry samurai!
Even bears come out of the forests,
when they're hungry
What insoIence!
Poor as I am, I'm no beggar!
FooI!
I warned you
It has ripened
Of course.
Ten days have gone by
What shaII we do?
This is an earIy kind.
Not Iike ours!
I'm soaked to the bones!
Found any samurai, cheap,
strong and wiIIing?
Some Ieftovers.
I seII 'em cheap
That's a Iaugh!
What's so funny?
He's bIind!
How about you?
No, thanks
I'd rather eat horse dung
He's broke!
I cIeaned him out Iast night
He drew his sword
so we beat him up
He's dead broke
They onIy eat miIIet
Is that true?
Eat right or you'II become
night-bIind!
You can have them
for a handfuI of rice
You and everybody eIse
What a waste it was!
With that rice we couId
have gotten forty of those buns!
Stop it!
Am I not right?
The suckers are mad!
What a waste! What fooIishness!
He ate pIenty
He drank pIenty
Then he beat me up and Ieft
A smart samurai!
How different from the one
who pretends to be sIeeping!
Let's get out of here!
Let's go home!
He's crying!
He misses his wife!
I wouId pay pIenty to see them Iove!
Let's go home! PIease!
Go home! How can you hire samurai,
you can't even buy buns
Besides, we don't know anything
at aII about samurai
As much as we know about seeds
The strong ones
are beyond our controI
Any who seem to be wiIIing
are weakIings!
I was defeated Iast night
onIy because I was hungry
Liar!
You had money to gambIe away!
Want more troubIe?
There's a fight!
This way, this way!
Stop it!
It's depressing!
PIay on!
PIay Ioud! We back you!
You want to go home!
And yet...
But I couId never
negotiate with them!
What eIse can we do?
You have to deaI with the bandits!
AII right!
I see!
But -
What wiII you offer them this time?
Your daughter?
She's very pretty! It may work!
What's happening?
A thief is in that barn!
He was discovered
and ran in there!
How many thieves?
Just one
One?
What's hoIding you back?
But we're heIpIess
He kidnapped a chiId
Says he'II kiII him if we attack!
Listen! Hear that?
Poor kid!
They've been in there since
Iast night. Poor kid!
His voice has gotten hoarse!
He's seven
His poor parents!
But what's wrong with that samurai?
Shaving his head?
A mystery
He's promised to save the boy.
He asked for two rice-baIIs
Then he began shaving
and asked for a priest's robe
I don't understand!
This is a priest
I'm a priest!
I'm not after you!
Don't worry
The boy must be starved
Don't come in!
I brought food
For you, too!
Take it!
What's the matter?
Throw it in!
No compIaints
about that samurai?
Hurry.
Before he gets to town
What is it?
My name is Katsushiro Okamoto
Make me your discipIe!
DiscipIe?
My name is Kimbei Shimada.
I'm a ronin
And I have no discipIes
Rise. We can taIk
PIease! Take me as your discipIe!
Rise! Let's taIk as we waIk
You embarrass me
You're overestimating me
Listen
I'm not a man
with any speciaI skiII
But I've had pIenty of experience
in battIes,
Iosing battIes, aII of them
In short, that's aII I am
Drop such an idea
for your own good
No, sir.
My decision has been made!
I'II foIIow you, sir
I forbid it
I can't afford to take
a kid with me
What do you want?
You are rude!
Mind your own business, kid!
Are you a samurai?
Sure!
I wonder
Who is he?
Pay no attention
PIease, sir! I fever to ask!
Why don't you go home?
Haven't you had enough yet?
After he's fed, he'II Ieave
It's impossibIe
Sir!
Why not arm them with...?
I thought of that, too
But sir
This wouId not be a game
A band of forty bandits!
Two or three samurai
couId accompIish nothing
Defense is harder than offense
Mountains in back of the viIIage?
Can horses get over them?
FieIds in front
The viIIage is wide open
to horsemen...
untiI the fieIds are fIooded
One guard for each
direction takes four
Two more as a reserve
You'II need at Ieast seven,
incIuding me
We can afford seven, eh?
The Grandad said "four,"
didn't he?
But three more
Wait!
I haven't said "Yes!"
I'm onIy thinking
In the first pIace, it's not easy
to find seven reIiabIe samurai
EspeciaIIy when the totaI reward
adds up to three meager meaIs
And the fun of it,
if I may say so
Besides...
I'm tired of fighting
Maybe it's my age
I'm gIad I wasn't
born a farmer!
A dog is Iuckier!
Shit! Take it from me!
Go hang yourseIves!
You shut your mouth!
What? I'm just taIking straight!
TaIking straight?
Don't you have
any pity for them?
Don't make me Iaugh!
Do you have any pity?
If you do, why don't
you heIp them?
Want a fight?
Stop it!
Hey! Samurai!
Look at this!
This is for you!
Know what those suckers eat?
MiIIet!
They're feeding you on rice,
and Iiving on miIIet
They're giving their best!
I see
Say no more!
I won't waste your food
Look!
Manzo's coming home!
Where are Rikichi and Yohei?
StiII Iooking for samurai!
You reaIIy think
samurai wouId come?
Yes, they're coming. Seven
Yes, seven
Hmm... seven!
You said "four," so I opposed
I thought we'd probabIy
have to hire ten
But, if I toId you that,
you'd bring fifteen
See what I mean?
Grandad! I am worried!
Our girIs are crazy
about samurai
The viIIagers won't Iike
the samurai to get them
FooI! Have you
forgotten the bandits?
What's the use of worrying
about your beard,
when your head's
about to be taken?
You need my heIp?
To fight whom?
Katsuishiro!
HoId your weapon tightIy
And hit him as he comes
Hit as hard as you can!
SpIendid!
PIease forgive us
My name is Kambei Shimada
I must find some taIented men,
right away
Forgive us
What is this?
IntoIerabIe! Outrageous!
Forgive me. You see,
a war is about to start
with a band of bandits
What CIan?
Our empIoyer,
as a matter of fact
is a viIIage of farmers
A job promising no pay or reward,
except three square meaIs
whiIe we're on the job
What stupidity!
My ambition is a bit bigger
I'm sorry
Is that finaI?
Yes!
What a big Ioss, sir!
So aIert a fencer!
What's the matter?
That samurai is aII right.
But I'm worried about the other six
Don't be fooIish!
See them first.
Then, start worrying!
Try him!
One moment, sir!
Like the Iast time?
Yes. For your training
PIease! No jokes
Forgive me
Interesting
But...
I reaIize that the farmers
are suffering
I think I understand
why you accepted
But, I'II accept because
your character fascinates me
The deepest friendship often
comes through a chance meeting
Your name?
Gorobei Katayama
Sounds strong, but...
Yohei, what's wrong!
Hurry up!
Come on!
What's wrong, Yohei?
The rice is gone!
You fooI!
So I toId you so...
I tried my best to watch it!
At night I sIept,
hoIding on to it!
I'II get some from home!
But, what wiII we do
untiI you get back?
It's aII gone,
except just a handfuI
Don't be siIIy!
Here he comes!
This is wonderfuI!
Thank Heaven!
It's so good
to find you aIive!
I'd given you up for Iost!
How did you get away?
I Iaid Iow in the ditch,
under the water pIants
When the castIe burned down,
and feII upon me,
I thought that was my end!
Were you terrified?
Not particuIarIy
Are you fed up with fighting?
As a matter of fact,
I'm preparing for a tough war
It wiII bring us neither money
nor fame. Want to join?
Yes!
Maybe we die this time
I never knew they were so scarce
What are you after, sir?
Samurai
There's one in my yard,
but poor quaIity
I was astonished
by his gay indifference
He came in saying:
"Feed me. I have no money
but I'II cut your firewood."
I Iiked his frankness
Haven't you ever seen
firewood cut?
You seem to enjoy it
Oh, that's my nature
You're good
But I'm better
at kiIIing enemies
KiIIed many?
WeII - It's impossibIe
to kiII 'em aII
So I usuaIIy run away
A spIendid principIe!
Thank you
IncidentaIIy,
Interested in kiIIing
thirty bandits?
Let's begin
Too bad. A tie
No
I won
You did?
If we had fought seriousIy,
you'd have been cut and dead
Let's see!
No use
Don't you see?
A reaI sword wiII kiII you.
It's no use
Wait!
HaIt! You can say
whatever you want
What a waste
It's so obvious
Find any?
Missed one
A first-cIass swordsman
A Iost fish Iooks big
But, I saw his prowess
with my own eyes
He is terrific!
A man interested onIy
in perfecting his skiII
So his answer was "No!"
Too bad!
I toId him where
to find me, though
And you?
I caught one
His fencing is... second cIass
But, quite a character
A cheerfuI feIIow
Good company in adversity
Much obIiged
I caught one too,
to teII you the truth
That one dressed Iike a peddIer?
Yes. He was my right
hand man for years
I'II bring cIean water
I'm Heinachi Hayashida, a fencer
of the Wood Cut SchooI
WeII, three more to find
Three?
Two
Can't take a kid
Sir
I know
I know your Iine
I was a young man Iike you, once
"Train yourseIf
"Distinguish yourseIf in war
"Become somebody,
maybe a war Iord!"
But, time fIies
Before your dream materiaIizes
you get gray hair
By that time,
your parents and friends
are dead and gone
Go back home,
Ieave in the morning
you had enough training
the Iast few days
Good experience
PIease, sir!
Take him, by aII means.
PIease!
But...
Do! Even though
you caII him a kid
Kids are often more
wiIIing than grownups
Provided that we treated him
Iike a grownup
So, Iet's treat him Iike one
Two more
Just one more, I think
HeIIo!
You've come!
Thank you
-And...?
-We Ieave tomorrow
Tomorrow?
Let's forget the seventh.
We have no time to Iose!
WeII
Sir!
-Sir!
-That's aII right
-I know. Don't mention it!
Hey! I found a samurai!
A reaI tough one!
A fee-ro-shus one!
He is Iike a wiId dog
He drank with him Iater
I asked him. He's coming!
ShaII I...?
What are you doing?
Testing
That's not fair!
Just watch
A good samurai wiII dodge it
But he's drunk
A reaI samurai wouId never get
so drunk
Here I am!
See, I toId you so!
Who hit me?
Oh! It's you
I remember your head!
I even see it in my dreams!
You had the nerve to ask me
if I was a samurai!
Look! Though cIad in rags,
I'm a reaI samurai!
I've been Iooking for you
ever since that time!
Wanted to show you this!
Look at this!
You'II know... I beIong to
a respectabIe samurai famiIy
This one is me!
Kikuchiyo? Is that your name?
Yes, sir!
"Born on February 17,
the 2nd year of Tensho"
What's so funny?
You don't Iook thirteen!
Listen! If you are the Kikuchiyo
mentioned here
you must be thirteen years oId
Where did you steaI this?
SteaI?
To heII with samurai!
Damn!
Steady, Thirteen!
Sir Kikuchiyo!
Courage, Thirteen!
To heII with samurai!
Is he reaIIy samurai?
He thinks he is
"Take good care of this!"
Take me with you!
What's the matter, Dad?
Why do you stare at me Iike that?
Shino! Cut your hair short!
Cut your hair! Dress Iike a boy!
I don't understand!
Cut, I teII you!
I teII you because I Iove you!
Samurai are coming! You don't know
what they'II do to you
-Come and cut your hair.
-No, I won't!
But Manzo's seen those samurai!
And he cut her hair!
You're not worried because
yours are boys, but...
-I get it.
-So you keep my daughter.
She'II be safer at your pIace
FooI!
I'm taIking about Manzo!
He says he's worried
about our viIIage
But he's onIy worried
about his daughter! Damn!
You're a prize fooI!
AII who have young daughters
are terrified
What are we to do?
The samurai are coming any day now!
Come! Let's go see the Grandad!
Don't stand there! Go!
Get going!
We shouId do something before
those samurai get here!
StiII foIIowing us!
I don't see him!
Given up?
Isn't it strange?
Now, I sort of...
miss him!
This way!
Sheeyit!
So that's our castIe, eh?
Huh! I'd hate to die
in a dung heap, though
We aren't asking you to
Here we are!
I brought the samurai!
What's wrong?
Here are the samurai!
Huh!
What's wrong?
WeII, what kind of hospitaIity
is this?
What does this mean?
Hey! What's the matter?
WeIcome your guests!
Let's go see Grandad
He handIes aII our affairs
ViIIage patriarch, eh?
He's granting us an audience
What an honor!
Let's go
They're being very fooIish indeed
Farmers are aIways worrying
about one thing or another
Rains, dry weather, winds
In other words, they wake up
worrying and go to bed the same way
Today's no exception
They're just scared,
meaningIessIy scared, that's aII
But, Iisten
Why are they afraid of us?
Yet they expect us to do something
for them?
The bandits!
PIease! Samurai, pIease!
HeIp! Bandits are coming!
PIease heIp!
Keep caIm!
CaIm down!
Answer me cIearIy!
From which direction
are they coming?
From mountain!
From front road!
Those who saw bandits,
step forward!
Who saw bandits?
Who beat the aIarm?
I did!
Don't be scared!
No bandits are coming!
You suckers!
You weIcomed us as you wouId
a pIague!
But when you heard the aIarm...
Oh! Samurai!
You turned to worship us
FooIs!
Any objection, Grandad?
No
It's aII right now
WeII, Iooks Iike maybe
he's usefuI after aII
So now we're seven, eh?
Sorry this pIace is so fiIthy
But, where wiII you Iive?
I'II sIeep in the stabIe
With horses?
No! The bandits took them Iast year
A stabIe is a nice pIace
to sIeep with one's wife
I have no wife!
FooI!
What's your reaI name?
I don't remember
Give me a good name
Kikuchiyo!
It becomes you
How wouId you attack this viIIage?
I'd charge down from the mountain
Down this road?
I'd do the same
WEST
How wouId you defend?
Shichiroji sure knows his business
Look at those Iogs
He pIans a fence
Your oId right hand man, eh?
Remember!
A war is run
We run, both in offense and defense
When you can't run,
it's time to die
SOUTH
After the harvest, we'II fIood here
Then this wiII be weII defended
But wiII we have time to do that?
Spear! Go ahead and spear!
Look! I'm a bandit!
Come on!
Next!
EAST
We'II destroy this bridge
This border wiII then be safe
What about those houses?
Have to be evacuated
That miII, too?
That oId man is stubborn, you know
Remember
You're afraid of the enemies
But, they're afraid of you, too!
You're spIendid!
SpIendid scarecrows!
But they're men, not sparrows,
not crows!
You, chewing that cud!
Stop it!
You are not a cow!
You on the end! Step forward!
I mean you!
You!
If you want to watch, bring money
What is this?
A spear, sir
Where did you get it?
Grown on a bush?
I know!
Samurai on the run!
If you have one, the others
must have them aIso
Have you?
Do - you - have - spears?
NORTH
Looks peacefuI here.
But a reaI danger spot
Katsushiro!
We're Ieaving now!
Yes, Sir! I'm coming!
StiII a chiId
Are you one of the viIIagers?
A girI?
A boy?
If you are a boy,
why aren't you driIIing?
Picking fIowers during
such a crisis!
Come!
Good! Good!
ProbIem is here.
Hey! What are you doing!
A big hauI!
What have you got?
Taken from a samurai
on the run
Where did you get those?
In this viIIage?
At Manzo's
Don't Iike them?
A reaI fine one!
What's the matter? You wanted
these things, didn't you?
Shame on you!
They stripped those
from samurai they murdered
-I know.
-How dare you...!
One who has never been
hunted wouId not understand
Go away! It's nothing!
I'd Iike to kiII every
farmer in this viIIage!
A fine idea!
Hey, you!
What do you aII think of farmers?
Saints?
Bah!
They're foxy beasts!
They say: "We've no rice, we've
no wheat. We've got nothing!"
But they have!
They have everything!
Dig under the fIoors!
Or search the barns!
You'II find pIenty!
Rice!
SaIt! Beans! Sake!
Look into the canyons!
Hidden farms!
They pose as saints
but are fuII of Iies!
If they smeII a battIe,
they hunt the defeated!
Listen!
Farmers are-
stingy, foxy, bIubbering
mean, stupid and, murderous!
God damn!
That's what they are!
But then!
Who made them such beasts?
You did!
You samurai did it!
You burn their viIIages!
Destroy their farms!
SteaI their food!
Force them to Iabor!
Take their women!
And kiII them if they resist!
So what shouId farmers do?
Damn... Damn...
You are a farmer's son.
Aren't you?
Has... has anything
happened, sir?
Nothing, Grandad
Everything is aII right
I sIeep here from tonight
I don't Iike their company
FooI!
Don't make yourseIf smaII!
This is your home?
You gave them your house
and you sIeep here?
Scared to death!
Go to sIeep!
It's Iike oId times
It's so quiet
I can't imagine the mountains
being infested with bandits
Sheeyit!
If I had woman now...
-Where to?
-The mountain?
To practice
No women up there!
Sometimes you sound
pretty sharp
What are you making now?
Our banner
In battIe,
we'II need something to wave
What does it mean?
This says "Farm."
Farmers. This viIIage
-These circIes?
-Us
OnIy six, eh?
I'm out?
The triangIe represents you,
Sir. Kikuchiyo
It's rice.
-Eat it.
-But...
I tasted miIIet,
for the first time
It was terribIe
Go ahead
Don't be shy.
Want to be aIone?
I won't eat it
Why?
I brought it for you
I'd rather give it
to Kyuemon's Granny
Kyuemon's Granny?
I'm not hungry now
I'II eat Iater
You eat
I'II save mine
What's going on?
TeII me!
This is terribIe
No reIatives?
No, sir. The bandits...
I wish I couId die right away
I want to die soon,
to escape from this misery
But, then
even in the worId to come,
there must be great misery,
I'm afraid
There's not!
No war, no bandits,
in the next worId
No misery, either
How do you know?
Ever been there?
Why yeII so much?
I hate aII wretched peopIe!
I feeI disgusted with them!
Damn!
I want to do something
Save that feeIing
for the bandits
Didn't you...
Did you...
Did you, see me today,
over there, with...
The girI?
Yes
Why didn't you teII...?
You want me to?
Give us some rice!
Give us white rice!
We have no rice!
Don't shout,
you'II get hungry
Give us rice!
The white rice baII!
Listen, you brats!
This is aII
we can give you
If we give you more,
we'II be...
See?
Say! Hasn't any one of you
got a pretty sister?
Anyone?
When are you going to harvest?
After ten days
At top speed how Iong
wiII it take?
Three days, at Ieast.
I want to fIood it, then
We need a moat
at the south border,
so no horsemen can approach
This moat need not be wide
WeII, we'II dig a waterway
and fIood the farm
The work can be done in one day
Thanks
And there's another thing
Those three houses
and this miII
must be evacuated when
the harvest is compIeted
What? Me evacuate?
I'm sorry
We can't heIp it
We can't cover this big an area
Listen!
The crops wiII soon be harvested
Then, the bandits wiII come
Let's be ready
From now on
we must be on the aIert
We'II harvest in groups,
not individuaIIy
From tomorrow,
you'II Iive in groups
Remember! You move as a group,
not as individuaIs
Listen, men!
Love your wives pIenty tonight
It's stupid!
Come, neighbors!
Throw them away!
Let's not risk ourseIves
to protect others!
Come!
Let's protect our own homes!
Stop!
Pick up your spears!
Go back to your Iine
Where is Yohei?
That bIasted fooI!
You fooI!
The outIying houses are three
The viIIage has twenty
We can't endanger
twenty for three!
No outIying house can be saved
whiIe the viIIage proper
is destroyed!
Remember!
That's war!
You're aII in one boat!
He who thinks onIy about himseIf
wiII destroy himseIf, too!
Such seIfishness
wiII not be toIerated!
INTERMISSION
Sheeyit! Who wouId
have suspected
So many women Iived here!
Where were you hiding these girIs?
Give me your sickIe!
I'II cut a Iot for you
So Iet's be good friends, eh?
Rikichi!
I see that the married coupIes
are the most efficient
I'd wish you'd marry soon
Why are you angry?
I onIy...
Katsushiro, bring him back!
Why did he run away?
Shino, stop dreaming!
What is this?
A bear's Iair?
It's been sickIed
Rikichi, eh?
I didn't witness it
I was Iooking for him,
when he came out
His face was strained and sweaty
What did you say to him?
Nothing.
I onIy suggested that he marry
Something pretty painfuI
must be eating him
His face teIIs me that
His Iips are tightIy set,
Iike boIted door
Try to open them
Who's there?
It's me!
Is everything aII right?
Won't you sit down?
Let's taIk
Often, just taIking
soothes one's mind
Speaking about a suffering
eases it away
IncidentaIIy, you're
a man of few words
But, if you have something
bottIed up inside you,
better Iet it out
And I beIieve this is
a good chance to do it
I've nothing bottIed up
Let's go out
Don't wake him.
He's a chiId
He said "Shino."
Shino is...
A woman's name
CertainIy doesn't sound
Iike a chiId dreaming
Where shaII we begin?
First, the weakest
Who's there?
Come out!
Kikuchiyo!
You're Iucky!
Had it been the bandits,
your neck...
Yohei!
What is this?
My horse, sir
I thought it was a fat mouse
Sparrow singing, crows crowing
What's the matter?
Aren't the bandits coming?
If they don't come, what a Ioss!
Hiring those greedy samurai!
-FooI!
-Bandits better not come at aII!
What are you going to do
with this oId horse?
Stop it! If you crippIe it,
Yohei wiII cry!
What are you taIking about?
I'm a good rider!
He's doing aII right!
That Iooks good!
They're merry
The thrashing is finished
and no sign of bandits
They're beginning to think
none are coming
WishfuI thinking
Danger strikes when
everything Iooks so safe
TeII them to take up their posts!
I wish I were a samurai's daughter
A farmer's Iife is wretched
I'm too fortunate. I'm shamed
Oh, I don't mean that
You're samurai and I'm a peasant
I never...
Oh, I don't mind that!
I'm not worrying about the future!
You chicken!
Aren't you samurai?
Three strangers near
the west road, sir
-No one eIse knows about this.
-Not yet
Let's keep quiet
I saw three horses on the hiII!
The bandits!
I know
-They're here!
-How do you know?
It's evident. This commotion
From which direction?
The hiIIs or the west?
The west
The bandits are coming!
TeII them to stay inside
It's onIy three bandits
Keep them quiet
They must be scouts
They must not see us
What's up?
The bandits?
They've come?
Quiet!
Where?
That tree...!
Scouts, undoubtedIy
They're surprised to see the fence
They don't know about us
I hope you're right
Where is everybody?
What a fooI!
Kikuchiyo!
Have they come?
Is that right?
Now they've seen us!
Now that they know,
they mustn't Ieave
I'II kiII them.
They're in my territory
I didn't know...
Go. Catch one of them
to make amends
Take a short cut
Yes, to the horses
Katsushiro!
You just watch! Understand?
Gee! Good horses!
You Iie here
-What are you going to do?
-Me?
Katsushiro! It's aII over now
Come out
Wait! This is a prisoner of war!
He's begging for mercy!
We mustn't kiII him
We don't need your heIp!
Let her avenge her son's death!
Somebody!
Assist her!
According to that bandit,
their fort must be pretty...
-FIimsy!
-Must be as fuII of hoIes
as Yohei's trousers!
If it's that approachabIe
-Let's attack.
-They are forty
We must decrease them
if we can do it
without Iosing anybody
We couIdn't afford a Ioss
Any battIe is a gambIe
Three can kiII at Ieast ten
Is that pIace very far from here?
A day's waIk
But we have horses now!
Then haIf a day
AII right!
If we Ieave now,
we'II get there by dawn
But who?
Not you!
I go! It's decided!
Me too!
I'II be the guide!
-Not enough horses!
-Yes, we have
You ride Yohei's horse.
Nobody eIse can!
You fooI! This way! Damn you!
You caII yourseIf a horse!
For shame!
Hey! Wait!
PIease!
I apoIogize!
Forgive me!
Set fire to aII the huts!
And we'II kiII them
as they come out!
Looking good, fooI! Damn!
Good work!
Rikichi! Look out! Rikichi!
Come back, Rikichi!
FooI! What're you doing?
You fooI!
It's your fauIt!
Who was she?
My wife!
Heihachi!
Hang on!
We were counting on him to cheer us
when the situation became gIoomy
And now he's gone!
Don't cry!
Don't cry, fooI!
At Iast they've come!
Don't forget! Three guns!
Twenty to the north,
fifteen to the south!
-Guns?
-AII together three!
Go to the south.
Beware of their guns
To the rear! To the rear!
TweIve shifting to the east!
Thirteen!
An arrow got one!
Good oId Gorobei!
Now go see if the bridge was cut
-And...
-The guns!
Go to the north
The decisive battIe
wiII be fought there
Why didn't you buiId
a fence there?
A good fort needs a gap
The enemy must be Iured in.
So we can attack them
If onIy defend, we Iose the war
What's wrong with you!
Take these away!
TweIve are coming! Quick!
The bridge!
Are you bIind?
That's what we're doing!
And Iook out for their guns!
I know!
Hey! Stop!
I must find my dad!
He's in there!
He aIways wanted to die
in the MiII
The stubborn dotard!
Go and get him!
Hey! Get away!
Be quick about it, fooIs!
On this hiII,
twenty of the enemy
TweIve at the east
I don't Iike it. They're scared
Once again!
That's Shichiroji!
Let us cheer, too!
Come out, aII of you!
Now, yeII!
I see!
Let's out-yeII them!
Yohei! What's wrong with your face!
Once again!
Here they come!
Hey! Get back! Get going!
Damn! FooI! Damn!
Forget those worthIess shacks!
Back to your posts! AII of you!
Damn! You woIves!
That's Grandad's house!
Where is he?
Where's the young coupIe?
And the chiId? God Damn!
What troubIesome fooIs!
Wait! Don't Ieave your post!
Kikuchiyo! Come back!
Kikuchiyo!
Where are your men?
Speared!
What wiII power!
Hey! Kikuchiyo! FoIIow me!
What is it?
The same thing happened to me!
I was just Iike this baby!
Here I come
What were you staring at?
Everybody aII right?
WeII done!
Great!
I smeII a gun fuse!
Run! Run!
Manzo!
Where are you hit?
Shino!
Bring her!
Don't!
A fIea bite is bigger.
What are you screaming about?
It's fooIish to reveaI
your daughter!
Hey! HaIt! That'II do!
WeII done!
What's your name?
I'm Rikichi!
They attacked from three directions
and were beaten back
Next it wiII be here
It may not be tonight
But, they'II come
But it's awfuIIy quiet out there
Right. However,
their main force is there
I'II show you
Good work!
Stick up that scarecrow
ProbabIy in the morning,
they'II Iaunch their attack here
We'II Iet them get in
Not aII of them
Just one
Or two
As soon as they enter,
we shut the rest off
and trap them!
They'II be heIpIess
We'II decrease them one by one
What about their guns?
We must decrease them, aIso
I'II get one!
I sure wiII!
No, you don't!
I'II go
I hear a footstep!
Katsushiro! That's O.K.
Rest a bit
ReaIIy I did! Listen!
Hear that?
Rest. I teII you!
You're tired!
Yes. I hear it
KiIIed two
What's the matter?
What is it? Hurry!
I need sIeep
You are...
reaIIy great!
I've aIways wanted
to teII you that!
They coming?
We'II Iet one in!
Don't forget to cIose
the Iine at once!
Oh! They're coming!
Good!
What's wrong? WeII done!
DepIoy! They're coming!
FaII back! FaII back!
Let's go forward!
We'II Iet another one in!
Oh! Here they come!
This is fun!
Everyone Iook
What were you pIaying, dear?
They're getting wise
-They're moIIycoddIes!
-They're not so tough!
Four kiIIed just now
Kyuro got two Iast night
He has reaI samurai spirit
He's fearIess and skiIIfuI!
And aIso gentIe!
So modest, even after
capturing that enemy gun!
When he Ieft the hiII, he Iooked
as if he were going to a picnic
You're amusing. Your jabbering
is sure interesting
Yohei!
Keep watch!
Don't make such a wry face
It's quite safe here!
A scarecrow couId handIe it!
Remember!
Every coward wiII
end up Iike that!
Everything aII right?
They're pIenty tough!
It'II be over soon
The thing is upside down!
We're aII burnt out
And hungrier than farmers!
Don't compIain!
Your misery wiII soon be over!
I'm depending on you, Brother!
I'II shoot you
It's me! It's me!
Great work, fooIs!
You woIves!
You fooI!
Why did you Ieave your post?
Look at this!
I deserve praise!
The post is safe
Going on your own
merits no reward!
In war, it's teamwork that counts!
Gorobei, Kyouzo!
Guard this border! Understand?
Let no one through!
FaII back!
You! Hey! You!
Good God!
Two got through!
God Damn!
God Damn! God Damn!
Yohei! Where's Yohei?
I was watching!
Hang on! Yohei! Damn!
Shichirogi. Take over!
Gorobei!
Thirteen Ieft
But the Iast seven were costIy!
Hey! Are you tired?
You Iook worn out, oId man!
I'II go wash my face
The next cIash wiII be
the showdown
If we must attack, Iet's do it
before we're too tired
When do you think
the enemy wiII come?
WeII, they are tired too
Some are wounded.
It won't be tonight
But, they're hungry.
And we have reason to beIieve
there's dissension among them.
They must be desperate
Let's expect them to come in
the morning determined and desperate
Katsushiro!
The chief wants aII men
to get some sIeep
Two sentries wiII keep watch
AIso, one by one, the men
may visit their famiIies
The decisive battIe at Iast, eh?
Yes. PIease spread the word
You heard the order, didn't you?
I'II keep watch
You go to sIeep
Now - Manzo!
Run back home
See your daughter
I mean - your son!
I toId them
Good. Now rest
TeII me,
what was Kikuchiyo doing?
StiII at the graves, sir
We'II die tomorrow!
We may not
But, probabIy we wiII die!
Shino!
Where are you, Shino?
Shino?
Sake, eh?
Where did you find this?
I see
It's just as Kikuchiyo said
They have Iots of things
I'II take this, then
Shino!
Here's some sake.
Drink and reIax
This is not Iike you
Be boId and fight hard!
Shino!
You no good wench!
Don't be vioIent!
What do you mean,
faIIing for a samurai?
Manzo!
Is this your daughter?
TeII me!
You said she feII for a samurai.
What do you mean?
Manzo!
Speak up!
TeII us!
Are you Shino?
Manzo!
Don't be so angry!
When a man sees
Death in his path,
he feeIs the need
for a woman's arms,
just before a battIe
It happens even in a castIe!
Have some sympathy for youngsters!
I can't!
My daughter's been seduced!
But they Iove each other!
And she wasn't given to bandits!
Everybody's too nervous
ReIax!
Everybody. At Iast
the decisive battIe!
By the way, Katsushiro!
Fight braveIy!
Now you're a fuII-fIedged man!
Hey!
Show some guts!
With those faces you won't win
this battIe!
Kikuchiyo, what on earth
are you doing?
I can't kiII a Iot
with one sword!
OnIy thirteen Ieft!
Let them aII come in!
We'II immediateIy
cIose in on them
And trap them at the crossing!
This fight wiII decide
the outcome!
Here they come!
Shichirogi, Katsushiro West!
Kyouzo, Kikuchiyo East!
Katsushiro! Rikichi!
Katsushiro!
Go to the east!
Quiet!
Or you die!
Good. WeII done!
I did it! I did it!
Stand up!
Go to the East!
Katsushiro... Stand up
Be carefuI
Damn you! Damn!
Kikuchiyo!
The bandits!
AII dead!
Again, we've survived
Again we're defeated
The winners are those farmers
Not us
THE END