She shivers in the wind
like the last leaf on a dying tree.
l let her hear my footsteps.
She only goes stiff for a moment.
Care for a smoke?
Sure. I'II take one.
Are you as bored
by that crowd as I am?
I didn't come here for the party.
I came here for you.
I've watched you for days.
You're everything
a man couId ever want.
It's not just your face.
your figure. or your voice.
It's your eyes.
AII the things I see in your eyes.
What is it you see in my eyes?
I see a crazy caIm.
You're sick of running.
You're ready to face
what you have to face.
But you don't want to face it aIone.
No.
I don't want to face it aIone.
The wind rises electric.
She's soff and warm
and almost weightless.
Her perfume a sweet promise
that brings tears to my eyes.
l tell her that everything
will be all right.
That l'll save her from whatever she's
scared of and take her far, far away.
l tell her l love her.
The silencer
makes a whisper of the gunshot.
l hold her close until she's gone.
l'll never know
what she was running from.
l'll cash her check in the morning.
Just one hour to go.
My last day on the job.
Early retirement. Not my idea.
Doctor's orders. Heart condition .
"Angina" , he calls it.
l'm polishing my badge
and getting myself used
to the idea of saying good-bye to it.
lt, and the 30-odd years
of protecting and serving and tears
and the blood and terror
and triumph it represents.
l'm thinking about Eileen's slow smile.
About the thick. fat steaks
she picked up at the butcher's today.
And l'm thinking about
the one loose end l haven't tied up.
A young girl
who's out there somewhere.
helpless in the hands
of a drooling lunatic.
Damn it. Hartigan.
I won't Iet you do this.
You're gonna get yourseIf kiIIed.
You're gonna get us both kiIIed.
I won't Iet you. I'm warning you.
Let go of my coat. Bob.
You're dragging me down with you.
I'm your partner. They can kiII me. too.
I ain't putting up with that.
I'm getting on the horn
and caIIing for backup.
Sure. Bob. We'II just wait.
Sit on our hands whiIe that Roark brat
gets his sick thriIIs
with victim number four.
Victim number four.
Nancy CaIIahan. age 11.
And she'II be raped
and sIashed to ribbons.
And that backup that we're waiting on
wiII just so happen to show up
just Iate enough for Roark
to get back to his US Senator daddy.
Take a deep breath. Hartigan.
SettIe down and think straight.
You're pushing 60
and you got a bum ticker.
You ain't saving anyone.
You got a great attitude. Bob.
ReaI credit to the force. you are.
EiIeen's at home waiting for you.
Think about EiIeen.
Heck. Bob.
maybe you are right.
I'm gIad to hear
you're finaIIy taIking sense.
Hell of a way to end a partnership.
Hell of a way to start my retirement.
Nancy Callahan, age 11.
For all l know, she's dead already.
You've been a very good girI. Nancy.
You've been very quiet.
Don't be scared.
We're gonna be
taking you home reaIIy soon.
But first. we're going
to introduce you to somebody.
He's a very nice man.
Halfway to the warehouse where
we evil said they took her, and it hits.
wicked spot of indigestion .
At least that's what l pray it is.
The briefest induIge-ment
in automotive pIeasure.
For cheap thriIIs.
Such short-Iived durabiIity. Mr. ShIubb.
You wouId risk engender-ating iII wiII
on the part of our empIoyers.
Burt Shlubb and Douglas Klump,
two any-dirty-job-there-is thugs
with delusions of eloquence.
This Jaguar you so pin-headedIy covet.
temporariIy remanded
to our custody though it may be.
remains the property
of the son of Senator Roark.
Gotta keep this quiet.
Take them down fast.
A singIe dent.
the merest scratch thereupon.
and the before
mentioned consequences
of which I so recentIy made mention
shaII sureIy be athwart us.
Catch your breath.
Give your heart time to slow down.
But it won't slow down.
Get over it.
She needs you.
We're aII done here. Benny.
Let's give them some time together.
Give them some privacy.
Be with you in a minute. Lenny.
I'm just making sure
they get aIong reaIIy weII.
And what kind of beast
couIdn't get aIong
with a precious IittIe girI Iike this?
You must be awfuIIy scared now.
But you've got nothing to be scared of.
AII we're gonna do
is have a nice IittIe taIk.
That's aII. Just a nice taIk.
Just you and me.
Don't you cry now.
Doctor said it'd be like this.
Just take the pill he gave you .
No need to play it quiet.
Not any more.
Breathe steady, old man .
Prove you're not completely useless.
what the hell? Go out with a bang.
He likes to hear them scream.
l've seen his victims
and their twisted little faces.
all wide-mouthed and bug-eyed,
frozen in their last
horrible moment of living.
No screams.
Either l'm just in time,
or l'm way too late.
lt's nothing. Barely a flesh wound.
On your feet, old man.
Roark. Give it up.
Let the girI go.
You can't do
a goddamn thing to me. Hartigan.
You know who I am.
You know who my father is.
You can't touch me.
you piece of shit cop.
Look at you. You can't even Iift
that cannon you're carrying.
Sure. I can.
Cover your eyes. Nancy.
I don't want you watching this.
I mean it. baby.
Cover your eyes right now.
I take his weapons away.
Both of them.
Hell of a way to end a partnership.
For God's sakes.
don't make it any worse.
-Don't make me kiII you.
-Doing fine. Bob.
Never better.
I'm ready to kick your ass.
Keep him talking. Buy time.
Just a few more minutes.
Just till the backup gets here.
Sit down and stay down.
I'II kiII you if I have to.
Keep his mind off the girl,
skinny little Nancy.
He can't kill her
once the backup gets here.
Run home. Nancy. Run for your Iife.
Hey. Don't Iisten to him.
He's a crazy man.
-What a tough man you are. huh?
-You stay right where you're at.
You shoot your partner in the back
then you try to scare a IittIe girI.
Maybe I'II puII my spare rod.
pIug you a coupIe of times.
show you how it's done.
We couId've worked something out.
but you've bIown that.
Sit down or I'II bIast you in haIf.
-You're so sIow. you'II never stop me.
-Sit down.
You'II never be abIe to stop me.
I finally sit down,
just like you told me to.
The sirens are close now.
She'll be safe.
Things go dark. l don't mind much .
Getting sleepy. lt's okay.
She'll be safe.
An old man dies.
a little girl lives.
Fair trade.
The night is hot as hell.
lt's a lousy room
in a lousy part of a lousy town .
l'm staring at a goddess.
She's telling me she wants me.
l'm not gonna waste one more second
wondering how l've gotten so lucky.
I want you.
She smells like angels ought to smell.
The perfect woman .
The goddess.
I need you.
Goldie.
She says her name is Goldie.
Three hours later and my head
is feeling several sizes too big.
And that cold thing
happens to my stomach .
And l realize Goldie's dead.
Not a mark on her.
You'd have to check her pulse
or notice those perfect breasts of hers
aren't moving like they would
if she was breathing.
She was murdered and l was
right here when it happened.
Lying next to her,
stone drunk, just like she was.
Damn it, Goldie. Who were you
and who wanted you dead?
Who were you
besides an angel of mercy,
giving a two-time loser like me
the night of his life?
lt sure as hell wasn't my looks.
So why the sleazy saloon?
why the kindness, Goldie?
The cops, they're telling me too much ,
showing up before anybody
but me and the killer
could know there's been a murder.
Somebody paid good money
for this frame.
No reason at all to play it quiet.
No reason to play it any way
but my way.
Whoever killed you
is gonna pay, Goldie.
Open up. poIice!
I'II be right out.
l don't know why you died, Goldie.
l don't know why and l don't know how
l never even met you before tonight,
but you were a friend and more
when l needed one.
And when l find out who did it.
It won't be quick and quiet
like it was with you .
lt'll be loud and nasty, my kind of kill.
And when his eyes go dead,
the hell I send him to
will seem like heaven
after what l've done to him.
l love you, Goldie.
CIaire?
Now. don't worry. LuciIIe.
I was just grazed.
-You got any beers around this pIace?
-No way am I giving you any aIcohoI.
Besides. it's not what
you came here for anyway. is it?
No.
Go ahead. You're worse without them.
Thanks. You're the best.
Lucille's my parole officer.
She's a dyke, but God knows why.
With that body of hers
she could have any man she wants.
The pills come from a girlfriend
who's a shrink.
She tried to analyze me once
but she got too scared.
Haven't seen you Iike this in a whiIe.
Got in a fight with some cops.
Didn't happen to kiII any of them.
did you?
Not that I know of.
But they know they've been in a fight.
that's for damn sure.
How the hell do you suppose
I'm gonna square this with the board?
There ain't no squaring it.
Not this time.
This isn't some barroom brawI.
Or some creep with a gas can
trying to torch someone.
Hey. hey. This is big.
-SettIe down. Marv. Take another piII.
-Hey. there ain't no settIing down !
This is bIood for bIood.
and by the gaIIons.
This is the oId days and the bad days.
the all-or-nothing days.
They're back. There's no choices Ieft.
And I'm ready for war.
Prison was heII for you. Marv.
It's gonna be Iife this time.
HeII's waking up every goddamn day
and not even knowing why you're here.
But I'm out now.
It took somebody who was kind to me
getting kiIIed to do it.
But I'm out.
I know exactIy what I gotta do.
So you were scared,
weren't you, Goldie?
Somebody wanted you dead
and you knew it.
So you hit the saloons, the bad places,
looking for the biggest,
meanest lug around and finding me.
Well, l'm gonna find
that son of a bitch that killed you ,
and l'm gonna give him
the hard good-bye.
walk down the right back alley
in Sin City. . .
Leave your hands off Nancy.
. . .and you could find anything.
That coat Iooks Iike Baghdad.
So does your face. Take off!
He's new here. Marv. He didn't know.
Kadie's is my kind of joint.
Nancy's just getting started
with her gig,
but already the crowd's
breathing hard.
Plenty of nights
l've drooled over Nancy,
shoulder to shoulder
with all the other losers like me.
But that's not
what l'm looking for tonight.
What'II it be. Marv?
A shot and a brew. SheIIie.
and keep them coming.
Sure. honey. You take it sIow. now.
Most people think Marv is crazy.
He just had the rotten luck
of being born in the wrong century.
He'd be right at home
on some ancient battlefield.
swinging an axe into somebody's face.
Or in a Roman arena
taking a sword
to other gladiators like him.
They'd have tossed him girls
like Nancy back then .
Show's over. dickwad. Drink up.
Now. that's one fine-Iooking coat
you're wearing there.
Your kiIIing days are over.
you over-the-hiII.
do-gooder son of a bitch.
l love hit men . No matter what
you do to them, you don't feel bad.
-Take it off.
-What?
A fine coat Iike that.
and you're bIeeding aII over it.
AII right. it's aII yours. Oh. God !
It wasn't you Iosers who kiIIed GoIdie.
The guy who did that.
he knew what he was doing.
So teII me. man. Who sent you?
I don't hear you giving me any names.
So I guess when I shot you in the beIIy
I aimed a IittIe too high.
You keep holding out on me like this,
and l'm gonna have to get really nasty.
It was TeIIy. . .
TeIIy Stern passed me the order.
He runs the tabIes over
to the TripIe Ace CIub.
Thanks again.
Then the damnedest thing happens.
For a second, I smell the angel smell
that belonged to my Goldie.
Just need my medicine, is all.
Bastard.
You're gonna pay
for what you did to me.
FeeI Iike taIking. Louie?
How many got paid off
for the frame. Louie?
How many for the kiII?
It was ConneIIy. He set me up.
He'II never taIk.
I don't know about you.
but I'm having a baII.
Connelly talks. They all talk.
And what have been
your sins. my son?
WeII. Padre.
I don't want to keep you up aII night.
so I'II just fiII you in on the Iatest batch.
These here hands of mine.
they got bIood aII over them.
You're speaking figurativeIy.
When I need to find something out.
I just go out and Iook for somebody
that knows more than me.
and I go and I ask them.
Sometimes. I ask pretty hard.
By way of a for instance.
I kiIIed three men tonight.
Tortured them first.
You might say I been
working my way up the food chain.
First two were minnows.
smaII-time messengers.
But it was ConneIIy. the money man.
who fingered you. Padre.
Dear Lord. man. this is a house of God.
Just give me a damn name.
Roark.
You reaIIy are pushing your Iuck.
Padre.
feeding me garbage Iike that.
It can't be that big.
There's a farm
at North Cross and Lennox.
It's all there. Find out for yourseIf.
And whiIe you're at it.
ask yourself if that corpse of a sIut
is worth dying for.
Worth dying for.
Worth kiIIing for.
Worth going to heII for.
Amen.
His keys say
the padre drove a Mercedes,
or at least that's what they're
passing off as a Mercedes these days.
Modern cars.
they all look like electric shavers.
GoIdie.
GoIdie!
It couldn't be Goldie.
It's my own fault, and nobody else's,
that l got confused.
I've been having so much fun
I forgot to take my medicine.
That wasn't Goldie back there.
Goldie's dead.
and that's the whole reason that l've
been doing what l've been doing.
When you got a condition ,
it's bad to forget your medicine.
The cold thing,
It creeps into my gut and tells me
one more time it won't let go.
This is a bad place, this farm.
People have died here,
the wrong way.
I don't want to fight. pooch.
I got no gripe with you.
Easy. boy.
No way l was gonna use
my gun on you , buddy.
It's whoever owns you
I'm curious about.
because there's blood on your breath ,
and l think l know what kind.
So I sniff around to see what's buried.
Here we go.
It's impossible.
Nobody can sneak up on me.
I go blind.
Not a sound. Nobody's that quiet.
Nobody except the one who snuck
into that hotel room two nights ago.
It was you. you bastard. You kiIIed her.
You kiIIed GoIdie.
It was. . .
l blew it. Goldie.
l found your killer,
but he was better than me.
Too quiet, too quick.
A killer born.
why didn't he finish the job?
He keeps the heads. He eats the rest.
-LuciIIe?
-It's not just that woIf of his.
The woIf just gets scraps.
Bones.
It's him.
He eats peopIe.
-He cooks them Iike they were steaks.
-Let's get you warm.
Just Iike they were steaks.
Now he's got both of us.
It's all right. Take a nice. sIow breath.
Just Iook at the heads on the waII.
The heads on the wall.
Son of a bitch !
He kept smiIing that damned smiIe.
He made me watch him
suck the meat off my fingers.
-He made me watch.
-Oh. Jesus.
He made me watch !
Christ. I couId use a cigarette.
Dames. Sometimes all they
gotta do is let it out.
And a few buckets later.
there's no way you'd know.
You've brought us
some big troubIe this time. Marv.
Whoever's behind this whole thing
has his connections right
in the department.
Any leads?
One guy I taIked to toId me
it was Roark running the show.
Whoever it is.
he knew I was checking out
that hooker aImost before I did.
-What hooker?
-The one you've been obsessing over.
The dead one.
GoIdie.
I didn't know she was a hooker.
Doesn't make any difference
about anything.
-But I didn't know that.
-She was high-cIass stuff.
She must have shown you quite a time.
Quiet. There's a car coming.
Kevin.
All i've got is a face and a name.
I'II see you later. Kevin.
Let's go.
They're done checking the house.
They're coming this way.
Bastards. I'll show them.
You're not gonna get
either of us kiIIed. Marv.
No. don't shoot. PIease.
Listen to me. I'm his paroIe officer.
He's unconscious and unarmed.
so there's no need to kill him.
Captain. the target.
there's no sign of him.
Here's a sign.
That there is one
damn fine coat you're wearing.
I keep coming back to that cop
I just killed and what he told me.
l was pretty steamed about
what he'd done to Lucille.
so l took my time
with that son of a bitch.
lt wasn't till I showed him all those
pieces of himself that he said it.
Just a name.
Patrick Henry Roark, man of the cloth .
Could've become president,
but he chose to serve God.
Along the way,
he just happened to become
the most powerful man in the state.
He's brought down mayors
and governors like they were nothing.
He even made his rotten brother a
US senator without breaking a sweat.
And here he's gonna get killed
in the name of a dead hooker.
I'm getting used to the idea.
More and more.
I'm liking the sound of it.
Then it hits me like a kick in the nuts.
what if I'm wrong?
I've got a condition .
I get confused sometimes.
And with Lucille dead.
I can't get my medicine.
what if i've imagined all of this?
what if i've finally turned into what
they've always said
l was gonna turn into?
A maniac.
A psycho killer.
Can't kill a man
without knowing for sure you ought to.
I've gotta know for sure.
The merchandise is on display
by the time i make my way
to Old Town.
For an hour or so.
I asked around about Goldie.
l don't get any answers,
but l know I'm bound to.
Lucille said Goldie was a hooker.
and if she was. she has roots here.
friends, maybe even family.
You can't be Goldie. Goldie's dead.
Goldie. Yeah. sure. right.
I haven't eaten anything
or taken my medicine for days now.
No wonder I'm seeing things.
Bastard.
He's crazy.
Hit him again. Wendy. Harder.
Wait a minute.
Why did she call you Wendy?
Because that's my name. you ape.
Goldie was my sister. My twin sister.
I guess she was the nice one.
Goldie and the other six.
where are they?
What did you do to them?
You crazy goddamn broad.
Just take a look at this mug.
WouId any of you dames let me get
close enough to you to kill you?
None of you wouId. but Goldie.
And she onIy did because
she thought I couId protect her.
And I'll bet those cops didn't do a damn
thing about those other girIs. did they?
But as soon as they had me
for a fall guy.
they showed up. guns blazing.
But they didn't get me.
and I've been killing my way
to the truth ever since.
So. go ahead. doll.
Shoot me now.
or get the hell out of my way.
Aw. nuts.
Okay. I'm gIad we got
all that sorted out.
-What the hell?
-I tied those knots. That's my speciaIty.
You sat there and took it.
when you could've taken my gun away
from me any time you wanted to.
Well. sure. I thought I might be abIe
to talk some sense into you.
And I probably wouId have had
to paste you one.
and I don't hurt girIs.
I need a pair of handcuffs.
What styIe do you want?
I got a collection.
Just give him the ones
you got with you. Gail.
It was a farm boy named Kevin
who killed Goldie.
but it was CardinaI Roark who
was behind it. and I don't know why.
I know that sounds crazy.
No. it doesn't.
Goldie worked the clergy.
Just like that, a whopper of
a puzzle piece falls smack in my lap.
l'm too dumb to put
the whole picture together yet,
but she fires up two cigarettes
and hands me one.
and i taste her lipstick on it.
And suddenly, my heart's pounding
so loud i can't hear anything else.
l want to reach over and touch her
and taste Goldie's sweat
one more time.
But she isn't Goldie.
Yeah , yeah . This'll do.
I'm also gonna be needing a dozen
two-foot lengths of this rubber tubing
and a spool of razor wire
and a pair of those special gloves
that'll let me handle the wire.
Beefing up the old home security. huh?
You can bet your ass.
She was my sister.
so I'm in this one to the end.
But why are you willing
to go up against Roark
for someone you barely knew?
She was nice to me. gave me
something I didn't even know existed.
I wasn't never even able
to buy a woman.
You know. the way I look.
I take my mind off her
and I crawl back inside myself.
It's almost killing time,
and I'd better get sharp.
I check the list.
rubber tubing, gas, saw,
gloves, cuffs, razor wire, hatchet,
Gladys and my mitts.
-We're close enough. Pull over.
-Yes. Marv.
Keep the engine running.
If I'm not back in 20 minutes. you get
the hell outta here and don't look back.
KiII him for me. Marv.
KiII him good.
I won't let you down. Goldie.
Heading downstairs to the kitchen .
Getting himself a midnight snack,
and I can guess what kind.
Come on. you son of a bitch.
Damn . he's slick.
Is that the best you can do. creep?
That's right. Get personal, get close.
I can take it.
I got you. you littIe bastard.
Let's see you hop around now.
l try to slow my heart down
and breathe the fire out of my lungs.
My muscles make me
a thousand promises of pain to come.
Let me do it. Marv.
She was my sister. Let me finish him.
You wasn't supposed
to come down here. Wendy.
Oh. but I want to. . .
l'm sorry, kid, but I haven't
even started with this creep,
and I don't want you watching the rest.
It'll give you nightmares.
God. I gotta tell you.
I'm good and bushed.
And it's not that fight of ours
that did me in. either.
It's all that sawing and tying.
It's not as easy as it looks.
Could have been
a real mess around here
If I didn't have that tubing
for tourniquets.
I gotta admit. there was a spurt or two.
to get the scent in the air.
to get that friend of yours
to come running.
Well. what do you know?
Look who's here.
Here he comes.
That's a good dog.
He doesn't scream.
not even when the mutt's had its fill
and Kevin's guts
are lying all over the place.
Somehow the bastard is still alive.
still staring at me.
Not even when i grab the saw
and finish the job.
He never screams.
I put in a call to Kadie's
and ask Nancy to get her clothes on
and meet me at her place.
She says, "Yes" , like always.
Hey. Nancy. you got any beers?
Sure. Marv. Who's the babe?
There isn't much of anything
Nancy wouldn't do for me.
Not since a year back
when a frat boy roughed her up
and I straightened him out but good.
It really gets my goat
when guys rough up dames.
So. what do you want me
to do with her?
Well. your best bet is drive her
all the way up to Sacred Oaks.
What about you?
Are you leaving town?
Hell. no. I like it here.
I hot-wire a parked cab
and stay under the speed limit
so as not to get any attention .
My head starts to clear.
Things start to make sense.
I owe you, Goldie.
I owe you one and I'm gonna pay up.
So, if going after Roark
means dying, win or lose,
hell, l'll die laughing
if l know l've done this one thing right.
Quiet as a grave out here.
No sign of target.
All right, keep a lookout.
-Kevin?
-What's left of him. anyways.
The dog ate the rest.
Oh. my God. You monster.
You demon.
Don't scream or I'll pIug you.
He had the voice of an angel.
yet he spoke only to me.
And he's dead now
because of one stupid whore.
It's not a real good idea for you to talk
about Goldie that way while I'm around.
When he came to me
he was a tormented boy.
Tormented by guilt.
I tried to counsel him.
But the eating.
it filled him with white light.
Tearful. he swore to me
that he felt the touch of God Almighty.
What the hell do you know?
I know it's pretty damn weird
to eat people.
He didn't just eat their bodies.
he ate their souls.
And I joined in.
They were all whores.
Nobody cared for them.
Nobody missed them.
And then your Goldie
almost ruined everything.
She stayed in public places.
And then with you .
You were so convenient.
You'd broke a man's jaw
that very night.
Who would beIieve a thug like you?
Kevin killed her.
I ordered the police in for you ,
but you wouldn't be caught.
You wouldn't stop.
And now he's dead and you're here to
eliminate me.
Will that give you satisfaction. my son?
Killing a helpless old fart?
The killing. no.
No satisfaction.
Everything up until the killing
will be a gas.
Kevin.
we're going home.
You can scream now if you want to.
It's beautiful. Goldie.
It's just like I promised, only better.
And when his eyes go dead,
the hell I sent him to must seem like
heaven after what l've done to him.
Freeze!
Oh. my God !
Jerks.
They should've shot me in the head,
and enough times to make sure.
It's so stupid.
Everybody knows what's coming,
but they go through
the motions anyway.
what a waste of time.
Months fall off the calendar
while I breathe and eat through tubes.
Night after night, I wait for somebody
to come and finish me off.
After a while. I realize
it's not gonna be so easy as that.
I'm on my feet for about 10 minutes
before the cops kick them out
from under me.
They don't ask me any questions.
They just keep knocking
the crap out of me
and waving a confession in my face.
And I keep spitting blood all over it
and laughing at how many
fresh copies they come up with .
Then along comes this worm
assistant district attorney
who turns the recorder off
and says if I don't sign
their confession , they'll kill my mom.
I break his arm in three places
and I sign it.
From then on .
it's the circus everybody wants it to be.
They nail me for the works,
not just the people l did kill,
but even Lucille and the girls
that Roark and Kevin ate.
and even Goldie.
The judge is all fire and brimstone
when she hands down the sentence.
Midnight and my death
are only a few hours away,
when I get my first surprise
in 18 months.
My only visitor.
I'm ready for anything but that scent.
I got them for you good.
didn't I. Goldie?
I'm sorry. Wendy. I got confused again.
Just seeing you like this.
You can call me Goldie.
She smells like angels ought to smell.
The perfect woman .
The goddess.
Goldie.
She says her name is Goldie.
They fix me a pretty decent steak
for my last meal.
They even throw in a brew.
It's the first I've had
since back at Nancy's.
Then they shave my head and fix me
with a rubber diaper and get to it.
And it's about damned time.
if you ask me.
"Yea. though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of death. . ."
Would you get a move on?
I haven't got all night.
You heard the man. Hit it.
Is that the best you can do.
you pansies?
He's gone.
Forget it. man.
You can bang on that door
aII night if you want to.
There is no way in hell
I'm letting you in.
I can't believe
you're doing this to me. Shellie.
Everything we've shared.
it has to mean something to you.
It meant plenty.
Plenty of lost pay on account of how
nobody wants to fIirt with a waitress
whose face is all purpIe
and swollen up with bruises.
I know you're angry. baby.
And I forgive you for that
without you even asking me to.
There's a difference
between getting honked off
at a guy who's generally not so bad.
and finding out that you've been
sweet-talked by a total jerk Ioser
who skips out on a wife
that he doesn't even tell you about
every time he gets drunk.
which is way too often.
Especially the kind of totaI jerk loser
who has to beat up on a girl
to make himself feel like a man.
That hurt. Shellie.
It's one thing for you
to pIay hard to get.
but don't go trying to cut my nuts off.
I am impossibIe to get.
Do yourself a favor. Jackie Boy.
and get help. like a shrink.
Get help and get lost.
Just open the door.
Go ahead and open the door. Shellie.
I'll take care of this.
Just open the door and you'll see
how wrong you've been about me.
Oblige him. Shellie. I'm ready for him.
No! If he knew
that you were here with me.
you don't know how bad this couId get.
This clown's got a big. mean drunk on.
And he's got four friends
out there in the hall.
breathing hard
and just as drunk as he is.
Hey. I couId swear I heard somebody
in there with you just now.
Somebody! Jackie Boy.
it's a regular African Iove fest in here.
-I'm no racist.
-I mean. I got me all five starters.
and half the bench of the Basin City
Blues keeping me company.
You feel like taking them on?
You are teasing me. baby.
Some of my best friends. . .
But you're really pushing my buttons.
And the whole time
you've been doing me like this.
I've been too polite to point out
that at any time I want to.
I could kick this damn door to splinters.
Okay. baby. you know what I can do.
-You know what I can do. One. two. . .
-All right. then.
All right. All right. all right.
Troops. make yourseIf at home.
You brought your whole pack with you?
None of these bozos got lives.
they gotta hang out with you?
You're gonna love this. baby.
You're gonna call up some
of your friends who work in the saloon.
With you and the bunch of us.
we're gonna hit every joint in town.
and it's gonna be great.
I ain't caIIing up nobody.
That's a man's shirt.
and I'm sure as hell it ain't one of mine.
You got somebody's love stink
aII over you.
You've been with another man
and you've been with him tonight.
-Who is he?
-He's Superman.
He fIew out the window just as soon
as he heard you were coming.
'cause you scared him so bad.
You think I have no feeIings at all.
If you're gonna slug me.
just go ahead and get it over with.
you sick bastard.
There you go. lying about me again.
right in front of my friends.
I have never hit a woman in my Iife.
That's showing her. man.
You goddamn bastard.
You goddamn coward.
Baby. we're all here
to have a good time.
Yeah.
I gotta take a leak.
Wish you'd dropped by earIier.
Jackie Boy.
Then you could've met my boyfriend.
Could've seen
what a real man looks like.
There you go. after my nuts again.
But I forgive you.
I'm a generous guy.
He is generous.
But that temper of his. . .
You never should have
picked on him like you did.
My temper you don't have
to worry about.
Shut up and keep your hands
to yourseIf
or I'll cut your littIe pecker off.
Oh. I've been told.
Hey. baby.
I don't hear you making those calls.
Answer me.
Oh. I don't need this grief.
Hi. I'm Shellie's new boyfriend
and I'm out of my mind.
You ever so much
as taIk to Shellie again.
you even think her name.
and I'll cut you in ways
that'll make you useIess to a woman.
You're making a big mistake. man.
A big mistake.
Yeah?
You already made
a big mistake yourself.
You didn't fIush.
Troops. get outta here.
No questions. damn it. No questions.
Now!
Dwight. what in the devil
did you do to him?
I just gave him a taste
of his own medicine.
I don't think
he'll be bothering you again.
-How's your jaw?
-I've been slapped around worse.
Dwight. he was from a while back.
before you showed up again
with that new face of yours.
And it was onIy
'cause I felt sorry for him.
And it was only once.
I've done some dumb things.
Seeing as how
I'm one of those dumb things.
I can't give you
too hard a time about that. Shellie.
But this guy. he's a menace.
He might kill somebody
if I don't stop him.
I'll call you later.
No. don't go.
Shellie shouts something
I can't quite make out
over the racket
of a passing police 'copter.
Stop!
It sounds like "stop" ,
but I can't be sure.
It's a chance i shouldn't be taking,
but I can't just go home
and forget about it,
and let Jackie Boy
and his pals find their fun .
They're a pack of predators
and they're out for blood tonight,
a woman's blood.
Damn it. Dwight. Damn it.
You fool.
You damned fool.
I cut my Caddy across the park
to pick up Jackie Boy heading
like a bat outta hell up the hill.
l'm speeding.
That's a good way
to get yourself noticed.
And if you're a murderer
with a new face
who's one fingerprint check away
from the fast track
to the gas chamber like I am,
the last thing you want
is to get noticed.
I don't have nearly enough cash on me
to bribe this cop, and even if i did,
there's always the outside chance
he's one of the honest ones.
Do I try to talk my way out of this,
or do l take this cop down
and risk it all?
Then Jackie Boy saves me
a great, big, steaming pile of trouble.
Watch it. Jack.
Cops. They're right on our ass.
Not for Iong. Not where we're headed.
My gut tightens up.
Jackie Boy's leading us
straight to Old Town.
The cop shuts off his siren .
He knows he's not the law.
not in Old Town.
The ladies are the law here.
beautiful and merciless.
If you've got the cash
and you play by the rules,
they'll make all your dreams
come true.
But if you cross them, you're a corpse.
Hey. baby. Hey. baby.
Hop in. sugar. We'll get you there.
Sweetheart. I work the day shift
and it's been a long day.
Besides. I don't do group jobs.
Get in the car. baby.
We'll just taIk. It'll be nice.
I don't do talk jobs. either.
Babydoll. I've had me
one hell of a bad day.
I've been beat up
every time I turn around.
But the day I get turned down
by a hooker
when I got good.
hard-earned cash to pay her with.
Well. there's onIy so much
a man can take.
Go try the Alamo over on Dillon Street.
That's the Alamo. not the Amigo.
The Amigo's a fag joint.
Are you having a good time
humiliating me
Like this for no damn reason at all?
That's far enough. Dwight.
We've been on top
of these peckerwoods
since they first showed up
with that cop behind them.
Everything's under control.
Enjoy the show.
There's no use arguing with her.
The ladies are their own enforcers.
So. how's the barmaid?
You know.
the one that never shuts up?
Not right now. Gail.
Wound up a littIe tight. aren't we?
That's your whole problem. Dwight.
You worry too much.
That. and your lousy taste in women.
These days. anyway.
Damn it. Gail. Not right now.
Those clowns down the way.
they some of the barmaid's boyfriends?
One of them thinks he is.
He's outta control.
I followed him here to make sure
he didn't hurt any of the girIs.
Us helpless littIe girls.
All kinds of death is about to hit
less than 20 yards ahead of us,
and still it's hard
to take my eyes off her.
Us girls are safe
as we can be. LanceIot.
Those boys in that Chrysler
are one mistake away
from seeing what Miho can do.
And she's been aching
for some practice.
She guides my glance upwards to
the pixie perched on the roof's edge.
Deadly little Miho.
You're running out of alley. cowboy.
Turn around. Save yourself
and your buddies a ton of grief.
You're a sassy littIe thing.
You ain't hardly in any kind
of position to be making threats.
The trap is set,
locked and ready to spring.
So what? They're scum.
They deserve what's coming.
So why this rotten feeling in my gut
that something is awfully wrong?
They haven't killed anybody
I know about.
It got pretty bad at Shellie's pIace.
but they didn't kill anybody.
And they won't.
why this rotten feeling?
Something Shellie said. l can't place it.
Okay. okay. okay. I sounded off
a littIe more than I shouId have.
-I'm a little on edge.
-Over the edge.
It's not a woman you need.
It's a good night's sleep.
You couldn't handle a woman.
the state you're in.
She's saying you ain't got
what it takes. Jack.
You wanna see it?
You wanna see what I got?
I've seen all shapes. all sizes.
You seen this one?
Get in the car.
Sugar. you just gone and done
the dumbest thing in your whole life.
Oh. God. no.
This is crazy.
Out of nowhere. for no reason at all.
Go ahead.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
-He's got the drop on her.
-He's got squat.
He's dead.
He's just too damn dumb to know it.
I got you right where I want you.
This is a career-ending wound. whore.
-And there's gonna be hell to pay.
-Watch your step. Jackie Boy.
Yeesh.
This isn't funny.
Don't anyone Iaugh.
I got friends you can't imagine.
Everyone of you is gonna burn.
Hang it up she`s just playing with you.
-You're only making it worse.
-You shut the hell up.
Don't pull the trigger.
She bIocked the barrel. It'll backfire.
I toId you to shut up.
I can't see.
What's happening?
I can't hear anything.
For God's sake. Miho. finish him.
Yeah. Make it quick. will you?
She doesn't quite chop his head off.
She makes a Pez dispenser
out of him.
Then it's straight to business,
stretching the corpses out
on the alley floor
and going through their pockets,
divvying up cash when they find it.
I'm fishing around
in Jackie Boy's pants.
His wallet is packed.
Master Card. Discover.
Platinum American Express,
and nearly 300 bucks
worth of twenties
that l'm not too proud
to stuff into my own pockets.
Then l find an atom bomb.
Jackie Boy,
you son of a bitch .
There was a helicopter
that kicked up such a racket,
I couldn't quite make out
what she said.
I thought Shellie said "Stop."
She said "Cop" .
Detective Lieutenant Jack Rafferty.
Iron Jack, the papers call him.
A goddamn hero cop.
It's held for years, the shaky truce.
The cops get a slice of the profits
and free entertainment
when they throw a party.
The girls get to administer
their own brand of justice.
They get to defend their own turf.
If a cop blunders
into the neighborhood
and he's not shopping
for what the girls are selling,
they send him packing,
but they send him back alive.
That's the rules.
That's the truce.
The cops stay out.
That keeps the girls free
to keep the pimps and the mob out.
Old Town will be left wide open.
It'll be war.
The streets will run red with blood.
women's blood.
The cops. The mob.
Things are gonna go back
to the way they used to be.
The hell they will. We got guns.
We'll fight the cops and the mob
and anybody else
who tries to move in on us.
-We'll go to war.
-Don't be stupid. Gail.
You wouldn't stand a chance.
Get me a car.
Make sure it's a hardtop
with a decent engine.
I'II hide the bodies.
Did you forget that cop car
that trailed them here?
The cops know Rafferty came here.
They'll check the river.
they'll check the sewer.
They'll find him
and they'll come gunning for us.
I'll haul the bodies to the pits.
The cops won't check the pits.
Get that gun out of my face
or I'll smack you.
Who do you think you are.
giving orders?
-You got what you wanted out of us.
-Shut up. Gail.
You got what you wanted out of me.
And you were gone.
off playing with that barmaid.
Gone until you brought
this unholy mess on us.
Miho moves to my back.
One word from Gail
and she'll cut me in half.
They'll be watching the roads.
They'll catch you.
It'll be the bad old days all over again.
The pimps. the beatings.
the drugs. the rapes.
They won't be watching the roads.
Not yet. they won't.
Get me a damn hardtop.
If I don't make it.
you can have your war.
Get that gun out of my face now.
Bastard !
I forgot how quick you are.
My warrior woman .
She almost yanks my head clean off,
shoving my mouth into hers
so hard it hurts.
An explosion that blasts away
the dull, gray years
between the now and that one
fiery night when she was mine.
A hardtop with a decent engine.
And make sure it's got a big trunk.
I'll always love you. baby.
Always and never.
Where'd you find that heap?
Just look at that trunk.
We'll never fit them all in.
Gail? Unless there's something else
you want me to do.
you think maybe I couId go home?
All this blood and stuff's got me kind of
feeling like maybe I'm gonna hurl.
Sure. Becky. go home.
But don't you talk to anybody.
not even your mom.
They'll never fit in that trunk.
Not like this. they won't. Miho.
Dry your hair as soon as you get home.
You'll catch cold if you don't.
Yeesh.
Hey. Becky. Gail said no calls.
I just want to hear my mom's voice.
I won't tell her nothing.
PIease. don't say nothing to Gail.
Hey. Mom?
Dizzy dames.
what were they thinking,
sticking me with a beat-up bucket
of bolts like this?
we were barely able to get the trunk
to stay closed as it was,
we packed it so tight.
There wasn't anything we could do
but pile Jackie Boy in right next to me,
out where anybody who cares to look
will see him.
Go ahead, take one of his cigarettes.
It'll help.
It's got you smoking there. bud.
You shut the hell up. Jackie Boy.
You're dead.
I'm just imagining this.
so shut the hell up.
Well. it tells you something
about your state of mind. don't it?
It's got you hearing things.
It's got your nerves shot.
It's got you smoking.
You know it's true.
Nobody ever really quits.
A smoker's a smoker
when the chips are down.
-And your chips are down.
-I'm fine. You shut the hell up.
Will you look at that?
Those hookers let you down.
What are you gonna do
when you run outta gas. call AAA?
You sucker for the babes. you.
You ain't even gonna make it
to the pits.
You shut the hell up. I'll make it.
Not unless you keep
your eyes on the road. sugar pie.
Watch it!
This is great.
Just like being in a buddy movie.
Shut up!
Boy. you're screwed.
It's over.
You're flushed.
This time. I can't bring myself
to tell him to shut up.
Sure. he's an asshole.
Sure. he's dead.
Sure. I'm just imagining
that he's talking.
None of that stops the bastard from
being absoluteIy right.
I don't have a chance in hell
of out running this cop.
Not in this heap.
Pull over.
The only question left
is whether I'm gonna kill him or not.
Tough call.
For all I know.
he's an honest cop. regular guy.
a working stiff with a mortgage.
a wife and a pile of kids.
My hand moves all on its own.
sliding one of my guns to my lap
and thumbing back the hammer.
I don't know what to do.
You better stop.
You're making him mad.
Whatever you say.
Your friend here.
party a littIe too hard tonight?
I'm the designated driver.
You're driving with a busted tail light.
I'll let you off with a warning.
What next?
The tank goes dry
a quarter mile from the pits.
l shove the T-Bird the rest of the way.
A few minutes' more work
and it'll all be over.
Jackie Boy
will go into the damn tar pits,
l'll catch a train out of Sacred Oaks.
go home and call it a. . .
No more questions. Dallas.
Do what I say.
Clear the streets, We`re in lockdown
We're not selling any tail in Old Town.
Not tonight.
Don't struggle. You'll only hurt yourself.
Your cause is lost.
We know everything.
Soon the corpse of Detective Rafferty
will be in our possession.
and the truce between your prostitutes
and the police will be shattered.
There'll be arrests. There'll be deaths.
My employer will seize
what remains of this neighborhood.
You will all be slaves.
Nothing can stop this.
But. it is within your power
to save many lives
by facilitating the process of transition.
by negotiating the terms
of the surrender of Old Town.
Son of a bitch. I know you.
I have suffered your kind before.
the dregs of Sin City.
I serve a new master now.
and soon you
and all your wretched kind
will serve him as well.
Now. get dressed and shed a tear
for Dwight McCarthy if you must.
because. by now. he is surely dead.
You don't know him.
My man will find a way.
He always finds a way.
I can't fathom
these Americans always whining
and going on about
how they got it so bad.
This is a fine. grand country.
Guiding light of the modern world. it is.
Low taxes. land of opportunity.
Where else would one bullet buy us
the fortune that we're getting for this?
Sure beats the living hell out of
blowing up airports and churches
without shite to show for it.
Yeesh.
You find something. Murphy?
Looks to be a poor. dead cop's badge.
It's all bent up.
What's this stuck in it?
Bloody hell. It's the bullet.
You son of a bitch ! Bastard !
They weren't cops, these four.
They were mercenaries.
And if they were hired
by who i think they were,
the bad times haven't even started yet.
And everything seemed
to be going so well.
Remember. we don't have to deliver
every last inch of the man. Brian.
You got a good point there. Ronnie.
Lend me your knife.
Should I take a nap
while I'm doing all this waiting?
I'm at the bone. all right?
There we go.
Have you ever seen anything so pretty
in your whole life?
We'll be back for the three of you.
and if anyone happens by.
use your imagination. okay?
Silence. now.
No air to breathe.
Only the horrid, oily tar taste
creeping up my nostrils.
Let it in . Let it fill your lungs.
They were counting on you
and you blew it.
Skinny, steely fingers at my wrist.
Miho, you're an angel.
You're a saint.
You're Mother Teresa.
You're Elvis.
You're God.
And if you'd shown up
10 minutes earlier.
we'd still have Jackie Boy's head.
Dwight. they got Gail.
It's a cinch.
You got yourseIves a spy in OId Town.
A stoolie who sold you out to the mob.
We gotta find out who it is
and rescue Gail.
But first. we gotta get
our hands on Jackie Boy's head
before it gets to wherever it's going
and this whole situation
blows wide open.
Miho. I hope to hell you Ieft
one of them alive enough to talk.
I let him know l'm not fooling around.
we talk.
Stay smart. Stay cool.
It's time to prove to your friends
that you're worth a damn .
Sometimes, that means dying.
Sometimes, it means killing
a whole lot of people.
There they are. What do we do?
We stop them. Dallas.
Jackie Boy's head is so close to me
I could almost reach out
and grab it right then and there.
Get the head ! Get the head !
I got it! I got it!
Suck on this. you stupid slag.
I can't tell if Miho is alive or dead.
but I'm on my feet and every ounce
of me wants to get some killing done.
You want the head now.
sweetheart? So come down and get it.
Brave lad.
I couId've put a bullet
straight down your ear just now.
if I hadn't got me revolver
all wet and useless.
You got the drop on me. love.
I'm as helpless as a baby.
I got to come clean with you.
sweetheart.
It was an outright lie I was giving you
about me revolver being wet.
You see. I'm not too fond of shooting.
It's my preference to blow things up.
Once you blast the roof off a pub
and seen all the parts fIying off peopIe.
a littIe bang bang's
never gonna match the sight of that.
And here's me.
with all these fine grenades
and such a sweet beauty of a remote.
But it's me knife I'll be doing you with.
You killed me mates.
Someone should have told you.
never give an Irishman
good cause for revenge.
Deadly little Miho.
You won't feel a thing
unless she wants you to.
She twists the blade.
He feels it.
I tell Miho what we're gonna do
and how we're gonna do it.
I grab poor Dallas's car phone
and make the most important call
of my life.
First, we gotta rescue Gail,
then comes the kill.
The big, fat kill.
Do we just gotta stand here
and watch this?
What. are you kidding me. man?
I couId watch old Manute do his thing
all night long and not get tired of it.
I mean. the man's an artist.
Only an artist should be allowed
to touch such a beautiful subject.
Your skin is perfect.
Your nerves. responsive.
Beautiful.
Just give them what they want. Gail.
-Becky?
-It's over. Gail.
There's no fighting them.
Dwight's dead.
They got what's left
of that cop we killed.
The mob's gonna turn it over
to the police chief.
the cops are gonna mow us down.
We gotta cut a deal.
You littIe bitch. You sold us out.
I didn't have no choice.
They was gonna hurt my mom.
You gotta cut a deal with these people.
It's selfish. you holding out like this.
You're gonna get a lot of girls killed
for no good reason.
It wasn't your mom.
We couId have protected her
and you know it.
It was the money. you stupid little bitch.
Sure. there's money.
Sure. you couId've moved my mom
into Old Town
and let her know that her daughter's
a goddamn whore.
Breaks your heart. doesn't it?
They offered me what you couldn't
never offer me. a way out.
I had to watch out for my own neck.
Your neck.
Your precious. scrawny. littIe neck!
You're crazy. You could have
ripped my throat out. you crazy whore.
Schutz. fetch my blades.
-Stuka. kill this one.
-No. I was promised.
Stupid little bitch. You deserve worse.
I knew there was a reason
I got out of bed this morning.
Hey!
Nobody. I don't see nobody.
Will you look at that?
It's right through me. Guys. Iook.
There's something wrapped around it.
Some kind of note.
Give it to me.
It's poked right through me. Guys. look.
-It's starting to really hurt
Now, back everyone.
And bring the women.
Do you think somebody
shouId call me a doctor or something?
McCarthy. you fool.
Guys?
Dozens of them. armed to the teeth .
I'm outnumbered, outgunned.
But the alley is crooked,
dark and very narrow.
They can't surround me.
Sometimes, you can beat the odds
with the careful choice
of where to fight.
You can have Old Town. I don't care.
Just give me the woman.
Shut up.
Dwight. don't do this.
Hey. wait a minute.
Something's not right.
Shut up. or I'll plug you.
Of course. Mr. McCarthy. A fair trade.
She's all yours.
Now. if you'll explain to me why we
shouldn't bIow both of you to pieces.
Dwight. what have you done?
Exactly what I had to.
Every step of the way.
No. It isn't right.
There wasn't no tape over his mouth.
How come there's tape over his mouth?
where to fight counts for a lot.
Cute trick. McCarthy.
but it will do you no good.
But there's nothing like having
your friends show up with lots of guns.
No! McCarthy. you shit!
The girls all know the score.
No escape, no surrender, no mercy.
We gotta kill every last
rat bastard one of them.
Every last one.
Not for revenge,
not because they deserve it,
not because it'll make
the world a better place.
we need a heap of bloody bodies
so when mob boss Wallenquist looks
over his charts of profits and losses,
he'll see what it cost him
to mess with the girls of Old Town.
The Valkyrie at my side
is shouting and laughing
with the pure, hateful,
bloodthirsty joy of the slaughter,
and so am l .
The fire, baby.
It'll burn us both.
There's no place in this world
for our kind of fire.
my warrior woman , my Valkyrie.
You'll always be mine.
Always and never.
Evening. officer.
I don't have to introduce myseIf. do I?
You read the papers.
This being an election year.
you've seen plenty of my picture.
You know who I am and what I can do.
And I'm doing you. Hartigan.
Cold and hard. I'm doing you.
You blew my son's ear off.
You bIew his arm off. You even
blew his nuts and his pecker off.
He's in a coma right now.
They say he may never come out of it.
My boy.
He could've been the first Roark
to become the President
of the United States.
but you went and turned him into
a brain-damaged. dickless freak.
Pulling that trigger
make you feel powerful?
Power don't come
from a badge or a gun.
Power comes from lying.
Lying big. and getting the whole
damn world to play along with you.
Once you got everybody agreeing
with what they know in their hearts
ain't true.
you've got them by the balls.
There's what.
maybe 500 peopIe in this hospital?
I could pump you full of bullets right
now. and I wouIdn't even be arrested.
Everyone would lie for me.
everyone who counts.
Otherwise. all their own lies.
everything that runs Sin City.
it all comes tumbling down
like a pack of cards.
But I want you firm and fit and healthy.
I'm even putting up cash of my own
to get you more surgery.
Fix that heart condition of yours.
You're gonna keep on living
a long time.
I'm gonna make sure of that.
You're gonna be convicted of raping
that littIe brat. and shooting my boy.
And you're gonna spend
the rest of your life in prison.
disgraced. destroyed.
alone.
Your wife?
You tell her the truth and she's dead.
You tell anybody the truth
and they're dead.
They won't let me testify.
I toId the cops that you saved my Iife
and they just acted like I was crazy.
They talked my parents
into keeping me away.
They said that you'd done things
that you didn't do.
I told them that you saved me
from that Roark creep.
but they won't even check me out
to see that I'm still a virgin.
I'm still a virgin. still aIive.
thanks to you.
They got it all backwards.
Sometimes. the truth
doesn't matter like it ought.
But you'll always
remember things. right.
That's gonna mean a lot to me.
But stay away. Nancy.
They'll kill you if you don't stay away.
Don't visit me.
Don't write me.
Don't even say my name.
Maybe you won't let me visit.
but I'll still write to you. Hartigan.
I'll sign my letters "Cordelia."
That's the name of a really cool
detective in books I read.
I'll write you every week. for forever.
Sure. kid.
Now. run on home.
It's not safe for you here.
Bye. Nancy.
I love you.
John Hartigan.
Mr. Law and Order.
Mr. By the Book.
Mr. High and Mighty.
I gotta give you credit. being such a
straight arrow for so damn many years
without it catching up with you.
It's catching up with you now.
friend of mine.
It's catching up with you but good.
Maybe I ought to look at him.
He doesn't look too good.
He's hale and hearty. Tammy. See?
He's the picture of health.
That Tammy. there.
she's fine. isn't she?
I rented her out of Old Town.
I wanted to show you what you won't
be getting any of. not in prison.
You hear me. Hartigan?
If you stop being stupid.
start pIaying aIong with us.
you might just get some of Tammy.
You see that? She fIinched.
You make her sick.
She heard about you and that littIe girl.
This is nothing but a price i promised
myself I'd pay, and I'm paying it.
You don't save a little girl's life,
then turn around
and throw her to the dogs.
Not in my book, you don't.
They want a confession .
They won't get it.
There was a letter from Nancy waiting
when they put me in solitary.
She calls herself Cordelia.
just like she promised.
She makes no mention of anything
that would give her away.
At first, l figure
she'll send another note or two
before her young mind
moves on to better things.
But every Thursday,
another one arrives.
what a sweet kid.
I do my best to keep my hand
from shaking when l reach for it.
She's the only friend I've got,
the daughter I never had.
My sweet Cordelia.
Skinny little Nancy Callahan.
Eight years pass.
Then comes a Thursday
when I bound from my cot,
excited as a kid at Christmas.
only to find myself staring
at the damn floor of my damn cell,
looking for a letter from Nancy
that isn't there.
Then another Thursday with no letter.
Is she all right?
Did something happen to her?
Nothing.
Two months now.
not a word from Nancy.
Did they find her? Did they get to her?
Of course. Stupid old man.
Do your math . Nancy's 19 years old.
How long did you expect her
to keep writing?
She was a saint to keep it up
as long as she did.
She's forgotten you, old man.
You're alone.
You're all alone.
This guy smells awful, like bad food.
Like a corpse left in a garbage
dumpster in the middle of summer.
He stinks so bad, l want to throw up.
Practically knocked my head off,
the bastard.
when i come to. I see it.
The same kind of envelope
Nancy always uses,
but there's no letter inside of it.
There's something soft,
something that ought to be alive,
a hunk of meat and bone
that ought to be the index finger
of the right hand of a 19-year-old girl.
How the hell did they find her?
She was so careful.
She never gave away
where she lives or where she works.
I've got to get out. l've got to help her.
Nothing else matters,
not my life and not my pride, either.
It's only one final surrender they want.
You got me, Roark. You beat me.
I say everything they want to hear,
just the way they want to hear it.
I tell them l'm a twisted.
wretched child molester.
I agree to everything
they want from me.
I love you , Nancy.
It's a lot of miIes into town. Hartigan.
-You care for a ride?
-Long as you stay in front of me.
Prison's made you paranoid.
Talk about water under the bridge.
Christ.
Eight years.
Yeah. Eight years.
Well. if it's any consolation to you.
you made me hate myseIf.
-Any word from Eileen?
-Yeah.
She got remarried four years ago.
She had two kids. I'm sorry. John.
Don't be.
I'm glad.
Eileen always wanted kids.
She'll make a good mother.
Like you said. Bob.
water under the bridge.
Bob and I get on
with our fond farewells to each other.
then I go looking
for the only human being on the planet
who means a damn to me.
Nancy.
How could they have found out it was
you writing all those letters to me?
How did they find out who you are?
And what have they done to you ,
baby?
Not a sound.
No sign of life.
Has Roark gone to all this trouble
just to torture a broken old man ,
like a kid poking at a fly
when he's already torn his wings off?
what has he done to Nancy?
It's like all she ever does
is read and study and write.
No diary, no phone numbers
or addresses written down anywhere.
Closest thing to a clue is a pack
of matches from a lousy saloon .
It's a long shot, but maybe she's got
some friends there.
A dead-end.
Nancy wouldn't have anything to do
with a pack of drunks and losers
like this.
But if there's anything
to be found here.
the faintest lead to wherever Nancy is
or whoever kidnapped her
and mutilated her, this is the place.
Excuse me. Miss.
Wondering if you couId heIp me.
I'm Iooking for somebody.
CoId night like this. everybody's
looking for somebody. stranger.
It's not like that. Her name is Nancy.
Eyes to the stage. pilgrim.
She's just warming up.
Skinny little Nancy Callahan.
She grew up.
She filled out.
Nancy Callahan, 19 years old.
And here I was.
expecting a skinny little bookworm,
maybe a bit too shy for her own good.
How little she told me about herself
in all her letters for all those years.
How the hell did they find her?
Then it hits me.
They were bluffing.
I've led them straight to her.
She hasn't spotted you yet.
Turn around and walk out the door.
Lead the creep outside.
Get that Beretta away from him
somehow. and kill him.
I'm just a horny ex-con
watching an exotic dancer.
Just a few seconds and she'll be safe.
No, Nancy. Don't notice me.
Don't recognize me.
There's no time to explain.
I've made a terrible mistake.
put you in terrible danger.
We need to get out of here
right this second.
Whatever you say. Hartigan.
Let me throw some clothes on.
And here I'd figured
you'd forgotten all about me.
Me and my dumb letters.
Kept me going.
Kept me from killing myseIf.
Hurry up. will you?
Maybe I shouId drive.
Not a chance.
Nobody but me
can keep this heap running.
Besides. from the sound of things.
you might have to shoot somebody.
-I don't have a gun.
-Under the seat.
It's loaded and it works.
Yeah. this'll do.
Taken it to the range a couple of times.
Kicks like a mule.
Hartigan. there's so much
I've wanted to say to you.
You've never been far
from my thoughts.
I've lain awake nights. thinking of you.
What are you talking about?
Keep driving. Nancy. Keep driving
and keep the car on the road.
She's counting on you, old man.
What are you doing?
Prove you're still worth a damn .
Try and keep it on the road. Nancy!
He's a decent shot.
He's got skill,
but he's in too much of a hurry.
Throwing away bullets
like they were candy.
He doesn't know how to take his time.
Aim careful
and look the devil in the eye.
Stop the car. Nancy.
Gotta confirm the kill.
-What?
-Stop the car. now!
Right. Stop the car. confirm the kill.
Sorry. I got a littIe rattled.
It's okay. You did great.
Sit tight. I'll be right back.
No. Let me stay close.
Nothing can happen to me
when I'm with you.
PIease? Let me stay close.
The stink. I almost gag.
His blood smells
even worse than he does.
Jesus.
And it's all over the place.
But the creep himself, he's gone.
We're out of time.
The sirens.
I used to welcome the sound.
There's nothing to do now but
find a place to hole up for the night,
get Nancy calmed down ,
and figure out
what on Earth l'm going to do next.
The stink, somehow it stays with us
all the way to the motel.
Nancy. I went to your apartment.
Your window was thrown wide open.
The rooms looked almost empty.
That's why I was sure
you'd been kidnapped.
My window? Robbed again?
That's the third time this year.
I swore if I ever saw you again.
I'd show you I grew up strong.
But there I was. just like before.
scared and helpless.
-I'm such an asshole.
-You should sit down.
You'll feeI a little bit better
if you sit down.
I've never been
all that good with people.
when it comes to reassuring
a traumatized 19-year-old,
I'm as expert as a palsy victim doing
brain surgery with a pipe wrench .
It's aIways been you. Hartigan.
All these years.
It's just nerves
making you say that. Nancy.
You're just exhausted.
You need to sleep.
-Sleep with me.
-Stop it. Nancy.
Eight years.
Why do you think
I keep writing you those letters?
It wasn't just gratitude.
I tried to faII in Iove with boys.
Even thought I did once or twice.
But I was aIready in Iove with you.
That's enough. Jesus Christ.
I'm oId enough to be your grandfather.
-You're just scared.
-I'm not scared.
No.
There's wrong and there's wrong
and then there's this.
For God's sakes. you're just a kid.
I Iove you.
I Iove you. too.
With aII my heart.
Cold shower, it helps.
No. Nancy.
Recognize my voice. Hartigan?
Recognize my voice.
you piece of shit cop?
I Iook different.
but I bet you can recognize my voice.
Sure. I recognize your voice. Junior.
Everything's gone straight to hell.
l've been suckered
into betraying the only friend l've got,
and put her in the hands
of a murdering rapist
l thought l'd put down for good.
Suckered by a spoiled brat
son of a senator.
lt's all gone to hell.
KIump. it's me.
I got a dead man needs to be fetched.
I want you to set me up for a party.
I've aIready got the girI. you dumb shit.
Hey. it better be perfect
or I'm caIIing my dad.
My tooIs better be cIean and sharp.
It better be ready. It better be perfect.
I get to do whatever I want.
however I want. whenever I want it.
My dad. I'd Iove him if I didn't hate him.
He spent a fortune
hiring every expert on the pIanet
to grow back that equipment
you bIew off from between my Iegs.
just so the oId fart can hoId out some
kind of hope of having a grandkid.
AIthough. as you can see.
there were some side effects.
I'm not compIaining. though.
Since you've been gone.
I've been having the time of my Iife.
And now you've Ied me back
to your darIing CordeIia.
We aII wondered
who wrote aII those Ietters.
She Ieft not a cIue.
CIever girI. And so pretty. so pretty.
A IittIe oId for my taste.
but I can forgive that just this once.
Nancy. don't scream.
Whatever he does to you.
don't scream.
She'II scream.
I'm gonna take aII night
doing dear oId Nancy.
And you're gonna die knowing
that it's aII your fauIt.
They've aII screamed. Hartigan.
Dozens of them. maybe a hundred.
Eight years' worth.
Every one of them has screamed.
And if there weren't
so many peopIe hereabout.
I wouId show you how I'm gonna make
dear oId Nancy scream.
It's gonna be one heII of a show.
This is it. No way to fight it now.
No hope left.
No chance.
This is it. This is the end.
No.
Give it a shot. old man.
Keep your neck tight. Move.
The window, maybe there's an alarm.
The window.
Keep your neck tight, God damn it.
Stay conscious.
No alarm.
The glass. Cut the rope.
You can do it. You can do it.
It is incIement upon me
to comment with marked dispIeasure
on your rash impuIsiveness
in seIecting such an eye-catching
and impracticaI car to heist. Mr. ShIubb.
IrreIevant to said mission
is the foIIowing query.
which I now put forth to you.
Wherein this most streamIined
and trunkIess of transports.
boner-inspiring though it may be.
wherein are we to reposit
our recentIy deceased cargo?
I can onIy express puzzIement
that borders on aIarm.
TeII me where Roark takes the girIs
or I'II cut your damn head off.
In pIain EngIish. creep.
The answer you seek is ruraI.
even agrarian.
The farm.
That's aII I need to hear.
Every cop on the force
knows about the Roark family's farm
and to stay away from it.
Shlubb and Klump
were packing an arsenal.
Once things get loud,
l'll probably have use for the cannons.
But at first, l'll have to play it quiet.
Quiet and nasty.
Nancy's car, six miles from the farm.
"Nobody but me can keep
this heap running" , she told me.
Good girl.
The car stalled out
on that yellow bastard
and you didn't tell him
how to start it up again .
You kept your mouth shut.
l'll bet Junior was furious.
l'll bet he slapped you around
something fierce.
But you stayed strong.
You bought a few extra minutes.
There's still a chance, Nancy.
Don't scream.
l ditch the car a mile or so
from the farm
and make my way through the woods.
l'm not halfway there when it hits.
My heart. Can't be my heart.
l was cured.
Bad cough , blood in it.
Doesn't matter now.
l don't have to stay alive
that much longer, anyway.
Rotten way to kill a man , but it's quiet.
Hate yourself later.
You're onIy
making this worse for yourseIf.
you stupid cow!
Do you think I'm tired?
Is that it?
Do you think I'm getting tired?
You're the one who's gonna crack.
You'II crack.
You'II cry and beg.
You'II scream.
Oh. yeah. you'II scream.
you big. fat. ugIy cow!
You'II scream.
You're thinking the whip
was the worst I couId do?
That was forepIay.
Hartigan was right about you.
You can't get it up unIess I scream.
You're pathetic.
It's not wise at aII
to make fun of me Iike that.
It brings out the worst in me.
Stupid old man.
ln too much of a hurry.
Damn. It can't be.
Charging in like Galahad,
just like l told myself l wouldn't!
Stupid old man.
You tagged him good.
Don't take no chances.
Perforate the fooI.
Good advice.
Give it up. Junior.
It's over. Let her go.
You're dreaming. Hartigan.
I get to see your eyes whiIe I fiIIet
the woman of your dreams
right in front of you.
Look at you. You're about to keeI over.
You can't even Iift that cannon.
Sure. I can.
You gave me a scare there
for a second. oId man.
Nancy. I'm sorry.
I'm taking no chances with you.
First I soften you up.
and then it's showtime.
Here it comes.
It's gonna hurt.
You're right about that.
Sucker.
l take away his weapon .
Both of them.
Eight Iong years. son of a bitch !
After a while, all l'm doing is pounding
wet chunks of bone
into the floorboards, so l stop.
So Iong. Junior.
Been a pIeasure.
I didn't scream. Hartigan. not once.
I didn't scream.
I know it. baby.
You grew up strong.
By the time l get her to the car,
Nancy stops shaking.
Her skin is warm again .
She's herself again.
Thanks for remembering my coat.
And for aII the IittIe things.
Like saving my Iife. twice.
-You better get roIIing.
-You're not coming aIong?
No. I have friends on their way.
to coIIect evidence.
I'm gonna bIow
this whoIe sick mess wide open.
I'm gonna cIear my name.
I'm gonna put Senator Roark
behind bars where he beIongs.
I can't Iose you. not again.
You'II never Iose me. Nancy.
Nancy Callahan, the love of my life.
Shame to lie to her.
l hope she forgives me for it.
Get Senator Roark behind bars? Sure.
And maybe after
l've pulled off that miracle,
l'll go and punch out God.
There isn't a prosecutor in the state
who'll go after Senator Roark.
l killed his only son .
The bloodline is cut.
Roark's lost his goddamn legacy.
He'll use all his power
to get revenge on me.
He'll go after me through Nancy.
He'll find her again .
There'll be no end to it.
She'll never be safe.
Not as long as l'm alive.
There's only one way to beat him.
An old man dies.
a young woman lives.
Fair trade.
l love you , Nancy.
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Mom. don't go on Iike that.
It's not the city. I couId've gotten
in a traffic accident anywhere.
Yeah. just a fracture.
The doctor said it's a cIean break.
It shouId be right as rain in no time.
Uh-huh.
Mmm-hmm.
Turn the right corner in Sin City
and you can find anything.
Becky.
Care for a smoke?
Love you. too. Mom.
Anything.