NARRATOR: In the last century,
before the birth of the new
faith called Christianity,
which was destined to overthrow
the pagan tyranny of Rome
and bring about a new society,
the Roman Republic stood
at the very center of the civilized world.
"Of all things fairest,"
sang the poet,
"first among cities and home
of the gods is golden Rome".
Yet, even at the zenith
of her pride and power
the Republic lay fatally
stricken with a disease
called human slavery.
The age of the dictator
was at hand
waiting in the shadows
for the event to bring it forth.
In that same century,
in the conquered
Greek province of Thrace,
an illiterate slave woman
added to her master's wealth
by giving birth to a son
whom she named Spartacus.
A proud, rebellious son
who was sold to living death
in the mines of Libya
before
his thirteenth birthday.
There, under whip
and chain and sun,
he lived out his youth
and his young manhood,
dreaming the death of slavery
2,иии years before
it finally would die.
SOLDIER: Back to work!
Back to work!
Get up, Spartacus,
you Thracian dog!
Come on, get up!
Get up! Get...
Oh, my ankle!
My ankle!
Guard! Guard!
Spartacus again, huh?
Well, this time he dies.
Move along!
Back to work, all of you!
Welcome,
Lentulus Batiatus.
Welcome, indeed,
my dear Captain.
Oh, 11 miles through this
disastrous heat
and the cost of hiring an escort,
ruinous.
Even so, I warrant you have
nothing fit to sell me,
have you, Captain?
I've wasted both
my time and my money.
Tell me the truth.
We have a few
you might be interested in.
These? Carrion.
The buzzards are late.
This one's not bad.
He's a Gaul.
I don't like Gauls.
Hairy.
Can he come down
unassisted?
Come down,
you.
Come down!
Be good enough
to show me the teeth.
Open your mouth.
Thank you.
Yes, as the teeth go,
so go the bones.
This mouth
is really impermissible.
The fellow's
made of chalk.
We have
many others.
The sun's over there.
I have to pay these people.
Who's that?
This one's a
Thracian.
I'm making an example
of him.
How?
Starve him to death.
It's the only thing
that impresses slaves.
What a pity.
He reacts.
Good muscle tone.
Can I see
his teeth?
Open your mouth,
Spartacus.
You smell
like a rhinoceros.
Captain, the teeth.
You asked him to open his mouth.
He doesn't
obey you?
His teeth are
the best thing about him.
He hamstrung a guard with them
not more than an hour ago.
Marvelous. I wish I'd been here.
I'll take him.
Let's look
at some of the others.
Come along.
In spite of
sickness and death,
we will profit
11,000 sesterces.
Including your commission,
of course.
Oh, no, sir.
Without my commission.
Marcellus,
there they are.
They're a dirty-looking lot,
but it's the best I could find.
No one else could have made
so fine a choice.
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
Slaves,
you have arrived at the gladiatorial school
of Lentulus Batiatus.
You'll be trained
by experts
to fight in pairs
to the death.
You won't fight
to the death here.
That will be
after you've been sold
and then for ladies
and gentlemen of quality,
for those who appreciate
a fine kill.
A gladiator's like a stallion,
he must be pampered.
You'll be oiled, bathed,
shaved, massaged,
taught to use your heads.
A good body with a dull brain
is as cheap as life itself.
You'll be given
your ceremonial caudas.
Marcellus, please.
There.
Be proud of them.
On special occasions,
those who please me
will even be given the companionship
of a young lady.
Approximately
half our graduates
live for five, 10,
10 years.
Some even attain freedom
and become trainers themselves.
Marcellus.
I congratulate you.
And may fortune smile
on most of you.
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
Marcellus, watch the second
from the right.
He's a Thracian.
They were going to kill him
for hamstringing a guard.
We'll break him of that.
Don't overdo it.
He has quality.
MAN: Next.
(SHRIEKING)
Next.
I like you.
I want you
to be my friend.
I want to be
your friend.
All I ask is that
you get along with me.
What's your name,
slave?
Spartacus.
I feel
you don't like me.
Give him your sword.
Take it!
I have a feeling
you want to kill me.
This is the only chance
you'll ever get.
Kill me.
Don't be afraid,
slave.
You have
that sword.
I only have
this piece of wood.
Are you
going to disobey me?
Take his sword.
You're not as stupid
as I thought.
You might even
be intelligent.
That's dangerous for slaves.
You just remember,
from now on everything
you do I'll be watching.
You did
the right thing.
Every once in a while
Marcellus likes to kill a man as an example.
I think he's picked you.
Better watch him.
How long
have you been here?
Six months.
I wish
he'd pick me.
I want one chance at that pig before
they carry me out!
MARCELLUS: Quiet!
No talking down there.
Dionysius, you'll get us
in trouble just like in the mines.
What's your name?
You don't want to know
my name.
I don't want to know
your name.
Just
a friendly question.
Gladiators
don't make friends.
If we're ever matched
in the arena together,
I'll have to
kill you.
(DOOR OPENS)
Helena
with Galino.
Patricia,
Crixus.
Priscilla,
David.
Claudia,
Pharox.
Varinia,
Dionysius.
No, no.
Spartacus.
Felicia...
I've never
had a woman.
(MAN LAUGHING)
You have one now, Spartacus.
You must take her.
Go away.
What will she think of you?
Indeed,
what will I think of you?
Go away.
Come, come.
Be generous.
We must learn
to share our pleasures.
I'm not an animal!
You're not trying to escape,
by any chance?
Direct your courage
to the girl, Spartacus.
I'm not an animal!
I'm not an animal.
Neither am I.
What's your name?
Varinia.
You'll have to take her
out of here, Marcellus.
You may not be an animal,
Spartacus,
but this sorry show gives me little hope
that you'll ever be a man.
First rule, you get
an instant kill on the red.
Here, here.
Always remember,
go for the red first.
If you don't,
your opponent will.
In the blue,
you get a cripple.
Here, here,
here and here.
Second rule,
go for the cripple
before the slow kill.
Here's a slow kill
on the yellow.
Here, here
and here.
Remember,
a slow kill may have
enough left in him
to kill you
before he dies.
With a cripple,
you know you've got him
if you keep your distance
and wear him down.
The rest is all right
for a public spectacle in Rome,
but here at Capua
we expect more
than simple butchery
and we get it.
Spartacus, why are you
looking at that girl?
Varinia! Stand still.
(CHUCKLES)
Since all you can do
is look at girls,
all right, slave,
go ahead and look.
I said, look.
No. No, this one goes
to the Spaniard.
Have a good night's rest,
Spartacus.
(DOOR BOLTING)
MARCELLUS: In there.
(MARCELLUS LAUGHING)
(DOOR LOCKING)
Woman!
I've warned you
about this kind of thing.
All right,
bring them in.
No talking!
Move along.
Did they hurt you?
No.
MARCELLUS: That's a kill.
One, two,
three, four, five.
three, four...
We have visitors,
tremendous visitors.
Two simply enormous
Roman lords on the hill.
How easily impressed
you are, Ramon.
Just 'cause they're Romans,
I suppose they're enormous.
Tell them to wait
for me when they arrive.
Master,
you don't understand...
How enormous
do these Roman lords get?
One of them
is Marcus Licinius Crassus.
What?
Wait a minute.
Crassus here?
My red toga with the acorns.
Chairs in the atrium.
Second-best wine.
No, the best,
but small goblets.
Gracchus. You know
how Crassus loathes him.
Take him away.
I can't lift it.
Use your imagination.
Cover him.
Tell Marcellus
to get the men ready.
Crassus has expensive taste.
He'll want a show.
Forgive me, Gracchus.
Marcus
Licinius Crassus.
Most noble
radiance,
first general
of the Republic,
father and defender
of Rome, honor my house.
Bless it
with your presence.
Wine, sweetmeats!
Can't you see that
Their Honors are exhausted?
Have the goodness
to sit.
Is anything wrong,
Your Nobility?
No.
Welcome to the
Lady Claudia Maria,
former wife of
Lucius Caius Marius
whose recent execution
touched us all deeply.
Honor
to the Lady Helena,
daughter of the late
Septimus Optimus Glabrus,
whose fame shall live on
forever in the person of his son,
your brother,
Marcus
Publius Glabrus,
hero
of the Eastern War.
How very much
he knows.
Allow me to bring you
up-to-date.
We're here to celebrate the marriage
of my brother to the Lady Claudia.
A mating of eagles,
Your Sanctity.
Fan His Magnitude.
He sweats.
No, no.
My young friends desire
a private showing of two pairs.
Two pairs?
Oh, yes. I have something
that would please them.
Two pairs
to the death.
To the death,
Your Ladyship?
Surely you don't think
we came all the way to Capua
for gymnastics?
But I beg,
Your Honors,
we train the finest
gladiators in all Italy.
We can give you
a display of swordsmanship
which is better than
you can see in Rome.
When they're sold,
their new masters
may do with them
as they wish.
But here, no,
we never fight them to the death.
Crassus.
Today is
an exception.
But the ill feeling,
it would spread
through the whole school.
Then the cost.
Oh, the cost.
Name your price.
25,000 sesterces.
Arrange it.
Are you serious,
sir?
Arrange it
immediately.
Of course, we shall want
to choose them ourselves.
You do have
a certain variety?
Inexhaustible.
Spartacus, there's going to be
a fight to the death.
To the death?
How do you know?
I heard Marcellus
tell one of his guards.
Who fights?
I don't know.
To the death.
What if they matched
you and me?
They won't.
What if they did?
Would you fight?
I'd have to.
So would you.
Would you try
to kill me?
Yes, I'd kill.
I'd try to stay...
I'd try to stay alive,
and so would you.
MARCELLUS: All gladiators
up to the training area.
Some visitors
want to admire you.
Form a line in front of me.
Would Your Excellencies
care to make
your selection now?
Claudia.
Oh, they're
magnificent.
For you,
Lady Helena,
may I suggest
Praxus?
A veritable tiger.
I don't like him.
I prefer that one.
Which one?
No, no.
David?
Oh, Crixus, yes.
Ah, Marcellus,
Crixus for the short sword.
(EXCLAIMS)
Have you ever seen such a pair of shoulders?
Dionysius.
I admit he's small,
but he's very compact
and extremely strong.
In fact, he looks...
He looks smaller here
than he does in the arena.
Optical.
Give me that one.
Oh, Galino.
Yes, yes. Galino.
You have a shrewd eye,
Your Pulchritude,
if I may permit
myself the...
Galino.
Practically every man
in this school
is an expert
with a Thracian sword
but the trident is something
very rare these days.
May I suggest
the Ethiopian?
(GIGGLING)
There are very few Ethiopians
in the country.
Ethiopians are recognized
as masters of the trident.
I'll take him.
Draba? Oh, no.
For you I want the best.
I do think the Ethiopian...
I want the most beautiful.
I'll take
the big black one.
Draba.
Only one man in the entire school
stands a chance
with the Thracian knife
against the trident.
There.
Over there,
Lady Helena.
He's impertinent.
I'll take him.
And he's a coward to boot.
Have him flogged.
Over there, Lady Helena.
The beast of Libya.
I prefer
the coward.
Spartacus.
If both men are down and refuse to fight
your trainer will slit their throats.
We want no tricks.
BATIATUS: Tricks, madam?
At the school of Batiatus?
You heard the instruction,
Marcellus? Remember it.
I feel sorry for the poor things
in this heat.
Don't put them
in those suffocating tunics.
Let them wear just
enough for modesty.
Whatever they wear, Lady,
they'll bless your name.
MARCELLUS:
Back, the rest of you.
Our choosing
has bored you?
No, most exciting.
I tingle.
Do let's get out
of the sun.
May I conduct Your Magnificences
to the gallery?
An eavesdropper.
Oh, the gods.
(ALL LAUGHING)
How far from Rome must I go to avoid
that cunning face?
Don't talk about Gracchus.
He's so hateful.
For Gracchus, hatred
of the patrician class is a profession
and not such
a bad one, either.
How else
can one become
master of the mob
and first senator of Rome?
Crassus,
it's so boring.
I believe that girl
smells of perfume.
GLABRUS: Whatever it is,
she smells most delectable.
You can't keep slaves from stealing
unless you chain them.
CLAUDIA: When a slave's as pretty as she is,
she doesn't have to steal.
An arrangement is made.
If her ankles
are good,
you can be sure
an arrangement was made.
Oh, master!
BATIATUS: A catastrophe.
I've been anointed.
Why, you trollop!
You did that on purpose.
It was an accident.
Come here, girl.
Don't be frightened.
What country
are you from?
Britannia.
How long
have you been a slave?
Since I was 13.
You have
a certain education.
My first master had me tutored
for his children.
I like her.
She has spirit.
I'll buy her.
BATIATUS: Buy her,
Your Magnificence?
I have spent quite
a lot of money on her.
I've no doubt of it.
2,000 sesterces.
She'll be waiting
at your litter.
No, I don't want her
feet spoiled by walking.
Send her to Rome with your steward
the next time he has to go there.
He leaves tomorrow,
and the girl with him.
More wine,
and thank your gods.
You provoke me, Crassus.
I shan't be nice to you anymore.
Why distress me
so much?
You're horribly rich, yet you're the only one
of my brother's friends
who hasn't given him
a wedding present.
I was saving it
for a more suitable moment.
Here.
Give it to him, child.
What is it?
As from this moment, your husband
is commander of the garrison of Rome.
Wonderful.
(HELENA CLAPPING)
I don't know how
I shall ever be able to repay you.
Time will solve
that mystery.
The garrison of Rome.
CRASSUS: Yes.
The only power in Rome strong enough
to checkmate Gracchus and his Senate.
You are clever.
Open up.
Through that door.
(WOMAN GIGGLING)
You will have to
watch him, Claudia.
Father almost disinherited him
because of slave girls.
The marriage contract
absolutely forbids a harem.
GLABRUS: What about
your litter bearers?
Every one of them is under 20 and taller
than they should be.
CRASSUS: She sets rather
a high standard for you.
BATIATUS:
Your pleasure, Your Highness.
CRASSUS:
To you, my dear,
shall go the honor of starting
this poetic drama.
MARCELLUS: Open up.
First pair!
Crixus and Galino!
Those who are about
to die salute you.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(GLADIATORS GRUNTING)
(SWORDS CLASHING)
(CRASHING)
(GLADIATOR SCREAMING)
(AUDIENCE CLAPPING)
Crixus.
Next pair!
Those who are about
to die salute you.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Your Thracian's
doing well.
How were you able to get my appointment
without Gracchus knowing?
I fought fire
with oil.
I purchased the Senate
behind his back.
I still think the trident's
going to win.
CLAUDIA:
Why doesn't he kill him?
HELENA: Kill him.
What's the matter now?
Kill him!
Kill him,
you imbecile!
Kill him!
(WOMEN EXCLAIMING)
He'll hang there
till he rots.
Take a last look,
Spartacus.
She's going to Rome.
She's been sold.
She's been sold?
No talking
in the kitchen, slave.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
There's trouble
in the mess hall.
They killed Marcellus
and maybe the other two.
Call out the guard.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Move, move.
On second thoughts,
I'll deliver the girl personally.
Ride to Capua.
Call out the garrison. I don't trust this lot.
I hold you
responsible.
Yes, sir.
(ALL YELLING)
(GLADIATORS CHEERING)
Around Capua,
they ravaged the countryside,
forcing other slaves
to join them.
Looting, robbing,
burning everything,
while they make
their camp
in the escarpments
of Vesuvius.
Each day
swells their numbers.
The situation lies
in the hands
of this august body.
(SENATORS MURMURING)
Where's
the mighty Crassus?
Out of the city.
At least, you're here.
No need to fear for Rome
as long as Glabrus is with us.
Let me add,
over 100 estates have been burned.
Among them,
gentlemen, my own.
Burned to the ground
and 3 million sesterces lost.
I propose the immediate recall
of Pompey and his legions from Spain.
(WHISPERING) I could raise 500 men
and bring the lot of them in.
(WHISPERING)
Don't make a fool of yourself.
Why call back the legions
when the garrison of Rome
has nothing to do
but to defend us
from sausage makers?
Let's send Glabrus
against these scoundrels.
Give them a taste
of Roman steel.
(SENATORS CLAPPING)
I protest.
I most strongly protest.
There are more slaves
in Rome than Romans.
With the garrison absent,
what's to prevent them
from rising, too?
I did not say
the whole garrison.
Six cohorts
will more than do the job.
The rest can stay in Rome
to save you
from your housemaids.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
Will you accept
such a charge, Glabrus?
I accept the charge of the Senate,
if the Senate truly charges me.
The garrison of Rome
stands ready.
Slave hunting's
a dirty business.
It takes a brave commander
to consent to it.
I propose we turn
the city out tomorrow
in tribute to Glabrus
as he marches through.
And for temporary command
of the garrison during his absence,
I propose
Caius Julius Caesar.
(SENATORS MURMURING)
You don't look very happy
over the newjob.
It's not a serious disturbance.
Glabrus will be back.
Maybe.
At least
it gives me a chance
to separate Glabrus
from Crassus for a while.
You know,
this Republic of ours
is something like a rich widow.
Most Romans
love her as their mother.
But Crassus dreams of marrying the old girl,
to put it politely.
Hail Glabrus.
Hail Glabrus!
God be with you,
Glabrus.
And with you,
too.
I hope he returns
to such applause.
Oh, one fat one,
Fimbria.
(CLUCKING)
Keep the change.
Give it to your wife.
May the gods
adore you.
Only through
your prayers.
Let's make an old-fashioned sacrifice
for Glabrus' success, hmm?
I thought you had reservations
about the gods.
Privately, I believe in none.
Neither do you.
Publicly,
I believe in them all.
Greetings,
Marcus Clodius Flavius!
Is Marcus Glabrus
in attendance?
He awaits you
in the atrium, sir.
Excellent.
What have we here?
A gift from
the Governor of Sicily.
"Antoninus.
Sicilian, age 26,
"singer of songs".
For whom did you practice
this wondrous talent?
For the children of my master
whom I also taught the classics.
Classics, indeed.
What position have we,
I wonder, for a boy of such varied gifts?
You shall be my body servant.
Instruct him.
All of you,
come with me.
CRASSUS:
Are you on guard duty?
My dear Crassus,
congratulate me.
Or better still,
let us congratulate each other.
I congratulate us.
Tomorrow I lead six cohorts of the garrison
against the slaves on Vesuvius.
The whole city
is turning out to see us off.
Great merciful
bloodstained gods!
Your pardon.
I always address heaven
in moments of triumph.
Did Gracchus have something to do
with this brilliant affair?
Yes, he proposed it.
Rather decently, too.
And you?
Do you think I made you commander
to control some rock patch on Vesuvius?
It was to control
the streets of Rome!
I only take six cohorts.
The rest of the garrison remain.
Under whose command?
Under Caesar's.
Oh, excellent,
excellent.
Finding Gracchus in control
of the mob and the Senate,
you felt impelled to hand over
the garrison to him also.
I see.
I'll refuse,
withdraw from the expedition.
One of the disadvantages
of being a patrician
is that occasionally
you're obliged to act like one.
You've pledged to go,
and go you must.
If Gracchus should decide
to move against you...
He won't!
Has no need to.
He has, with your assistance,
immobilized me altogether.
Your legions are in camp
outside the city walls?
My legions?
Do you truly believe
I'd order my legions to enter Rome?
You can, if you have to.
Are you not aware
of Rome's most ancient law,
that no general may enter the city
at the head of his armed legions?
Sulla did.
Sulla?
To the infamy
of his name!
To the utter damnation
of his line!
No, my young friend.
One day I shall cleanse this Rome which
my fathers bequeathed me.
I shall restore all the traditions
that made her great.
It follows that
I cannot come to power or defend myself
by an act which betrays
the most sacred tradition of all.
I shall not bring my legions
within these walls.
I shall not violate Rome
at the moment
of possessing her.
Go.
Prepare your troops
at once.
March out of Rome tonight,
but the tribute is impossible.
We've already been made to look a fool.
Let's not add the trappings of a clown.
Leave by unfrequented streets
without fanfare, without even a drum.
Sneak out.
As you wish.
And for heaven's sake,
my young friend,
see to it that you don't
have to sneak back again.
Farewell.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
Come on,
fat boy!
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN 1: Spartacus, come on!
MAN 2: Come on!
Noble Romans.
Fighting each other
like animals.
Your new masters,
betting to see who'll die first.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Drop your swords.
No! No!
(ALL SHOUTING)
I want to see their blood
here where Draba died!
When I fight matched pairs,
they fight to the death.
I made myself a promise,
Crixus.
I swore that if I ever
got out of this place,
I'd die before
I'd watch two men fight to the death again.
Draba made that promise,
too.
He kept it.
So will I.
Go on. Get out!
What are we,
Crixus?
What are we becoming?
Romans?
Have we learned nothing?
What's happening to us?
We look for wine when
we should be hunting bread.
When you've got wine,
you don't need bread!
(ALL LAUGHING)
We can't just be a gang
of drunken raiders.
What else
can we be?
Gladiators.
An army of gladiators.
There's never been
an army like that.
One gladiator's worth
any two Roman soldiers.
We beat the Roman guards here,
but a Roman army's different.
They fight different.
We can beat anything
they send against us if we want to.
MAN: It takes a big army.
We'll have
a big army.
Once we're on the march, we'll free every slave
in every town and village.
Can anybody
get a bigger army?
Once we cross the Alps,
we're safe.
Nobody can cross the Alps.
Every pass is defended by its own legion.
There's only one way
to get out of this country.
The sea.
What good is the sea
if you have no ships?
The Cilician pirates
have ships.
They're at war
with Rome.
Every Roman galley that sails out
of Brundusium pays tribute.
They've got the biggest fleet in the world.
I was a galley slave with them.
Give them enough gold,
they'll take you anywhere.
MAN: We haven't got
enough gold.
Take every Roman we capture
and warm his back a little.
We'll have gold all right.
(MAN LAUGHING)
Spartacus is right!
Let's hire these pirates
and march straight to Brundusium!
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN: Come join us.
All of you, come join us.
Come on
and join us!
Come on!
Hey!
Back to Vesuvius!
Varinia.
I thought
I'd never see you again.
Everything's so different.
The last time I saw you,
you...
You were waiting
in the arena to...
I... I thought
you were in Rome.
How'd you escape?
I...
I jumped out of the cart
and Batiatus was so fat...
I flew out of the cart
and Batiatus
was so fat
that he couldn't
catch me.
He couldn't
catch up with me.
Do you realize
nobody can ever
sell you again?
Nobody can sell you.
Or give you away.
Nobody can ever
make you stay with anyone.
Nobody can make you
stay with anybody.
Oh, I love you,
Spartacus.
I love you.
I love you. I love you.
I still can't believe it.
Forbid me
ever to leave you.
I do forbid you.
I forbid you.
It was funny
at the time.
How good you are to me,
if I may say so.
You may.
Thank you.
Don't just eye those birds.
Eat them.
There's no need to be on your
best behavior here.
May I remind you you've been good
to me in the past.
I've been good to you?
Oh, ho, ho.
Oh, yes.
You've sold me slaves
at an extremely reasonable price.
And you arranged gladiatorial
jousts at cost, practically.
You are both
ethical in business
and certainly
farsighted socially.
Zenobia's put on weight
since I last saw her.
Hasn't she?
I like it.
So do I.
You and I have a tendency
towards corpulence.
Corpulence makes a man reasonable,
pleasant and phlegmatic.
Have you noticed the nastiest of tyrants
are invariably thin?
In spite of your vices,
you are the most generous Roman of our time.
Vices?
Ladies.
Ladies?
Since when are they a vice?
Perhaps I used the wrong word.
An eccentricity, a foible.
I hope I pronounced
that word...
It's well-known that even your groom
and butler are women.
I'm the most virtuous man
in Rome.
I keep these women out of my respect
for Roman morality.
That morality which
has made Rome strong enough
to steal two-thirds of the world
from its rightful owners,
founded on the sanctity
of Roman marriage and family.
I happen to like women.
I have a promiscuous nature
and unlike these aristocrats,
I will not take a marriage vow
which my nature
will prevent me from keeping.
You have too great a respect
for the purity of womankind.
Exactly.
It must be tantalizing to be surrounded
by so much purity.
It is.
Let's mix business with pleasure.
How may I help you?
Great Gracchus,
I find it difficult to hate,
but there's one man
I can't think of without fuming.
Who's that?
Crassus.
You've grown
very ambitious in your hatred.
Do you blame me? There I was,
better than a millionaire in the morning
and a penniless refugee by nightfall
with nothing but rags and my flesh.
All because Crassus decides
to break his journey at Capua
with a couple of capricious,
over-painted nymphs.
These two daughters of Venus
had to taunt the gladiators,
force them to fight to the death,
and before I knew what had happened,
revolution on my hands.
What revenge have you in mind?
I sold Crassus
this woman Varinia.
Whom?
Varinia. May the gods
give her wings.
There was no contract,
but she was clearly his slave
as soon as the deal was made.
Now she's off with Spartacus
killing people in their beds.
And Crassus,
no mention of money.
You never offered me
this woman. Why not?
Well, she's not
remotely your type, Gracchus.
She is very thin and...
Look around you.
You'll see women
of all sizes.
Well, yes.
500 sesterces deposit
on Varinia.
Since he hasn't paid, this gives me first
call over Crassus when she's caught.
May the gods adore you.
Why do you buy a woman
you've never seen?
To annoy Crassus, of course,
and help you.
Fetch a stool,
Antoninus.
In here with it.
That will do.
Do you steal,
Antoninus?
No, master.
Do you lie?
Not if
I can avoid it.
Have you ever
dishonored the gods?
No, master.
Do you refrain from these vices
out of respect for the moral virtues?
Yes, master.
Do you eat
oysters?
When I have them,
master.
Do you eat
snails?
No, master.
Do you consider
the eating of oysters to be moral
and the eating of snails
to be immoral?
No, master.
Of course not.
It is all a matter
of taste, isn't it?
Yes, master.
And taste is not
the same as appetite
and therefore not a question
of morals, is it?
Hmm?
It could be
argued so, master.
That will do.
My robe, Antoninus.
My taste
includes
both snails
and oysters.
Antoninus, look.
Across the river.
There is something
you must see.
There, boy,
is Rome.
The might,
the majesty,
the terror of Rome.
There is the power that bestrides the known
world like a colossus.
No man
can withstand Rome.
No nation
can withstand her.
How much less
a boy?
Hmm?
(CHUCKLING)
There's only one way
to deal with Rome, Antoninus.
You must serve her.
You must abase yourself
before her.
You must grovel at her feet.
You must love her.
Isn't that so, Antoninus?
Antoninus!
Antoninus?
Take your time!
How are they coming?
Good.
Give me another thousand like them
and we can march on Rome.
Come on,
once again.
(CRYING)
Here, on Vesuvius, we're safe from attack
while we organize ourselves into an army.
It may take six months,
a year.
Once we're strong, we're gonna fight
our way south to the sea.
We're going to arrange
for ships with the Cilician pirates.
The sea will be
our road home.
If you agree,
you may join us.
If you don't agree,
go back before your escape is discovered.
Too many women.
What's wrong
with women?
Where would you be now,
you lout,
if some woman hadn't fought
all the pains of hell
to get you into
this accursed world?
I can handle a knife in the dark
as well as anyone.
I can cast spells
and brew poisons.
I have made the death shrouds
for seven Roman masters.
(WOMAN CHATTERING)
I want to see
Spartacus.
All right, grandmother.
I'm Spartacus.
Stay with us.
We'll need a million Roman shrouds
before we're through.
Where do you
come from?
Most of us come
from the estate of Lillius.
What kind of work
did you do there?
Sixteen years a carpenter,
a mason.
Good.
We can use carpenters.
What kind of work
did you do?
Chief steward.
You'll help with the food supplies.
Report to Patullus.
What kind of work
did you do?
Singer of songs.
Singer of songs?
But what work
did you do?
That's my work.
I also juggle.
Juggle.
What else do you do?
I can do
feats of magic.
Magic?
Maybe he can make
the Romans disappear.
(LAUGHING)
I'll need one volunteer,
man or woman.
How about you?
You, sir?
Here we have
a likely subject.
You'll notice there is nothing
in my hand, true?
How many fingers do you see?
Three.
How many fingers
do you see?
Three.
I make a bowl.
My hand is upside down
and I ask you to blow at it.
Not hard enough.
Hard!
Thank you.
(BIRD CHIRPING)
ANTONINUS:
Would you like to try?
Hit it against the rock,
gently.
(CHICK CHIRPING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Poet, I haven't had
an egg in days.
You haven't?
Here.
Thank you.
I'm not going to
let mine get away.
(ALL LAUGHING)
MAN: Sing us a song.
Sing us a song,
Antoninus.
MAN 2: Sing, Antoninus.
ANTONINUS: When the blazing sun hangs low
in the western sky,
when the wind dies away
on the mountain,
when the song
of the meadowlark turns still,
when the field locust clicks
no more in the field,
and the sea foam
sleeps like a maiden at rest,
and twilight touches the shape
of the wondering earth,
I turn home.
Through blue shadows
and purple woods,
I turn home.
I turn to the place
that I was born,
to the mother who bore me
and the father who taught me,
long ago, long ago, long ago.
Alone am I now, lost and alone in a far,
wide, wondering world.
Yet still when the blazing sun
hangs low,
when the wind dies away
and the sea foam sleeps,
and twilight touches
the wondering earth,
I turn home.
Where'd you
learn that song?
My father
taught it to me.
I was wrong
about you, poet.
You won't learn to kill.
You'll teach us songs.
I came here to fight.
Anyone
can learn to fight.
ANTONINUS:
I joined to fight.
What's your name?
Antoninus.
There's a time for fighting
and a time for singing.
Now you
teach us to sing.
Sing, Antoninus.
ANTONINUS: When the blazing sun
hangs low in the western sky...
You like him,
don't you?
Who wants to fight?
An animal
can learn to fight.
But to sing
beautiful things
and make people
believe them...
Hmm.
What are you
thinking about?
I'm free.
And what do I know?
I don't even know
how to read.
You know things
that can't be taught.
I know nothing.
Nothing.
And I want to know.
I want to...
I want to know.
Know what?
Everything.
Why a star falls
and a bird doesn't.
Where the sun
goes at night.
Why the moon
changes shape.
I want to know
where the wind comes from.
The wind
begins in a cave.
Far to the north,
a young god sleeps in that cave.
He dreams of a girl
and he sighs,
and the night wind
stirs with his breath.
(CHUCKLES)
I want to know
all about you.
Every line,
every curve.
I want to know
every part of you.
Every beat
of your heart.
Go on about
the city of Metapontum.
What garrisons
will we find there?
There are two legions in the garrison.
Some have been sent south...
MAN:
Set the litter down there.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Well, where is this
slave general?
Dionysius, get the litter bearers
out of the rain.
Give them food,
a bed and their freedom.
DIONYSIUS:
All right, follow me.
We'll pay you
for them.
We have no slaves
in this camp.
Tigranes Levantus
at your service.
My credentials.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
Come in.
"To the General of the Italian slaves
called Spartacus
"from lbar M'hali,
Cilician Governor of Delos".
Sit down.
"Greetings.
"Word has been received that you wish
to embark your armies on the Cilician ships
"from the Italian port
of Brundusium.
"Receive my agent,
Tigranes..."
Levantus.
"...who bargains
in my name.
"May Isis and Serapis
bring victory to your cause.
"The Governor of Delos".
Who are
Isis and Serapis?
Gods of the East.
Why should they
want us to win?
Because
they favor Cilicia,
and Cilicia, like you,
fights against the Romans.
Would you like
some wine?
I drink only after the bargain
has been concluded, never before.
How many ships
do these Cilicians have?
Five hundred, at least.
But no deal is too small,
I assure you.
SPARTACUS:
We'll need them all.
All?
What is the price?
Price is
100,000 sesterces per ship.
For 500 ships,
that would be
50 million sesterces.
You have such a sum?
We will have.
See for yourself.
Beautiful.
When will the ships
be ready?
Beautiful.
I love to see
such beauty.
When will the ships
be ready?
Ah, my friend,
when will you be ready?
How long
will it take you
to cross one-third the length of Italy
fighting a major battle in every town?
One year?
Two years?
If we're not in Brundusium seven months
from now, we'll never be there.
LEVANTUS: What if we
assemble the ships,
and there is no longer
a slave army to board them?
We'll give you a chest of treasure now,
the rest when we get to Brundusium.
This one?
Yes.
Done!
Seven months from now
the ships will be assembled.
Arrange to have
the chest loaded.
And now,
with your permission,
I should like to have
the wine you offered me.
Will you join me?
I will.
Excellent workmanship.
It came from the estate
of a wealthy nobleman.
I've heard that you are
of noble birth yourself.
I'm the son
and grandson of slaves.
I knew that,
when I saw you couldn't read.
Of course, it pleases Roman vanity
to think that you are noble.
They shrink from the idea
of fighting mere slaves,
especially a man
like Crassus.
You know him?
I entertained him
one afternoon.
You?
In the arena.
Excellent wine.
May I...
May I ask you something?
You can ask.
Surely you know you're going to lose,
don't you?
You have no chance.
At this very moment,
six cohorts of the garrison of Rome
are approaching
this position.
What are you going to do?
We'll decide that
when they get here.
Let me put it differently.
If you looked into
a magic crystal
and you saw your army
destroyed and yourself dead,
if you saw that in the future,
as I'm sure you're seeing it now,
would you continue to fight?
Yes.
Knowing that you must lose?
Knowing we can't.
All men lose
when they die.
And all men die, but a slave
and a free man lose different things.
They both lose life.
When a free man dies,
he loses the pleasure of life.
A slave loses his pain.
Death is the only freedom
a slave knows.
That's why
he's not afraid of it.
That's why we'll win.
ANTONINUS: Spartacus,
that pirate was right.
The garrison of Rome,
they're setting up camp.
How many are there?
About six cohorts.
Where?
At the mouth of the valley,
against the cliffs.
Strong camp?
They've built
no stockade.
No stockade?
Are you sure?
I'm very sure.
This campaign
is great sport for them.
The Romans
are having a picnic.
Did they see you?
No. We were hidden.
Maybe we ought to join
this Roman picnic.
Form your men.
Six cohorts.
A lot of arms and weapons
to build our army with.
Crixus always wanted
to march on Rome.
Now he doesn't have to.
Rome's come to us.
(MAN SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Half this way!
The rest over there.
Stand up, the way
a noble Roman should!
MAN: That's Roman pride
for you!
(ALL LAUGHING)
That's better.
What's your name?
Marcus Glabrus.
Glabrus.
Commander
of the garrison of Rome.
Commander?
He was commanding it on his belly
when we found him, playing dead!
(ALL LAUGH)
You disappoint me,
Marcus Glabrus.
Playing dead.
You afraid to die?
It's easy to die.
Haven't you seen enough gladiators
in the arena
to see
how easy it is to die?
Of course you have.
What are you...
What are you
going to do to me?
I don't know.
What should we
do with him?
Let's have a matched pair,
him and me.
(ALL CHEERING)
I'll not fight
like a gladiator!
(ALL JEERING)
You keep staring at this.
Do you recognize
this baton?
Yes!
You should!
It was in your tent.
The symbol
of the Senate.
All the power
of Rome!
That's the power
Take that back
to your Senate.
Tell them you and that broken stick
is all that's left of the garrison of Rome!
Tell them we want
nothing from Rome.
Nothing,
except our freedom!
All we want is to get out
of this damn country!
We're marching south
to the sea.
And we'll smash every army
they send against us.
Put him on a horse!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Their leader said
their hatred of Rome was such
that all they wished
was to escape from her rule.
If unopposed, he promised
a peaceful march to the sea.
If opposed, he threatens
to ravage the countryside
and destroy every legion
sent against him.
SENATOR: And once they
get to the sea?
They plan to take ship with Cilician pirates
and return to their homes.
From which port
do they propose to embark?
I don't know.
But city garrisons
can't stand up to them.
If they are to be intercepted,
it's work for the legions!
What sort of a man
is this leader of the slaves?
I don't know.
I think
they called him Spartacus.
Spartacus.
Is that name
familiar to you?
Yes, it does
seem to be.
I can't place it.
After he talked to you,
what happened?
I was tied to a horse
and lashed out of camp.
How many of your company
escaped?
Fourteen
have reported thus far.
I, myself, was taken prisoner
in my own command tent.
The camp was thoroughly infiltrated before
an alarm could be sounded.
Did you surround your camp
with moat and stockade?
No.
(ALL MURMURING)
We arrived after sunset.
Sentries were posted every 10 paces.
There was no reason
to expect an attack by night.
Then again,
well, they...
Continue.
They were only slaves.
I see.
I submit that Publius Marcus Glabrus
has disgraced the arms of Rome.
Let the punishment
of the Senate be pronounced.
(SENATORS MURMURING)
If we punished every commander
who made a fool of himself,
we wouldn't have anyone left
above the rank of centurion.
(SENATORS LAUGHING)
But this is a case
of criminal carelessness!
Six cohorts
have been slaughtered.
Crassus sponsored this young man.
Let him pronounce sentence.
The punishment
is well-known!
Let Publius Marcus Glabrus be denied fire,
water, food and shelter
for a distance of 400 miles
in all directions from the city of Rome.
(SENATORS MURMURING)
One thing more.
Glabrus is my friend and I will not dissociate
myself from his disgrace.
I now lay down the command of my legions
and retire to private life.
(SENATORS CHATTERING)
Goodbye, Crassus.
This is no time for a man of honor
to withdraw from public affairs!
All: Shame, shame!
SENATOR: Sit down.
GRACCHUS: This sort of heroic
public behavior is nothing new.
I've seen it before,
and I know the meaning of it.
Crassus acted
on a point of honor!
Patrician honor!
No matter how noble
this looks from the outside,
I don't like
the color of it.
Crassus is
the only man in Rome
who hasn't yielded to republican corruption
and never will!
I'll take a little republican corruption
along with a little republican freedom
but I won't take
the dictatorship of Crassus
and no freedom at all!
(ALL SENATORS APPLAUDING)
That's what he's out for
and that's why he'll be back.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(THUNDER CRACKING)
To the mother
that bore me,
to the father
that taught me,
to the god...
To the blue woods
and the purple shadows, I...
To blue shadows
and purple woods.
Spartacus,
you frightened me!
SPARTACUS: I'm sorry.
(COUGHS)
How long
have you been there?
A little while.
Why didn't you
say something?
You seemed so happy.
I didn't want to bother you.
I am happy.
Spartacus, I've been trying to remember
the song that Antoninus sang.
Is it blue shadows and purple woods,
or is it purple woods and blue shadows?
I want to make love
to my wife!
Spartacus, put me down.
I'm dripping!
I don't care.
You've got, you've...
Yes?
You have to be gentle
with me.
Why?
Why, darling?
I'm going to have a baby.
Now put me down.
What?
A baby.
A baby? When?
In the spring.
Well, how? I mean,
how do you know?
I know.
A baby in the spring.
I'm gonna have a son.
It might be a daughter.
Why didn't you tell me?
I just did.
You're cold.
Here, get underneath this.
Did I hurt you?
No, you didn't.
I didn't mean
to be so rough.
Why don't you kiss me?
This is the first time
I was ever going to have a baby.
Varinia.
A baby.
I'm just the same
as I ever was, Spartacus.
I won't break.
SENATOR: These slaves have already cost us
a thousand million sesterces.
If now they want to relieve us
of their unwelcome presence,
let them go!
Lmpossible.
They've infected half of Italy
with this uprising.
If we permit them
to escape,
this will spread
throughout the entire empire.
(SENATORS MURMURING)
The Republic
is still weak
from 20 years of civil strife.
We're engaged
in two wars,
one in Spain
and the other in Asia.
Pirates have cut off
our Egyptian grain supply,
and Spartacus raids the commerce
of all south Italy.
Half the precincts of Rome
are without bread!
The city is
close to panic.
There are two things
we must do immediately!
Confirm Caesar as permanent commander
of the garrison
(SENATORS APPLAUDING)
And...
And assign two legions
to intercept and destroy Spartacus
at the city of Metapontum!
(CROWD CHEERING)
If we could only have had Batiatus
in the other pot!
Now you're talking!
Varinia, wonderful meal.
Varinia.
A small piece of land
with a few goats on it.
Oh, no, no.
MAN 1: I don't care.
MAN 2: The best wine
in the world.
MAN 3:For wine,
you've got to go to Aquitania.
(MEN CHATTERING)
Come to Lidya for wine.
That's the best.
The best wine
comes from Greece.
Everybody knows that,
even the Romans!
No, Lidya!
(ALL CHATTERING)
You're all wrong!
The best wine comes from home,
wherever it is.
I agree with you.
Gentlemen.
Any reports
on Metapontum?
Heralds are crying
the news now.
We lost 10,000 men,
including Commodius and his officers.
Nineteen thousand?
Have you estates
in Metapontum?
No.
A son with Commodius.
With your permission,
good day.
We take five years
to train a legion.
How can this Spartacus
train an army in seven months?
There's something wrong,
something very wrong.
We should have
an investigation.
By all means,
Where is
Spartacus now?
He's nearing
the seaport of Brundusium.
I need a few moments
of the Commander's time.
Will you excuse us?
I hear you've taken a house
in the fourth ward.
Not a very
splendid house.
And you feasted 11,000 plebeians
in the Field of Mars.
It scarcely could've been
called a feast.
For 200 years, your family and mine
have been members
of the Equestrian Order
and the Patrician Party,
servants and rulers
of Rome.
Why have you left us
for Gracchus and the mob?
I've left no one,
least of all Rome.
But this much I've learned from Gracchus,
Rome is the mob.
No!
Rome is an eternal thought
in the mind of God.
I had no idea
you'd grown religious.
That doesn't matter.
If there were no gods at all,
I'd revere them.
If there were no Rome,
I'd dream of her
as I want you
to do.
I want you to come back
to your own kind.
I beg you to.
Is it me you want,
or is it the garrison?
Both.
Tell me frankly.
If you were I,
would you take the field against Spartacus?
Of course.
Why?
We have no other choice
if we're to save Rome.
Ah, Caesar!
Which Rome?
Theirs
or ours?
You know Gracchus
is my friend.
I won't betray him.
Caesar?
Which is worse?
To betray a friend or betray Rome herself?
My dear Crassus,
I face no such choice.
You will,
sooner than you think.
Good afternoon, Crassus.
I've been looking for you.
Your new master.
The Senate's been in session
all day over this business with Spartacus.
We've got eight legions
and no one to lead them.
The minute you offer
the general's command,
they start wheezing
like winded mules.
I've seen such epidemics before,
haven't you?
How's your health?
Excellent, as you
very well know.
I take it the Senate's
now offering the command to me.
You've been
expecting it.
I have.
Have you thought how costly
my services might be?
We buy everything else
these days.
No reason why we shouldn't be charged
for patriotism.
What's your fee?
My election as First Consul,
command of all the legions of Italy,
and the abolition of senatorial authority
over the courts.
Dictatorship.
Order.
Let me know if my terms
are acceptable.
I can tell you now.
They're unacceptable.
For the present, perhaps,
but times change and so does the Senate.
When that day comes,
I shall be ready.
Convey my respects
to your wife.
With pleasure.
He's right,
you know.
If something isn't done about Spartacus,
the Senate will change.
And Crassus will save Rome
from the slave army by assuming dictatorship.
But that depends on which way
Spartacus jumps.
Just now he's trying
to get out of Italy.
If he succeeds,
the crisis is over
and Crassus may stay
in retirement indefinitely.
I've arranged for Spartacus
to escape from Italy.
What?
I've made a little deal
with the Cilician pirates.
I've assured them
that we won't interfere
if they transport
Spartacus and his slaves out of Italy.
So now we
deal with pirates.
We bargain with criminals.
Don't be so stiff-necked.
Politics is a practical profession.
If a criminal has what you want,
you do business with him.
How far are we
from Brundusium?
About
20 miles.
Our army will camp here tonight.
They're six hours behind us.
Patullus, ride ahead to Brundusium.
Bring Tigranes here.
Marco, report back
to Spartacus.
Tell him we camp tonight
by the sea!
(ALL CHEERING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
If all goes well,
we can load
150 ships a day.
That's your job, Dionysius.
Work with the Cilician pirates.
That ought to
keep him busy.
Saves me finding
someplace to sleep.
Crixus, keep giving me
reports on Pompey.
There won't be
any surprises.
I still want patrols up to the time
we call them to board ship.
I'll get them together.
Spartacus,
the harbor district in Brundusium
has food warehouses,
but not enough to provide
for the whole fleet.
The countryside's
filled with cattle.
We've salt
to preserve them.
I'll handle it.
Find out how many men we have in camp
who were galley slaves or sailors.
Tigranes Levantus.
Ah!
My dear General.
Welcome, Tigranes.
No, no. You needn't look for litter bearers
to emancipate. I rode a horse.
Your gods, Isis and Serapis
must've been good to us.
The balance of the 50 million
sesterces we owe you.
General, I...
I bear a heavy burden
of evil tidings.
What is it?
Pompey and his army
has landed in Italy.
At the port of Rhegium
three days ago.
We get complete reports
on their movements.
But do you also know
that a Roman fleet
carrying Lucullus and his army
arrives tomorrow
at Brundusium?
Lucullus, here?
You have no ships.
I saw them in the harbor.
The Cilician fleet,
out of strategic necessity,
has been obliged
to withdraw.
Withdraw?
There are
no ships at all?
Cilician pirates can destroy
any Roman fleet that ever sailed.
If they run away now,
it's not because they're afraid!
You better give me
a better reason.
I'm as desolated
as you are, General.
Stand up. Up!
On your toes.
You'll cut the skin.
Why did the Cilicians
run away?
They were paid.
And who paid them?
Who?
Crassus.
(GASPS)
Crassus won't
fight us himself.
The reports say he won't take
the command of an army.
Why would he bribe your pirates
to keep us from escaping?
I don't know.
How can I answer, when there is no answer?
I've been betrayed just as you have.
There is an answer.
There must be an answer
to everything.
Five miles
from Brundusium.
Here's Rhegium.
Pompey's march must've brought him
to about here.
He's four days away,
maybe more.
Lucullus lands
at Brundusium tomorrow.
If we engage Lucullus,
Pompey will have time
to march against our rear.
If we turn west
to meet Pompey,
Lucullus will march
against our rear.
The only other army
in all of Italy is here.
Rome.
Yes, of course!
Crassus is inviting us
to march on Rome,
so he can take the field
against us.
Crassus wants us
to march on Rome?
He's forcing us to.
He knows I won't let myself be trapped between
two armies with my back to the sea.
He knows my only
other choice is Rome.
Somewhere on the way,
we meet.
If he beats us,
he becomes the savior of Rome,
and there's his final victory
over the Senate.
General, allow me to redeem myself
in your eyes.
For a small commission,
I can arrange for you,
your family and your leaders, of course,
to be smuggled out of Italy and transported
to one of the eastern countries
where men like you are welcome
and appreciated.
You can live like kings
for the rest of your lives.
What do you think,
General?
Go away.
Go away?
Tell the trumpeters
to sound assembly.
Tonight, a Roman army lands
in the harbor of Brundusium.
Another army is approaching us
from the west.
Between them, they hope to trap us here,
against the sea.
The Cilician pirates have betrayed us.
We have no ships.
"By order of the Senate
"be it known that we have
this day elected
"Marcus Licinius Crassus
"First Consul of the Republic
"and Commander-in-Chief
of the armies of Rome".
ALL: Hail Crassus!
Rome will not allow us
to escape from Italy.
We have no choice
but to march against Rome herself
and end this war the only way
it could have ended.
By freeing every slave
in Italy.
I promise you a new Rome,
a new Italy and a new empire.
I promise the destruction
of the slave army
and the restoration of order
throughout all our territories.
I'd rather be here,
a free man among brothers,
facing a long march
and a hard fight,
than to be the richest
citizen of Rome,
fat with food
he didn't work for,
and surrounded by slaves.
I promise the living body
of Spartacus
for whatever punishment
you may deem fit.
That, or his head.
This I vow by the spirits
of all my forefathers.
This I have sworn
in the temple that guards
their bones.
ALL: Hail Crassus!
We've traveled
a long ways together.
We've fought many battles
and won great victories.
Now instead of taking ship
for our homes across the sea,
we must fight again.
Maybe there's no peace in this world,
for us or for anyone else.
I don't know.
But I do know
that as long as we live,
we must stay true
to ourselves.
I do know that we're brothers.
And I know that we're free.
We march tonight!
Hail Crassus!
Greetings to you,
Crassus.
Caius. Gentlemen.
Have your dispositions
been made?
Each maniple knows its position, sir,
and exactly what's expected.
Every legion commander
has been given his battle orders.
Excellent. All positions
will now be changed.
Changed?
Spartacus takes too keen
an interest in our plans, I fear.
New battle orders will be issued
in a short while.
Spartacus has every reason
to believe that he has outdistanced
the pursuing armies
of Pompey and Lucullus.
However, there are passes through
the Apennine Mountains unknown to any map.
It may fortify your courage
to know
that Pompey is encamped
some 20 miles to the west
and that the army of Lucullus
approaches from the south
by forced night march.
Sir, allow us to pledge you
the most glorious victory of your career.
ALL: Aye!
I'm not after glory!
I'm after Spartacus.
And, gentlemen,
I mean to have him.
However, this campaign
is not alone to kill Spartacus.
It is to kill
the legend of Spartacus.
You may go, gentlemen.
Hail Crassus.
Lentulus Batiatus
awaits Your Excellency.
Who?
The lanista, sir.
Ah! Admit him.
Most Blessed Highness,
as soon as I received your message I hurried
into your distinguished presence.
I'm glad you were able
to spare the time. Sit down.
Oh, how gracious.
I understand...
I'm informed
that Spartacus once trained
under your auspices.
Yes!
In fact, if it isn't too
subversive to say so,
I made him
what he is today.
You're to be
congratulated.
You're so
admirably qualified
to give me what up to now
I've not been able to obtain,
a physical description
of Spartacus.
Oh, yes.
But you saw him.
What?
In the ring.
When?
When you visited my school
with those two charming ladies.
What!
I trust they're both
in good health.
They selected him to fight
against Draba, the negro.
I remember the negro.
You had good cause to.
If I... If I may say so,
a brilliant dagger thrust,
difficult angle.
Spartacus
was the opponent?
Yes.
What did he
look like?
That's a matter of some importance
to Your Highness?
Yes, to every man who loves Rome
and wishes to see her strong.
We're both Roman patriots.
You're a great one. I, of course, smaller.
We both believe
in Roman fair play.
You want
something from me.
I would be lacking
in respect for my conscience,
if I did not say that I wish
something from you.
Name your price.
If... Uh, no.
When you win
your victory tomorrow,
presumably the survivors
will be auctioned off
in order to pay for the expenses
of this heroic expedition.
Could not the agent
for that sale
be he who shares this tiny moment
of history with Your Honor?
I authorize you to be the agent
for the sale of all survivors.
In return,
you will remain here
until after the battle and aid me
in identifying Spartacus.
After the battle?
Mm-hmm.
You misunderstand me.
I'm a civilian.
I'm even more of a civilian
than most civilians.
If you wish to remain so,
I strongly advise you to stay here
and be our guest. Guard!
Hmm?
My dear, all-conquering
Marcus Licinius Crassus,
what if it is Spartacus
who crosses the battlefield looking for you?
In such circumstances,
I have no doubt you will be helping him.
This fellow remains with us
until after the battle.
Make him comfortable.
Don't let him feel lonely.
Mommy? Mommy?
When do we go home?
Go to sleep, dear.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
No pains yet?
He's a bad child.
He hits me with his fists.
He wants to see his mother.
Can you blame him?
Can you feel it?
No, I don't.
I hope he waits
till we get to Rome.
Rome.
They've never
beaten us yet.
No.
But no matter how many times
we beat them,
they still seem to have another army
to send against us.
And another.
Varinia, it just seems like
we've started something
that has no ending.
If it ended tomorrow,
it would be worth it.
Oh, Varinia,
don't make me weak.
You're strong enough
to be weak.
Oh, Varinia.
Oh, Varinia,
I love you
more than my life.
Yet, sometimes,
even with you sleeping beside me
I feel so alone.
I imagine a god
for slaves and I pray.
What do you
pray for?
I pray for a son
who'll be born free.
I pray for
the same thing.
Take care of my son,
Varinia.
And if he never knows me,
tell him who I was
and what we dreamed of.
Tell him the truth.
There will be others to tell him lies.
I can't live without you,
Spartacus.
Varinia,
Varinia.
(SOBBING)
Varinia, for you and me
there can be no farewells.
As long as one of us lives,
we all live.
I felt it.
Did you feel it?
Yes, I did.
That was so strong.
Does it hurt you?
No.
That was so strong.
Oh, Varinia,
Varinia, Varinia.
(SOLDIERS MARCHING)
(ARMY SCREAMING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Lucullus and Pompey.
(SHOUTING)
(SWORDS CLASHING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(ARMY SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(BABY CRYING)
(HORSES APPROACHING)
Have we
a count of prisoners?
We haven't made
the final count, sir.
MESSENGER: I bring a message
from your master,
Marcus Licinius Crassus,
Commander of Italy.
By command of His
Most Merciful Excellency,
your lives are to be spared.
Slaves you were
and slaves you remain.
But the terrible penalty
of crucifixion has been set aside
on the single condition
that you identify the body
or the living person
of the slave called Spartacus.
(CROWD MURMURING)
I'm Spartacus!
MAN: I'm Spartacus.
(ALL SHOUTING)
I'm Spartacus.
MAN: I'm Spartacus.
(ALL SHOUTING)
Forgive me for being one of the last
to congratulate you.
There's an ugly rumor
going round the camp
that the prisoners
are to be crucified.
That is true.
Perhaps this is the moment
to remind Your Highness
that you promised me
I could be the agent in their auctioning.
You promised Spartacus to me!
Where is he?
In return, I promised you the sale
of the survivors and there will be none!
(BABY CRYING)
But
it's Varinia.
CRASSUS: Yes, I remember.
You're the woman of Spartacus?
I'm his wife.
And this is
his child?
Yes.
Where is Spartacus?
Dead.
Did you
see him killed?
Yes.
You're lying.
Where is he?
(SCOFFS)
At least here is someone
worth selling, Your Enormity.
I'll even take the child
as an investment.
How many women
have been taken?
Under 40, sir.
Those who weren't killed have run off
to the hills with their children.
You may sell all the others
but not this woman.
You haven't seen the others.
They're of surpassing ugliness!
A genius wouldn't be able
to sell them.
Flog that scoundrel
out of camp.
This woman and her child
are to be conveyed to my house in Rome.
Halt them!
Halt!
Antoninus?
Tribune!
Slaves are to be crucified
along the roadside
the full distance between here
and the gates of Rome.
Hold this man
till the end.
And that man, too.
March on.
March on!
I've more stripes
than a zebra.
Every time I touch my wounds,
they sing like larks.
But in spite of that, I found
something I never had before,
with all my wealth.
What is that?
Don't laugh at me,
but I believe it to be dignity.
In Rome, dignity shortens life
even more surely than disease.
The gods must be saving you
for some great enterprise.
You think so?
Anyone who believes
I'll turn informer for nothing is a fool.
I bore the whip
without complaint.
Indeed, that sounds like
a bad attack of dignity.
I hope this
will not deflect you
from the revenge you were going
to take on Crassus.
On the contrary,
it only strengthens my resolve.
That's enough.
I'm glad to learn that.
This woman, Varinia, is in his house.
All Rome knows about it.
Malicious tongues even say
that he's in love for the first time.
Yes! Oh.
I noticed a strange look in his eye
when he first saw her.
It would take a great woman to make Crassus
fall out of love with himself.
I'll be honest with you.
She's not as unattractive
as I told you she was.
Dignity and honesty in one afternoon.
I hardly recognize you.
But she is
an impossible woman.
Beautiful?
Well, beautiful.
The more chains you put on her,
the less like a slave she looks.
Proud?
Proud, proud.
You feel that she would surrender
to the right man which is irritating.
I like Crassus.
Let's save him from his agony.
Let's steal this woman.
Steal the woman? Why?
I can no longer hurt Crassus
in the Senate
but I can hurt him where he'll feel it most,
in his pride.
Attack our enemy
from within.
The scheme is excellent,
but I hope you're not suggesting
that I steal the woman.
Yes!
Buy some horses
and a cart with a canopy.
Bring her here by nightfall.
Oh, no.
Add courage
to your newfound virtues.
Would half a million sesterces
make you brave?
Half a million?
Well, Crassus
does seem to dwindle
in the mind, but...
Let's reduce him further.
A round million!
A million.
For such a sum,
I could bribe Jupiter himself!
With a lesser sum,
I have.
(DOOR OPENS)
Forgive the intrusion.
I'm not in the habit of coming uninvited.
You've always been
welcome here.
As a pupil.
You're not alone.
No.
This time
you've come to teach.
You've joined Crassus?
Am I arrested?
No.
But I must ask you to come with me
to the Senate immediately.
What I do,
I do not for myself but for Rome.
Rome? Poor,
helpless Rome.
Let's go and hear more
about Rome from Crassus.
Did you truly believe
500 years of Rome
could so easily be delivered
into the clutches of a mob?
Already the bodies of 6,000
crucified slaves
line the Appian Way.
Tomorrow the last of their companions
will fight to the death
in the temple of my fathers,
as a sacrifice to them.
As those slaves have died,
so will your rabble
if they falter one instant in loyalty
to the new order.
The enemies of the state
are known.
Arrests are in progress.
The prisons begin to fill.
In every city and province,
lists of the disloyal have been compiled.
Tomorrow they will learn
the cost of their terrible folly,
their treason.
Where does my name appear on the list
of disloyal enemies of the state?
First.
Yet, upon you
I have no desire for vengeance.
Your property
shall not be touched.
You will retain the rank
and title of Roman senator.
A house...
A farmhouse in Picenum
has been provided for your exile.
You may take your women
with you.
Why am I to be left
so conspicuously alive?
Your followers are deluded enough
to trust you.
I intend that you shall
speak to them tomorrow for
the sake of their own good,
their peaceful
and profitable future.
From time to time thereafter,
I may find it useful
to bring you back to Rome
to continue your duty to her,
to calm the envious spirit
and the troubled mind.
You will persuade them
to accept destiny and order,
and trust the gods!
You may go.
Halt!
(MEN SCREAMING)
Why hide behind
that stola, hmm?
That's better.
That dress took some weeks
of a woman's life.
You, above all people,
should respect the work
of slaves and wear it proudly.
Come here.
This belonged to a queen,
the Queen of Persia.
It's heavy.
In time you will
wear it lightly enough.
Sit down.
Will you have
some squab and honey?
No.
You'll enjoy it.
And a piece
of melon?
And some wine,
of course.
Eat.
(CHUCKLES)
I did not command you
to eat, I invited you.
You find the richness of your surroundings
makes conversation difficult?
Why am I
here?
Good question.
A woman's question.
I wish the answer could be as good
and straightforward.
The infant,
it thrives?
He thrives.
I purchased a wet nurse for him, yesterday.
I hope the milk agrees with him.
I sent her away.
I prefer to nurse
the child myself.
I'm not sure
I approve.
It ties you
to the old life.
I want you to begin
to look forward to the new.
I don't care
about my new life here.
You care about the life
of your child, don't you?
Why do you threaten me
with my baby?
I belong to you.
You can take me anytime you wish.
But I don't want
to take you.
I want you to give.
I want your love,
Varinia.
You think by threatening
to kill my child you'll make me love you?
I did not threaten
to kill your child.
I'm sorry, Varinia.
One shouldn't grieve
forever.
I'm not grieving,
I'm remembering.
Do I interfere
with your memories?
Oh, no.
(SCOFFS)
You tread the ridge between truth and insult
with the skill of a mountain goat.
Well.
What do you remember,
when you think about Spartacus?
It doesn't distress you
to talk about him?
No.
Well, then,
what sort of a man
was he, really?
He was a man who began
all alone, like an animal.
Yet on the day he died,
thousands and thousands
would gladly have died in his place.
(CHUCKLES)
What was he?
Was he a god?
He wasn't a god.
He was a simple man.
A slave.
I loved him.
He was an outlaw!
A murderer!
An enemy to everything fine and decent
that Rome ever built!
Damn you!
You tell me.
Why did you love him?
I can't tell you.
I can't tell you things
you can never understand.
But I want to understand.
Don't you see?
I must understand.
You're afraid of him,
aren't you?
That's why
you want his wife,
to soothe your fear
by having something he had.
When you're so afraid,
nothing can help.
Nothing.
We shall see.
Could we have won,
Spartacus?
Could we ever
have won?
Just by fighting them,
we won something.
When just one man says
"No, I won't,"
Rome begins to fear.
We were tens of thousands
who said no.
That was
the wonder of it.
To have seen slaves
lift their heads from the dust,
to see them rise from their knees,
stand tall
with a song on their lips,
to hear them
storm through
the mountains shouting,
to hear them sing
along the plains.
And now they're dead.
Dead.
Varinia
dead.
And the baby.
All of them.
Are you afraid to die,
Spartacus?
Hmm.
No more than
I was to be born.
Are you afraid?
Yes.
(HORSES APPROACHING)
Hail Consul!
Guard, fall in.
Where are
the gladiators?
Over there,
sir.
Antoninus, the night passes
slowly, doesn't it?
Spartacus.
You are he,
aren't you?
Gladiator,
I'm Marcus Licinius Crassus.
You must answer
when I speak to you.
(SCREAMING)
Centurion!
Let them fight now.
Unchain them.
The entire city's been told
they'll fight tomorrow
in the temple of your ancestors.
They will fight now
for me. Here!
And to the death.
And the victor shall be crucified.
We will test this myth
of slave brotherhood.
Unchain them!
(CHAINS RATTLING)
(HAMMER TAPPING)
Form a circle.
Don't give them
the pleasure of a contest.
I'll kill you
on the first rush.
I won't let them crucify you.
It's my last order.
Obey it.
Let them begin.
I won't let them
crucify you.
Do you realize how long
it takes to die on a cross?
I don't care!
Forgive me,
Antoninus.
(ANTONINUS GRUNTS)
I love you, Spartacus,
as I loved my own father.
I love you like my son
that I'll never see.
Go to sleep.
Here's your victory.
He'll come back.
He'll come back
and he'll be millions!
I wonder what
Spartacus would say
if he knew that the woman,
Varinia, and her child
are slaves
in my household?
Yes.
Spartacus.
Crucify him!
(CHAINS RATTLING)
I want no grave for him.
No marker.
His body's to be burned
and his ashes scattered in secret.
Did you fear him,
Crassus?
Not when I fought him.
I knew he could be beaten.
But now I fear him,
even more than I fear you.
Me?
Yes, my dear Caesar.
You!
I don't see the letter here
to the leader of the Senate.
Oh, yes. Julia, I don't like
the sound of weeping.
This is a happy house.
Please stop.
Oh, there you are.
Go away, Julia!
Where have you been?
The city is full of Crassus' legions.
We've been hiding.
I don't know Rome
as well as I know Capua.
They're arresting
everyone.
So this is the woman it took
Crassus eight Roman legions to conquer.
I wish I had time to make
your acquaintance, my dear.
Unfortunately, we all have to make journeys
to different destinations.
Where are we going?
You're going to Aquitania.
The governor's one of my innumerable cousins.
Here's a senatorial pass.
It's valid in all the known world.
Why do I have
to go to Aquitania?
GRACCHUS:
'Cause I asked you to.
It's very good of you,
Gracchus, but I...
Double the money I promised you.
Here's two million sesterces.
Two million?
Here. Articles of freedom
for the woman.
And here's a smaller document
that I've prepared for the child,
befitting its size.
Where are you going?
Hmm?
Oh, to Picenum.
Picenum?
That's the dreariest town in Italy.
Will you please leave me?
(BABY WHIMPERING)
Come with us.
See to it that I don't misuse the money.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm a senator.
Will you please go
before the soldiers come here?
Oh!
This would really
make Crassus jealous.
Go and make my joy
complete.
Save your tears now.
Save them for the journey.
Well. Prettier.
Halt!
Identify yourselves,
please.
Lentulus Batiatus.
Climb down, please,
and identify yourselves.
I object
to that tone.
I've got
my orders.
Come down and
identify yourselves, please.
As I told you,
I'm Lentulus Batiatus, the lanista from Capua.
This...
My sister-in-law.
Lady, please.
She's traveling
with her child to Aquitania
on a senatorial pass.
Take a look through
his baggage.
Not a word,
please.
What did you say?
(WHISPERING)
Oh, Spartacus.
Tell the lady
no loitering's allowed.
Instantly.
Move on.
Yes.
(BABY CRYING)
This is your son.
He's free, Spartacus!
Free!
VARINIA: He's free.
He's free.
He'll remember you, Spartacus,
because I'll tell him.
I'll tell him who his father was
and what he dreamed of.
Varinia, have mercy on us.
Get in the wagon.
Oh, my love,
my life.
Please die, die.
Please, please die,
my love.
Oh, God,
why can't you die!
Come on. Come on.
Goodbye, my love,
my life.
Goodbye, goodbye.