Spring, Summer, Fall, Winter...
And Spring
Spring
Wake up
- Master!
- Yes, my boy?
Where do you want to go?
l want to pick herbs for medicine
Then let us go.
Come along
l'm going to pick herbs now, Master
Watch out for snakes
- Wait for me, Master
- Yes
l've picked a lot of herbs, Master
Really? You've picked a lot?
Careful!
Stop! Throw this away, my child
Why? lt looks the same
Even though it looks the same,
this is a deadly plant
The other one can save lives
lt still looks the same.
How can l know?
Look closely. Here at the tip
you can see a white line
lf you ate this plant, you'd die
You mustn't pick
this sort of plant next time
- ls this one alright to eat?
- Yes, this one is good
Master, there is a stone on my back.
Please take it off
- Does it torment you?
- Yes, Master
Didn't you also do it to the fish?
Yes, Master
Didn't you also do it to the frog?
Didn't you also do it to the snake?
Yes, Master
Stand up!
Walk around!
l can't walk, it's too heavy
How do you think the fish,
the frog and the snake endured it?
lt was wrong to do it
Go and find all the animals
and release them from the stones
Then l will release you too
But if any of the animals, the fish,
the frog or the snake is dead,
you will carry the stone in your heart
for the rest of your life
Summer
You look so very healthy
This tree is over 300 years old
You will become
as healthy as this tree
Greetings
Come in
Will she recover, wise one?
l believe that her soul is suffering
When she finds peace in her soul,
her body will return to health
Please take care of her!
Excuse me
You are not allowed to sit on that
The master will be angry with you
Why are you praying all of a sudden?
Would you like to come along?
Softly!
lt must prepared with a true heart
Drink!
lt will clear your head
The boat is floating away!
Stop it!
Have you recovered now?
Yes, l have completely recovered
Strange
When l can't see you,
l go insane
What is wrong with me?
Cold! lt's cold!
What shall l do?
l did wrong, Master.
Forgive me
That happens by itself.
lt is just nature
Are you still sick?
No
Then it was the right medicine
Now that you have recovered,
you can leave this place
No, Master! She can't!
Lust awakens the desire to possess.
And that awakens the intent to murder
Get in
Fall
That was tiring, huh?
MAN, 30, FLEES AFTER MURDERlNG WlFE
You have grown a lot!
Get in!
So? Have you led
a happy life up till now?
Tell me something
interesting about your life
The world of men has grown
agonizing for you, hasn't it?
Leave alone, Master.
Can you not see that l am suffering?
What causes you to suffer?
My only sin was to love
l wanted nothing except her
So?
She went with another man
Ah, that was it
How can that be?
She said that she'd love only me
- And then?
- l couldn't bear it any more
Didn't you know beforehand
how the world of men is?
Sometimes we have to
let go of things we like
What you like,
others will also like!
But still, how could she do that?
The bitch!
- ls it so unbearable for you?
- Yes!
Master!
Young fool!
Though you can so easily kill,
you yourself cannot be easily killed
Carve out all of
these characters with the knife
And while you cut out each one,
drive out the anger from your heart
Holy one!
We've come to investigate something
- Drop the knife!
- Otherwise l'll shoot!
What are you doing?
Continue cutting!
Prajnaparamita Sutra.
lt helps restore inner peace
Please let him finish
How long will it take?
Until tomorrow morning
- No connection
- No?
lt's quite a deep valley, isn't it?
What?
They make white paint
from these mussels
Stand up
lt's time to go
Detective Choi,
let's go as we are
Detective Chi,
the boat won't go forwards
Ah, now it's moving