Psagmeno.com
MOViE iNFO WiTH .srt FiLES!
- Chow time!
- It's time!
Floyd, step up to the door. Dinner time.
Only my friends call me Floyd.
You ain't got no friends, Floyd.
What's that?
- That is called loaf.
- Loaf.
It's got a little bit
of pasghetti in there.
Toenails.
Rat shit.
Everything a growing fella needs,
like you.
Come here. Can I tell you something?
Can I tell you a secret?
Yeah.
One day,
somehow, some way,
I'm gonna get outta here.
And I'm gonna rain down on you
like the Holy Ghost.
Man, you just threatened a staff member.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, you have.
Do something.
Let's have some fun.
Open the goddamn gate!
Come on, guys.
Don't waste my time.
Sector C!
Pull your heads outta your ass!
Boss is on deck!
Open!
Bravo 14, open perimeter fence.
Stay back!
If she moves, fire her up, all right?
You gonna come down from there or what?
Look at you.
You know the rules, hotness.
You gotta keep off these bars.
- What, these bars?
- Yeah. Those bars.
Oh, my God.
You are really
in bad shape upstairs, lady!
Gonna come in here and tell me that?
Or are you too scared?
Come on, I'm bored.
I'm bored. Play with me.
You put five of my guards
in the hospital, honey.
No one's gonna play with you.
You sleep on the ground.
I sleep where I want,
when I want, with who I want.
Oh, man. I love you.
Alpha One, hit her.
Come on, man. You're
six foot four. She's a tiny little girl.
You got a choice tonight.
What we got here?
We got chocolate, strawberry, or vanilla.
My job is to keep you alive until you die.
Do you understand that?
Ahh!
Spring break!
Whoo.
That is just a whole lot of pretty
in a whole lot of crazy.
The world changed
when Superman flew across the sky.
And then it changed again when he didn't.
And that is why I'm here.
We lose a national hero,
but you sit there looking like
the cat that ate the canary.
I've eaten a lot of canaries.
It's taken some work.
But I finally have them.
The worst of the worst.
There's rumors, Amanda,
that some of them have abilities.
Well, the rumors are right.
You know what the problem
with a metahuman is?
The human part.
We got lucky with Superman.
He shared our values.
The next Superman might not.
You're playing with fire, Amanda.
I'm fighting fire with fire.
You're not going to pitch us that
Task Force X project
of yours again, are you?
Yes.
But this time, you're gonna listen.
Floyd Lawton, aka Deadshot.
He's the most wanted hitman in the world.
Let's say he has an elite clientele.
- What?
- Hey, Angelo.
This is the exterminator
you called for your rat problem.
My account's looking a little thin.
No one gets paid until
what needs to get done gets done.
Nope. That's not the rules.
No money, no honey.
Whoa. Here's your boy right now.
With about 20 of his new best friends.
I'm still seeing zeroes over here, Angie.
Listen, stop being cute and do your job!
They're taking him
outta the car now.
In about 30 seconds,
your window is gonna close forever.
Okay. Okay, okay. Relax.
There was an accounting error.
We sent it.
Now double it for being a dickhead.
You got 10 seconds.
We're not the kind of people
you play with.
Did you just... Did you threaten me?
This dude's gonna get a sore throat
from all the singing he's about to do.
You son of a bitch.
Pleasure doing business with you, Angie.
But everyone has a weakness.
And a weakness can be leveraged.
His is an 11 -year-old honor student
in Gotham City.
His daughter.
So we watched her and waited.
You should talk to Mama more.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Mama stays in bed a lot.
Yeah. She's still going out at night?
Dad, it's okay. I can take care of her.
I know how to make pancakes now.
Hey, babe, that's beautiful.
Um, she's supposed to be
taking care of you.
You know, that's how
that's supposed to work.
I want you to come live with me.
All right? I came into some resources.
I'mma get us a spot.
It's gonna be nice, all right?
Mama says I can't live with you
because you kill people.
That's not true.
That's a lie. She's lying to you.
Daddy... I know you do bad things.
Don't worry, I still love you.
Come on.
- And you caught him?
- Not me.
I just gave an anonymous tip
to the right guy in Gotham City.
I'mma figure this out. All right?
It's over, Deadshot.
I don't want to do this
in front of your daughter.
- Daddy, please.
- Zoe, move!
Please, Daddy. Don't do it.
Please.
Don't do it.
All right.
Love you, Daddy.
So now we have the man who never misses.
Where'd you put him?
Let's just say, I put him in a hole
and threw away the hole.
Harley Quinn.
Before she ran off
and joined the circus,
she was known as Dr. Harleen Quinzel.
A psychiatrist at Arkham Asylum.
She was assigned to The Clown himself.
Dr. Quinzel.
You know,
I live for these moments with you.
- What do you got?
- I got you a kitty.
So thoughtful.
She thought she was curing him,
but she was falling in love.
There is something
you could do for me, doctor.
Anything. I mean, yeah.
I need a machine gun.
A machine gun?
Talk about a workplace romance gone wrong.
Get off me.
Shh!
What do we have here?
I did everything you said. I helped you.
Ah.
You helped me.
By erasing my mind?
What few faded memories I had.
No.
You left me in a black hole
of rage and confusion.
Is that the medicine
you practice, Dr. Quinzel?
What are you gonna do?
You gonna kill me, Mr. J?
What?
Oh, I'm not gonna kill ya.
I'm just gonna hurt ya
really, really bad.
You think so?
Well, I can take it.
I wouldn't want you to break
those perfect porcelain-capped teeth
when the juice hits your brain.
They became the king
and queen of Gotham City.
And God help anyone
who disrespected the queen.
We finally meet.
Nah, he don't shake hands.
But sit down and have a drink.
Hey, J.
On behalf of everybody, welcome back.
I wanted to come by
and personally say thank you.
You making me good money.
I'm making you good money.
Are you sweet talking me?
I love this guy.
He's so intense!
Mmm. You're a lucky man.
You got a bad bitch.
Oh, that she is.
The fire in my loins.
The itch in my crotch.
The one, the only,
the infamous Harley Quinn!
Oh, come to Daddy.
Puddin'!
Listen,
you are my gift
to this handsome hunka hunka!
You belong to him now.
Well...
You're cute.
You want me?
I'm all yours.
I don't want no beef.
You don't want no beef?
Why, what's wrong?
You don't like me?
Fine. Don't waste my time then.
This is your lady.
Look, are you enjoying yourself?
No.
That's your lady, Joker.
That's right.
Yo, J.
And that was just the beginning.
Come on, Puddin'. Do it!
Oh.
We have got company.
Batsy, Batsy, Batsy.
She's crazier than him.
And more fearless.
Stupid Bat, you're ruining date night!
Puddin'.
Puddin', I can't swim!
But the Bat got her, too.
She's in the same hole as Deadshot.
And then there's the Aussie.
Digger Harkness.
Or as the tabloids call him,
Captain Boomerang.
We're gonna be rich.
Yeah, you and me, mate.
Go and get the car.
He robbed every bank
in Australia at least once.
Then he came to America
for a fresh target set.
Doesn't work well with others.
No honor among thieves, eh?
But he tangled with a metahuman
and lived to tell about it.
And have you heard of
the pyrokinetic homeboy?
How'd you catch him?
We didn't. He surrendered.
Chato Santana.
On the streets they call him El Diablo.
This LA gangbanger thought
he was king of the world...
until he lost his queen.
Gets jumped in a prison riot
and incinerates half the yard.
The security video is incredible.
Oh, Jesus. The hell is that?
His name is Waylon Jones.
Evolution took a step
backwards with this one.
Yo, K.C., it's supper.
Go ahead, open that up, B.
Got something
real nice for you today, boy.
Hey, boss,
it true he chewed a dude's hand off?
Look at that, right there.
Vulcanized rubber.
Give me that, Smitty.
Where you at?
Don't make me get you.
They call him Killer Croc.
Here you are! You hungry?
You want some food?
Go ahead, feed the man.
What are you in the mood for tonight?
I got a double cheeseburger,
onion rings, a little coleslaw.
Or a giant skinless goat.
He looked like a monster.
So they treated him like a monster.
Then he became a monster.
He was chased out of Gotham by the Bat.
Went searching for sanctuary elsewhere.
He never found it.
I saved the best for last.
- The witch.
- A witch?
I'm talking a flying, spell-casting,
making-shit-disappear witch.
A sorceress from another dimension.
Another world.
Archeologist Dr. June Moone,
wandered into the wrong cave.
June...
She opened something she shouldn't have...
releasing a metahuman more powerful
than any we've encountered.
The Enchantress.
She inhabits Dr. Moone's body now.
And where is this witch?
In my pocket.
Now tell him
why she won't turn you into a frog.
Some say the witch
has a secret buried heart,
and whoever finds it
can control the witch.
So we searched the cave
where she turned up
and we found her heart.
That thing's her heart?
Mmm-hmm. She's vulnerable without it.
You want to put our national security
in the hands of
witches, gangbangers, and crocodiles?
Don't forget about The Joker's girlfriend.
These are villains, Amanda.
What makes you think you can control them?
Because getting people to act
against their own self-interest
for the national security
of the United States
is what I do for a living.
You take the finest special forces officer
this nation has ever produced,
Colonel Rick Flag.
Help me.
I assigned him to watch Dr. Moone,
and just as I hoped, it got personal.
Are you gonna kiss me or not?
I have the witch's heart.
And Dr. Moone has his.
Now he'll follow my orders as Holy Writ.
In a world of flying men and monsters,
this is the only way
to protect our country.
What if Superman had decided to fly down,
rip off the roof of the White House
and grab the President
of the United States
right out of the Oval Office?
Who would've stopped him?
We got contingency plans
for nukes in North Korea,
anthrax in our mail.
We got fluoride in our water.
But what happens if the next Superman
becomes a terrorist?
Amanda Waller has a plan. Amanda?
I wanna build a team
of some very bad people
who I think can do some good.
Like fight the next war,
defeat the next Superman.
Not on my watch.
You're not putting those monsters
back out on the street in our name.
General, we run them
covertly, non-attributed.
Strictly need to know.
And if they get caught,
we throw them under the bus.
The next war will be fought
with these metahumans.
Ours, or theirs.
We're not the only ones
kicking up rocks looking for them.
You know we can't control these people.
June, be strong.
Dr. Moone.
Enchantress.
Meet the Enchantress.
Everything we know about her
is in your briefing packs.
She's walked this earth
for a very long time
and will likely be here
when we're long gone.
This meeting is now a magic show?
Magic or not, this girl can do
some pretty incredible things.
Go get it, girl.
How about a little something
from the weapons ministry vault in Tehran?
We've been chasing these plans for years.
Uh, please don't touch me.
Please don't touch me.
Thank you. We'd like Dr. Moone back.
Enchantress.
Please. Please.
I'm sorry, I can't do that again.
Flag, get her out of here.
I move to, uh, authorize Amanda Waller
to establish Task Force X
under the ARGUS program.
All right.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
I know you do bad things.
Don't worry, I still love you.
Welcome to Belle Reve,
special security barracks.
How you doing, man?
Why don't you kiss her ass?
She's in charge.
Welcome, ma'am. How are you?
I'm here to assist you in any way.
Where are they?
Are you the Devil?
Maybe.
Ain't you scared?
Why'd they put you down here?
I asked.
Open that gate.
Yo, ese.
Hola, amigo.
Put that burrito down.
You got visitors, man.
What's up? Hey, you want some of this?
Then come down here.
That ain't me.
That wasn't you?
Nah, they say it's me, but that ain't me.
That guy's gone.
He's dead.
- And yet, here you are.
- Ma'am.
Let me try to talk to him.
You wanna die in here, buddy?
You got a real shot
at walking the block again.
Have a nice cold beer, a nice meal.
A woman.
Look, man, you ain't the first to ask,
and you ain't gonna be the last.
Ask what?
I'm a man, okay? I ain't no weapon.
I'mma die in peace
before I raise my fists again.
I've caused enough harm.
All right, unlock him.
- What?
- You heard me.
You know what this man can do?
I'm here to find out. Lose the restraints.
Okay.
What is this? Uh, cheerleading tryouts?
Let's go. Let's see what you can do.
They say you never missed a shot.
Prove it.
Mmm-hmm.
Now you got one in the chamber.
What you gonna do with it?
Shit!
Give me the word, boss. I'll drop him.
Everybody calm down.
Griggs, tell your men to stand down.
Tell them, "Put it down."
Stand down.
Colonel, for the record, this is exactly
what I was concerned about.
What's for dinner?
Ames, if this man shoots me,
I want you to kill him
and I want you to go clear
my browser history.
See, uh,
the firing pin is filed down, right?
Mag full of dummy rounds.
If I pull the trigger, nothing happens.
You're absolutely right.
Why would we give a loaded weapon
to an infamous hitman?
Go ahead, pull the trigger. Empty it.
Don't empty nothing.
You don't even know this lady.
I've known you, like, nine months.
Remember when I brought you that cookie?
That was a real cookie.
What?
Oops.
Y'all jokers must be crazy.
All right. Now you know
what you're buying.
Let me tell you the price.
First, I want out of here.
Second, I want full custody
of my daughter.
All right? And her mom can have, like,
supervised visits.
But her stank-ass boyfriend can't come.
Darnell can't come.
- Darnell's out.
- He's out.
Third, y'all gonna pay
for my daughter's whole education.
Best schools.
And then I want her to go to college.
Like Harvard. Or Yale.
- So Ivy League.
- Ivy League, yeah.
- One of them big joints, you know?
- Mmm-hmm.
And, uh, if she can't cut it
and her grades start slipping,
I need you to white-people that thing.
- Mmm-hmm.
- You know how y'all do.
- Oh, yeah.
- You know, right? Okay.
Now that's my price.
But I'm concerned 'cause I don't see
nobody writing shit down.
You're in no position to make any demands.
Oh. I'm sorry.
You thought I was talking to you.
No, errand boy. I'm talking to your boss.
That's my price, sweetie.
You know what it is.
You notice these are criminals, hmm?
They're psychotic, antisocial freaks.
It makes no sense.
Let me hit the Tier One units
and I'll build you
a team of pipe hitters who'll
do anything you can dream up.
I mean, you need real soldiers.
Not these scumbags.
In World War Two,
the US Navy made a deal with the mafia
to protect its ships on the waterfront.
This ain't World War Two.
It's World War Three.
What are you really up to?
It's a "need to know", and all you need
to know is you work for me.
That can change with a phone call.
I have friends, too, you know.
There you go. Call.
But without you minding her,
your lady friend stays here strapped
to a board in a drug-induced coma.
They warned me about you.
My dumb ass didn't believe the stories.
Nobody does.
Where is she?
It's complex. This is not just her.
Everybody's disappearing.
There's this new law,
where if you're a bad enough bad guy,
they stamp "terrorist" on your jacket.
They send you to this swamp in Louisiana.
A black site.
That's where she is.
So what are we doing?
Bring the car around.
We're going for a drive.
Lester, Lester!
Hit me one more time!
Come on, man!
You gotta call upstairs and tell them
to float me another 10 K.
- Hey!
- Ow!
- Boss wants to see you.
- You know who I am?
Good job, man. He's killing it.
Come on, man. Why am I here?
All right, yeah, I'm down.
I get it, all right?
I've had a run of bad decks.
Not my fault. All right?
Dude, this is real.
I had to stop these guys from burning
down your house with your kids in it.
But you're lucky.
Maybe. Why do you think so?
Yo, slick. What's up?
Griggs. You are?
You might wanna keep your mouth shut.
Can I go, man?
What the hell is going on, man?
This is crazy.
Blah, blah-blah, blah-blah.
Blah-blah, blah, blah.
All of that chitchat's gonna get ya hurt.
Oh! My God!
Mmm.
I could tell you meant that.
Yeah.
You're gonna be my friend.
Enchantress.
- Log time of death. 1620.
- June?
Let's get her down to the morgue.
June? June?
June.
What did you do?
Shh.
Okay.
Plus, it could be the routing number.
Wanna go for drinks?
Enchantress.
God damn it!
June! June!
June, I'm sorry.
Shh.
She went somewhere.
If you have to choose between her or me,
stop her.
Promise me you'll stop her.
Even if it kills me.
Sir. Sir. You okay?
Can you breathe? Did you take anything?
This is 21.
Send medical to my location.
I'm a physician.
Roger. Bringing medical to your location.
No pulse. Starting compressions.
Sir.
Midway City is under attack.
It's a non-human entity.
I think you know what to do, sir.
Activate Task Force X
and get Amanda Waller
and her whole circus on scene ASAP.
Sir.
We're going live
with Task Force X. Pull 'em.
Prisoner,
get down on your knees, now!
Down on your knees!
Hands in the air! Turn around.
Hands up high!
Hey, I'm cooperating. All right?
- This is me being cool.
- Take her.
Do not fire
that goddamn weapon!
Damn it!
Open the gate!
Everybody, line up for extraction.
Let's go! Let's move, move.
Yeah. Open the door! Let's go!
Hit him!
Hurry up, before he smokes us!
Where you at?
Whoa!
Is that the new guy?
What is that? What is that? Who are you?
- Stand by. Arming device.
- Who are you?
- I don't know who you are.
- Device armed.
Hey! Hey, I'm talking to you.
Hey, I'm talking to you.
Injection successful.
Location verified.
- Anybody who touches me is dead.
- Anybody who...
- Lady. Hey.
- Injection successful.
- Hey! Miss? What was that?
- Location verified.
Next!
Oh, you deaf. You one of them deaf hoes.
Come on.
Shut up, and get it done.
Whee!
Listen, you're being transferred.
I don't know where you're going.
It's from Mr. J.
You gonna tell him I took care of you?
You're so screwed.
What do you mean by that?
Get off me! Get off me!
Harley, what do you mean by that?
Harley!
Hey, I got a delivery.
I have a gift basket for Dr. Van Criss.
You're not on the access list.
I can't let you in. Sorry.
Hey, cool if I leave it with you?
I'm way behind today.
Thank you. You're a good man.
Open up!
Just please, do whatever they say.
Do whatever they say. Just do it.
Hmm.
This looks neat.
Light it up!
Light it up! Light it up!
He's right above us.
This is a mistake. Rick, I can't do this.
- I can't...
- Listen, listen.
There's no other way.
Just get it done.
Enchantress.
Flag, talk to me.
What's going on down there?
Amanda, she bolted.
Say it again?
She bolted!
Shit!
Go!
Worldwide military is on alert.
Our weapons are ineffective.
I thought this was contained!
This is the worst day of my life!
All evacuees
must report to a FEMA representative.
What's going on in that city?
Those assholes here yet?
Yeah, they're here.
Alpha, Bravo team, on me.
What the hell, Flag?
Unlock 'em.
Mmm!
Hi, boys! Harley Quinn.
How do you do?
Huh?
What was that?
I should kill everyone and escape?
Sorry. It's the voices.
I'm kidding! Jeez!
That's not what they really said.
What do we got here?
Twelve pounds of shit in a 10-pound sack.
Welcome to the party,
Captain Boomerang.
Hey, what's going on, man?
Calm down.
Hey, one minute
I'm playing Mahjong with me nanna,
then this red streak hits me
outta nowhere.
Shut up! You were caught
robbing a diamond exchange.
I was not!
Here comes Slipknot,
the man who can climb anything. Wonderful.
Have a good time, scumbag.
Ooh.
Straighten up.
She had a mouth.
Listen up!
In your necks,
injection you got,
it's a nanite explosive.
It's the size of a rice grain,
but it's powerful as a hand grenade.
You disobey me, you die.
You try to escape, you die.
You otherwise irritate or vex me,
and guess what?
You die.
I'm known to be quite vexing.
I'm just forewarning you.
Lady, shut up!
This is the deal.
You're going somewhere very bad,
to do something that'll get you killed.
But until that happens,
you're my problem.
Mmm.
So was that like a, uh, pep talk?
Yeah. That was a pep talk.
There's your shit.
Grab what you need for a fight.
We're wheels up in 10.
You might wanna work on
your team motivation thing.
- You heard of Phil Jackson?
- Yeah.
He's like the gold standard, okay?
Triangle, bitch. Study.
What?
Won't fit anymore?
Too much junk in the trunk?
Nah. Every time I put this on,
somebody dies.
And?
I like putting it on.
Goody.
Somethin' tells me
a whole lotta people are about to die!
Yeah. It's us.
We're being led to our deaths.
Speak for yourself, mate.
Hey, what's that crap on your face?
Does it wash off?
Hey, if you like a girl, can you light
her cigarette with your pinkie?
Because that would be real classy!
Hey, y'all might
wanna leave old boy alone.
He could torch this whole joint.
Ain't that right, ese?
Ain't got nothing to worry about from me.
I'm cool, homie.
Behold the voice of God.
For those of you
who don't know me officially,
my name is Amanda Waller.
There's an active terrorist event
in Midway City.
I want you to enter the city,
rescue HVT-1, and get them to safety.
I'm sorry. Uh...
For those of us who don't
speak good guy, what is HVT-1?
The only person
that matters in the city,
the one person you can't kill.
Complete the mission,
you get time off your prison sentence.
Fail the mission, you die.
Anything happens to Colonel Flag,
I'll kill every single one of you.
Remember, I'm watching.
I see everything.
There's your pep talk.
Compared to your shit, she killed it.
So that's it?
What, we some kind of Suicide Squad?
I'll notify your next of kin.
Alpha, Bravo team. Mount up!
You're late.
This is Katana. She's got my back.
She can cut all of you in half
with one sword stroke,
just like mowing the lawn.
I would advise not getting killed by her.
Her sword traps the souls of its victims.
Harley Quinn. Nice to meet ya.
Love your perfume.
What is that? The stench of death?
Whoa! Easy, cowgirl.
Ain't that kind of a mission. Have a seat.
She seems nice.
Shh.
Hey.
Is he supposed to be green like that?
Oh!
Party foul!
Not cool.
Ooh. Look at the pretty lights!
Are you guys seeing this?
What happened?
Terror attack.
Dirty bombs, bad guys
shooting up the place with AKs.
You know, usual shit.
Right.
Yeah, you're a bad liar.
I don't know if they told you,
but I'm a hitman. I'm not a fireman.
I don't save people.
Anything for a dollar, right?
You know the dark places, too.
Don't act like you don't.
I'm a soldier!
And you're a serial killer
who takes credit cards.
When the shooting starts,
and it will, you'll cut and run.
Six-one is going down.
Six-one is going down hard.
Stand by. Drop the ramp.
Whoo! What a ride!
We're okay. We're okay.
Assets are undamaged.
- Mind games.
- What's that?
All this bomb in the neck crap.
That ain't real, mate.
See, they're trying to trap us
with our own minds, right?
But you look around, we're free, brah.
How do you know this?
Just trust me. I know, all right?
It's a con.
Now I'm going,
because I got a life to live.
Question is, are you coming?
Yeah. Smart!
Hold your fire.
Sorry. It's what I do.
Damn it.
Now that's a killer app!
Okay. You wanna keep playing
the Hollywood Squares version
of "I'll Blow Your Freaking Head Off"?
Are you next?
You tripping, homie.
You next, Deadshot?
You just threatened me?
Oh, yeah.
He just threatened me.
Move.
You got a boyfriend?
All right, I'm gonna kill him.
Well, you better make it quick
'cause he's gonna kill
all of us one by one.
I'm gonna drop him, the sword lady,
five or seven of these SEALs.
After that, I'm gonna need
some help. You down?
Always. What about the shit in our necks?
Your friend's gonna
help us out with that, right?
You're my friend, too.
Stay evil, doll face. Spread the word.
So...
I'm thinking if we move together,
we can kill all these guys
and go our separate ways.
- Yeah?
- Sounds good.
Spread the word.
Psst. Oi. Oi.
We need your help, man.
When the time's right,
you hit Flag with a fireball.
He'll be too busy burning to death
to have a go at us with his phone of doom.
Then what?
Then we get out of here.
And do what?
What are you,
bloody Socrates, with all the questions?
Freedom, man.
Freedom! You remember that, don't you?
We're criminals. You know that, right?
Yeah. It's great.
Come on, do the bastard.
Hey, be careful.
He eats people.
Sorry, Mother Superior, what?
He eats people for reals, homie.
He's a cannibal.
Oh.
No.
What did you say to him?
Nothing. Just having a laugh.
No worries.
I'm standing by for follow on tac team.
C2, what is the operational load
of the PLS?
Boss, we got people up here.
I'm on my way.
Shit.
Amanda, we have hostiles up ahead.
Flag, get out of there.
We're not here to fight them.
We know that doesn't work.
Copy that.
We're diverting.
Bump out second squad two blocks east.
We'll pass through you, continue north.
Take Bravo two blocks east.
We'll leapfrog through you
once you're in position.
Copy that.
Hey. I like these odds, mate.
You just say the word.
Yeah.
Come on.
Yeah, uh...
Hold that thought.
Rick, why do they look like that?
Just stay cool.
The hell are they?
You cut and run, I'll blow your head off.
Hit them!
Huh.
Hey.
Ha!
Get off me!
Get off me! Son of a...
Flag!
- Good riddance.
- Harley!
He dies, we die.
- Thanks.
- Shut up.
Backblast, clear!
Pinky.
That's how I cut and run.
Hey.
Hey, come on.
What? I saw it move.
See? It flinched. I think.
Hey, you were some help, princess.
It's better this way.
Trust me.
Oh, yeah, you're the fire bloke, eh?
- Yeah, I was. Yeah.
- Right. Yeah. Hey.
Well, looky here.
Whoo! It's fire.
Whoo!
The brief said terrorists.
You wanna start explaining this?
If I told you, would you believe me?
- What are they?
- I don't know.
That's bullshit.
Thing has on a $3,000 watch.
Is that a person?
It was.
Now it's not.
Hey, don't!
What?
We got a job to do.
We're moving.
Get your boys moving.
Let's go.
Waller,
we're moving on the objective.
We lost contact with Bravo.
You got a visual?
Stand by.
- Anything on the other squad?
- No, ma'am.
Go-7, I need your sensors
on those coordinates.
Flag, it's a negative.
They were engaged when you were,
but we lost them.
Seriously?
The hell is wrong with you people?
We're bad guys. It's what we do.
Hey, Deadshot. I've been thinking.
If we don't come together,
no one's walking out of here alive.
Hmm.
And?
These people respect you.
You got influence.
All right. What's your play right now?
You're a man of your word, right?
I want my mission.
You want your life and your kid back.
You help me keep this Mardi Gras parade
in line and I'll hook you up.
Waller is the puppet master.
You ain't got shit to hook me up with.
I got plenty of my own strings to pull.
You just get them
to the top of that target building
and get my rescuee
on that extraction helo.
And you're gonna make sure I get paid?
And you get paid.
You get paid,
and you get your fresh start.
Take a knee.
Our body's at the top of that building.
We get up there,
pull them out of the vault
they're hiding in.
Helos extract us off the roof.
- It's Miller time.
- Check.
Flag, who's up there?
That's none of your concern.
- Do you know who's up there?
- No.
Is it the President?
It's not the President.
Argh!
Oh, you!
You're not leaving me.
You're not leaving me!
You're a pain in the ass.
I have done everything you said.
Every test, every trial, every initiation.
I have proved I love you. Just accept it.
Got it, got it, got it, got it.
I am not someone who is loved.
I'm an idea.
A state of mind.
I execute my will according to my plan.
And you, Doctor...
Are not part of my plan.
Just let me in. I promise...
Let me in! I promise I won't hurt you.
A promise-promise?
Hey, dickface!
Mind screaming at your bitch
somewhere else?
I was gonna say,
"I wouldn't do that if I were you."
Don't hurt me.
I'll be your friend.
Do it. Do it, do it, do it.
My heart scares you, and a gun doesn't?
Do it!
If you weren't so crazy,
I'd think you were insane.
Go away.
Harley, you coming?
Why do you eat people?
Gives me their power.
Would you like to eat me?
Hell, no.
Aw, why not?
I don't want your crazy.
Says the guy who lives in a sewer.
At least I know it's a sewer.
Oh, I get it.
'Cause like, this is a sewer, too,
only with
nice shops and restaurants, right?
- Mmm.
- You hate mankind much?
Let me guess.
Mommy didn't take you to Chuck E. Cheese
on your sixth birthday.
I can recommend a good therapist.
Why?
Because I'm bored.
I need a victim,
a mind to pry apart and spit in.
Leave it, mate.
She's a rabbit hole. Don't fall in.
And here's one now.
Japanese, female.
Mid-20s, 5'5", good health, athletic.
And...
An only child.
With deep-seated father issues.
Daddy wanted a son,
so she has to hide behind a mask.
I am not
hiding.
Now, that was gangster.
Harley.
Why don't you
stop acting like a drunken stripper?
You wanna tell me
what the hell is going on, then?
'Cause...
I smell a rat.
If they don't blow our heads off,
we'll have to
fight our way out of this city.
I need you to
play nice with the other children.
And quietly return to my cage.
Sure, okay.
Hey, that's okay, sellout.
I get it. I get it.
I know how the world works, okay?
And when it comes to the heart,
everyone for themselves, right?
Waller?
We're about to enter the building.
Get that chopper ready.
What do you say we get this over with?
What the hell? Deadshot. Fall back.
You mind if we tag along?
Whoo! Looks like we have
a spot of luck, eh?
Be a walk in the park.
Easy peasy.
Don't make me shoot you.
God damn it. Harley!
Go, go, go, go!
Hey, guys!
Come on. Let's go.
Ma'am. I got motion detectors going off
on the secure floors.
- Flag, they're all around you.
- Hold.
Use extreme caution.
I don't like this, Flag.
I don't like it either.
Pussy.
I will knock your ass out.
I do not care that you're a girl.
They're after Flag again.
Son of a bitch. Get off me.
Circle up. Circle around him.
- Let me fight!
- You die, we die.
Clear! Everyone move out!
- Where you been, homie?
- This ain't my fight!
You know what? You don't stand for shit.
You ain't about shit!
Don't touch me, man!
Don't touch you? What you gonna do?
- Don't touch me!
- I'm touching you! I'm touching you!
- Do something. Do something!
- Don't touch me!
- You wanna see something?
- Oh, yeah, I wanna see...
- Yes, I wanna see something.
I was just trying to get you there.
Phil Jackson. We good, right?
I knew you'd come through.
That shit crazy.
Clear.
I gotta work on my cardio.
Question.
Would you die for me?
Yes.
That's too easy.
Would you...
Would you live for me?
Mmm?
Yes.
Careful.
Do not say this oath thoughtlessly.
Desire becomes surrender.
Surrender becomes power.
Do you want this?
I do.
Say it.
Say it. Say it.
Pretty, pretty, pretty...
Please.
Aw! God, you're so...
Good.
Whoa!
Relax. Just me.
You ever been in love?
Nah. Never.
Bullshit.
You don't kill as many people
as I've killed
and still sleep like a kitten
if you feel shit like love.
Another textbook sociopath.
Clear.
All right, secure the roof.
Sweep for shooters
so we can bring in our aviation assets.
Going to the roof.
Oh. Wait here.
Please.
I don't wanna give this dude
a heart attack. Okay?
Aw, he's embarrassed of us!
Hey, Flag.
This dude better cure cancer
after all of this shit.
You ready? Let's go.
You wouldn't have made it without them.
We got lucky. I don't do luck.
I do planning and precision.
Admit it, Rick. I was right.
Yeah, I told you to get on the damn truck.
Why'd you stay?
I was studying your girlfriend.
She takes an average person,
a yoga mom, an elderly retiree,
and she turns them into a soldier
who can take a headshot and still fight.
It's an instant army.
How'd she do it, Flag?
How'd she game the system
with you watching her every move?
I'll accept the consequences.
I am your consequence.
You might need to be careful.
They think we're rescuing Nelson Mandela.
I can take care of myself.
Shut it down, wipe the drives.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Copy that.
Uh, hey, man. I know you can't hear me
'cause you're trapped
in your temple of soldierly
self-righteousness,
but a two-faced dude like you
wouldn't survive a second on the street.
Oh, says the guy
who shoots people for money.
My cards is on the table, man.
It got done, didn't it?
Damn. That is just a mean lady.
Yeah. You get used to it.
And I'm the bad guy?
That's gangsta.
What?
They weren't cleared for any of this.
Any of it.
Hey, I'm not judging.
I've buried a lot of mistakes, too.
No way.
Let's go home.
Yeah, let's go home.
That sounds good.
You guys wanna go home? Hmm?
Or you wanna go back to prison?
I'm not going back to prison.
What I'm saying is we kill the pair of 'em
now before they kill us.
I got this.
You all made it this far.
Don't get high-spirited on me
and ruin a good thing.
I like her.
Savior One-Zero,
this is Ground Element.
Savior One-Zero, how copy?
Savior One-Zero, the LZ's clear.
Boss, they're not talking to me.
Our bird's been jacked.
Light it up!
What? I got a hickey or something?
Professor,
could you pick up the pace?
Harley!
Hello, baby.
Kill her!
Her nanite's disarmed!
Come on, baby.
Deadshot,
shoot that woman right now!
She ain't do shit to me.
You're a hitman, right?
I got a contract.
Kill Harley Quinn.
Do it for your freedom and your kid.
Now she dead.
I missed.
Good one, mate.
It's Waller.
Savior One-Zero's been hijacked.
Shoot it down.
Roger that, ma'am. Going hot.
Puddin'!
You got all dressed up for me?
Oh, you know I'd do anything for you.
By the way,
I've got some grape soda on ice,
and a bear skin rug waiting.
Yeah?
Boss, we got a problem!
Huh?
- This bird is baked.
- No.
Okay, honey. It's me and you.
Let's do it.
Target destroyed, ma'am.
Thank you. Now get me off this roof.
Yes, ma'am. We are inbound.
The Joker and Harley Quinn are no more.
You couldn't save her.
Roger. I see ya.
Watch your step, ma'am.
Stand by. I'll send another helo!
Waller's down.
It's over.
Ops just confirmed. She's down. 1 k west.
Let's go get her.
The mission's not over.
Nah. It is for me. We had a deal.
Without Waller, you got nothing.
Hey, guys. I'm back!
I missed you all so much.
We're glad you could make it.
Hey, craziness.
With my heart returned,
I can finish my weapon.
Now tell me how to destroy your armies.
Do your worst, bitch!
So let me guess.
We're going to
the swirling ring of trash in the sky.
You know, 'cause why wouldn't we?
When does this end, Flag?
Load up. We're in for a fight.
You tell everybody everything.
Or me and you gonna go right now.
Three days ago,
a non-human entity appeared
in the subway station.
Waller, we're almost there.
So Waller sent me and a woman
with incredible abilities.
Enchantress.
A witch.
See, nobody could get near this thing,
but the witch could.
Bomb's ready.
Set for two seconds.
You just press the button and drop it.
Needless to say,
the whole thing was a bad idea.
She bolted!
Shit!
And that's how she escaped from Waller.
So now you know.
You can just kill me right now,
but I'm going to have a drink.
Hey, Deadshot, I need your help.
No, sir. You need a miracle.
What ya having, K.C.?
Bloody Mary, right?
Drink dulls the mind.
K.C., it's the end of the world.
Have a drink with us.
Beer.
There he is. Give the man a beer.
How about you, hot stuff?
Water.
That's a good idea, honey.
Ninja?
You want some sake?
Whiskey.
Okay.
What am I, 12?
Here's to honor among thieves.
I'm not a thief.
Oh. She's not a thief.
I actually prefer to think of myself
as an asset relocation specialist.
Mmm.
Well, we almost pulled it off
despite what everybody thought.
We weren't picked to succeed.
You know that, right?
We were all chosen to fail.
Yeah, I know that.
Worst part of it is, they're going to
blame us for the whole thing.
And they can't have people
knowing the truth.
We're the patsies.
The cover-up.
Don't forget, we're the bad guys.
So you gonna tell us now
what your "big deal" with Flag was?
Same thing Waller offered me, to kill you.
The chance to be a father.
Chance at a life outside the shadows.
I trusted Flag.
Flag had you
chasing a carrot on a stick, homie.
You don't... You don't know that?
I love this guy.
You played yourself, dawg.
Bitch, I'm having a drink.
I'm breathing fresh air.
And, uh,
for two sweet seconds...
I had hope.
You had hope, huh?
Hope don't stop
the wheel from turning, my brother.
Hmm. You preaching?
It's coming back around for you.
How many people you killed, man?
You don't ask nobody
no question like that, ese.
You ain't ever whacked down no women.
No kids.
I don't kill women or children.
I do.
See, I was born with the Devil's gift.
I kept it hidden
for most of my life, but...
The older I got, the stronger it got.
So I started using it.
For business, you know.
The more power on the street I got,
the more fire power I got.
Like, that shit went hand in hand.
You know? One was feeding the other.
Ain't nobody tell me no.
Except my old lady.
You know, she used to, uh, pray for me.
You're welcome.
Even when I didn't want it.
God didn't give me this.
Why should he take it away?
Hey.
This is our home.
You put that back where you found it.
I'm taking my kids to Mom's.
You ain't taking my kids nowhere!
See, when I get mad, I lose control.
You know, I just...
I don't know what I do...
till it's done.
And the kids?
He killed them.
Didn't you?
Own that shit.
Own it!
What'd you think was gonna happen? Huh?
Hey, Harley. Come on.
What, you were just...
Thinking you can have a happy family
and coach little leagues,
and make car payments?
Normal's a setting on the dryer.
People like us, we don't get normal!
Why is it always a knife fight
every single time you open your mouth?
You know, outside you're amazing.
But inside, you're ugly.
We all are.
We all are! Except for him.
He's ugly on the outside, too.
Not me, shorty.
I'm beautiful.
Yeah, you are.
We don't want you here.
You get to the part in that binder
saying I was sleeping with her?
Yeah.
I never been with a witch before.
What's that like?
Apparently, that's why the creatures
chase him all the time.
'Cause, uh, the witch is scared of him.
The only woman I ever cared about
is trapped inside that monster.
If I don't stop the witch, it's over.
Everything is over.
Everything.
You're free to go.
Your daughter writes you every day.
Every single day.
You had these the whole time?
You had letters from my daughter
the whole time?
I'm gonna get you there.
And you're gonna end this.
I'm gonna carry your ass if I have to.
'Cause this shit is gonna be
like a chapter in the Bible.
Everybody's gonna know what we did.
And my daughter is gonna know
that her daddy is not a piece of shit.
I'll come.
What?
You got something better to do?
Come on!
Pussies.
We think that thing's a weapon.
Here. Lower.
We gotta take out the big one.
I left a big ass demo charge
down there in that subway.
There's a flooded tunnel,
leads right underneath that building.
SEALs, they can recover the charge,
swim in underneath that thing's feet.
We get in its face and distract the hell
out of that son of a bitch
so the swimmers can blow the bomb.
That's how we take it out.
I'm going with ya.
We got this.
I'm not asking, bro.
I live underground.
Y'all are just tourists.
The man who killed her husband
used that sword.
His soul's trapped inside of it.
She talks to him.
Hey, well,
you know what they say
about the crazy ones.
Huh?
Let's do this.
You must really love this girl.
Man, I thought love was bullshit.
Dead serious.
Desire, mutual benefit, whatever.
I mean, I get that, but actual love?
I rated that with UFOs.
Lot of believers, no proof.
And then I met June.
Do what you gotta do.
I got your back.
You gonna fight with us?
What if I lose control?
Then maybe we'll have a chance.
Duck in.
Hey, everyone can see
all this trippy magic stuff, right?
Yeah. Why?
I'm off my meds.
So that's your old lady, huh?
Yeah.
Well, you need to handle
this shit, all right?
Get up there, smack on her ass,
tell her, "Knock this shit off."
I do not think that'd be wise.
I'm gonna draw out the big one.
My boys will detonate the bomb
underneath him.
You know, we should get a drink sometime.
I've been waiting for you all night.
Step out of the shadows. I won't bite.
Hmm.
What the hell? Grab her.
Why are you here?
Because the soldier led you?
And all for Waller.
Why do you serve those who cage you?
I am your ally.
And I know what you want.
Exactly what you want.
Baby. Baby.
Baby, it's just a nightmare.
It's just a bad dream.
I'm here.
Miss me?
I'll put the kids to sleep
and then maybe we can kick it?
Yeah?
I can't change what I did.
And neither can you!
He married me!
It's not real.
I killed the Bat.
Nah, homie. You don't want that.
What? I want that.
She trying to play games with you, man.
- It's not real!
- He's right.
It's not real.
How long have you been able to see?
My whole life.
You can't have them.
These are my people right here.
But it is our time.
The sun is setting, and the magic rises.
The metahumans are a sign of change.
Lady, you are evil!
Oh, wow.
Uh-oh.
Who's this?
- It's gonna be bad!
- We should run.
GQ, come in. We're in position.
We gotta get him in that corner.
That's where the bomb will be.
I'll do it! I'll get him there.
I lost one family.
I ain't gonna lose another one.
Look, think it through.
I got this.
Let me show you what I really am.
Over here!
Go!
Rick, in position. Standing by.
Diablo, drive him into the corner!
- Get him, mate!
- Come on.
Yeah, do it!
Diablo, get clear! Get outta there!
Blow it!
Blow it.
- Now, GQ. Now.
- No!
Everybody, down!
You next.
My spell is complete.
Once you and your armies are gone,
my darkness will spread across this world.
And it will be mine to rule.
That was our main satellite uplink.
How did this witch even know
how to target this thing?
It's a secret facility.
You got a move here, Flag?
We gotta cut her heart out.
While we're fighting,
that thing's laying waste
to the whole damn world.
Where is she?
I don't know.
Hey.
Look out. Look out!
Uh-oh.
Sorry.
Flag!
Enough!
Of all who have faced me,
you have earned mercy.
For the last time,
join me, or die.
I'm not much of a joiner,
but maybe we should.
Hey!
She's trying to take over the world.
So?
What's the world ever done for us, anyway?
It hates us.
Hey, Harley!
Hey, lady? Um...
I lost my Puddin'.
But you can get him back, right?
I can, my dear.
Anything you want.
You promise?
Yes, child.
You need only bow
and serve beneath my feet.
I like what you're sellin', lady.
There's just one teeny problem.
You messed with my friends.
Her heart's out! We can end this!
Hey, Croc!
Harley!
Please, Daddy. Don't do it.
The only way for us to be together
is if you don't pull the trigger.
Daddy, I love you.
Please, don't do this.
That was a great shot, man.
Hey, I don't do hugs. I'm not a hugger.
I'm not a hugger. All right?
Let me join my brother.
Katana, no!
Give me that.
You bring June back. You bring her back.
She's not coming back.
I'll crush this. Do you hear me?
You bring June back or I'll crush this!
Go ahead.
You don't have the balls.
Hey, Flag.
June!
She's gone.
I thought I killed you.
Y'all don't mind,
I got me a sewer to crawl back into.
Yeah, and I got some business to handle
back in Gotham.
I'm going to hotwire a car. Need a ride?
Your ass is not driving.
Why not?
How are you not dead?
We just saved the world.
A "thank you" would be nice.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, we did all of this
and we don't get shit?
Ten years off your prison sentences.
Nah, that's not enough.
I'm seeing my daughter.
That can be arranged.
Any other requests?
Ooh. An espresso machine.
BET.
Ten years off a triple life sentence?
Darling, I'm walking
out of here a free man
or we're going
to start having some real fun.
Why don't we have some fun?
You're trying to figure out this length.
That's the hypotenuse.
So, you have to know this angle.
Okay. So, if you're up here,
like in a building,
and you shoot a man
down here on the street,
that's how far the bullet actually goes?
Yeah. That's right.
You are so smart. Right.
The hypotenuse. Good one. Um...
So, that would make you
have to know the angle
between the building and the sidewalk.
You got to know that angle.
No, I mean, in real life,
you have variables.
You know, you got rifling twist.
You got chamber pressure.
You got bullet weight.
Some shots you'll even
have to take the curvature
of the Earth in with the...
It's time.
Wind effect.
You know, there's a lot of variables
in the street.
I gotta go.
Are you coming back?
Yeah.
I'm working it out. All right?
You know, I promised my friends
that I would just, you know, go,
without killing them all.
Bring it in.
I love you, Daddy.
Hmm.
I love you.
Hey! Let me out!
Let me out of here right now!
Hey! You feel that? Yeah.
Let me out of here, darling, please.
Please, I'm begging you, seriously.
Listen to me. Have you got a car?
Because I'm a brilliant driver.
Come on!
Puddin'!
Let's go home.
This is crown jewels here,
Mr. Wayne.
And you do understand my legal exposure.
If anyone knew what I procured for you...
Listen, I can keep a secret, okay?
What do you want?
People are asking questions
about Midway City.
The kind of people
who can get the answers.
And if they can get those answers,
my head will be on a pike.
Consider yourself under my protection.
If you deliver.
Why, Mr. Wayne?
Just like to make friends.
That's the difference between us.
You believe in friendship.
I believe in leverage.
Good night.
You look tired.
You should stop working nights.
You should shut it down,
or my friends and I'll do it for you.
Psagmeno.com
MOViE iNFO WiTH .srt FiLES!