According to legend,
in the late 19th century
something terrible happened,
to the Valdemars.
They were initiated
into the dangerous art of the occult,
and during a session,
awakened a being
far beyond their control.
The result of their boldness.
The beautiful Leonor was sacrificed.
Her bloodline would be forever joined
to the curse known as.
The Valdemar Legacy.
The Valdemar house
remained sealed for years.
No one dared go inside.
Until two weeks ago,
when an expert historian,
fascinated by its secrets,
ventured into the mansion.
He was never heard from again.
The legend was brought back to life,
and new faces appeared in the story.
Luisa Lorente,
an estate valuer sent to finish
the work of her predecessor,
found out what happened to him,
and met the mansions caretaker.
She would later escape,
but her whereabouts remain unknown.
Four days after she went missing,
her boss, Maximilian Colvin,
hired detective Nicolas Tramel,
to find her and put an end
to these strange disappearances.
Tramel set off,
on a bizarre journey to the house,
with Doctor Nora Cervia,
Maximilians assistant,
who told him about the Valdemar legend,
although she withheld,
certain secrets from him.
A similar fate awaits Eduardo and Ana,
Luisa's co-workers,
who dont understand
why the police haven't been involved
or why Maximilian has ordered them
to join the search immediately,
leaving that very night
forthe Valdemar house.
A mystery hidden in the shadows,
and the most horrible of all...
grows near.
THE FORBIDDEN SHADOW
Are we almost there, honey?
Civilization is nowhere in sight.
They probably speak
a different language out here.
Ana, whas wrong?
Did I say something?
No, honey, really.
We haven't done anything together
in three months.
I was hoping this weekend...
I know. This is just
something that happened.
- After we find Luisa...
- Thas another thing.
I dont mean her, its just...
I dont like how quiet
they're keeping this.
Inmoberance has always kept
a low profile.
We did sign a confidentiality clause.
The pay is great, the pension
couldnt be better...
But no questions asked.
What if we do ask?
What would be the answer?
Two cover-ups, no statements,
two people missing...
Were probably exaggerating.
Luisa isn't a child.
Watch out!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
- Where are you going?
- Stay here.
- Dont leave me.
- Hold on.
Shit.
Use your cell, call for help!
Ana, what is it?
You were telling me
about last year.
And after the divorce?
I was in Naples working on
the "Monster of Florence" case
and then I came here.
I opened my own detective agency and...
I think you know more about me now
than my own therapist.
Ls your turn.
You want to hear about me?
Im warning you, my life
isn't nearly as exciting as yours.
I was just hoping that...
we could set aside the formalities
and be a little more cordial.
We're having dinner.
Okay.
Tell me about the etchings
at the end
of the book.
I thought your job was clear.
Find a missing woman.
The other distractions are irrelevant.
And I thought you were obliged
to help me
- in any way you could.
- All right.
Anything to not have to listen
to you groan the whole way.
Les make a new deal.
I'll tell you more about the past
if we focus on the present.
I want to hear how you plan
to continue investigating.
Great.
Ls a deal.
Where am I?
My head...
Is okay. You're safe.
My name is Selene.
You had quite a fall.
This area is full of ditches and caves,
but you were lucky.
Ls just a scratch.
But youre still weak.
I made you some lemon balm
and natural boldo.
It will make you strong again.
Please, don't trouble yourself.
I can't stay.
Go ahead.
Its five miles of forest
in every direction.
The only path
leads to a large abandoned house.
But youve already been there,
haven't you?
What do you want from me?
I don't have anything.
Don't be ridiculous.
What would I want from you?
If you leave, theyll find you.
And trust me, they won't be as nice.
- How do you know?
- That they're after you?
Because youre not the first.
But we'll make sure you're the last.
After the Valdemar tragedy,
Lazaro tried to get his life back.
But instead of managing
his fortune intelligently,
he invested all his capital
in a strange, forbidden book.
Sir, you havent eaten in days.
For Gods sake.
This can't go on.
What you're doing is blasphemy.
An abomination.
Ill end up having to bury her
somewhere else.
Get out of here.
Get out.
Sir, Ive served you
since you were a child.
I saw you grow up and become a man.
But you're a stranger to me now.
And you scare me just as much as
the room you made me board up.
Get out!
Yes, sir. I'll go.
But first I have one thing to say.
She chose to die with pride.
She sacrificed everything for you.
She devoted her last breaths to you.
Believe me, she wouldn't want to see
what you're turning into.
Get out of here.
I said get out.
Never speak her name again.
Never.
Yes, sir.
I'm leaving.
She isn't dead.
You hear me, Jervas?
Leonor isn't dead!
I know what you mean.
The Necronomicon.
The Book of the Dead.
It has...
almost 10 pages about him.
Exactly.
He may have been persecuted
by the Church,
but he wasn't a Satanist
or anti-clerical.
His cult was based on the so-called
Great Old Ones,
Gods that precede any religion.
After searching for years,
he was finally
able to buy it from some merchants
in northern Iran.
What was never clear
is why he wanted it.
Maybe he had new plans
he thought it could help him with.
Right after that,
he regained his wealth and returned
to high society.
Hello!
Good evening.
Welcome. Good evening.
How are you?
Good evening.
I love the way you decorated.
Thank you.
Obviously a feminine touch.
If you'll excuse me...
Gentlemen.
Get your brother out of here.
How rude!
- Who is that?
- I dont know.
Lovecraft.
Come with me.
What are you doing here?
I don't recall inviting you.
Is that what bothers you,
or that I came?
What do you want?
Wherever I go...
Istanbul, Prague, Tehran...
Stop following me.
I'll never give you the Necronomicon.
I don't want you to.
I'm not here to ask you for it,
but to free you from it.
Money is no object, of course.
I'll pay anything you ask.
The problem is, I have no intention
of parting with it.
Is that so?
Could I at least examine it?
Just for a moment.
Then I'll go.
Definitely the real thing.
One of a kind.
I lied to you.
I cant afford to buy it.
Not even a fraction of its value.
Ls no secret youre broke, Lovecraft.
Everyone knows that.
Then you also know I've dedicated
my life to studying the Necronomicon.
Many a careless person
thought he could use it
to make money.
Isn't that your case?
Not at all.
I shall be its only owner.
Utter foolishness, my dear friend.
Indeed it is the book
that owns you.
Before I leave,
here's some advice
about how to use it correctly.
There's a universal code
that equally affects
all the occult.
One simple rule.
The laws of Nature cannot be altered.
Please, allow me to demonstrate.
This is a simple levitation trick.
Yes, the book floats.
But it is bound by
the forces of Nature: Gravity
and weight remain.
And yes,
it is enshrouded by magic,
but its effect is exclusive.
Gravity, the essence of Nature,
can never disappear.
When the spell wears off
the book once again
depends on its own weight.
Very good.
Thanks for the trick.
Trust me, I've seen
more spectacular displays.
Now please return the book to me.
I've been far too tolerant with you.
Incredible.
You offer advice
and end up lecturing me.
Enough is enough.
Please leave my home.
- I have guests to attend to.
- How odd.
You're just like the others.
You neither listen nor learn.
You're oblivious to the forces you're
dealing with, and you don't care.
This isn't mysticism,
is demonology.
No one,
absolutely no one who has handled
that book has survived.
Ive warned you a thousand times
and you always
reject me, making things
more complicated.
Mysteries and secrets
are everything to you.
- Secrets and mysteries.
- They aren't the same thing?
No.
Absolutely not. Mysteries
are wonders that can be pondered
and shared.
Secrets are a heavy burden
people carry by themselves.
Thas your problem.
A heavy burden on your shoulders.
Ls nothing compared
to whas in store for you.
Nothing!
- Any luck?
- Were you listening?
I was praying quietly,
asking God to restore sanity
to all this.
You must be Jervas,
the man who wrote to me
these last months
and asked me to come.
Yes.
Please forgive my boldness,
but you're my last hope.
I told my master
not to bother with all this,
that all this fear was unnecessary.
But...
I can't get through to him.
Ive never seen him like this.
He rejected the help of his friends
and took refuge in the comfort
of the unknown.
Then there will be plenty to fear.
I warned him, in any case.
There is a great deal at stake.
Hes lucky to have
a guardian angel like yourself.
But he must see the fine line
between perseverance
and sheer stupidity.
I'm sorry, sir.
Good evening.
Thank you, Mr. Lovecraft.
Goodbye.
- They didn't hit it off.
- No.
Oddly enough, because Lazaro
was the best of hosts.
He treated his guests exquisitely.
Then what happened?
How did it end?
You think we'd be here
if it were over?
Nothing will happen to you.
What is that?
I'm sorry, I'm pretty skeptical
about this stuff.
You don't need to believe,
but I must understand.
Choose seven cards.
There are three parts to Tarot:
Recent past,
present and immediate future.
Each part determines the next.
The first thing we need to see
is your recent past.
It marks the tone of the questioner.
Intelligence over
brute force, morality,
tranquility.
Continue.
The second card
shows your situation
in the recent past.
- The house.
- It means the end
of fortune, adversity,
chaos, professional issues.
Four days ago I was called to value
an old house, thas when it all began.
Not yet.
Dont tell me anything yet.
Pick up the third card.
People who have influenced you lately.
Acts of evil,
hatred, perversion.
It all coincides, doesn't it?
- Yes.
- Good.
Now you must tell me everything,
from the beginning.
Our stop.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Let me see.
It doesnt look bad.
Trust me, Ive twisted my ankle
a hundred times.
- Does it hurt to put weight on it?
- No.
Well?
Are you taking advantage
to get closer to me?
No first names,
but I can stroke your leg?
Fine.
No problem.
So what do we do now?
There's nobody around.
Except him.
Well walk, is not far.
The next day, I woke up
in a strange boarding house.
No telephone, no explanations, nothing.
So I tried to find a ride into town.
Hello?
Is anybody here?
Damaso, don't be angry.
It really hurts.
You scared me.
I thought I was alone.
I thought you were Damaso.
What are you doing here?
I was looking for a ride into town.
I think the car keys
are around here.
Thank you.
What are all these photographs?
People who have been through here.
I collect them.
They were all friends of mine.
There are 180 in all.
All friends of yours?
Thas a whole lot.
Yeah, 180.
Nice number, huh?
It sure is.
Trust me, numbers are important.
We all have one.
If you give me a photo,
I'll post it.
You'd be number 181.
What about these children?
They're police photos.
Missing people, hikers.
The rough terrain. Ls easy
to get lost around here. Look.
I volunteer for search parties.
Sometimes the police come and study them
to help with their cases.
All these missing people...
I can't believe this hasnt gotten out.
Have you called the press?
What for?
What do you mean?
To investigate.
They have no respect for anything
or anyone.
- No, but...
- Yeah, they've been here.
All they do is lie and make up stuff.
They don't care what happens.
They just want an excuse
to snoop around inside the house.
Shit...
Are you okay?
Yeah, sometimes my head...
What about them wanting
to get in the house?
Do you think maybe they already have?
- Don't you think?
- What?
Something may have happened to them.
If they minded their own business,
nothing would.
The fucking keys are gone.
Whas the problem?
I don't understand.
You've been nice to me,
- why not to them?
- Ls different.
You came here to work,
not to meddle.
You asked permission,
treated me with respect,
you were nice.
The others are fucking brats.
They don't give a shit.
I'm glad what happened did,
they deserved it.
What do you mean?
What happened to them?
Youre smart.
Take a guess.
No...
Thas impossible.
If something had happened to them
they would have found remains.
Bodies dont disappear just like that.
And the leftovers of the chicken
you ate last night?
Where are they?
Whas the matter?
What is it?
I didn't take my medicine.
I need my hearing aid.
My ears ring constantly.
You'll find something for the pain
in that cupboard.
And for the voices.
Take any of them.
The ones in the white bottle
calm me down.
These are for animals.
Give me the fucking pills!
No!
Dont take them!
What are you doing?
- You want to kill yourself?
- Dont shout at me!
You know what you just took?
These could kill you.
They're for animals, for horses!
God...
No.
What did you say?
Tell her the truth.
I said no at first.
But they made me eat them
during my initiation.
You can't imagine the feeling
when you taste them.
I dont know what you mean.
Ls only sometimes.
When he doesnt want them.
They make me.
What happened to all those children?
I couldn't help it.
Their meat has no fat,
or poison.
I mean...
adults...
aren't bad,
but children...
Children are caviar.
You shouldnt have come here.
They'll hurt you just like the others.
They'll feed you to it and then to me.
You must leave!
Hurry!
You had to screw it up, didn't you?
This is important!
I've told you a thousand times.
Talk, talk, talk!
You know what happens to people
who talk too much?
What do you want?
To know why she's here?
She knows about the party.
Everyone does!
The fat guy told me.
So you know what's at stake.
What happened?
It was Damaso.
Oh my God, darling.
We're so sorry.
You can't go on like this.
How many times has it been?
Telling the truth isn't cowardly.
You know hes not allowed to hurt you.
This is the last time, I swear.
I'm going to stand up to him.
No, you arent.
Not until you admit what you are
and face up to it.
Its time to stop being a child.
To grow up, not just get back
at that bastard.
You have to change your behavior,
be smarter than him.
Beat him at his own game.
You know what you're doing
isn't right.
We've talked about it many times.
This is your big chance
to redeem yourself.
Shes your main concern now.
She's been locked up for two days.
Remember what happened yesterday?
What do you want from me?
You didnt help her, you backed out.
That can't happen again.
You have to help her, free her.
Remember how she treated you?
Does she deserve what she has coming?
Ls true, she doesn't.
Act fast, while he's napping.
We're running out of time.
Go and then tell us everything.
Okay, I will.
Santi, look at me.
Before you leave, I want the little boy
to close his eyes...
and the man to open them again.
You can do it, Santiago.
Finish him off!
Kill him!
Carve him up
into little pieces!
Were proud of you.
Now youre acting like a man.
I have something for you
before you leave.
Shit!
It was my second day in captivity,
when suddenly...
What do you want?
Let me out!
Ls okay. Its me,
- Santi.
- Santi, please.
Get me out of here.
Keep quiet.
Damaso is downstairs.
Listen to me.
Ill help you,
but I don't have the key.
So we have to pick the lock.
I already tried, but I couldnt.
Find a wire or a hair pin.
A wire?
Theres nothing in here.
I havent got anything.
Look under the bed.
Under the bed.
The springs.
After the house, I fled through
the forest until I reached a road.
But I almost got run over by a car.
I know I fell on the asphalt,
but I was so dazed
I couldnt recognize the driver.
I managed to get away,
but I fell in a ditch.
The rest you know.
The rest is the present.
Its a bridge card that links
to the immediate future.
The wheel of fortune.
Upside down.
What is it?
Is something wrong?
I see sudden changes.
Unfavorable,
dangerous.
I think you should go.
They need you there.
Where? At the house?
Did you hear a word I said?
Wait a minute.
Of course.
You're one of them!
All this was just to keep me here,
- to gain time.
- No, no.
Thats not it, I swear.
I swear.
I see it all clearly in the cards.
Let me explain.
They...
the same ones, they drugged me
and stole my baby.
My son!
Thas why I said you werent the first.
You have no idea
what they're capable of.
I gave birth to my baby here.
By myself!
I tried to protect him,
but they found out about him
and there was nothing I could do.
I was terrified.
I know hes still alive.
Please.
I'm not going back.
But I promise...
I can't walk, but I can guide you.
There's a safe path,
it only takes an hour.
I need to know he's okay.
I can't help you.
I can't even help myself.
But youre in time. They still haven't
got the amount they need.
What if I tell you a secret about
what they were going to do to you?
What are you talking about?
Listen to me, sweetie.
Listen carefully
because your life is at stake.
You're not here by chance.
First let me say...
Is them! They've found me...
There's nobody here.
The light is on, but...
- Are you crazy?
- Who are you? What do you want?
Calm down!
We were looking for a hotel.
We got lost
and we saw the light on.
Put that down.
Wait a minute.
You're Luisa Llorente.
I can't believe we found you.
Everybodys looking for you.
We thought you were missing.
Listen, is okay.
Were from the foundation.
I'm Nora Cervia, the president.
And he's a cop, look.
You see?
Thank God!
Ls over.
Is that better?
Good.
Help me wake him up
and we'll figure out what to do.
Please, we have to leave.
We need to wake him up first.
He won't wake up.
Im sorry, Im really upset.
Wake up!
Come on... Please, react.
Olympus calling Mars, over.
This is Mars, over.
- Everything okay? Over.
- I can't complain.
My first time in the woods
and I've caught two prize specimens.
By the way, did one get away?
Curly blond hair, blue shirt.
Over.
You've got Luisa?
Thank God.
That fool Santiago let her go.
Wait till I get my hands on him.
I owe you one. Over.
Remind me to collect.
And don't you dare hurt Santi,
you hear me?
He has to be there.
We'll clear things up later.
Ill give you my position,
come and find me.
We have to carry these two.
Over and out.
Santi!
I have a girl here with me
asking for you.
She stopped by to say hello.
Santiago, sweetie. It's me, Nora.
Please, come and say hi.
Its about time.
Where have you been?
You shouldn't keep a lady waiting.
Santi.
What's wrong?
Don't you want to say hello?
And I thought
we were friends.
You're not even happy to see me?
Hello, Nora.
Nice to hear your voice.
Finally.
I thought you were avoiding me.
Listen.
I'll find the boss to get things ready
and I'll see you soon.
Big kiss. Bye.
Out.
I knew you'd come out
if you heard her voice.
Thas the problem
with a broken hearing aid.
You can't tell a walkie-talkie
from real sound.
Why did you say there was a girl
asking for me?
Because there is.
Please, don't hurt her.
I'm begging you.
Of course not.
Were going to be great friends.
Ls okay.
Everything will be fine, I promise.
You're lucky I was specifically told
not to touch you.
But I want you to know what will happen
if you screw me again.
Please, anything you want.
It won't happen again.
Please, don't hurt her.
Leave her alone.
The things I've had to put up with
over the years.
Youve never told me
about the raunchy stuff
you do. Anyway,
people are into different things.
I can admit that.
But I will not tolerate
being made a fool of
in front of them.
Santi, Santi, Santi.
I suggest you do the right thing.
Because the next head to roll
won't be plastic.
Youd better be ready
to do your job.
Wake up.
Its okay, is okay.
No sudden moves.
Theyre loose.
Get your hand loose.
Where are we and who are you?
I'm a cop. Do you know her?
Ana, wake up.
Is she Luisa Llorente?
The valuer?
Yes.
Luisa.
Luisa, wake up.
Ana, come on, wake up.
Ls okay.
Don't be frightened.
This room belongs to a sadist.
Im Nicolas Tramel.
I'm a detective.
And I've seen this before.
Though never like this,
with so many people.
This is what we call his playroom.
Somebody
scares the victims
and makes them beg.
Then they record the moment.
If you look closely,
the bars and chains are fake.
They create false hope
and they can play
over and over again.
A taser gun.
Ls charged.
Why are we here?
What is this place?
This must be the basement
of the Valdemar mansion.
How do you know?
Because I was valuing the house.
Why lock us in?
They didn't lock us in.
They kidnapped us.
What do you mean?
How do you know?
Because I disappeared four days ago.
And they locked me up,
among other things.
So I know what I'm talking about.
God!
- Who did that to you?
- Damaso.
The guy who locked us in here.
And trust me, this is nothing
compared to the rest of the place.
- The day I got here I found...
- Luisa, excuse me.
Tell us your adventures
some other time.
- We need to get out of here.
- Yeah, but how?
Okay, everybody calm down.
We don't know what they want from us.
All I know is
I was sent here by your boss,
Maximilian Colvin.
So I suggest we try
to figure this out together.
At least that way we'll be ready
for whatever happens.
All right?
You mean were somehow
involved in all this?
Yeah, but how?
The only thing we have in common
is we work together
valuing historic estates.
Besides, our supervisor is missing.
Orquicia isnt here.
- Pablo is dead.
- What?
What do you mean, dead?
I found him in the house.
Dismembered.
Please!
What about you?
You act like you knew him.
What does that matter?
There's still no link between us.
Well, there is now.
- Is everything ready?
- Yes, sir.
Everything is going
according to plan.
No.
How could I be so stupid?
When they told me about the case
they accidentally mentioned
Orquicia was missing.
I tried to find out more,
but they gave me the run around
and I got sidetracked.
Hours of myths and legends
on the train,
all just to keep me
from solving your case.
Can you get to the point?
Yeah.
A few months ago, Pablo and I
discovered that Inmoberance
was making a series of large
undetected money transfers.
They were so irregular
we thought we could set ourselves up
with a piece of the action.
The amount was always the same,
one million euros,
reaching a total
of more than 650 million euros,
ready to be transferred.
All we needed
was a plate to duplicate
the seal used on company documents.
Then, after the summer,
we found part of the plate,
but Pablo
lost interest and said that...
he had come across something
much bigger,
something much better than money.
He never told me what it was.
And I never heard from him again.
Until today.
After the summer.
Thas when we were in a meeting
and that guy showed up.
Remember?
A strange man walked in
and said we needed to value
the Valdemar mansion
as soon as possible.
Orquicia volunteered
and named us as his support team.
Wait a minute. This is all about
you two trying to embezzle money?
Take it easy.
And don't point at me.
What we had in mind
never got past the planning stage.
Yeah, and what about the plates?
The fat guy was capable of anything.
And involving us to get rid of him
isn't that far-fetched.
Yeah, right. First of all, the fat guy
had a name, and it was Pablo.
Have the decency to not insult him
in the grave.
Leave me alone!
First somebody tell me how the hell
they found out about something
that we were only considering.
I cant believe Im here
because of a couple of schmucks!
Take it easy!
Don't even talk to her.
Stop it! We all got each other
into this, like a vicious circle.
You, detective, got Orquicia into it,
who involved us
by naming us as his team.
We sent Luisa to value the house,
and when she went missing,
you were hired to find her.
Fuck!
Santiago.
Santi, is me, Luisa.
What are you doing?
- What if hes one of them?
- He is.
He helped me before.
But my adventures
- were boring you.
- Stop it.
Some of us
want to get out of here.
Santiago,
can you hear me?
Luisa. They caught you again?
Yeah, I'm afraid they caught us all.
Then we haven't got much time.
Can you open the door?
Yes, I can.
But if I do, I want you to do
- something for me.
- Anything.
Okay.
Here's the deal. I'll open the door
and show you the way to Luisa's car.
In return, you have to take
someone else with you.
Someone else?
There are more people locked up.
Promise me.
- Okay, we promise.
- Anything.
You promised.
You can't take it back.
Who is this kid?
Thank you, Santi!
I'm not a kid, I'm a man.
I can't see anything.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Lets go.
You promised.
You said you'd help.
Fuck the promise.
I'm getting out of here.
Eduardo, have you any idea
what Santiago is risking for us?
No, I don't. What I do know
is his friends locked us up.
I have no one to thank
for trying to escape.
Wait a minute.
- Come on. This way?
- Yes.
- Whas wrong?
- I dont want to leave the group.
Or you either.
Come on.
Honey.
Lets go.
Come on, quick.
Okay, Santiago.
Thats your name, right?
Santiago. I'm Nicolas.
Now tell me.
Who's coming with us?
Someone very special.
You're about to meet him.
Yeah, sure. He must be.
Hold on a minute.
I did some bad things.
I was ordered to kidnap a baby.
What are you talking about?
When I said no,
Damaso broke something in my ear.
The gypsys baby?
What did you do with him? Where is he?
He's downstairs sleeping.
This guys a fucking wacko.
Take it easy, okay?
Calm down.
He's our only way out of here.
And were still in time to stop
something terrible from happening.
I know you hate me.
But I stole him and hid him myself
to protect him from Damaso.
The baby had better be okay.
Go on.
I said move it!
And dont turn around.
Don't look at me, weirdo!
Ana, give me your hand.
We're not going the right way.
How do you know?
You... That way?
Were going that way?
Are you fucking nuts?
The exit is the other way.
No, we're close.
Ls down there.
Then we'll go out the other side.
How? I dont remember any back doors
in the plans.
There's a cave under the mansion
with an exit to the outside.
- Im not going in a cave.
- Me neither.
Ls less than a mile long
and it opens out into a clearing.
Ls the best short cut.
If you want, we can turn around
and cross the mansion.
- We have no choice.
- You believe him?
- What choice do we have?
- Les go.
- Follow him.
- Move it.
Come on!
Wait here.
They ordered me to keep him here.
I know is wrong
and his mothers
probably looking for him.
I don't know anything about babies.
But I did the best I could.
You have to take him with you.
Crazy son of a bitch!
- We're following this guy?
- You know the way out?
- Calm down!
- Shut up!
You don't, do you?
We have no choice.
Yes, we do.
Let him help us.
Okay, we have no choice.
Okay, well take him.
But you show us the way out.
Come on, les go.
Thank you. Thank you all.
Santiago, do you know why
they locked us up?
They don't tell me, but I can imagine.
Is it related
to them stealing the baby?
- I dont want to scare you.
- Enough nonsense.
Ls because these two bozos
tried to rob them.
You're getting on my nerves. I told you,
theres no way they could know.
- Of course not.
- Quiet!
We're entering the cave.
For your own good,
remain completely silent.
Trust me, you dont want to wake up
what sleeps in here.
Thanks for suggesting this route.
Ls the fastest and safest,
except for
total boneheads!
Typical troublemakers.
You never follow instructions.
Give me the flashlight, I'll lead.
- Give it to him.
- Take the fucking flashlight.
Take the baby. Careful.
What bullshit.
Come on!
Here... your baby.
Give me the flashlight.
Come on.
Quick, run!
Luisa!
Jump!
Come on, come on!
Hurry!
That way...
Come on, Eduardo!
I think is gone.
Eduardo!
Help!
The gun.
Please, help me!
- Eduardo!
- Ana!
Ana, no! Come on!
Calm down.
- What was that?
- I don't know, I swear.
- What the fuck was that?
- They never tell me anything.
What? You're the one who warned us.
Seriously, they never tell me anything.
But sometimes Damaso feeds it.
- What does he feed it?
- Let me go.
Ana.
Listen to me!
We need you here, okay?
Come on.
We have to go,
the batteries won't last.
Come on, les go.
Come on.
Careful.
Luisa, wheres your flashlight?
- I dont have it.
- What do you mean?
I don't know where it is.
- You left it behind?
- I dont know, okay?
What is this?
Whas she doing?
Where are you going?
Ana!
Ana! Ana!
Move.
Theres a way out.
Sir! They're here!
Come on, les go.
Thas enough bait!
Come on, move it.
Come on!
Quickly!
Move it.
Max, what the fuck is this?
Everything in due time.
Please.
Cooperate and nothing
will happen to you.
Santiago, please.
Good dog, good dog.
Maximilian.
I know you think we were stealing
from you, but we weren't.
You were wrong
all along.
What are you talking about?
The money.
We know about the 661 million
you were hording.
Who else is aware
of that figure?
Nobody.
Pablo and I, nobody else.
Not even Luisa,
or anyone else in the department.
Of course not.
By the way,
where is Eduardo?
He's dead.
He was killed by that monster
you keep in there!
Ana...
I see.
Im sorry to hear that.
I had other plans for him.
Son of a bitch...
We need you alive,
but not necessarily uninjured.
I'll tell you something
to spare you the trouble
of having to wonder.
You were very close.
You almost figured right.
But its not about money.
Trust me, numbers are important.
We all have one.
They still don't have
the amount they need.
Ls not 661 million.
Ls not an amount of money.
What kind of joke is this?
What do you want from us?
We haven't done anything!
Ls a very bizarre joke.
The kind that aren't funny at all.
They're looking for people.
The three of us,
with Pablo and Eduardo,
add up to 666.
- I don't get it.
- Those medallions...
Cthulhu!
It can't be.
Its an ancient cult
that required a certain number
of human sacrifices
to realize a series
of arcane invocations.
But is impossible.
Are you all crazy or what?
Your explanation
is just about the most simplistic
Ive ever heard.
We're not going to invoke anything.
On the contrary.
And now,
let us proceed.
There isnt time.
Lazaro Valdemar tried it
over a century ago
and failed. Youll only make
the same mistake.
I intend to correct a mistake,
not make one. Now enough chit-chat.
Max.
You'll never get away with this.
You can't cover up 666 disappearances.
That won't matter after tonight.
What is he saying?
- Where are you taking us?
- What?
Where are you taking us?
You son of a bitch...
Nora? Nora!
What the fuck is going on?
Nora!
What the hell is all this?
Sommelier.
Chamberlain.
Everything in order?
Yes, theyve found the incubus
in the abyss.
It was unconscious.
They managed to chain it up
without incident.
They're bringing it now.
Even better.
The scariest thing of all
ended up being
- the easiest.
- I have one question.
Weren't there four?
One died in the cave. If necessary
we can use a volunteer from the Order.
No, we cannot.
Bringing in outsiders is already
a mistake. They mustnt be mixed.
Ive had enough from you,
Chamberlain.
You've disrupted this ritual from the
start with your presumptuous attempt
to take my place in the Order.
When this is all over,
I'll think of what to do with you.
Prepare the trays.
Ls time to begin.
Now.
As you command.
Tarantulas from Innsmouth.
Eat them quickly, without fear.
The blood of the spiders...
- Nora!
... will put your senses to sleep.
- It will protect you.
- Nora!
Bring it, please.
It must be done quickly.
He's starting to doubt.
Nora!
Eat them.
No mind can bear
gazing upon our lords
without first going insane.
Listen to us.
That man may have his revenge...
and that we may be rewarded
by your resurrection.
Lazaro, youll have to stand
on the seal.
Finally,
after all these years,
well finish this once and for all.
A long time ago
those words were spoken to me
by a man just as obsessed as you are.
What makes tonight different
is I have nothing to lose.
On the contrary.
Its not that you have nothing to lose,
but that you have so much to gain.
Turn around.
Ana, is okay.
Calm down.
You'll be fine.
No one must interfere
in the sacrifice.
It can't be...
This is our demand.
Return the demon to the flames of Hell.
What happens next exactly?
Are things going okay?
The ritual to control the demon
has successfully begun,
but time mustn't be wasted.
We offer you the last souls
as an offering.
Let their blood be the river
that joins us.
Sacrificing the baby isn't essential,
its only a link.
It facilitates protocol
between worlds.
Its like a cover letter
to the Great Old Ones.
To show our lords
we worship and respect them.
Now it must be killed.
Quickly and without hesitation.
Then the last four victims are offered,
reaching the number 666.
Finally the Devil will fall
and the Great Old Ones
will rise for a new kingdom.
Run!
Stop!
Nobody move!
Chamberlain, whas happening?
Carelessness always precedes calamity.
The Great Old Ones
must never be mocked.
Come on, come on!
Sir... This way.
Nobody move!
We beg mercy of you.
As men we worship you.
We beg you to enslave us!
Sir, this must be stopped.
The ritual must be performed again.
We no longer need an infant.
The obelisk has been completed.
Those required by the ritual
have been killed by the devil.
Now is the time to make the request.
But please, quickly.
There's no time to lose.
In my right as a signatory,
I wish to make my request.
I ask you to stop
the invocation just performed
along with the curse on my family.
My love!
Leonor?
Leonor, whas wrong?
Sommelier, whas happening to us?
Sir, theres something
you must understand.
Your decline
was not due to witchcraft,
but to the very nature of time.
Without the curse,
you both return to your rightful age.
150 years old.
Wait a moment.
The agreement.
There might be time
for one last request.
Sir,
the Necronomicon
will soon be destroyed.
But as long as it remains active,
theres still hope.
There's time for one last prayer.
Do it.
No. All I want is to stop the aging.
Leonor,
my love.
I'll find a way
to stop the process.
No.
I dont want our family name
stained in blood any longer.
Their souls...
The Great Old Ones don't want them.
Free them.
Please.
How do you know?
I've spent the last 100 years
in Purgatory.
I never stopped hearing
their cries of sorrow and grief.
Yes, but...
There's still time for another request.
- Just one, my love.
- No.
Let two old people die
and the innocent souls
find their rest.
In my right as a signatory,
I wish to make
my last request.
I ask for
the release
of the souls
that have been sacrificed
for this
ritual.
Well, well, well.
Little Red Riding Hood
wants to fight the Big Bad Wolf.
I should have killed you
a long time ago.
You've caused nothing but trouble,
and tonighs little slip up...
Congratulations.
You got your way.
Oh, youve got a weapon.
Great.
I've got one too.
But mine is better!
What now, you moron?
Thats what you are, a fucking moron!
Thats why you'll always be alone.
Wait till you see the present
I got you.
Where do you want it?
Here? Here?
Carve him up into little pieces!
I might be crazy.
You've called me that before.
But you know what?
I think I've found
a cure for it!
Santiago.
- Can we help you?
- They're dead.
A bunch of people are dead.
Shit, he's bleeding again.
Santiago.
We'll get you to a hospital,
okay?
Give us your exact location.
Sir? Are you all right?
Wait till you see the present
I got you.
We're almost there.
Hang on a little longer.
We need a doctor. Over.
Sir, they've found the wounded.
- They're out of danger.
- So whas the bad news?
Ls worse than bad.
I've never seen anything like it.
There was a massacre in the ruins.
I couldn't even write the report.
Walter's counting the bodies.
Prieto couldn't take it.
I had to send him home.
Call for back up.
If is as bad as I think,
I don't even want to think about
what we might find under that trap door.
Ls Santiago.
We're here in Montenegro where something
shocking has just occurred.
The place is full of ambulances,
police, bodies and reporters.
- You can't be here.
- Something amazing has happened.
How is he?
He held on just to make sure
you were all right.
We're doing what we can,
but he's lost a lot of blood.
Let me through!
- Ma'am, you can't be here.
- Thas my son!
My baby!
I'm sorry, he just passed away.
I'm here, baby.
Its me, Mommy.
I'm here with you.
Santiago, sweetie.
Ls Mommy.
You'll never be alone again.
Ls impossible.
The ECG is unplugged.
Good morning.
I hope you're feeling better.
I know is inconsiderate of me
to ask you for a statement
in your condition,
but in extreme situations
if we wait too long
people forget things
that can be relevant.
What were they doing here exactly?
Were not sure.
There was a lot of confusion.
Please, do it later.
They need more treatment and rest.
Of course.
By the way,
the vultures just got here.
No talking to the press
until you talk to me first.
I'll be back with something to eat.
He's one of them.
He wants to see if you know anything.
How do you know?
They're nervous because
theyd never got this far.
They're worried that outsiders
may have survived.
Its of vital importance
that you stick together.
Be smart and play dumb.
Play dumb!
- Maam, wait...
- Well.
Victory in the face of horror.
I only came to make sure
you're all right.
I imagine you're frightened
and have a thousand questions.
Youre the man who came...
To the office? Yes.
And many other places.
It was my job, to observe you
without interfering.
To avoid distractions.
To lead us to slaughter.
Involving you in all this
was a serious mistake.
I tried to persuade Maximilian not to,
but he wouldn't listen,
as usual.
His death has ended a cycle.
Now another shall begin.
But it must be a clean break
from the errors of the past.
You understand, don't you?
And with a new guide.
A sommelier.
I have a proposition to make.
Join us. Join the Order.
It hasnt been easy,
but you would be welcome.
Are you joking?
Does it look like I am?
I think we all understand
the situation, dont we?
Considering how much you know,
Im doing you a favor.
Believe me, the alternative
would be much more
unpleasant.
Ls funny.
It looks like were going to have
to live in permanent uncertainty.
What do you mean?
Were not the only survivors of...
the horror.
Someone else
was compiling data,
taking notes about the foundation
to gain influence and embezzle money.
He planned to offer his findings
as a tribute to enter the Order.
No.
The fat guy never offered us anything.
He was trying to blackmail us.
I don't mean Pablo Orquicia.
Eduardo.
Eduardo kept it all.
Names, dates...
Orquicia only found out about
a small part.
He tried to make a buck.
We know where it all is.
And we'll make it public
if something happens to one of us.
Nice try.
You dont expect me to believe that.
- Ls a lousy bluff.
- What is?
The transfers to buy silence?
Birth certificates
belonging to 650 people?
Erasing public archives?
Should I go on?
Being held captive
brings out the honesty in people.
But if you want proof...
Here's some of the stuff he showed us.
He thought he'd get a chance
to talk to Maximilian.
You can keep those.
There are boxes full of them.
Why not go straight to the police?
Because we want to live free
of the threat of revenge.
If youre smart and leave us alone,
well play dumb.
But if you do anything stupid,
well get smart.
Be careful.
When you bite off
more than you can chew,
you might end up choking.
We're waiting for the witnesses.
What happened?
Will you make a statement?
How many people died?
What happened exactly?