(Flynn Ryder narrates)
This is the story of how I died.
Don't worry, this is actually
a very fun story. And the truth is, it isn't even mine.
This is the story of a girl named,
Rapunzel.
And it starts, with the sun.
Now, once upon a time, a single
drop of sunlight fell from the heavens.
And from this small drop of sun,
grew a magic, golden, flower.
It had the ability to heal the sick,
and injured.
Oh, you see that old woman,
over there?
You might want to remember her.
She's kind of important.
Well, centuries pass and a hop
skip and a boat ride away there grew a kingdom.
The kingdom was ruled by a beloved
King and Queen.
And the Queen, well she was about
to have a baby,
but she got sick,
really, sick.
She was running out of time.
And that's when people usually start
to look for a miracle.
Or in this case, a magic golden flower.
Ahhh, I told you she'd
be important.
You see instead of sharing the
suns gift,
this woman, Mother Gothel,
hoarded its healing power
and used it to keep herself
young for hundreds of years.
And all she had to do,
was sing a special song.
Mother Gothel: *Flower gleam and glow,
let your power shine*
*Make the clock reverse,
bring back what once was mine*
*What once was mine*
Flynn: All right, you get the jist. She sings
to it, she turns young, creepy, right?
We've found it!
Flynn: The magic of the golden flower,
healed the queen.
A healthy baby girl,
a princess was born.
With beautiful golden hair.
I'll give you a hint.
That's Rapunzel.
To celebrate her birth, the King and
Queen launched a flying lantern into the sky.
And for that one moment,
everything was perfect.
And then that moment ended.
Mother Gothel: *Flower, gleam and glow,
let your powers shine*
*Make the clock re...*
HUH!
(Baby cries)
Flynn: Gothel broke into the castle,
stole the child, and just like that...gone.
The Kingdom searched and searched,
but they could not find the Princess.
For deep within the forest
In a hidden tower.
Gothel raised the child
as her own.
*...bring what has been lost, bring back what
once was mine, what once was mine.*
Flynn: Gothel had found her new magic flower.
But this time she was determined
to keep it hidden.
Why can't I go outside?
The outside world is a dangerous place.
Filled with horrible, selfish people.
-You must stay here, where you're safe.
Do you understand, flower?
-Yes, Mommy.
But the walls of that tower,
could not hide everything.
Each year on her birthday, the King
and Queen released thousands of lanterns
into the sky.
In hope that one day, their lost
Princess, would return.
HAH!
Hmm, Well I guess Pascal's
not hiding out here.
GOTCHA!
That's twenty two for me.
How about twenty three,
out of forty five?
Okay, well, what do you want to do?
Yeah, I don't think so.
I like it in here and so do you.
Oh, come on Pascal, it's
not so bad in there.
*Sings "When will my life begin"*
*7a.m. the usual morning line-up*
*Start on the chores I sweep
'til the floors all clean.*
*Polish and wax, do laundry and
mop and shine up.*
*Sweep again, and by then
it's like 7:15.*
*So I'll read a book,
or maybe two or three.*
*Ill add a few new paintings
to my gallery.*
*I'll play guitar, and  knit, and cook
and basically.*
*Just wonder when will my
life, begin.*
*Then after lunch, it's puzzles,
and darts and baking.*
*Papier-mâché, a bit of ballet,
and chess.*
*Pottery, and ventriloquy, candle making.*
*Then I'll stretch, maybe sketch.
Take a climb, sew a dress, and I'll re-read the books.*
*If I have time to spare, I'll paint the wall
some more, I'm sure there's room somewhere.*
*And then I'll brush, and brush, and brush,
and brush my hair.*
*Stuck in the same place
I've always been.*
*And I'll keep wondering, and wondering,
and wondering...*
*Wondering, when will my life begin?*
*Tomorrow night, the lights will appear.*
*Just like they do on my birthday,
each year.*
*What is it like, out there
where they glow?*
*Now that I'm older. Mother
might just let me go.*
Wow!
I could get used to a view like this.
-Ryder, come on.
-Hold on.
Yep, I'm used to it.
Guys I want a castle.
We do this job, you could
buy your own castle.
Oh, hay fever?
Yeah.
Huh?
Wait, wait.
Hey, wait!
Can't you picture me in a castle of
my own?
'Cause I certainly can.
Oh, the things we've seen and
it's only eight in the morning.
Gentlemen, this is a very big day.
This is it. This is
a very big day, Pascal.
I'm finally going to do it.
-I'm going to ask her.
-RAPUNZEL!
Let down your hair.
It's time.
I know, I know. Come on, don't
let her see you.
Rapunzel, I'm not getting any
younger down here.
Coming, mother.
Hi, welcome home, mother.
Oh, Rapunzel. How you manage to do
that every single day,
without fail, it looks absolutely
exhausting, darling.
Oh, it's nothing.
Then I don't know why it
takes so long.
Oh, darling. I'm just teasing.
All right...so, mother.
As you know tomorrow is a very big day.
Rapunzel look in that mirror.
You know what I see?
I see a strong, confident,
beautiful young lady.
Oh look, you're here too.
I'm just teasing, stop taking
everything so seriously.
Okay, so mother. As I was saying, tomorrow...
Rapunzel, mother's feeling a little run down.
Would you sing for me, dear?
-Then we'll talk.
-OH! Of course, mother.
*Flower gleam and glow, Let your power shine,
Make the clock reverse, bring back what once was mine.*
*Heal what has been hurt, Change the fate's design.
Save what has been lost, Bring back what once was mine.*
-Rapunzel!
-So, mother,
Earlier I was saying that tomorrow was a
pretty big day, and you didn't really respond,
So I'm just going to tell you.
It's my birthday!
TADA!
No, no, no can't be.
I distinctly remember. Your
birthday was last year.
That's the funny thing about birthdays.
They're kind of an annual thing.
Mother, I'm turning eighteen.
And I wanted to ask,
what I really want for this birthday.
Actually what I want for
(Mumbles 'every birthday')...
Rapunzel please, stop with the mumbling.
You know how I feel about the mumbling.
Blah, blah, blah,...blah.
It's very annoying.
I'm just teasing, you're adorable
I love you so much, darling.
Oh, I want to see the floating lights.
-What?
-Oh,...
Well I was hoping you would
take me to see the floating lights.
Oh, you mean the stars.
That's the thing
I've charted stars and they're
always constant.
But these, they appear every year
on my birthday, Mother.
Only on my birthday.
And I can't help but feel that they're,
They're meant for me.
I need see them, Mother.
And not just from my window.
In person.
I have to know what they are.
You want to go outside?
Oh, why Rapunzel.
Look at you, as
fragile as a flower.
(Gothel Sings "Mother knows best")
*Still a little sapling, just a sprout.*
-*You know why we stay up in this tower*
-Rapunzel: I know, but...
*That’s right, to keep you safe,
and sound, dear.*
*Guess I always knew this day was coming.*
*Know that soon you'd want
to leave the nest.*
-*Soon, but not yet. Shhh..*
-But
*Trust me pet,
Mother, knows best.*
*Mother knows best,*
*listen to your mother.*
*It's a scary world
out there.*
*Mother knows best.*
*One way or another, something
will go wrong, I swear.*
*Ruffians, thugs, poison Ivy,
quicksand.*
*Cannibals, and snakes,
the plague...yes.*
*Also large bugs, men with pointy teeth.*
*And stop, no more,
you'll just upset me.*
*Mother's right here,
mother will protect you.*
*Darling here's what I suggest.*
*Skip the drama,
stay with Mama.*
*Mother, knows best.*
*Mother knows best.
Take it from your mumsey.*
*On your own, you won't survive.*
*Sloppy underdressed, immature, clumsy,*
*Please, they'll eat you up,
alive.*
*Gullible, naïve,
positively grubby.*
*Ditzy and a bit,
well, hmm vague.*
*Plus I believe, getting
kinda chubby.*
*I'm just saying,
'Cause I wuv you.*
*Mother understands,
Mothers here to help you.*
*All I have is one request.*
-Rapunzel?
-Yes?
Don't ever ask to
leave this tower, again.
Yes, Mother.
Ahh, I love you very much, dear.
I love you more.
I love you most.
Don't forget it.
*You'll regret it.*
*Motherrrrrrr.*
*Knows best.*
Ta, ta, I'll see you
in a bit, my flower.
I'll be here.
No, no no. This is bad, this is
very, very bad, This is really bad.
They just can't get my nose right.
Who cares.
Well it's easy for you to say.
You guys look amazing.
All right, okay. Give me a boost,
and I'll pull you up.
Give us the satchel first.
Wha..? I just...
I can't believe, that after all
we've been through together,
you don't trust me.
Ouch.
Now help us up, pretty boy.
Sorry, my hands are full.
What?
RYDER!
-Retrieve that satchel with any force.
-Yes, sir!
We got him now, Maximus.
Heeyah!
Heeyah! Come flea-bag, forward.
No.
No, stop it.
Stop it.
Give it to me.
HAH!
-AHHHHH!
-WHINNEYY!
Oh!
Alone at last.
(((CLANG!!!)))
Huh?
(((CLANG!!)))
Aah!
Okay, okay, I got a person
in my closet.
I've got a person in my closet.
I've got a person in my closet!
To weak to handle myself
out there, huh Mother?
Well, Tell that to my frying pan.
(((Clang!)))
Hmmm.
Rapunzel!
Let down your hair.
One moment, Mother.
I have a big surprise.
Uh, I do too.
Oh, I bet my surprise is bigger.
I seriously doubt it.
I brought back parsnips. I'm going to make
hazel nut soup for dinner, your favorite.
Surprise!
Well mother, there's something
I want to tell you.
Oh Rapunzel, you know I hate
leaving you after a fight.
Especially when I've done
absolutely nothing wrong.
Okay, I've been thinking a lot
about what you said, earlier.
I hope you're not still talking
about the stars.
Floating lights, and yes
I'm leading up to that.
Because I really thought
we dropped the issue, sweetheart.
No Mother, I'm just saying,
you think I'm not strong enough
to handle myself out there.
Oh darling, I know you're not strong
enough to handle yourself out there.
-But if you just...
-Rapunzel, we're done talking about this.
-Trust me,...
-Rapunzel.
-...I know what I'm
-Oh, come on.
-Enough with the lights, Rapunzel.
You are not leaving this tower,
EVER!
Oh, great. Now I'm the bad guy.
All I was gonna say, mother
is that...
I know what I want for my
birthday, now.
And what is that?
New paint. That paint made from
the white shells you once brought me.
Well that is a very long trip,
Rapunzel.
Almost three day's time.
I just thought it was a
better idea than, uh, stars.
You sure you'll be all right,
on your own?
I know I'm safe, as long
as I'm here.
I'll be back in three days time.
I love you very much, dear.
I love you more.
I love you most.
Okay.
Hmm.
AHHH!
Is this...hair?
Struggling...struggling is pointless.
Huh?
I know why you're here.
And I'm not afraid of you.
What?
Who are you, and how
did you find me?
Ah hah.
Who are you, and how
did you find me?
I know not who you are.
Nor how I came to find you.
But may I just say.
Hi!
How you doing?
The name's Flynn Ryder.
Flynn mumbles:
How's your day going, huh?
Who else knows my location,
Flynn Ryder?
-All right, Blondie.
-Rapunzel.
Gesundheit, here's the deal.
I was in a situation,
Gallivanting through the forest.
I came across your tower and...
Ho, oh no, where is my satchel?
I've hidden it, somewhere you'll
never find it.
It's in that pot, isn't it.
(((Clang!!)))
Huh?
Ahh, will you stop that.
Now it's hidden where you'll never find it.
So, what do you want,
with my hair?
-To cut it?
-What?
-Sell it?
-No!
Listen, the only thing I want
to do with your hair,
is to get out of it.
Literally.
Wait, you don't want my hair?
Why on earth would
I want your hair?
Look, I was being chased, I saw a
tower, I climbed it, end of story.
You're, telling the truth?
Yes.
Hmmm.
I know, I need someone
to take me.
I think he's telling the truth, too.
Doesn't have fangs,
but what choice do I have?
Uh, okay Flynn Ryder,
I'm prepared to offer you a deal.
-Deal?
-Look this way.
Oh...oomph!
Do you know what these are?
You mean the lantern thing
they do for the princess?
Lanterns...
I knew they weren't stars.
Well, tomorrow evening
they will light the night sky,
with these lanterns.
You will act as my guide,
Take me to these lanterns,
and return me home safely.
Then, and only then, will
I return your satchel to you.
That is my deal.
Yeah, no can do.
Unfortunately, the kingdom and I
aren't exactly, simpatico,
at the moment. So I
won't be taking you anywhere.
Something brought you here,
Flynn Ryder.
-Call it what you will, fate, destiny.
-A horse.
So I have made the decision to
trust you.
A horrible decision, really.
But trust me, when I tell you this.
You can tear this tower apart,
brick by brick.
But without my help, you will
never find your precious satchel.
Let me just get this straight.
I take you to see the lanterns.
Bring you back home,
and you'll give me back my satchel?
I promise.
And when I promise something, I never
ever break that promise.
EVER!
All right, listen, I didn't want
to have to want to do this,
but you leave me no choice.
Here comes the 'smolder'.
This is kind of an off day for me.
This doesn't normally happen.
Fine, I'll take you to see the lanterns.
Really!
-Ooops.
-You broke my 'smolder'.
You coming, Blondie?
*Look at the world so close, and I'm
half way to it*
*Look at it all, so big
do I even dare?*
*Look at me, here at last
I just have to do it.*
Should I? No.
Here I go.
(Laughs)
*Triumphant music*
(Rapunzel sings When will my life begin)
*Just smell the grass, the dirt.
Just like I dreamed they'd be.*
*Just feel that summer breeze.*
*The way it's calling me.*
*For like the first time ever,
I'm completely free.*
*I could go running, and racing,
and dancing...
*and chasing, and leaping
and bounding.*
*Hair flying, heart pounding
and splashing and reeling.*
*And finally feeling,*
*That's when my life
begins.*
I can't believe I did this.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I DID THIS!
Mother would be so furious.
That's okay, what she doesn’t
know won't kill her, right?
Oh my gosh, this would kill her.
THIS IS SO FUN!
I am a horrible daughter,
I'm going back.
I am never going
baaaccckkk!
I am a despicable human being.
WAHHOOOOO!
Best day, ever!
You know, I can't help but notice,
you seem a little at war
with yourself, here.
-What?
-Now, I'm only picking up
bits and pieces,
of course, over protective mother,
forbidden road trip.
I mean, this is serious stuff.
But let me ease your conscious.
This is part of growing up.
A little rebellion, a little adventure.
That's good, healthy even.
(Laughs) You think?
I know. You're way over thinking
this, trust me.
Does your mother deserve it?
No.
Will this break her heart
and crush her soul?
Of course.
But you just got to do it.
Break her heart?
-In half.
-Crush her soul?
Like a grape.
She would be heart broken,
you're right.
I am, oh my, oh bother.
All right, I can't believe I'm
saying this, but...
I'm letting you out of the deal.
-What?
-Flynn: That's right.
Flynn: But don't thank me. Let's
just turn around,
and get you home, here's
your pan and your frog.
I get back my satchel.
You get back a mother
daughter relationship
based on mutual trust and viola!
We part ways as unlikely friends.
-No, I am seeing those lanterns.
-Oh, come on!
What is it going to take
to get my satchel back?
I will use this.
Is it, ruffians, thugs?
Have they come for me?
Stay calm, it can probably smell fear.
Oh, sorry.
Guess I'm just a little bit, jumpy.
Probably be best if we avoid
ruffians and thugs, though.
(Laughs)
Yeah, that probably be best.
Are you hungry?
I know a great place for lunch.
-Where?
-Oh, don't you worry.
You'll know it when you smell it.
Oh, a Palace horse.
Where's your rider?
Rapunzel.
RAPUNZEL!
Rapunzel, let down your hair.
Rapunzel?
Rapunzel!
RAPUNZEL!
I know it's around here, somewhere.
Ah, there it is.
The Snuggly duckling.
Don't worry, very quaint place,
perfect for you.
Don't want you scaring, and giving
up on this whole endeavor now do we?
-Well, I do like duckling.
-YAY!
Garcon, your finest table, please.
(Gasps)
You smell that?
Take a deep breath through the nose.
Really let that seep in.
What are you getting?
Because to me, it's part man smell.
and the other part is
really bad man smell.
I don't know why, but overall,
it just smells like the color brown.
Your thoughts?
That's a lot of hair.
She's growing it out, is that blood
on your moustache?
Goldie, look at this, look at
all the blood on his moustache.
Look sir, that's a lot of blood.
Hey, you don't look so good, Blondie.
Maybe we should get you home.
Call it a day.
Probably be better off. This is a five
star joint after all.
And if you can't handle this place, well
maybe you should be back in your tower.
Is this you?
No, no this is being mean.
Oh, it's him all right.
Gretel, go find some guards.
That reward's going to
buy me a new hook.
I can use the money.
What about me?
I'm broke.
-Boys, stop!
-We can work this out.
Hey, leave him alone.
-Gentlemen, please.
-Give me back my guide, ruffians.
HOO, HAH, HOO, HOO!
Not the nose, not the nose,
not the nose!
Put him down!
Okay, I don't know where I am,
and I need him to take me to see the lanterns,
because I've been dreaming about
them my entire life.
Find your humanity.
Haven’t any of you ever had a dream?
I, had a dream.
Once.
(Song: I've got a dream)
*I'm malicious mean and scary.*
*My sneer could curdle dairy.*
*And violence-wise my hands
are not the cleanest.*
*But despite my evil look,
and my temper and my hook.*
*I've always yearned to
be a concert pianist.*
*Can't cha see me on the stage
performing Mozart.*
*Tickling the ivories,
'til they gleam.*
*Yep, I'd rather be called deadly.*
*For my killer show-tune medley.
Thank you.*
*'Cause way down deep inside
I've got a dream.*
*He's got a dream,
he's got a dream.*
*See, I ain't as cruel and
vicious as I seem.*
*Though I feel like breaking femurs.*
*You can count me with the dreamers.*
*Like everybody else,
I've gotta dream.*
(Singing in distance)
*I've got scars and lumps and bruises.*
*Plus something here that oozes.*
*Let's not even mention
my complexion.*
Big nose thug: *But despite my extra toes.*
*And my goiter and my nose.*
*I really want to make a love
connection.*
*Can't you see me with a special
little lady.*
*Rowing in a row boat,
down the stream.*
*Though I'm one disgusting blighter.*
*I'm a lover, not a fighter.*
*'Cause way down deep
inside, I gotta dream.*
*I gotta dream,
I gotta dream.*
*And I know one day
will never reign supreme.*
*Though my face leaves
people screaming.*
*There's a child behind
it dreaming.*
*Like everybody else,
I've gotta dream.*
*Tor would like to quit
and be a florist.*
*Gunther does interior design.*
*Ulf is into mime,
Attila’s cupcakes are sublime.*
*Bruiser knits, Killer sews.*
*Fang does little puppet shows.*
*And Vladimir collects
ceramic unicorns.*
What about you?
-I'm sorry, me?
-What's your dream?
No, no, no. Sorry boys,
I don't sing.
*I have dreams like you,
no really.*
*Just much less, touchy-feely.*
*They mainly happen somewhere
warm and sunny.*
*On an island that I own,
tanned and rested and alone.*
*Surrounded by enormous
piles of money.*
*-I've got a dream...I've got a dream.
-(Thugs) She’s got a dream.*
*I just want to see the floating
lanterns gleam.*
*And with every passing hour.*
*I'm so glad I left my tower.*
*Like all you lovely folks,
I've got a dream.*
*She's gotta dream, He's gotta dream.
They've gotta dream, we've gotta dream.*
*So our differences ain't
really that extreme. We're one big team.*
*Call us brutal, say sadistic
and grotesquely optimistic.
*'Cause way down deep inside,
we've gotta dream.*
*We gotta dream,
I gotta dream.*
*Yes way down deep inside
I've got a...*
*Dreeeeeeaaaaamm.*
Yeah!
I found the guards.
Where's Ryder,
where is he?
I know he's in here somewhere.
Find him, turn the place
upside down if you have to!
Go, live your dream.
I will.
Your dream stinks,
I was talking to her.
Thanks for everything.
I believe this is the man
you're looking for.
You got me.
Sir, there's no sign of Ryder.
Maximus.
What's he doing?
A passage, come on men,
let's go.
Corman, make sure those
boys don't get away.
Play it safe.
We'll go get the crown.
I gotta dream,
I got some dream.
I..., ohhh, somebody get me a glass.
Because I just found me a
tall drink of water.
Oh stop it, you big lug.
Where does that tunnel lead out?
Knife!
Well, that got us safe.
Didn't know you had that in you
back there. That was pretty, impressive.
I KNOW!
I know...
Sooo, Flynn.
Where are you from?
Whoa, whoa, sorry Blondie,
I don't do back story.
However I am becoming very
interested in yours.
Now I...I know I'm not suppose
to mention the hair.
-Nope.
-Or, the Mother.
-Uh, uh.
-Frankly I'm to scared to
ask about the frog.
-Chameleon.
-Nuance.
Here's my question though, if you want
to see the lanterns so badly,
why haven't you gone before?
Uhh, hey, well...
Uh, Flynn...
Flynn!
Run,
RUN!
Who's that?
They don't like me.
-Who's that?
-They don't like me either.
-Lets just assume for the moment,
that everyone here doesn't like me.
Here.
I've waited a long time for this.
Oh mama, I have got to get me
one of these.
HAH!
You should know that this is
the strangest thing I've ever done.
How 'bout two out of three?
Flynn!
Flynn, look out.
-Whoa, WHOAAA!
-Hold on.
You should see your faces.
Because you look...
Ridiculous
Come on, Blondie.
Jump.
It's no use,
I can't see anything.
Hey, there's no point.
It's pitch black down there.
This is all my fault.
She was right, I never
should have done this.
I'm so...
I'm so sorry, Flynn.
Eugene.
What?
My real name is,
Eugene Fitzherbert.
So you might as well know.
I have magic hair that glows
when I sing.
What?
I have magic hair,
that glows when I sing.
*Flower gleam and glow.
Let your power shine.*
We made it.
Her hair glows.
We're alive.
I'm alive!
I didn't see that coming.
You're hair actually glows.
-Eugene...
-Why does her hair glow?
-Eugene!
-What?
It doesn't just glow.
Why is he smiling at me?
I'll kill him.
I'll kill that, Ryder.
We'll cut him off at the kingdom.
And get back the crown, come on.
Boys.
Perhaps you want to stop acting
like wild dogs chasing their tails,
and think for a moment.
Oh, please there's no
need for that.
Well if that's all you desire,
then be on your way.
I was going to offer you something
worth one thousand crowns,
would have made you
rich beyond belief.
And that wasn't even the best part.
Oh well, C'est la vie.
Enjoy  your crown.
What's the best part?
It comes with revenge
on Flynn Ryder.
So you're being strangely cryptic as  you wrap
your magic hair around my injured hand.
Sorry.
Just don't, don't freak out.
*Flower gleam and glow*
*Let your powers shine*
*Make the clock reverse*
*Bring back what once was mine.*
*Heal what has been hurt.*
*Change the fates design.*
*Save what has been lost.*
*Bring back what once was mine.*
*What once was mine.*
-Ah...
-Please don't freak out.
Ahhh. I'm not freaking out,
are you freaking out?
No, I'm just very interested in your hair.
and the magical qualities that it possesses.
How long has it been
doing that, exactly?
Forever, I guess.
Mother said when I was a baby
people tried to cut it.
They wanted to take it for themselves.
But, once it's cut.
It turns brown, and looses its power.
A gift like that, it has to be protected.
That's why Mother never let me...
That's why...I never left the...
You never left that tower.
And you're still gonna go back?
No...yes.
It's complicated.
So, Eugene Fitzherbert, huh?
Ah yeah, well. I'll spare
you the sob story of
poor orphan Eugene Fitzherbert, it's
a little bit of a...
It's a little bit of a downer.
There was this book.
A book I used to read every
night to all the younger kids.
The tales of Flynnigan Ryder.
Swashbuckling rogue,
richest man alive.
Not bad with the ladies either. Nothing
to ever brag about, of course.
Was he a thief too?
Ahh, well no.
Actually, he had enough
money to do anything that he wanted to do.
He could go anywhere that
he wanted to go.
And...and, for a kid,
with nothing.
I don't know, I...
It just seemed like a better option.
You can't tell anyone,
about this, okay?
It could ruin my whole reputation.
Ahh, we wouldn't want that.
Oh, the thing about a reputation,
it's all that a man has.
(Laughs)
Um, well I should uh...
I, I should get some
more firewood.
Hey.
For the record, I like Eugene Fitzherbert
much better than, Flynn Ryder.
Well, then you'd be the first.
But, thank you.
Well, I thought he'd never leave.
Mother?
Hello, dear.
But I...I..., don't we...
How did you find me?
Oh, it was easy really.
I just listened for the sound of
complete and utter betrayal,
and followed that.
-Mother...
-We're going home, Rapunzel.
-Now.
-You...You don't understand.
I've been on this incredible journey.
And I've seen and learned so much.
I even met someone.
Yes, the wanted thief.
I'm so proud.
-Come on, Rapunzel.
-Mother, wait.
I think
I think he likes me.
Likes you? Please, Rapunzel,
that's demented.
-But mother, I...
-This is why you never should have left.
Dear this whole romance that
you've invented,
just proves you're to naive to be here.
Why would he like you?
Oh come on now, really.
Look at you, you think
that he's impressed?
Don't be a dummy, come with mommy.
*Mother...*
-NO!
-No?
Oh.
I see how it is.
*Rapunzel, knows best.*
*Rapunzel's so mature, now.*
*Such a clever grown up, miss.*
*Rapunzel knows best.*
*Fine, if you're so sure now.*
*Go ahead then give him, THIS!*
How did you?
*This is why he's here.*
*Don't let him deceive you.*
*Give it to him, watch, you'll see.*
-I will.
*Trust me my dear, that's
how fast he'll leave you.*
*I won't say I told you so...no.*
*Rapunzel knows best.*
*So if he's such a dream boat.*
*Go and put him, to the test.*
-Mother, wait.
*If he's lying, don't come
crying.*
*Mother, knows best.*
So, hey uh, can I ask you something?
Is there any chance that I'm going
to get super strength in my hand?
Because I'm not going to lie.
That would be stupendous.
Hey, you all right?
Oh, sorry, yes.
Just um, lost in thought,
I guess.
I mean because here's the thing.
Superhuman good looks,
I've always had 'em.
Born with it, but superhuman strength?
Can you imagine the possibilities, I'm just...
Patience boys. All good things
to those who wait.
Hmm, what?
Well I hope you're
here to apologize.
AAAAAAAH!
No, no put me down.
Stop it. Let...me...go!
-Give me, him.
-OW!
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Easy boy, easy,
calm down.
Easy boy.
Easy.
That's it.
Now sit.
-Sit.
-What?
Now drop the boot.
Drop it.
Oh, you are such a good boy.
Yes you are.
You all tired, from chasing the bad
man all over the place?
Flynn: Excuse me?
Nobody appreciates
you, do they?
Do they?
Oh come on, he's a bad horse.
Oh, he's nothing but
a big sweetheart.
Isn't that right?
Maximus.
You've got to be
kidding me.
Look, today is kinda the
biggest day of my life.
And the thing is, I need you
not to get him arrested.
Just for twenty four hours and then,
you can chase each other to
your hearts content.
Okay?
And it's also my birthday.
Just so you know.
OOMPH!!
(Mouths) WOW
Ahh!
Sorry.
(Flynn whistles)
Thank you.
It's for the lost Princess.
(Snickers)
To the boats
Hey, Max.
What? I brought them.
Most of them.
Where are we going?
Well, best day of your life.
I figured you should have
a decent seat.
You okay?
I'm terrified.
Why?
I've been looking out the
window for eighteen years.
Dreaming about what it would feel
like when those lights rise in the sky.
What if it's not everything
that I dreamed it would be?
It will be.
And what if it is?
What will I do then?
Well that's the good part,
I guess.
You get to go find a new dream.
*Solemn Music*
(Rapunzel sings, "I see the Light")
*All those days
Watching from the windows.*
*All those years
Outside looking in*
*All that time
Never even knowing*
*Just how blind I've been
Now I'm here*
*Blinking in the starlight
*Suddenly I see
Standing here*
*It's oh, so clear
I'm where I'm meant to be*
*And at last, I see the light
And it's like the fog has lifted*
And it's like the sky is new*
*And it's warm and real and bright
And the world has somehow shifted*
*All at once
Everything looks different*
*Now that I see you*
I have something for you, too.
I should have given it to you
before, but I was just scared.
And the thing is,
I'm not scared anymore.
You know what I mean?
I'm starting to.
*All those days
Chasing down a daydream*
*All those years
Living in a blur*
*All that time
Never truly seeing*
*Things, the way they were
Now she's here*
*Shining in the starlight
*Suddenly I know
If she's here*
*It's crystal clear
I'm where I'm meant to go*
*And at last, I see the light*
*And it's like the fog has lifted*
*And it's like the sky is new*
*And it's warm and real and bright
And the world has somehow shifted*
*All at once
Everything is different*
*Now that I, see you.*
*Now that I...see you.*
Is everything okay?
Huh? Oh yes.
Uh, yes of course.
I just...
I'm sorry, everything is fine.
There's just something I
have to take care of.
Okay.
I'll be right back.
It's all right, Pascal.
Ahh, there you are.
I've been searching everywhere for
you guys. Since we got separated.
Hey the sideburns are coming
in nice, huh?
- Uploaded by: ChE -
0neClickMovies.blogspot.com
You gotta be excited about that.
Anyhow, just wanted to say,
I shouldn't have split.
The crown is all yours.
I'll miss you, but I think
its for the... best.
Holding out on us again?
Hey, Ryder?
-What?
-We heard you found something.
Something much more valuable
than a crown.
We want her, instead.
I was starting to think you
ran off with the crown and left me.
He did.
What?
No.
He wouldn't.
See for yourself.
Eugene?
Eugene!
Fair trade.
A crown, for the girl
with the magic hair.
How much do you think someone
will pay to stay young and healthy forever?
No, please.
NO!
AHH!
Rapunzel!
Mother?
Oh, my precious girl.
Mother.
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
-Mother, how did you?
-I was so worried about
you dear.
So I followed you.
And I saw them attack you.
All right, let's go, let's go
before they come to.
You were right, mother.
You were right about everything.
I know darling.
I know.
Look!
The crown.
Rapunzel.
RAPUNZEL!
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
Guys, guys.
Rapunzel!
Let's get this over with, Ryder.
Where are we going?
Oh...
There, it never happened.
Now, wash up for dinner.
I'm making hazel nut soup.
I really did try, Rapunzel.
I tried to warn you,
what was out there.
The world is dark, and selfish,
and cruel.
If it finds even the slightest
ray of sunshine.
It destroys it.
How did you know about her?
Tell me, now!
It wasn't us.
It was the old lady.
Old lady?
Wait, no, wait!
You don't understand,
she's in trouble.
Wait!
Rapunzel?
Rapunzel, what's going on up there?
Are you all right?
I'm the lost princess.
Oh, please, speak up, Rapunzel.
You know how I hate the mumbling.
I am the lost Princess.
Aren't I?
Did I mumble, Mother?
Or should I even call you that?
Oh, Rapunzel, do you even hear yourself?
Why would you ask such
a ridiculous question?
It was you!
It was all, you.
Everything I did, was to protect you.
-Rapunzel.
-I spent my entire life,
Hiding from people who
would use me for my power.
-Rapunzel!
-And I should have been hiding.
From you.
Where will you go?
He won't be there for you.
What did you do to him?
That criminal, is to
be hanged for his crimes.
-No.
-Now, now. It's all right.
Listen to me.
All of this is as
it should be.
NO!
You were wrong about the world.
And you were wrong about me.
And I will never let you
use my hair, again!
You want me to be the bad guy?
Fine.
Now I'm the bad, guy.
What's this?
Open up.
What's the password?
-What?
-Nope.
Open this door.
Not even close.
You have three seconds
One...
Two...
Three...
(((Clang!)))
Frying pans.
Who knew, right?
AAAAH!
(Thug roars)
-Head down?
-Head down.
-Arms in?
-Arms in.
-Knees apart?
-Knees apart.
Knees apart?
Why do I need to keep my
knees apar...
AAAAAAAAH!
Max.
You brought them here?
Thank you.
No really, thank you.
Uh, I feel maybe this whole time
we've just misunderstanding one another.
And we're really just, yeah
your right. We should go.
Max.
Max!
WHOAAAAA!
Okay Max, lets see how
fast you can run.
Rapunzel.
Rapunzel, let down your hair.
Rapunzel, I thought I'd never
see you again.
Now look what you've done,
Rapunzel.
Oh don't worry, dear.
Our secret will die with him.
And as for us?
We are going where no one
will ever find you, again.
Rapunzel, really.
Enough all ready.
Stop fighting me.
NO! I won't stop.
For every minute of the rest
of my life I will fight.
I will never stop trying
to get away from you.
But, if you let me save him...
I will go with you.
No. No, Rapunzel.
I'll never run, I'll never
try to escape.
Just let me heal him. And
you and I will be together.
Forever, just like you want.
Everything will be
the way it was.
I promise.
Just like you want.
Just...let me...heal him.
In case you get any ideas
about following us.
Eu..Eugene!
Ah, AHHH!
Oh, I'm so sorry.
-Everything is going to okay, though.
-No, Rapunzel!
-I promise, you have to trust me.
-No..
-Come on.
-I can't let you do this.
And I can't let you die.
-But if you do this.
-Shhh.
-Then you...will die.
-Hey.
It's gonna be all right.
Rapunzel, wait...
Eugene, what...?
NOOO!
No...NO!
What have you done?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE!
No, no, no,
NOOO!
No, no, no, noooo.
NO!
Noooooooooo!
No, no, no, no, Eugene.
Oh, look at me, look me,
I'm right here.
Don't go, stay with me, Eugene.
*Flower gleam and glow,
Let your powers shine*
*Make the clock reverse,
bring back what once was mine.*
-Rapunzel...
-What?
You were my new dream.
And you were mine.
*Heal what has been hurt.*
*Change the fates design.*
*Save what has been lost.*
*Bring back what once was mine.*
What once was mine.
Rapunzel?
Eugene.
Did I ever tell you, I've
got a thing for brunettes?
(Eugene narrates)
Well, you could imagine what
happened next.
The kingdom rejoiced.
For the lost Princess had returned.
The party lasted an entire week.
And, honestly I don't
remember much of it.
Dreams came true
all over the place.
That guy went on to become the
most famous concert pianist in the world,
if you can believe it.
And this guy? Well he eventually
found true love.
As for this guy, well,
I assume he's happy.
He's never told me otherwise.
Thanks to Maximus, crime in the kingdom
disappeared almost over night.
As did most of the apples.
Pascal?
Never changed.
At last Rapunzel was home,
and she finally had a real family.
She was a Princess worth
waiting for.
Beloved by all, she led her kingdom
with all the grace and wisdom that
her parents did before her.
And as for me, well.
I started going by Eugene again.
Stopped thieving, and basically
turned it all around.
But I know what the big question is.
Did Rapunzel and I ever get married?
Well I'm pleased to tell you.
That after years, and years of asking,
and asking, and asking.
I finally said yes.
*Eugene*
All right, I asked her.
And we're living happily ever after.
Yes, we are.