[ Woman ]
Let me go, just for a minute.
[ Man ] You're going to stare
that baby right into a coma.
Stop exaggerating.
It's not good to check
the baby every five minutes...
imagining one terrible thing
or another.
I know, I know.
Here it starts.
Here we go.
Rudyard--
Rudyard, she's not breathing.
Honey, she's sleeping.
The baby's sleeping.
No.
Rudyard, it's crib death.
It's sleep!
She's asleep, honey.
Maybe.
Come on.
Emma.
[ Baby Cries ]
Oh, good.
There.
That's better.
No, thank you.
Thanks.
Emma?
Uh, he was one of
the most dependable men...
that ever worked for me.
I know. Thank you.
He was a good man.
I'm real sorry
about your daddy.
Take care of your momma.
Emma.
Emma, wake up, please.
Wake up.
What's wrong?
I was tense,
and I was wondering
how you were feeling.
Would you like
to sleep in my bed?
No, thank you.
Would you like to sleep
in my bed again?
Yes!
What are we going
to do with this hair?
Hey, Emma!
Patsy, hurry up!
You're going to miss him.
Oh, that's what
they were looking at?
Good night, honey.
Where's Momma?
Back with that old fart who's
trying to get in her pants.
Wait for the astronaut.
Oh, they got one on
every corner in Houston.
Say hi to Race.
Love ya.
Astronauts!
So?
We better get going.
I'll say good-bye
to my mother.
Want to go with?
No. I don't think
I'm up to it today.
Sure would be nice to have
a mother somebody liked.
Why don't you
face up the fact...
that you have
certain biological needs?
Because I don't.
Mom! I'm going now.
Excuse me.
Can you believe it?
He wants to take me to Tahiti.
I don't know why you
treat these men like this.
They have feelings, too.
Has the astronaut moved in yet?
Who?
Who? Is Patsy teaching
you coy lessons?
Breedlove, Garrett.
Next door.
Has he moved in?
Put your socks up!
Say good-bye to Patsy.
Be home by 11:00.
Good-bye, Patsy!
[ Patsy ]
Good-bye, Mrs. Greenway.
[ Ethel Merman
Speaking On Record ]
[ Emma Mimicking Merman ]
In this day and age, anything goes.
[ Singing Along ]
# Times have changed #
# And we've often rewound the clock #
# Since the Puritans got a shock #
# When they landed on
Plymouth Rock #
# If today #
# Any rock they
should try to stem #
# Instead of landing
on Plymouth Rock #
# Plymouth Rock#
# Would land on them ##
I feel foolish getting stoned
to hear Mary Martin.
See, Patsy,
this is Mary Mar--
This isn't Mary Martin.
This is Ethel Merman.
## [ Continues, Indistinct ]
This is the last time
we'll be like this.
I just plain refuse...
to get into that
kind of thinking.
It shouldn't stop.
I mean, we will be best friends.
Our babies will be best friends.
We'll all be best friends.
Emma?
Oh, God!
Just a minute.
Open the door.
Uh,
Emma, open the door.
Just a minute.
I need to talk to you!
All right.
I'm getting married.
What the hell.
Meet me in my room?
Yes.
What do you think she wants?
Maybe she's going
to tell you how to have sex.
No. She only knows
how to avoid it.
I can't believe
you said that.
I didn't mean it.
I swear.
What have you
been doing, Emma?
Nothing.
What is it, Momma?
I really want to get some sleep...
so I look halfway decent
for tomorrow.
Come on.
What is it?
Would you want me to be
silent about something...
that's for your own good?
Yes, ma'am, I would.
Okay, come on.
I've been in here all night.
I've been trying
to decide what--
what wedding gift
to get you.
I thought of that Renoir
that my mother gave me.
But I couldn't reach a conclusion.
Then I came to grips
with the reason why...
I couldn't think
of your wedding gift.
It's all right.
I need dishes,
Corningware,
a rotisserie--
the car,
a house.
Emma,
I'm totally convinced...
if you marry Flap Horton tomorrow,
it will be a mistake
of such gigantic proportions,
it'll ruin your life and
make wretched your destiny.
Why are you doing this to me?
You're not special enough...
to overcome a bad marriage.
Emma, use your brains.
Flap is limited.
He has no imagination.
All he wants
is a secure teaching job.
Mother,
I'm marrying Flap tomorrow.
I thank God Flap's
getting me out of here.
If this is your attitude,
don't come to my wedding.
Hmm,
that-- that's right.
No, I think you're right.
The hypocrisy
was bothering me, too.
My own mother's
not coming to my wedding.
[ Telephone Rings ]
[ Ring ]
Listen to her.
She's going crazy.
I'll give her until
noon tomorrow.
Emma, your mother
boycotted your wedding,
she hates your husband,
and she only holds you
in medium esteem.
[ Chuckling ]
Medium esteem.
That is so cute.
[ Ring ]
Wouldn't it have been strange...
if one of us married
a person who didn't read?
[ Ring ]
There's millions
of interesting people...
who never pick up a book.
[ Ring ]
Flap, I feel so
totally good about us.
I hope I get
pregnant tonight.
That would be nice.
Ah-choo!
Emma,
I love the way you look.
Uh,
you were--
you're so nice.
I'm--
You're my sweet-ass gal.
Oh.
Ah-choo!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Here comes the bride!
How do you do that?
Flap, where did you
learn how to do that?
## [ West Side Story,
"Officer Krupke"]
That is the strangest music
to make love to.
I know.
[ Ring ]
Leave me alone.
I'm happy.
I don't want to talk to you.
Did you see the tablecloth
Rosie gave me?
It's got red flowers on it.
She made it.
No, not yet.
I made omelets.
I started them.
Kind of Tex-Mex.
No.
That was the worst thing...
you've ever done to me.
I think you owe
my husband an apology.
Until you apologize,
I won't listen to your gossip.
He's right here.
Hold on.
Yes.
No.
No!
Yes!
Hello, Mrs. Greenway.
No, ma'am, I am not
enjoying your predicament.
Momma, be nice!
As a matter of fact,
I don't need an apology.
All I want is
for you to understand...
and appreciate my position,
to respect our marriage,
and to wait another 15 minutes...
before you call in the morning.
Yes, I guess I've said my piece.
Okay. I'll put her on.
He's so great!
I'll talk to you later.
[ Male Voice ] I don't care
about the neighborhood.
Can't you stay
a little while longer?
I thought we were
having a real good time.
Don't go yet.
One more minute.
I've got something to show you.
No, really.
Thanks.
Good night.
I bought you something.
What?
A tie.
Emma,
you didn't buy this for me.
You were worried about
how I'd look to your mother.
Now, stop being a quisling
where she is concerned.
Why is it whenever I get
happy, you turn perverse?
Buying this made you happy?
Yes. Yes!
I wish you could understand this,
'cause you really don't.
It made me very happy,
buying this tie.
I went to two or three places
before finding it.
Then describing your jacket
to the salesman,
and knowing
how perfect it would match.
Which, by the way,
it certainly does.
I mean, it was fun!
It was a goddamn Mardi Gras!
You're too dumb to understand
that kind of happiness.
I'm sorry.
I'm being terrible.
Going to your mother's,
it makes me
a little irrational.
Can I help?
Yes. Thank you, Flap.
Take this candle.
I need another one.
In the kitchen?
Yes.
That looks great.
Who's that short gentleman?
Not that it's any
of your business, but--
Just leave it at that.
What are you looking at?
She isn't there anymore.
She'll be back.
I'm Edward Johnson,
Aurora's friend.
Pleased to meet you.
Vernon Dahlart.
God, isn't she something?
Here she comes.
I met her two weeks ago
at church.
You might say she's
God's gift to Vernon Dahlart.
Then you like her?
Oh, no. Does it show?
Good food.
I served this
when I lived in Boston.
Vernon, you haven't said a word.
Is that right?
I feel like
I haven't stopped talking.
I guess because I've been
thinking about you so much.
Can I suggest
how to handle me?
Yes, ma'am.
Don't worship me
until I've earned it.
Thank you, ma'am.
I appreciate any advice
you can give me.
Don't talk
with your mouth full, Vern.
[ Vernon ]
I wouldn't do that.
I just did it to make you laugh.
What's wrong with you?
I got some good news.
What's that?
I'm unofficially pregnant.
We haven't gotten
the tests back yet,
but you know me--
I'm never late.
Well,
I don't understand.
Um, if you're not happy for me--
I'm going to get so mad
if you're not happy.
Why should I--
Why should I be happy
about being a grandmother?
You won't be knitting
the baby any booties?
Flap,
every time you get
more than two drinks,
you confront me.
And I won't have it.
I won't have it,
not in this house.
Excuse me.
[ Car Approaches ]
Do you need some help?
No. I'll be fine,
as soon as I stretch my legs.
Oh, God.
Mr. Breedlove.
You're bleeding.
Yeah.
It's okay.
Come on in.
No, thank you.
What are you afraid of?
Afraid?
Well,
why not--
Why not come on in?
Because you're much older
than the boys I date,
'cause you're drunk,
and because when I went
to see an astronaut...
give a lecture,
I didn't expect him
to prowl after us.
I didn't expect some silly flirt...
to keep his jacket open...
because his belly's
getting too big.
I expected a hero.
Well, okay, Doris, don't come in.
I don't want you in my house.
Lee Anne, would you like
to come in?
You better tend to that cut.
Tommy, show me your belly.
Come on.
How can you dress him like that?
He's adorable.
Look at him.
Oh.
Oh, great, Tommy.
Uh-oh.
[ Telephone Rings ]
That's Vernon.
So tell I'm, uh--
Out?
[ Ring ]
No. Tell him I'm resting.
Hello.
Hi, Flap.
Where?
No. Tell me now.
I want to know now.
Oh, Flap, you didn't
expect I'd be happy.
Let's be honest
with each other...
before we start pretending.
Um, look, Mom's
staring at me right now,
so can I talk about it
later to you?
Yeah.
All right.
Bye.
How long are you going
to keep this a secret?
The only school accepting Flap
for his associate professorship...
is in Des Moines.
He can't even do
the simple things,
Iike fail locally.
It's going to be fine, Momma.
It's Des Moines.
Say, "Bye-bye, house."
Bye-bye, house.
Be careful going down
these steps.
Don't break your leg.
Come here.
[ Rosie ]
Stay sweet, honey.
Rosie--
Uh, that's enough, Rosie.
They have to get started.
Tell Momma to drive you home
when you work late.
Have some fun, Rosie.
Don't act so brave.
I know you'll go crazy
without me to nag.
You be good to her
or else we'll get you.
I mean it.
Bye, Flap.
Have a good drive.
Okay, fingers and toes in.
Take Momma's purse.
Momma, that's the first time...
I stopped hugging first.
I like that.
Get yourself
a decent maternity dress.
Had to get one in, didn't you?
Did you tell her, Patsy?
She keeps thinking it's me.
Tom,
will you be good
to your mother...
and take care of her?
Bye, Mrs. Greenway.
Good-bye.
Write when you get there,
so I'll have your address.
You shape up, Patsy.
Oops!
Dropped my gum.
We'll get you another piece.
The phone bill will be
enormous, you know that?
I'll miss you, Momma.
Can we go now?
Yeah. Pull away slow.
[ Flap ]
It will be good for us...
to be away from your--
From our families.
I miss Houston.
You don't know
how lucky you are.
Everybody wants to go
to Des Moines.
People come to get
one look at Des Moines...
before they die.
Some people say
it's the best city in Iowa.
I know you're teasing me.
Texas is the best!
I think you should stop worrying.
You'll see some
terrific new things.
We are.
[ Garrett ]
Oohhh!
Ahhooo!
Whoo!
Would you please, if you will,
hold it down over there?
Sorry, I can't hear you.
Hold it down!
Have some respect
for other people's feelings!
Come over a little closer.
Hey, you in the bush,
I can't hear you.
I took a sauna.
It's hard not to yell...
when you hit cold water.
You're ignoring me
when I speak?
What am I supposed to say?
It's hard not to yell...
when you hit cold water.
Hey, uh, come here.
Come here?
What is your name?
Aurora?
Yes.
You-You want a shock?
No, not especially.
What?
Well, we're going to have this...
dinner at, uh--
NASA dinner at the White House.
You know, some cosmonauts,
and all of us--
I didn't know
who I could take.
All the people I flew with,
their wives are giving me
bitch bites all over my back...
if I show up
with one of my regular girls.
I didn't know
anybody old enough,
so I thought, "Well, I'll ask
my next-door neighbor."
Well, anyway, they
canceled the dinner,
but I was really thinking
about asking you out.
Seriously.
Ain't that a shocker?
Yes.
Imagine you having a date
with someone...
where it wasn't necessarily
a felony.
What would you have said
if I asked you?
Seriously.
I would've said I'd like
to see the White House.
So you would've come.
What the hell.
You want to have dinner
out sometime?
No, thank you.
What about lunch?
You ladies, you like
to have lunch a lot.
There's something
about your manner.
It's like you're trying
to toy with me.
That's right, Aurora.
I'm playing with you.
This is the element.
Do you want to play, Aurora?
Want to have lunch?
We'll have lunch.
If you want to have lunch
in some restaurant...
to improve the atmosphere
in this neighborhood,
I wouldn't exactly say no.
Come here.
We're too far apart to talk.
Now,
Aurora,
since you've agreed,
why don't we just
forget about the rest?
I mean, I know how you feel.
There were countdowns
when I had my doubts.
I said to myself,
"You agreed to do it.
"You're strapped in,
"and you're in the hands...
"of something bigger and
more powerful than yourself.
"So, uh, why don't you just...
Iay back and enjoy the ride??"
I'm not going.
There's something
wrong with you.
Oh, God.
I'm such a shit.
[ Flap ]
Wait! That must be it.
[ Emma ]
Right there? Oh, God!
Flap, it's great.
Is that it, really?
Oh, it's great.
Isn't that sweet?
Oh, that was a bump.
Oh, yeah.
What is that?
Shall we go see the house?
You stay there.
Come on.
Let's get this off.
Whoa! Come on.
Oh, sweetheart,
did you hurt yourself?
Nope, not yet.
Do you like it?
Oh, it's great.
Flap, it's great.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
Oh!
Leave the mattress here.
We can sleep here.
I'm really tired.
Ow! Ow!
You ever made love in Iowa?
Tommy's room is on
the other side of the hall,
so we can get noisy.
Good. You get to make
your little high-pitched squeak.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Flap, what about you?
What about you?
Here I come.
Here I come again.
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
Here I come again.
Yes.
Oh, God.
You just made me wet.
How can you do that
with your voice?
You just make
your voice like that.
If Tommy can't hear us,
we can't hear Tommy.
He's fine, Mother.
Don't get pissy.
I'll be right back.
# The bells are ringing #
# For me and my gal #
# The birds are singing #
Sing with me!
# Everybody's a-goin' #
# To a weddin' #
# They're knowin' #
# And for weeks they been callin' #
# Every Susie and Sal ##
I have papers to grade.
This isn't love, it's selfishness.
It's been a week
since we've been together.
We've never gone a week.
Sure, we have.
Only in the real pregnant months.
You're always getting home late.
Do me a favor.
Don't make me feel silly,
I won't make you feel guilty.
Fair enough.
I have to hurry.
Be a good boy.
Emma?
I love that you came back.
You're saving our lives
by doing this.
Tommy, breakfast
will be ready in a minute.
Hurry. I've got
to grade those papers.
I'll give everybody a "B".
Come on.
No, wait.
Emma, come on.
Emma!
Wait. Wait.
[ Emma Squeaking ]
[ Splashing In Swimming Pool,
Garrett Shouting ]
[ Splashing,
Woman Squealing ]
[ Ring ]
Hello.
Hi, Mother.
Could we talk later?
I've got to get the boys off.
Don't be so inconsiderate.
I'm all set to have a good talk.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Stop right here.
Tell me what it is.
Okay, Mother.
I need some money.
I need you
to loan me some money.
I really need it, so will you?
Oh, Mother, please don't be quiet.
You know that was hard for me.
You can say no,
but please don't be quiet.
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I was just thinking.
Thinking what?
How much I hate
to part with money.
I wouldn't have asked if--
Don't yell,
but I think that
I may be pregnant again.
Oh! No!
And you're going
to have it, I suppose.
Yes, of course.
What's happening to you, anyway?
Don't act like that's so terrible.
Bright young women
are having simple abortions.
Simple?
Then they get wonderful jobs.
You can have it in Colorado.
Why do I tell you anything?
I like you less and less.
You know why, Emma?
It's because only I
tell you the truth.
Go get dressed.
How will your life get better...
if you keep having his children?
What miracle will come
to rescue you?
Leave me alone.
I need the money.
Give me the painting to sell.
No! That's your security.
I will not have you
using that for rent.
Let's not do this.
All right?
I'll talk to you later, all right?
All right.
If the money would mean--
No, don't. It would
make you crazy.
Yes, it would.
We'll talk later.
Call me tonight if you want.
Good-bye.
Daddy just got home.
Hey, no kidding?
Is it tough being a genius?
Boy.
Great news.
I know what my topic is.
I have it all figured out.
What's wrong?
Where have you been
all night, Flap?
I fell asleep on that big sofa...
at the library again.
I don't know
what's wrong with me.
I'm on to you.
I'm not doing anything.
Oh, yes, you are.
We go through this stage every--
Don't change the subject.
What's the subject?
That I'm on to you.
You wouldn't look so innocent...
unless you were guilty.
You'll have to
take my word for it.
You have no other choice.
No, no, no.
No, no, no!
Whoa!
Excuse me.
Emma, you always
get a little paranoid...
in your first few months, okay?
Just--
If you are doing something...
and trying to make me
feel crazy because I'm pregnant,
you may have sunk so low...
you'll never recover.
You may have just panicked,
and trying to save yourself,
you've thrown out
your character and principles.
The only way you could
redeem yourself...
is to admit anything...
that you might have
been doing last night.
If you don't do that,
you are a lost man.
A shell.
A bag of shit dust.
You've got to tell me.
For us, honey.
[ Telephone Rings ]
Hello.
Hello, Aurora.
How are you?
Yes, she's--
She's right here.
Nice to hear your voice again.
[ Flap ]
Why don't you get a job?
[ Emma ]
What about the baby?
It's a great day
when you get tenure!
All tenure means...
is we won't have
enough money forever!
Why won't you ask your mother?
At your convenience, right?
Go ahead! Call her!
Why should today be any different?
Get on the phone, Emma!
Why don't you call?
Yeah, I'll call Aurora, right?
Get on the phone!
Get on the phone, Emma!
Get on the damn phone!
Mommy said to wait right here.
Just stay if you want.
What are you guys doing here?
I said to wait
in front of the house.
Answer me, Tommy.
I didn't want people
to think we lived there.
Cut it out.
You're allowed to say
one mean thing to me a year.
That'll do till you're ten.
You're driving Daddy away.
Tommy, stand up and follow me.
Don't make me hit you.
Hurry up.
I said hurry. Come on!
$44.
20, 30...
Let's see.
That's 38, 40--
You don't have enough money?
I don't have any checks,
so I'll put some things back.
Can I have the register key?
She doesn't have enough money!
It's no big thing.
I brought the wrong purse.
Here, take this.
$43.75.
$41.35.
Mom, you promised
I could have something.
I won't give her real food.
Give her this.
No way!
$40.35.
Mom!
All right.
Here.
$40.55.
$40.75. We're going
in the wrong direction.
Why must you be so nasty?
I mean, it's not going
to help anything.
We're both people, you know?
$40.75.
I don't need it.
Mrs. Horton,
I'm Sam Burns from the bank.
I turned down
the second on your house.
Oh, of course.
I remember who you are.
Can I help you
make up the difference?
Thanks. I'd appreciate it.
I'll pay you back tomorrow.
You're a very rude young woman.
I know Douglas from the Rotary.
I can't believe he'd want you
treating customers so badly.
I don't think I was
treating her badly.
Then you must be from New York.
Be careful, Teddy!
What?
Be careful!
Where's your car?
Right here.
That was worst time I've ever had.
I didn't know I could get
cheered up so fast.
No problem.
Come on, Mom.
Wait by the car.
Come on.
Wait.
No.
Wait by the car, honey.
But--
Wait, honey!
Over by the car!
Now!
Nice boys.
You're great with them, too.
Really.
I think all three of us
are going through a stage.
Hey, thanks again.
Oh, no thanks required.
I've had a lovely time.
Me, too.
I'll get the money back to you.
You can drop it
in the mail, if you like.
To the bank?
Sure. You could even use
a check-by-mail envelope.
Or, uh, you could come in.
Whichever.
Maybe I'll come in sometime.
Well, that'd be fine.
Can I help you with that?
No, thanks.
I'm used to this.
And so another birthday...
for a gal named Aurora Greenway.
Even though 50,
she still takes my breath away.
Mere mortals just gaze
as she lights up their sky.
A heavenly object, a siren's cry.
You're the best.
Happy birthday.
Thank you, Edward.
Thank you.
Do you want one, Vernon?
Would you like a kiss?
You're not lying
about your age, are you?
Of course not.
I thought you were 52.
How do you expect
to fool a family doctor?
She said her age.
The number doesn't matter,
but its concealment does.
Why does he keep talking?
Dr. Ratcher--
The way to adjust to old age--
Doctor, I think
you're a mite confused...
because of being
recently widowed and all.
[ Tapping On Window ]
You okay?
Hmm?
[ Vernon ]
Aurora?
Let's give her some privacy.
[ Buzz ]
Yeah?
The door's open.
Just a minute.
Well, hello.
Hi.
I was curious if you still
wanted to take me to lunch.
I wasn't aware that we--
A few years back,
you invited me to lunch.
A few years back?
Does the invitation still exist?
Would you like to?
To lunch.
Not dinner, remember.
It was lunch.
Why not? No.
Good.
When?
Uh--
Tomorrow?
All right.
Good.
12:30?
12:00.
Good.
If you mind the open air,
I could get the top.
No. Don't worry.
Grown women are prepared...
for life's little emergencies.
Us going out together--
Not bad, huh?
Do you think,
could you possibly put the top up?
The top's at home in the garage.
Hello. How are you?
How are you, Ali?
It's nice to see you.
[ Woman ]
That guy, Fred, at that bar?
He asked me out.
[ Woman #2 ]
Oh, God.
He took me to the Cadillac Bar.
It's a fun place...
if you're with the right people,
but I wasn't.
Well,
I'm starving.
No hidden meaning
in that remark.
Well, uh--
Would you like an oyster?
No.
Thank you.
It's good.
I think that is extremely rude,
noticing other women
when you're with me.
I, um...
think we're going
to have to get drunk.
I don't get drunk,
and I don't care
for escorts who do.
You got me into this.
Trust me about this one thing.
You need a lot of drinks.
To break the ice?
To kill the bug
that you have up your ass.
May I get you something?
I will have some bourbon,
preferably Wild Turkey.
Aurora?
You're not fun,
by any chance?
We shouldn't think
about that right now.
Impatient boys
sometimes miss dessert.
[ Honk ]
We both got here
at the same time.
Hi, Sam.
It's nice to see you.
It's always nice to see you.
I can hardly believe it.
You, too.
What I didn't expect was
that there'd be moments...
where I'd forget to be scared...
that someone
would see us together.
You don't have to be scared.
Contemplating sin
is all we've done.
I'm glad you've been
contemplating it, too.
I didn't know that.
Well, all these lunches,
all this hand-holding.
I'm not going
back to the bank this afternoon.
I have to go out
and inspect a new house.
It's pretty far out, and--
Well, it's empty.
I've got to pick up
my kids at 5:00.
Okay. I understand.
Don't give it a thought.
Emma,
I haven't made love
to a woman...
in almost three years.
How come?
My wife has a disc problem,
and she can't take having...
any weight on her.
I hope you don't
mind me asking this,
but have you ever thought of
your wife getting on top?
Oh, she wouldn't do that.
She may surprise you.
No. I don't think so.
It would be so unlike her.
Did you ask?
About 600 times.
[ Emma ]
What are you thinking?
[ Sam ]
Do you prefer Texas to Iowa?
What were you really thinking?
That's what I was thinking
when you just asked me that.
There seems to be
an absence of wildness,
even in the people.
Well, we're farmers,
and we talk poor...
because the farmer
aspect of things is,
"Don't let anybody know
you have anything,
and don't call attention
to yourself."
My wife says--
I guess we shouldn't
talk about Dotty.
Wind in the hair!
Lead in the pencil!
Feet controlling the universe!
Breedlove at the helm!
Just keep pumping that throttle!
Keep giving it that gas!
I see the Gulf of Mexico!
I'm not enjoying this!
Give it a chance.
I'm going to stop!
# Fly me to the moon ##
How are you?
It's not my fault, but I'm sorry.
If you wanted to
get me on my back,
you just had to ask me.
Aah!
Oww! My hand!
Get it out!
I can't! I swear!
I swear to God!
We were having a good time,
then you had to go do this!
Please, anything!
Bend down!
Why did you have to get drunk?
I am not drunk--
Anymore!
The pain sobered me up.
No!
Emma, this might be
a terrible thing to ask,
but are you thinking
about your husband?
A little.
We can go back.
No, Sam. Stop it.
Look, I want to do this.
I'm glad I don't know whether
Flap's been with someone else.
I'd hate to think I was
doing this just to get even.
Oh, just fucking great!
Fine.
Great.
You're parked in my driveway!
You're breaking the law!
Thank you!
Would you like to come in?
I'd rather stick
needles in my eyes.
Everything would've been fine...
if you hadn't gotten drunk.
Don't think I'm like
one of your other girls.
No danger in that
unless you curtsy
on my face real soon.
Garrett!
What is it that makes you...
so insistent on
shocking and insulting me?
I really hate
that way of talking.
You must know that.
Why do you do it?
I'll tell you, Aurora.
I don't know what
it is about you,
but you do bring out
the devil in me.
Where are you?
[ Sam ] In the laundry room,
so nobody could hear.
But I can't hear you either.
- [ Machines Rumbling ]
- Wait a minute.
We're getting a quieter cycle.
Okay.
Can you hear now?
Yeah.
Is it bad to call?
No. I'm in the market
for sweet talk.
- [ Knocking ]
- [ Teddy ] Mom, I have to go!
Really!
Hurry up.
What is it?
Just how absolutely good I feel.
And even though I'm scared,
and we've committed adultery,
no matter what happens,
I'm just so grateful
to God or the Devil...
for letting me
feel this way again.
I'm glad you told me that.
Don't flush.
You said to.
Not this time.
Emma, is everything okay?
It's all right.
Can I hold Melanie?
Yes.
Honey, is everything okay?
What?
Is everything okay?
Everything's fine.
Oh, yeah.
[ Operator] I have
an emergencyphone call...
from Mrs. Aurora Greenway
in Houston, Texas...
for Mrs. Emma Horton.
Oh, no!
She does that
when the line's busy.
Will you release?
Of course. We were just talking.
I'll talk to you later, Sam. Bye.
[ Telephone Rings ]
Hi. How'd it go?
The astronaut is impossible.
An arrogant, self-centered,
and, yes, somewhat
entertaining man...
who has realized his ambition,
and is at last a spoiled child.
A match made in heaven.
You'd think so, wouldn't you?
He doesn't want anything more
to do with me.
Oh? Why?
Let's not go into it.
Because you wouldn't go to bed?
On a first date?
It's hardly a first date.
You've lived next door for 15 years.
Why don't you talk
about the real reason?
I don't know what you mean.
It's been that long
since you've done it.
Shut up! Shut up!
It's just me. Call him.
No! I'm hanging up.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I'm hanging up.
So long.
Oh!
[ Telephone Rings ]
[ Ring ]
Hello.
Hello, Garrett.
Yes?
Well, I was just
sitting here realizing--
Realizing that I'd never
shown you my Renoir.
What are you talking about?
I'm inviting you to come over...
and look at my Renoir.
You're inviting me to bed.
Yes, it happens to be
in my bedroom.
Is the Renoir under the covers?
Don't cackle, Garrett.
Do you want to see it?
Do I want to
come to your bedroom?
Let me think.
Do you?
Just--Just--
Just give me a minute.
It's--
It's a tough one.
Um--
I guess-- I don't know.
Yeah, okay.
I guess so.
Sure. Why not?
I'll see you in a bit.
If I don't answer the bell,
the back door's open.
The back door's open.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
My God. He ran it.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Hi.
I was doing laps when you called.
Lucky for us,
I only did eight.
This is it.
This is the Renoir.
I like it.
I like the painting.
I like everything in here.
Relax, baby.
Just who do you think
you're talking to?
Don't you realize
I'm a grandmother?
It's not flattering
to look too surprised.
I'll just be a minute.
I like the lights on.
Then go home
and turn them on.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
Dad.
Wake up, Dad.
What?
Melanie's sick.
The baby's sick.
The baby's sick?
Are you coming, Flap?
What do you think's wrong?
I have to look first.
[ Baby Crying ]
Come on, Dad.
Thank you.
Go to bed.
She'll be all right.
I can't sleep.
It's bad enough
we're making this a drama.
It's not going to qualify
as high drama.
It's okay.
Thanks.
I'm sure it's the croup.
Remember,
Tommy had it twice?
Guess you were in the library.
[ Baby Coughing ]
God, that's the worst sound
in the world.
How long do you keep her in here?
Why? Are you going back to bed?
I just asked how long.
Until her throat clears...
or I lose 20 pounds.
Whichever comes first.
I don't know.
About 20 minutes, I guess.
I've been offered a job.
What?
Why didn't you say something?
I wanted to think about it.
It's head of the
English Department...
at Kearney State College--
For the same money.
Where is it?
Nebraska.
I don't want to move.
I love the school,
the pediatricians--
Head of the department.
We'll talk about it, all right?
I like it here, Flap.
Head of the department.
That's-- That's great.
Good-bye, Mom.
Come on, Teddy.
Don't kiss the baby.
She may still be sick.
Have a good day at school.
What a night!
Melanie decided
to get the croup,
and I haven't gotten any sleep.
He may be kidding,
but Flap says he's taking us...
to some college in Nebraska.
I think Sam is becoming
someone that I need.
I'm lying here
next to the astronaut.
Are you really?
How was it?
I'll speak to you later.
I feel so good for you.
Call me soon.
Bye.
Mel?
Okay, Mel.
[ Garrett ] I just want
to make this clear, you know.
I see other women.
I didn't exactly think
we were engaged.
Your ego. Really!
Okay. Let's stay in tonight.
You're saving a fortune on me.
I'll cook.
It's been three weeks,
and you haven't
even seen my house.
My best instincts
had me avoiding it.
What are you thinking?
Oh,
I'll tell you what.
I think this is really sad...
that you need this stuff
to impress girls.
Need it?
Mm-hmm.
Sometimes it isn't enough.
There's nothing wrong
with using your assets.
I think it turns your profession
into a sex trap.
Everybody uses
whatever they have.
I earned it!
There's 106 astronauts
in the whole fucking world,
and I'm one of them!
It's part of me.
Sorry. I didn't
mean to trip...
on such a deeply felt principle.
Do you want to know
what bothers me?
None of us ever
got together in one room,
Iocked all the doors,
and compared notes
on the experience.
I think we had to pretend...
it wasn't the fun that it was.
You do sense the speed.
I remember looking out
the window of the spacecraft--
I sound like somebody
with a big belly...
telling their stories about Korea.
Anyway, I'm looking
out the window.
I see a piece of the spacecraft,
and it's whistling
along the ground.
It doesn't make a sound.
The only sound you hear,
the only noise
in the entire world,
is your heart beating.
It's indescribable.
Anyway, I can't think
of a better way of saying it.
That was my moment,
the one that doesn't go away.
You know what I mean?
Yes.
Hey--
This is my moment.
No, don't get nervous.
Flap?
Anybody?
[ Girl ] You don't think it's love
because we're having fun.
Love can be fun.
Would you stop making faces?
That's wonderful.
[ Flap ] What we have here is
a typical grad-school girl crush.
Would you please stop
telling me this is a crush?
The fun with getting
involved with someone...
unavailable and slightly older...
is that sometimes you hear
what's really going on.
[ Girl ]
Flap, you are such an--
...incredible asshole!
Excuse me.
Emma!
God damn it, Emma,
you'll ruin us!
You're a spectacle!
I am not!
Stop jiggling her.
She'll throw up.
Your timing was perfect.
You caught us
before we did anything.
I'm taking the kids to Houston.
Give me the baby.
You don't know what I did,
just like I don't know
what you do...
on your afternoon drives.
[ Boy In Crowd ]
Professor Horton, can we talk...
about my grade?
You ought to be
happy I'm going.
If I stayed here,
I'd make life hell for you.
Don't follow me.
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
[ Horn Honks ]
It's them. It's them!
Garrett, come meet Emma.
No, you don't need outsiders.
You're no outsider!
I'll see them later.
Emma, this is Garrett.
Oh! Pleasure to meet you.
I've heard so much about you.
Your mother's been
looking forward to this.
So--
Go ahead.
Anything wrong, Garrett?
No.
Very nice to meet you.
Must be nice to be home.
Oh, it's great. It's great.
I'll be over later.
They're tired,
and will get to sleep early,
and I'd like to get to bed early.
Grandma, Grandma, Grandma!
Bye-bye.
[ Rosie ]
Come on out. All right.
This one likes to squeeze.
Teddy likes to squeeze,
Tommy likes to squeeze.
You both get a squeeze.
The baby.
Where's the baby?
Oh, there is my baby.
Look at the baby!
I think she looks
a little like you.
A little? She is like
looking in the mirror.
She loved the ride.
She hardly cried at all.
Bring in the suitcases.
Okay.
Mom--
I talk to you every day.
Mother, you look great.
You look terrible.
Nobody wants a girl who's
washed-out and tired-looking.
I just drove 1,000 miles.
Besides, men love me
the way I am.
You finally take one
small step away from Flap,
it's with an unavailable,
older Iowan.
Tell me about the astronaut.
You going to sleep now,
or are we going to talk?
How's the astronaut, Mother?
Really?
Oh, really?
He has a name, though.
You really like him.
Yeah.
Well, it's just so--
It's so strange that relatively--
relatively late in life,
I've found that sex is so--
so--
so fan-fucking-tastic!
Anyway, that's what he calls it.
A moth to flame.
This affair is going to kill me.
No. Maybe not.
Why do you say that?
Come on, Momma.
I never thought
I'd start to need him.
You're so lucky
you have a pool.
Stand there.
Stand there!
Okay.
Let's talk about Los Angeles.
Do you miss it?
[ Telephone Rings ]
It was interesting dating Jews
after the divorce.
They are so lively.
Really?
Yeah.
They were anxious
to make you feel...
they understood
your secret thoughts...
better than anybody.
I was just glad I had some.
Honey, there's
a telephone call for you.
Hello.
Oh, hi, Flap.
How are you?
I'm fine.
I look older,
like everyone else.
She does not.
You sound the same.
I'm not sure that's good.
She's right here.
No, we have other things
to talk about besides you.
Hello?
I'm fine.
What's up?
Feeling contrite?
You don't seem to understand.
I saw you together.
What?
I can't believe
you're doing this to us.
Well, I think you're spiteful,
and I don't know when
the hell that happened.
No! Good-bye. I'll--
Good-bye.
Flap accepted the job
at Kearney, Nebraska.
We're moving in a week.
I don't know why
you don't leave him.
Honestly, I don't know either.
He's cute.
I've been packing for us all week.
Sure remembers her Daddy.
So are you going to stay mad?
Being uprooted without my consent...
is at least worth
a pout, don't you?
Come on.
Head of the department.
I know.
Aurora?
Garrett, I'm back here.
Well, hello, stranger.
What's it been, about two days?
Your family still around?
No, they left.
What?
You probably know
what I'm going to say.
Oh, maybe not.
I hope not.
Well,
you're some kind of woman,
but I'm the wrong kind of man,
and it seems my shot
at being the right kind...
is as good as I was hoping for.
You don't know how much
you'll miss me.
I don't want to blow
smoke up your ass.
Oh!
What a relief.
It's just that I'm starting
to feel an obligation here.
It makes it rough,
especially living next door.
I'm starting to think...
I got to watch
what I'm doing--
Blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
I am going to miss you...
and I do feel bad.
You're lucky.
I feel humiliated.
Can I have your picture?
The one I have has Flap in it.
I don't mind.
Come here and give me a kiss.
I need this kind of type.
Fine. Hello, Emma.
Hi, baby.
She wanted her daddy
to see her dressed up.
I'll talk to you later.
Excuse me.
Miss?
Miss!
Don't make me run after you.
I have a toddler here.
Are you the reason that
we came to Nebraska?
I think that Flap
should talk to you.
We discussed that.
I don't want to say
anything until he does,
except that I don't think
there's an emotion you're having...
that I couldn't...
validate.
Tell you what.
If you see Flap,
tell him his wife and baby...
went to get
their flu shots, all right?
[ Man ]
Just hold still.
Ow!
That's a good girl.
[ Emma ]
Okay? You're all finished.
It's all over.
If it makes you feel better,
Mommy's getting a shot, too.
Can she have a pop?
Here.
There you go.
Will they tell me
if my husband calls?
You have a lump in your armpit.
How long has it been there?
I don't know.
Melanie, stop kicking the cabinet!
There's two of them.
Not very big, though.
I'm leaving town,
but you shouldn't wait.
They should come out.
Come out?
Should I be scared?
If you're scared,
you'll be happier...
when it turns out
to be nothing.
Dr. Budge,
Mom should get
a pop, too, for her shot.
Right. Here, Mom.
Thanks, Mel.
I know what it is.
Your sweat glands are clogged.
It's a cyst.
So I shouldn't worry?
It's a cyst, right where
your oil glands are.
You've never eaten right,
or learned how to wash.
You're right. Thanks.
Talk to Melanie.
Hello. I sent you a blouse.
[ Emma ]
Say good-bye.
[ Melanie ]
Bye.
Okay. Say good--
Say good-bye to your mother.
What's her name?
Janice.
What did the doctor say?
It's scary that he wants
to do it so fast.
Janice, with her little folder.
"I can't say
anything until he does.
We've discussed it."
Really, Flap!
"Validate my feelings."
Your taste!
But that thing
the doctor said--
No!
I won't make you feel better!
Dinner!
Dear, you have a--
- Malignancy.
-...malignancy.
Say it again.
Malignancy.
Rosie,
our girl is in trouble.
She has a cyst that's malignant.
They're taking her to
a hospital in Lincoln, Nebraska.
Oh,
We'll release her soon.
We do more on an outpatient basis.
She shouldn't need to come back
unless it escalates.
But you're not
telling me anything.
What are you confused about?
How is she?
I tell people to
hope for the best,
and prepare for the worst.
They let you get away with that?
You're wrong to take
a desperate attitude.
It won't do Emma any good
to get those signals.
What's wrong now?
I'm frustrated with that doctor.
You're getting out.
You don't have
to stay here again.
Unless the illness spreads.
I really don't feel sick.
Come to New York.
My treat.
We'll have to see.
Look at this letter from the kids.
Teddy says he couldn't sleep,
but Melanie could.
Tommy thinks there's
nothing to be concerned about--
I mean it!
You have some time.
Come see New York.
Not a bad idea,
a vacation by yourself.
Take advantage of your freedom.
I know you want to go.
This isn't like taking
those kids to Disneyland...
right before the end?
Stop!
Ow!
Patsy, I'm kidding!
Okay!
Oh, good.
Do you feel funny
about leaving the kids?
I'm not leaving them.
I'm entrusting them
to their father.
As long as your mother
and Rosie are in town--
Not them. You.
Emma!
Huh?
Emma, look! Look! Look!
Are we there yet?
God! I'm here!
Isn't it beautiful?
I want you to meet
some of my friends.
Hi.
Emma, this is Lizbeth.
Hi, Elizabeth.
Hi.
It's Lizbeth.
Isn't that what I said?
You said, "Elizabeth."
It's Lizbeth.
Two names?
Liz Beth?
No, one. Lizbeth.
Never mind!
This is Jane.
Thank heavens!
Here, that's Melanie.
Oh!
Look at that!
Teddy's the younger one,
Tommy's the older one.
Oh, isn't that--
Oh! Oh!
The little girl.
She's incredible.
Don't think
she don't know it.
Patsy's got a real thing
going with her.
Are you going back to work?
I never really worked.
Well--
Well, that's okay.
Thanks.
Great!
[ Woman ]
When did she find out?
[ Patsy ]
About a month ago.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It was a great honor meeting you.
Thanks.
Those children are lucky...
to have you for a mommy.
Y'all go ahead.
Take the first cab.
You're sure?
Yeah.
That's fine.
Bye-bye, Patsy.
You told them, didn't you?
You don't mind, do you?
Of course not.
They're jerks.
They don't know anything.
Why do they act like that?
Talk to me!
It's not you.
I don't mind them knowing.
In two hours,
two of them told me
they'd had abortions.
Three of them
are divorced.
One hasn't talked
to her mother in years,
and one has her little Natalie
in boarding school...
because she travels in her job?
I mean, hell, Patsy, that's all--
The one with the yeast disease...
that thought
she had vaginal herpes?
If that's fit
conversation for lunch,
what's so god-awful terrible
about my little tumors?
Yeah, of course, but--
What do you want me to do?
Tell them it ain't so tragic!
People do get better.
Tell them it's okay
to talk about the cancer!
Patsy tells us you have cancer.
We should talk.
I'm a nutritionist,
and my husband's with Ticketron.
Thanks, Patsy.
Hello.
Flap?
Have you heard anything?
No.
Emma hasn't called you
either, huh?
No. How are the children?
I wish I were so carefree.
They have nothing
to feel ashamed about.
You always seem to lose
your manners around me.
Stop it, Flap.
If you talk to Emma, don't
sound as frightened as you do.
I don't sound frightened!
Daddy--
Hi, mother.
I can't talk for very long.
I think I'm coming home early.
Not really.
It's about time
we had this room.
Mother, I can't believe
you did this.
Careful! They're worth more
than you'll ever make.
I grew up with her my whole life.
You can take it for a couple minutes.
That's fine.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Hmm!
Oh, they're wonderful.
They look good
next to each other.
Help me with this, Melanie.
Gorgeous isn't everything.
This one, this one.
Two more.
The response to
the drugs we tried...
isn't what we hoped.
There are investigatory drugs
which we are willing to utilize.
However, if you
become incapacitated,
or it becomes unreasonable...
for you to handle your affairs,
it might be wise
to make decisions now.
Any questions?
No.
I know what you're saying.
I have to figure out
what to do with my kids.
It's after 10:00.
Give my daughter the pain shot.
Mrs. Greenway, I was going to.
Go ahead.
Just a few minutes.
Please. It's after 10:00.
Why must she have this pain?
It's not my patient.
It's time!
Do something!
She only has to
hold on until 10:00!
It's past 10:00!
She's in pain!
Are you going to behave?
Give my daughter the shot!
Thank you very much.
Can I have 222, please?
Let's get her!
I'm pushing Grandma in!
Don't you dare!
I mean it.
Come on.
Say, "Hi, Granny."
Hi, Granny.
Aurora?
Well,
who would have expected you
to be a nice guy?
Who?
It's good to see you.
Wow!
Take care of yourself.
I'll call you.
I'm real glad I came.
It meant a lot to Emma.
It meant a lot to me.
I'll call you.
No. If there's someone there,
I'll hear that funny sound
in yourvoice.
Who cares?
I don't care.
I love you.
Garrett!
Come here.
I was curious.
Any reaction to my
telling you I love you?
I was just inches
from a clean getaway.
You're stuck, so face it.
I don't know what else to say...
except my stock answer.
Which is?
I love you, too, kid.
Bye.
I took him to the airport,
and we were standing there...
hugging and kissing
and saying good-bye,
and you know what?
What?
I told him I loved him.
You know what
his reaction was?
I don't give a shit.
I'm sick.
Not everything is about you.
I've got a lot to figure out.
I don't want to fight anymore.
What do you mean?
When do we fight?
You amaze me.
I always think of us as fighting.
That's from your end.
That's 'cause you're
never satisfied with me.
Have you seen her yet today?
Yes. I've been with her...
most of last night
and today, as usual.
I haven't, uh...
really talked to the kids yet.
I'm not sure
how much they realize,
but they know
something bad's happening.
Flap, Patsy wants
to raise Melanie...
and maybe the boys.
They should be with me.
What can you be thinking about?
Raising three children,
working full time,
and chasing women,
requires more energy
than you have.
A nice quality about you...
is you recognize your weaknesses.
Don't lose that quality now,
when you need it the most.
You have no right...
nor any invitation...
to discuss where or how
my children live.
From what the doctor says...
it's time we have the talk now.
Do you know how much
I hate the idea of losing you?
Yes.
Well, no--
nobody seems to know that
except you.
I just-- Well.
What?
I'm thinking about my identity,
and not having one anymore.
Who am I, if I'm not
the man who's failing Emma?
You didn't fail me, Flap.
I feel like I'm
sucking after forgiveness,
which I probably am.
You were no more
terrible than I was.
Except for the cheating.
You're right.
Let's not do this.
We had problems.
It was never over
whether we loved each other.
Oh, God! That tie!
I can't believe you wore that!
The mess it must've been finding it.
The house still isn't in one piece.
It was in the last box I looked in.
I'll bet.
God, you're easy to please.
Why couldn't I do more of it?
I'm so glad we're talking.
It means so much to me,
that we can still feel like this.
I swear, I don't know.
Listen, I am getting tired.
You really want to raise them?
I never thought
I'd give up my kids.
It's a lot of work.
As hard as you think it is,
you end up wishing
it were that easy.
Where do you want them?
I don't want them
to end up with Janice.
She's not so bad.
I really don't think
they should be with you.
Well,
to tell you
the honest truth,
I'd probably screw it up.
I'll really miss them.
Maybe Patsy should take them.
It'd be easy for me...
to work research
summers in New York.
Patsy really only
wants Melanie.
Mother should have them.
You can see them anytime.
You'll decide things
for them and everything.
She'll make that very difficult.
She won't.
I guess they should
be with your mother.
I probably have that coming.
Oh.
Will you bring the boys by
tomorrow?
That one's waiting for me.
I've got to do it.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Come on.
I've got to get ready.
Patsy.
The makeup!
Is it terrible to say...
I can't stand
seeing your mother...
getting her hands
on that little girl?
I'd love to raise
that little girl.
Look, I'd let you,
but Teddy couldn't spare her.
I can't stall anymore, all right?
You go out there
and send the boys in.
Do I get to say something?
No.
We don't have
to do that, right?
Come here.
You'll be fine.
You will.
It's just this.
You're my touchstone, Emma.
The boys.
[ Bed Whirring ]
Hi.
Come on.
I love you.
I miss you.
God, I want you to come home.
Close the door.
God, you both look
so gigantic to me.
I guess I look bad to you.
Not so bad.
You both have beautiful eyes.
Your hair's too long.
Keep your bangs cut, okay?
It's too long.
It's a matter of opinion.
Just keep it short, all right?
Are you getting well?
Uh-uh.
Look up.
I'm sorry about this.
I can't talk too long
or I'll get upset.
I want you to make
a lot of friends.
Be nice to the girls,
'cause they'll be
important to you.
We're not afraid of girls.
You may be later on.
I doubt it.
Why don't you shut up?
You shut up.
Teddy, give me a kiss.
Tommy, you be sweet.
Be sweet.
Stop pretending
like you hate me.
It's silly.
I like you.
Then listen especially close.
What?
Listen real hard.
I said what.
I know you like me.
I know it.
For the last year,
you've pretended like you hate me.
I love you very much.
I love you as much
as I love anybody,
as much as myself.
In a few years, when I haven't
been around to irritate you,
you're going to remember.
You'll remember when
I bought you the baseball glove,
when you thought
we were broke;
or when I read you those stories.
Or when I let you goof off instead of
mowing the lawn-- lots of things.
You'll realize that you love me,
and maybe you'll feel badly
because you never told me,
but don't.
I know that you love me.
So don't do that
to yourself, okay?
Okay!
Okay?
I said okay.
You two should run along.
Take care.
Give me a kiss.
I was so scared,
but I think
it went well, don't you?
Yeah?
Tommy, if you need to talk,
your dad will listen.
He's a very smart man.
Just say,
"Dad, I'm confused.
I need to have a talk."
This boy where I live...
said the Houston Cub Scouts
are the best.
We were never Scouts.
Our mother was
too lazy to check it out.
No! Stop!
Come on!
Stop it!
No!
Listen to me!
Listen.
It's okay, Tom.
It's okay.
Hey! Stop it!
I just can't have you
criticizing your mother around me.
[ Whimpering ]
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Mr. Horton.
She's gone.
God, I'm so stupid.
Somehow I thought--
Somehow I thought
when she finally went,
that it would be a relief.
Oh, my sweet little darling!
Oh, dear.
There's nothing harder.
There's nothing--
You want some cake?
Why are you standing over here?
I don't know.
You want to sit with me?
Everything's going to be
all right, Tommy.
Ah, there's fantastic
dance schools in Houston.
Tap?
Tap, ballet, aerobics--
Anything you want.
Come over here
and see your dad.
He really knows a pretty girl.
She's too old for him.
You're eating a wet bunny?
Go over to Dad and eat it.
Hi, Vern.
How you doing, Garrett?
I understand you're a swimmer.
Me, too.
But you're an astronaut, right?
Yep.
I'm an astronaut and a swimmer.
Pretty good-looking suit there.
A little closer.
Want to see my pool?
I don't know if the time is right--
funeral and everything--
Oh, I think it is.
Come on.
I'll show you
the internationally infamous...
uh, Breedlove Crawl.
A stroke I picked up
out in space.