[man 1]
You bringing Micky in?
[man 2]
Yeah, he's gonna come.
[man 1] He should
be here as well.
[man 2] You think
he'll answer questions?
They said it was gonna be
both of us here.
- Am I looking right in the camera here?
- Just look at me, right here.
All right. You don't want me to
look in the camera with the...
- Right over here.
- ...interviews?
[man 1] I started boxing
when I was 12 years old,
and I'd lie and say I was 18,
or whatever it was.
You know, I had a different
name and everything.
I mean, I don't know
how many fights...
I'd done a hundred, more than
that, before I turned professional.
- [man 2] Go ahead and sit right there.
- Why we doing this?
- I don't wanna do this.
- You want to start again?
[man 1] This is my younger brother.
I taught him everything he knows.
I'm still his trainer. You
know, we got different styles.
I'm fuckin' squirrelly as fuck.
I'm like... I'm not even there.
You know, that's
what Sugar Ray said.
I was the most tricky fighter
he'd ever come across.
In '78, I fought
Sugar Ray Leonard.
I went toe-to-toe with him.
He couldn't get to me.
They called me the pride...
the pride of Lowell.
Everybody still talks about it,
especially my brother.
His whole life he wanted
to do what I did, you know?
But we're very
different fighters.
Micky's, you know,
he's a heavy hitter.
He's got... a thunderous,
I'm telling you,
thunderous left punch.
Micky, he gets you and
he takes a punishment,
I don't know why he does it, till
you're right fuckin' in there.
He likes getting on the
inside, I stay on the outside.
[clattering, scraping]
Come on.
[Micky] Dicky.
Would you come on?
Will you stop...?
You gotta help me finish this.
- Come on!
- [Dicky shouts indistinctly]
- And predictable as ever.
- All right.
- You don't need to be Columbo
- Here you go.
to see where this
fight is headed.
[mimics impact sound]
Bam! Over right hand
- puts Micky Ward down!
- [melodramatic groaning]
HBO's making a movie
on me and my comeback!
And my brother is gonna beat
Saoul Mamby
in Atlantic City next week!
The pride of Lowell is back!
Quacka! Who wants some?! Who wants some!
[# The Heavy: How You Like Me Now]
# Now there was a time #
# When you loved me so #
-# I couldn't run #
- [indistinct chatter]
# Now you needed to know #
- Hey! I want a cut.
-# I've been a bad, bad, bad, bad man #
# And I'm in deep #
Are you good?
You guys having a good day?
How are ya?
Come on! What you got?
What you got going on?
Lou! Hey, Lou!
- How are you guys?
- Dicky.
# How you like me now #
-# How you like me now #
- Making my comeback.
# How you like me now #
Hey, naughty, naughty.
What's going on here, huh?
Hey, Dicky, Micky!
Take my picture.
- [Dicky] Take a picture?
- Yeah.
[chatter continues]
- Hey!
- Hey, Louie!
HBO's making a movie on me!
What's going on? Hey, beautiful.
Did you tap that?
I can't remember. I got CRS:
I Can't Remember Shit!
- [yelling, chatter]
- Hey, Jerry Garcia!
Are you nuts?
How'd you get here?
You drive around?
Hey, Ray. Ray.
I love you, Ray.
You're doing well.
[cheers]
[man 1] You're walking.
Get on it.
- [chattering]
- [fists hitting punching bags]
- [man 2] We make a mistake?
- Nah, I mean, he'll be here.
You know, like I said, sometimes
he goes on his own schedule
but when he gets here, we work hard.
You know, nobody pushes me harder.
He's supposed to be
training you right now, right?
Why don't you just go talk to them,
my sisters? They'll talk your ear off.
You gotta pay
them to shut up.
[woman] He can tell you
how Dicky was helping him.
[all] Yeah, come on, Micky.
- O'Keefe!
- Hey, we don't know where Dicky is.
You know where he is.
[woman] What's that
Keystone Kop doing in there?
Where's Dicky? Girls?
- I don't know.
- Did you see him, your brother?
- Not this morning?
- [Micky] Look at Ma!
All dressed up
for the movie, huh?
- [sisters chattering]
- Wow!
[mother] Get outta
the ring, O'Keefe.
My Dicky should
be doing that, huh?
[O'Keefe] Your Dicky
ain't here, Alice.
Micky's got an important fight
coming up and he's not training.
Don't. Just forget about him.
He's number two man.
- He's not part of this, all right?
- He's not being handled right.
You get me coming in all right?
You want me to do that again?
[Alice]
Get out of the ring, O'Keefe.
- Dicky's the trainer.
- [O'Keefe] I'm doing a favor, Alice.
I will show you over here
these scrapbooks
I've been collecting for years.
Micky used to follow
his big brother everywhere.
Taught ya everything,
didn't he, honey?
In '78, we got the offer
to fight Sugar Ray Leonard.
Oh, my God, it was...
Have you seen that video?
Oh, you're from HBO.
You gotta see it again. Come on.
Art, Art,
where's the video at?
[up-tempo intro music playing]
Tonight, my son is gonna
surprise everybody
and beat Sugar Ray Leonard.
Believe me, I know it.
[announcer 1] Sugar Ray might
have some trouble tonight.
[announcer 2]
That's a good possibility.
He comes in here against
a good boxer,
a young man who can punch, and
I would like to say at this time
that physically
they're just about equal.
[crowd clamoring]
[mock grunting]
- [crowd roaring]
- [announcer 1] Leonard is down.
Let's see if that's
a knockdown.
This is unbelievable.
Eklund just walked over him!
Nobody seems
to know what's happening!
[laughing]
[woman 1 muttering, clapping]
[woman 1] Dicky did it. Yeah.
Tricky Dicky did it.
- Dicky did it. - [man] Weren't you
supposed to be training Micky right now?
- No, it ain't till 9:00.
- [woman 2] Dicky, it's fucking 11:45!
- [woman 1] It's 11:45, Dick.
- What?!
Where'd you fuckin'
park the car, Boo Boo?!
- I didn't park it. You did.
- Huh?
- I didn't park it.
- Check your fuckin' pockets for the keys.
- You got the keys, yeah?
- I didn't park it, man.
- Down there? I don't know.
- Check your pockets, all right?
- You're fuckin' mental. - Aah, fuck it!
I'll run. I need the fuckin' roadwork.
- Roadwork? Are you crazy?
- He's a great runner.
[speed bag thumping]
Hey.
Hey!
[Dicky] Quacka!
- [Alice] Hey, Dicky.
- Better late than never.
Oh, look! Detective's
on the scene. Hm.
- [mocking, indistinct]
- [Alice laughing]
Gonna get to the bottom
of this. [grunting]
- Figure this one out, huh?
- Dick, you're an asshole.
[HBO producer] Hold it, hold it.
Let me get this straight.
You guys are working in the same
corner as Micky, together, right?
Yeah. Yeah, they're both in my
corner, and this is what goes on.
- [HBO producer] OK. - [Alice] Don't you
have a job to go to or something?
Really, O'Keefe has a job
that he should be at.
[HBO producer] Yeah, Sergeant
O'Keefe's working overtime here.
So we got Saoul Mamby, Jewish,
black, former world champ.
I think we got
all the bases covered.
And my kid brother,
he's lost
three fights in a row.
You know, he can't get used
to losing. It's a mental thing.
But we're gonna break
that with Mamby, right?
Yeah, I hope,
if we can train...
We can train, right. Enough of
you wasting time, Mick. You know?
- Wasting time?
- Half the fuckin' day's gone!
- We got work to do.
- Yeah, half the day's gone,
- and I been waiting here for you.
- You wanna win?
- [# The Breeders: Saints]
- # I like all the different people #
# I like every kind of fair #
# In a crowd
you bet I'll be there #
Jab, two, three, four.
Left, right, punch right. Jab...
And again!
One, two, three, four...
One, two, three, four,
five... Jab, jab...
[Alice] There you go!
There you go!
[bell dings]
# Saints alive you're saying #
# Walk in... squares #
[Dicky] Come on, move!
Might as well drop the weight,
we're gonna out-box Mamby. Huh?
- [Alice] Take it out on the mitts.
- [Dicky] Head, body, head.
That's your fuckin' combo.
Head, body, head.
[Alice] Head, body, head, body.
My Dicky taught him that.
You know,
Sugar Ray's gonna be there,
calling the fight for ESPN.
- I ain't seen him since I knocked him down.
- [chuckling]
Like 14 years ago
or somethin'. Right?
Hook!
[Alice] Let's get
a real sparring going on here.
[Dicky] Don't wanna
embarrass yourself.
Don't wanna embarrass yourself in
front of Sugar Ray, do you, Mick?
- [Alice] You got him...
- [Dicky] Come on. Head, body, head!
- [Dicky] Ooh, fuck.
- [Alice] Oh!
- Fuckin' yeah. That's your punch, Mick.
- Oh, my God.
- [Dicky] That's your punch.
- [Alice laughing]
[Dicky] That's your liver punch. It
shuts the whole fuckin' body down.
George's fingers are so fuckin'
fat, he can't even dial the phone!
- [chatter, laughter]
- Hey, right there, Tar!
- That's not helping, George!
- [laughter]
- Hold on. Wait a minute. I'm confused.
- [woman] What?
- Yeah, I'm confused, too.
- We're confused.
- George is whose father?
- You're confused? [chuckles]
Dick Eklund Sr. is Dicky's...
...Donna's, Gail's
and Phyllis's father.
- Is Dick Eklund.
- Yeah.
And even though Alice is an
Eklund, so is Cindy and Cathy,
- George is really their...
- And Micky...
- No. Micky and I are...
- [overlapping] Sherri Ward.
- We're Wards.
- The Wards.
It's not the way it sounds. Dick
Eklund and I were separated, right?
And then there was George,
just George. George is my man.
- Georgie's our poppa.
- After Dick, it was just George.
[overlapping chatter, laughter]
[man] Charlene! Charlene!
Hey, Charlene!
We're doing shots with Charlene!
- Yeah, you get over here.
- Come on! Come over here.
- [Charlene] Come on, drink yours.
- [all chattering]
[man] On the count
of three... Three!
- [all cheering]
- [bell dings]
Good job, fellas.
Oh, hey, one more time.
[dings]
Why don't you just go talk
to her? She's a nice girl.
I told her
all about you.
[Micky] I don't wanna ask her
if she's gonna say no.
[George scoffs] Can't
beat that ass, can ya?
Get out of the booth.
Come on. Come on.
[blender whirring]
Are you just gonna stand
there and stare at my ass?
Your father stares
at my ass,
but he talks to me.
Thinks you're the greatest.
He didn't tell me
you were mute.
[man] Keep
the change, doll.
He told me you're
Kenny Fleming's sister.
- [Charlene] This is a tip?
- [man] Yeah, that's my tip.
- You know what the bell says
about this tip? - [bell clanking]
Cheap bastard. Cheap fucker.
- Comes in here every day,
gives me shitty tips. - [man] Fuck that.
Yeah, fuck you, too.
- [man] Forget it, boys...
- You pave streets, right?
Yeah, I do.
And I'm a fighter.
Oh, yeah, I heard you
were a stepping-stone.
- No, I'm no stepping-stone.
- You're the guy they use,
against the other fighters
to move the other fighters up.
Oh, I've had a few tough fights,
but that's not who I am.
The next fight's
gonna show who I am.
[chuckles] Yeah, and he's
gonna lose that one, too.
Scotch and soda, Charlene.
And one for yourself.
So move that sugar ass
and get my... [grunts]
- [crowd gasping]
- You be nice. OK?
Be respectful.
Don't disrespect her.
Hey, don't hurt your hands.
We got a fight next week.
- Besides, you wipe your ass with that one.
- [grunting]
Don't lean up, or I'm gonna
hit you in the cocksucker.
- He's gonna beat Saoul Mamby, say it!
- Yeah, he's gonna beat him!
- [man grunting]
- [Dicky] Right? Right? Hey!
- [grunting] Right.
- That's right!
I'm gonna take your drink,
as well. I'm taking his drink.
Hey, this guy's gonna
be champion.
He's a great guy.
He's a great fighter.
You can't go wrong.
Thanks for the drink.
Those cameras are makin'
a movie about him.
He knocked down
Sugar Ray Leonard on HBO,
that's why they're following
him around with the camera.
And now they're making
a movie about his comeback.
Yeah, everybody's talking about
it. But who are you fightin'?
- Saoul Mamby.
- Saoul Mamby?
- What kind of name is that?
- Black and Jewish.
Where did they
find a guy like that?
He's no joke.
Former world champ.
- Former champ?
- Yeah.
- I match up good with him though.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- What does that mean?
Well, I got lighter, you know?
I have a reputation for brawlin',
but I'm not gonna brawl with him.
I'm gonna try and out-box him.
- And there's a difference?
- Yeah, you know.
Brawlin', you slug it out.
I hit you, you hit me.
Boxing's a chess game,
you know?
I pick my punches
to take him down.
And go head, body, head, body.
What is "head, body,
head, body"?
Well, I hit him
in the head,
and then his hand's gonna
go up to protect himself,
so it opens up his body, and
then when I hit him in the body,
the hand moves back down,
I go back up to the head,
hand goes back up,
hit him in the body.
People who don't know fighting
think you can do a lot of damage
hitting somebody in the head,
but you do more
hitting 'em in the body.
So what do you think?
Can I take you out?
Are you married?
No. Would I ask you out
if I was married?
- What kind of guy do you think I am?
- Happens all the time.
- Trust me.
- I'm not like that.
I'm not married.
I got a daughter.
I see her every other weekend.
Her name's Kasie. But that's it.
Come on.
Let me take you out.
When?
Saturday night.
I get back from Atlantic City.
[# Daryl Hall and
John Oates: Sara Smile]
- Is this the real number?
- You have to call it and see.
I will. Saturday.
Dinner and a movie.
- [men shouting indistinctly]
- [crashing sounds]
[women yelling]
[# Whitesnake: Here I Go Again]
# Here I go again on my own #
-# Going down the only road
I've ever known ## - [music stops]
[doorbell ringing]
- Hey. Jimmy.
- Micky, hey. How's it going?
I don't think Laurie's
expecting you right now.
[Laurie]
What's he doin' here?
This isn't your
visitation day, Micky.
Look, I just want
to say hi to Kasie.
It's not your day.
Good-bye.
Yeah, but I'm not
around next weekend.
You ditchin' the days
you do have?
No, I have a fight.
I told you that.
- Jimmy...
- I can't get in the middle.
I can't talk to her, OK?
So I'm asking you, Jimmy.
I want to talk
to my daughter. Now.
- Talk to your father.
- [Laurie] Goddamn it, Jimmy.
- Daddy's gonna fight Saoul Mamby.
- [arguing indistinctly]
That's right. I want
to tell you that after I win,
I'm gonna start making good money,
and I'll move into a bigger apartment
like we talked about so you
can live with me more days, OK?
- Yeah, bigger apartment!
- Wish me luck, all right?
Don't hold
your breath, Kasie.
It's cruel to mislead
your child, Micky.
Good luck, Daddy.
Thanks, Kasie.
I love you, honey. Bye, baby.
- [church bells chime]
- [George] Where is he?
[muttering] Jesus Christ.
Un-fucking-believable.
[sighs heavily]
- Quit worrying, for crying out loud.
- Blow that shit in my face.
You know, it's none
of my business.
I go to a lot
of meetings,
and they have a saying,
"Let Go and Let God."
You gotta let
him go, Mick.
He's taught me
everything I know.
He's been in my corner.
I can't do it without him.
You're already
doing it without him.
- No, I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
Look, you know where he is.
Why don't you just go get him?
- Can you get him?
- I'm not fuckin' going to get him.
Are we all gonna go over there
in the limo with Alice?
We can't do that.
[# Wang Chung: Dance Hall Days]
# When I, you
and everyone we knew #
- # Could believe, do #
- [loud knocking at door]
- [man] Dicky.
- [knocking continues]
- Your mother's outside.
- What?
[woman] Oh, Dicky, your mother's
outside! She's down there!
I'm not here.
- [woman] Oh, no.
- [man] What?
- I gotta go check...
- [woman] Dicky, no!
Don't Dicky! Dicky!
- [man] He's goin'... better get
out of here. - [woman] Dicky, no!
Quacka, what the fuck
are you doing?
You know we gotta go to the airport
now. We got a flight to catch.
You know how important
this fight is to me.
Hey, don't tell Ma
I'm here, all right?
- She knows!
- No, no, no.
- Pick me up back at the house.
- Are you fucking...
- I'll go through the yards.
- She's in the driveway right now.
All right, but hurry up.
She's in the fuckin' driveway.
- We got a flight to catch.
- You son of a bitch.
You do this on the day your
brother's traveling?!
- [yelling]
- What are you doing?
- [Dicky]Why'd you make me do that?
- What the fuck you hit him for?
[Dicky] Why'd you make
me do that to you?
- [George] Jesus!
- [Alice] Oh, my God, Dicky.
I was on my way! Ma...
What are you doing
in this place?
There you go. There you go.
Why can't we just go to the
fuckin' airport for once, please?
- We got a plane to catch.
- Hey, Alice, what about your husband?
He's laying on the fuckin' ground.
You wanna help your husband?
What are you doing running in here
like a silverback fuckin' gorilla?
We had to get him,
for Chrissakes.
Yeah, you got him all right.
You got him, pal.
[jazzy music playing]
- [lively chatter]
- [machines ringing]
[TV plays indistinctly]
[Dicky] You see Mamby? You see
how Mamby's arm comes up?
Leaves his side open, you just
light him up like a pinball machine.
He's gonna be pissin' blood.
No way you lose, Mick. No way.
- Hey, Lou.
- Dicky boy.
Hey, listen, what? ESPN can't
get us better rooms than this?
I wouldn't worry about
the rooms right now, Dicky.
- We got bigger headaches.
- Like what?
- Doctor won't let Mamby fight.
- [Micky] Why not?
- He's got the flu.
- Mamby got the flu?
- [Alice] Yeah.
- [Lou] Micky, we can still have a fight.
- With who?
- [Lou] Mike Mungin.
[Micky] Mike who,
Mungin? Who's that?
[Dicky] Guy from Philly?
Isn't he in prison?
[Lou] He's been out a few months. I've
called everybody, checked everywhere.
He's the only guy
I could find.
My last few fights
were rough, Lou.
This one's supposed
to be easier.
I mean, we've been fuckin'
preparing for Mamby.
Yeah, but this guy
just came off the couch.
He's been sittin' on his ass.
Could be an easy win for Mick.
Joey Ferrell, remember him?
He knocked his ass out.
[Alice] Micky knocked out
Joey Ferrell.
[Lou] Exactly. And Mungin
just got off the couch.
Can't make weight.
Might be a bit over, though.
- [Alice] How over?
- Maybe 162, 165.
One-sixty-five?
Micky dropped weight.
- He's 146.
- Lou, we prepared for Mamby.
All right?
We prepared for Mamby.
[Lou] This guy just got off
the couch. Micky's in shape.
Roadwork, everything else. This
other guy, he hasn't done dick.
Don't forget, you don't fight,
nobody gets paid.
- OK.
- [TV clicks off]
So, Lou...
Come on, please.
Mick, uh... Joey Ferrell
knocked him out.
[Alice] Gonna be
a hell of a fight, huh?
I'm not doing this.
165 is big.
You knocked out
Joey Ferrell.
- So what? He's a middleweight.
- He just got off the couch.
He's got 20 pounds
on me, Dicky.
Joey Ferrell knocked him out,
you knocked out Joey Ferrell.
- You just said that.
- Yeah, right. You can't be scared.
- Scared?
- Yeah.
Why don't you go
fuckin' fight him?
I'll go fuckin'
fight him. He's fat.
Good. Snap out the teeth. This
is your big comeback, right?
- That's what Alice wants.
- You knocked out Joey Ferrell.
All right. I knocked out
Joey Ferrell, OK?
But the guy is a middleweight.
I'm a welterweight.
They didn't have a fuckin'
heavyweight to throw in there?
Tell him, Dicky. He can do
it, right? He can do anything.
[Micky] Oh, yeah,
Alice. No problem.
You watch from
the outside, pal.
[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
Mike "Machine Gun" Mungin!
[crowd cheering]
[Micky] Holy shit.
Hey, hey, look.
That's Sugar Ray Leonard. Huh?
Hey, Ray. Ray, Ray, Ray.
Hey, Ray! Sugar Ray! Over here!
Dicky. Come on,
look at the size of that guy.
- [Dicky] Holy shit.
- [Micky] Yeah, holy shit.
[O'Keefe] That guy's
no welterweight.
All right, Mick.
We'll have to run
the first few rounds,
tire him out.
He did not just get off
the fuckin' couch.
If he did,
I'm gonna buy a couch like that.
[Dicky] I don't care
who that guy is...
Look at me.
You're Micky Ward.
- [bell dings]
- [crowd cheering]
[announcer] Micky Ward, fighting a
last-minute replacement from Philadelphia.
Ward, thrown around
by a much bigger man!
- Punches, smashing Ward back!
- Jab!
- [grunting]
- Now it's big Mike...
- [crowd clamoring]
- Ward goes down! Ward goes down!
- Come on! Come on!
- ...four, five...
- [cackling]
- ...six...
Micky Ward's a fuckin' bum!
Get rid of this dude!
- Shut up!
- Motherfucker!
[announcer] Mungin didn't even
know he'd be fighting today.
- [clamoring]
- Hey, you, back off!
- Aah!
- Come on! No, no, no, Mick!
[bell dings]
[announcer] Ward,
a respected fighter.
You hope this mismatch
doesn't hurt his confidence.
- [woman 1] You're a loser!
- [woman 2] You're a loser!
[jeering, whistling]
- [dings]
- [crowd jeering]
[grunting]
- [bell dings]
-[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
before we get started, a lot
of people have been asking
about the big night
of boxing on November 4.
Three world championship
bouts...
- [Dicky] Ray! Hey, Ray! Ray!
- [indistinct chatter]
- Hey! [chuckling]
- Dicky. How you doin', man?
- How are ya?
- All right, man.
He's 165 pounds.
ESPN screwed us. You know?
The guy was huge.
Hey. You know, I, uh...
I knocked Ray down.
I look like shit,
but I knocked Ray down.
[chuckling] Hey, let me buy
you guys a drink. All right?
- Want a cold one?
- No, no, no.
I got to leave. I got a plane
to catch. Next time, right?
Hey, Ray, wait, wait. HBO's
makin' a movie on me. You know?
Uh... Can I call ya?
I'm gonna get a fight, and I just like
ya to be there for old time's sakes.
- You commentate or something.
- What's the movie about?
My comeback. Right?
- Call me. Love you, brother.
- I'll call ya.
You don't be a stranger!
[chuckling]
He's funny, "What's
the movie about?"
- [Alice laughs]
- What's that?
[man] You can do better. You're
too good a boxer, I've watched you.
- Are you going to the hospital?
- What is that?
They said I need
get stitches.
Mick, nobody's
got heart like you.
You're a very talented fighter, but
you're not getting the right fights.
It's killing
your chances.
- What's he talking to Mike Toma for?
- [Alice] I don't know, Dick.
I want to give you a real shot.
I want you to come with me.
I want to pay you
to train with my guys.
- Where?
- Las Vegas.
Do it right and make one last run
at this thing before it's too late.
What about my brother?
With all due respect,
he's too much trouble.
You owe it to yourself
to come to Vegas.
Come on, Mick, what
has Dicky done for you?
He got you into fights, he lets
you get beat, like you did tonight.
You shouldn't have been
in that fight.
Eighteen pounds,
think of it that way.
You should've given it up.
- [lively chatter] - [George] Sit down
in the car there. Come on, you.
- Sit the hell down. - [Alice] Just a little
more Scotch for Mama.
There you go. Nice and easy.
Don't hurt yourself coming back.
- Will ya, ya old broad ya, huh?
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, that Sugar Ray,
he's a beautiful man, isn't he?
[Dicky] He didn't recognize me straight
away. You seen the way he was looking at me?
[laughing] He's a good guy.
I like him, I like him.
[Dicky] I seen him on ringside, he was
so happy seeing me and Mick together.
He's all about family, that guy.
Loves to see a family stick together.
[Alice] Mick, what'd Mike Toma
want with you last night, huh?
- He wants to train me in Vegas.
- [Alice] What?
[Dicky] You can't trust that guy,
Micky. He ain't family, you know?
You don't know him.
He say anything about me?
Did he say I could come?
- He didn't mention you.
- Oh.
What are you gonna do in Vegas
without your brother, huh?
That guy just wants to use you
like a piece of toilet paper.
What are you gonna do in Vegas
without Dicky? Without your family?
I know, that's what I told him.
- [Alice] You told him that, right?
- Yeah, I told him.
I said that I needed to
be with my family in Lowell.
[Alice] That's right.
Nothing wrong with that.
Sugar Ray said call him.
We're gonna call him, baby.
- [Dicky] That's right.
- [Alice] You guys can spar a little, right?
- [overlapping chatter]
- Where are they?
- There's my champ!
- [woman] Daddy's home!
Daddy's home!
Daddy's home! Ah!
- Give him a big hug.
- I love you!
- [all chattering]
- Thank you.
Your face hurting you,
sweetheart?
No? 'Cause it's killing me.
[chuckling] Come on.
[Little Dicky] Did Uncle
Micky win the fight?
No, Micky didn't win
this time. Not this time.
Hey, Mick, you take care.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Cheer up. We'll get
you another fight.
I don't know, Ma. I don't
think I wanna do this no more.
- [Dicky] Huh?
- What don't you wanna do no more?
Just, I don't wanna
do it anymore.
- What are you...?
- Hey, Mick, ESPN screwed us.
All right? They owe us. We'll
get another fight. You'll heal up.
- It's gonna be OK.
- Yeah, listen to your brother.
They owe us big-time,
sweetheart.
Maybe they'll even
do Dicky's comeback fight.
- What do you think, huh?
- [sighing]
Oh, come on, cheer up. You take
a little soak when you get home,
have a day or two
to think about it.
I'll find you
a better fight.
A much better fight.
I'm gonna talk to them.
- For Chrissakes, Alice.
- What?
He's been through the ringer.
Leave him alone, will ya?
- What are you talking about? - Let him get
some time to himself. He just got finished.
- What's your fuckin' problem?
- Come on.
Where's Micky?
Is Micky not gonna come in?
[George]
No, he's not coming in.
He needs to get back
and get some rest.
- [overlapping chatter]
- [George] Come on, let's go inside.
- [chatter continues] - [Alice] No. He's
gonna go rest. He's all grumpy.
[George] He's beat up, he's
a little embarrassed, I think.
- [woman] Look at him. Have you
even seen him? - [voices fading]
[TV plays indistinctly]
[no audible dialogue]
[knocking at door]
[knocking louder]
[Micky] Who is it?
[knocking continues]
[knocking]
[muttering quietly]
I saw the shade move.
Micky, the shade
is still moving.
I saw you come to the window,
I know you're in there.
Least you can do is open up
this door and tell me to my face
why you didn't call me
yesterday.
Why'd you stand me up
last night?
I started to call. I was gonna
call, but... I just couldn't.
'Cause you lost the fight?
Maybe, yeah.
'Cause I lost the fight.
How'd you know
my house, anyway?
I asked my brother.
Your thing's coming off.
I mean your other thing.
You got any tape?
Did the black Jewish guy
do this to you?
I didn't get to fight
the black Jewish guy.
You didn't get
to go head, body, head?
Saoul Mamby got the flu.
Guy who took his place
had 20 pounds on me.
I never should've
fought him.
- Why did you?
- Nobody would've got paid.
Everybody said
I could've beat him.
Who's everybody?
My mother, my brother.
So are you gonna take me
to dinner and a movie, or what?
[buzzing]
[sighs]
[footsteps approaching]
- Hey.
- You look great.
- Thank you.
Got a nice house, too.
It's an apartment building.
There's five of 'em in there.
One of my old roommates
lives in one.
Roommate?
What, were you in the Army?
- College.
- College. Wow.
Yeah, a lot of good it
did me. I work in a bar.
Well, you seem to enjoy it.
You're very popular down there.
[scoff] Yeah, popular.
I gotta get out of there.
If I don't drink while I'm
working, I'll fuckin' kill myself.
- What college?
- URI. Full boat.
Full boat's
a scholarship, right?
- Yeah.
- For what?
- I was a high jumper.
- High jumper? You gotta be kidding me.
Fuck you. I was good. I was New
England champ. I cleared 5'8".
- Wow.
- Never graduated. I partied too hard.
- You? [chuckling]
- Ha.
What are we doing
in Richie Rich Lexington?
You come to this
theater a lot?
Yeah, it's a good theater.
They got good movies here.
- Yeah, like what?
-Belli Epi-que.
I think it's Belle Epic.
It's "epic. "Belle Epic.
Belle Epoque.
The New York Times loved it.
Well, I never heard of it.
Where'd you hear about it?
The New York Times?
No, a guy from work.
[man] And the cinematography
is supposed to be gorgeous.
Oh, cool.
[soundtrack music plays]
[snoring softly]
[snorts]
Thank you.
That's the movie
you wanted to see?
There wasn't even
any good sex in it.
Had to read
the whole fuckin' movie.
Fuckin' subtitled.
And some guy from a road
crew recommended it to you?
A fuckin' subtitled movie?
[chuckles]
What's going on, huh?
What's going on? You got a girlfriend
or something? You hiding me from her?
I don't have a girlfriend,
all right?
I... I like you.
I came here 'cause I don't
wanna show my face in Lowell.
I told everybody I was gonna win
that fight and get back on track.
I told my daughter I was gonna get a
bigger apartment so she can move in.
You don't think
I wanted to call you?
I was embarrassed. I mean...
I'm sick of being a fuckin'
disappointment. I...
You really think your
family's looking out for you?
Don't say that
about my family.
What else can I say
after what you told me?
I mean, look at your face.
Look at you.
[Alice] Bullshit, Lou.
I'm not gonna stop callin'
till you make this right
and give us a fight that's fair.
My boy could've
got killed last time.
[TV plays indistinctly]
Yeah, like what?
Just don't tell me he just
got off the fuckin' couch.
Mm-hm.
He's coming off a loss?
Sounds very interesting.
I'll get back to you.
We got a great
opportunity here.
We gotta go find Micky.
Nobody's seen him
for like three weeks.
Jesus.
Used to be Dicky we couldn't
find, now it's both of them?
[Cindy] Ma, I think he's
with that girl from the bar.
- What girl?
- It's that fuckin' girl, Charlene.
That's who he's with.
That girl from the bar.
George was all fuckin' eager
for them to get together.
[Phyllis] I heard
she's into three-ways.
[Sherri] Yeah,
with other girls.
Yeah, like one
of those MTV girls.
[Alice] MTV...
What are you talking about?
Wild.
She acts all fuckin' superior
'cause she went to college.
You girls just go
find your brother, Micky.
Tell him we've got important
business to discuss.
I've gotta go find Dicky.
[child screaming, crying]
Dicky!
[kids chattering, indistinct]
- [window opening]
- [yelling, grunts]
[grunting]
[groans]
Hey, Ma, there's nothing
in there. I just...
It was just some
friends I was seeing.
Don't worry about it, Ma.
[sniffling]
I was just helping
him out, you know?
Hey, Alice...
Alice...
# I started a joke #
# Which started
the whole world cryin' #
# Oh, if only I'd seen #
# That the joke was on me #
# I started to cry #
# Which started
the whole world laughin' #
# Oh, if only I'd seen #
# That the joke was on me #
[both singing]
# I looked at the skies #
- [engine starting]
-# Runnin' my hands over my eyes #
[both continuing]
# And I fell out of bed #
# Hurting my head... ##
[TV plays indistinctly]
So you're Beaver
and you're Red Bear.
- Red Beard.
- She's Red Dog, and that's Beaver.
You're Red Dog. You're Beaver.
- [Phyllis] Yeah, don't use those names.
- [Gail] It's just for family.
Be nice.
Don't use the nicknames.
- [muttering] I don't think I'll fuckin'
call 'em anything. - [door closing]
[George] Speaking
of family...
Hello.
- Alice, this is Charlene.
- Hi.
I've heard a lot about you.
Really? I've heard
a lot about you, too.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Same thing you meant.
Can we just sit down
and talk about business?
I got you another fight, Mick.
Just like I said I would.
Lou Gold
and ESPN made it right.
Just like I told you. Joe
Belinc. Six weeks. The Foxwoods.
Kid's like, you know,
ten and eight, he's nothin'.
You know? And they're
gonna pay us 20 grand.
- Seventeen-five, Dick.
- Seventeen-five.
Which is still...
good money, Mick.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's good, Dick.
I'm just, you know,
trying to figure out
what's best for me.
Like what? Huh?
[Alice] What's best
for you, sweetheart?
Come on, Mick, I thought
you'd be more excited.
Why ain't you more excited?
It's a good fight, good money.
I got tough with Lou Gold.
Told him he owes us.
Yeah, I know, Ma. I don't want things
going the way they've been going.
Mick, that last fight,
it was unfair. That was unfair.
- And we ain't gonna repeat that. Right?
- No, not on your life.
[Dicky] No, but...
It's just you in the ring.
Yeah, I know
it's me in the ring.
But I don't like the way things
have been going here.
- [Alice and Dicky] Where?
- Here. This. Us. Lowell. The whole routine.
- [overlapping chatter]
- George, stay out of it.
You're doing all the talking.
Let him talk. Listen.
- [Alice] I'm askin' him.
- You're tellin' him. Listen.
- [Alice] Stay out of it.
- [George] Don't tell me to stay out of it.
[chuckling]
Mick, what's the problem?
- The problems.
- [Alice] What problems?
- Problems...
- Like what?
Like, maybe you not
showing up on time to train.
Like maybe him having to
come find you in a crack house
when you're supposed
to be at the airport.
[scoffing] I'm sorry.
I don't know who you are,
or why you're talking.
- I'm Charlene. We just met.
- [Alice chuckles]
We're together. Do we need to do
this again? Hi, I'm Charlene.
[sisters mocking]
Hi, I'm Charlene.
- Hey, we're together!
- [chatter stops]
[Alice] What are
you gonna do, Mick?
Listen to some MTV girl
who works in a bar?
What's she know about boxing?
I know that going to Vegas and
gettin' paid to train year-round
sounds a hell of a lot better
than what you got him doing here.
You gonna let her talk
like that to your mother?
[Cathy] Come on, Micky.
I told you, we're together.
This is my girlfriend.
I want her here.
I have done everything...
everything I could for you, Micky.
- This MTV girl comes along...
- Stop calling me an MTV girl,
whatever the fuck
that means.
- Skank.
- It's wild.
[Alice] I've been doing
this over 15 years.
She comes in,
disrespects me.
[Micky] She don't mean
no disrespect, OK?
I had a chance to get paid
to train year-round,
year-round, OK?
That's all she's talking about.
I would hope that you guys
could appreciate that.
[Dicky] I know
what you're talking about.
All right?
I could've had that.
You know? I had...
I had opportunities,
like maybe you're gonna have.
Now...
You want money so you can
train year-round? Yeah?
I'll get you money
so you can train year-round.
- You? How?
- Yeah, I'll do it. Trust me.
Hey, trust me. All right?
Done.
All right? Charlene?
Yeah? Everyone?
[# Sinn Sisamouth
and Pan Ron: Jasmine Girl]
[Dicky] So, you put
in $200, right?
[woman speaks foreign language]
Then you get ten other people
to put in 200...
[translates
in foreign language]
- ...and you got your 2,000.
- [translating]
[speaks foreign language]
Everybody give you $200?
No, not everybody,
just ten of you.
- Ten lucky ones.
- [woman translating]
[chuckles] You rip us off.
[Dicky] No, no, I'm
giving you an opportunity.
You give me $200.
No, you get that
from ten other people
who you offer
the opportunity to.
Right? You understand? No?
[speaks foreign language]
[woman] He thinks you think
Cambodian people are stupid.
I love Cambodian people.
I mean, look at Karen.
She's my girlfriend.
She's beautiful. I love her.
You know, and Brian. We
work on a road crew together.
Well, not so much lately.
We work on
a road crew together.
You haven't been showing up,
that's all I'm saying.
This ain't an
anti-Cambodian thing.
White people do this
to other white people.
It's what makes
the world go round.
Boo Boo, I don't
think that's helping.
I mean, this is... a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
[man speaking Cambodian]
[Dicky stammering]
I mean, they didn't understand.
You know, I mean,
they're practically my gang.
Usually, they listen
to what I say,
but they just didn't
understand the opportunity,
you know,
I was offering them.
- What were we talking about?
- Before you fought Sugar Ray.
Right, right, right. I mean,
Sugar Ray was too much too soon.
You know, I needed to build up
slow. You know, right?
What's this movie about, again?
[HBO producer] I told you,
it's about crack addiction.
Showing what it really is
so kids can see it for real.
[Dicky] Fuck.
We gotta get Mick's money.
[# Led Zeppelin:
Good Times Bad Times]
# In the days of my youth #
# I was told what
it means to be a man #
Yes! That was awesome!
# Now I've reached that age #
# I've tried to do all those
things the best I can #
[indistinct]
# No matter how I try #
# I find my way
into the same ol' jam #
-# Good times, bad times You know
I've had my share # - Go. Right now.
Go, go, go...
# Sixteen, I fell in love with
a girl as sweet as could be #
- # It only took a couple of days #
- [tires screech]
# Till she was rid of me #
- [Dicky] Get out of the car!
- Oh, shit!
Get out of the car,
now! Move!
Put your hands on the roof!
- That's it! Empty your pockets!
- Are you a cop?
Go to the fuckin'
sidewalk.
Move! Fuckin' move!
Don't turn around!
Don't turn around! Gonna
have to take your vehicle.
- How am I gonna get home?
- That's your problem!
Get us some rocks. How
much we got here? Count it.
- [tires squealing]
- [sirens chirping]
- What the fuck?!
- That's the guy!
He did it to me
and he's doing it again!
- Dicky, get on the ground, right now!
- [man] Get that fucking...!
[lively chatter, laughter]
- [grunts]
- [bottles clatter]
[tires squealing]
Ta-da! What do you think?
[applause,
indistinct chattering]
Open the door! Trying to get
off the fuckin' street!
What the fuck! I'm trying
to get off the fuckin' street!
Get your fuckin'
hands off me!
[crowd gasping]
- [sirens approaching]
- Did you hear me?!
[man] You gotta see this!
They're fuckin' up Dicky Eklund!
- [laughter]
- [siren approaching]
It's Dicky! It's Dicky Eklund.
The cops are all over him.
They're fuckin' punching him,
they're beatin' him. He needs help!
[chaotic chatter]
Stay here!
Don't get up. Stay here!
- Listen to him. You stay right here.
- I gotta go.
You better get back here.
Are you fuckin' kidding me?
- Aah!
- [crowd clamoring]
[sirens wailing]
[tires screech]
Hey, what the fuck? Come on,
just put him in the car!
You don't need to do that!
Just put him in the car!
- Come on, just let him go!
- You wanna get involved?
Now you're involved!
You're fuckin' up my brother!
I'll kill you!
- He's a fighter! Break his fuckin' hands!
- [screaming]
- Don't!
- I didn't do nothing!
- Shut the fuck up.
[crowd clamoring]
Move 'em out!
Micky, your hand. Your hand.
[George] Don't tell me to come on.
Back up yourself, for Chrissake.
[officer] Hey, separate
cars, separate cells.
I don't want them making up
some bullshit defense story.
Come on, folks,
time to go home. Let's go.
- [officer] No blankets.
- [Alice] Dicky!
[man shouting]
What the fuck, man!
- [Alice] Micky!
- Jesus Christ.
[officer] Don't get involved.
You shouldn't get involved, sir.
[man] Look at his hands.
Shit.
[sirens chirping,
engines starting]
Go home, folks. Good night!
[sirens wailing]
[typing sounds]
[man] Welcome back, Dicky.
That's 27 arrests.
Ward, one count
of disturbing the peace,
released on your
own recognizance.
Eklund, three counts of assault
and battery on a police officer,
two counts of
resisting arrest,
larceny from a person,
two counts of impersonating
a police officer.
Bail set at $25,000.
Case continued,
two weeks from today.
- [gavel bangs]
- [low chatter]
- Come on. - [man] Judy,
can I have the file three-57?
I need a copy of
the discovery reports as well.
Mick, you're gonna say it
was self-defense, right?
- You did it to yourself, Dicky.
- What?
You're gonna say it
was self-defense, right?
You came outside, you seen them
beatin' on me, I didn't do nothin'.
Right? I was just waitin' outside like
anybody? Mick, I was doing it for you!
You did it for me? What, this?
Do me a favor, don't do fuckin'
nothing for me no more, OK?
I'm fuckin' done
lyin' for you.
[Dicky] What are you
gonna do without me? Huh?
This isn't how
it was meant to go down!
They should've
just put me in the car!
[Dicky's voice echoing]
Huh? Oh, Mick, come on! Mick!
- [buzzing]
- [door clanging]
[chains rattling]
[man 1] Dicky!
Hey, what's up, Dicky!
[man 2] Hey, Eklund!
- [men] Dicky!
- [indistinct chattering]
Hey, you knocked out
Sugar Ray!
[prisoners chanting]
Dicky, Dicky, Dicky...
[door buzzing]
[intercom buzzing]
Who is it?
[Charlene]
I don't want to see you, Micky.
- Charlene...
-I can't take it.
I'm not gonna let you
or your family drag me down.
I'm quitting, Charlene, OK?
I'm done fightin'.
I don't need it anymore.
- That's fuckin' stupid.
-[Micky] What? Why?
Because it's sad that you
let them take it away from you
with their stupid bullshit.
What else can I do, Charlene?
There's a lot you can do, Micky.
There's this guy that
your dad wants you to meet.
You just don't think you
can do it without Dicky.
Charlene...
[Charlene] Don't call.
Come on.
- Don't call me, OK?
-[sighing]
[man 1] Hey, Dicky,
you hurtin', man?
[Dicky grunting]
[man 2] Poor fucker!
[crying out]
[man 1] Hang in there, man!
[man 3] Go, Dicky!
-[groaning]
- [voices overlapping, echoing]
[man 1] Hey, Dicky!
[man 2] Hey, keep it quiet!
[voices continue echoing,
overlapping]
Hey, Micky!
Bring another bucket, huh?
Good.
[intro music playing on radio]
[announcer] And this Friday,
an HBO original documentary.
Right here in Lowell, Mass,
the story of Dick Eklund,
a once-promising boxer
who turned criminal...
[switches off]
- [# 'Til Tuesday: Voices Carry]
- [indistinct chatter]
[woman 1] Oh, look who it is.
[whispering] That's him.
That's Dicky's brother.
- [woman 2] Hey, Micky.
- Regular.
[register buttons beeping]
Hey.
- Hey, what's up, Mick?
- [man] Look who's here.
- Good to see you, bro.
- How you doing?
How you feeling? How's the hand?
- Ah, it's gettin' there.
- Looks better.
Why don't you come down to the
gym? And work out. If you want.
- Hey, you fat fuck, you're getting big.
- Yeah, I know. I just...
Been roofin' with my father,
spending time with Kasie.
Now I gotta worry about
this movie on HBO tonight.
What are you looking at?
Movie's not about him.
It's about his crazy brother.
I gotta go.
- Come back to the gym, Mick.
- [woman 2] Bye, Mick!
Don't go watch
that crazy shit on TV, don't!
[prisoners cheering]
[man] Hollywood!
- [cheers]
- Get a look! Get a look, all right!
Going to Hollywood!
Going to Hollywood, oh, yeah!
All right! [laughing]
Whoo-hoo!
[all cheering, clapping]
All right, get this started!
[all chattering]
-[intro music plays]
- [cheers and applause]
[narrator] Lowell was the birthplace
of the Industrial Revolution in America.
- [mocking] Industrial Revolution... Lowell.
- [laughter]
I used to live over there. This
town got good memories, right?
- Check it out.
- [Boo Boo] Fuck, yeah.
- This house here, this white house?
- [Dicky] Oh, yeah.
White, big fat guy. First time
I got my crack, over here.
Did you ever know that? They
smoke crack at the White House?
-[prisoners laughing]
- White, black, Puerto Rican, everything.
The first time I did crack,
or whatever, I was about 23
and a friend of mine gave
me a gram, or whatever.
Fuck, I wish that'd
never happened.
Before that, I'd been doing
the Silver Mittens and stuff.
I was the only kid.
I'd be 12... I was shit-faced.
[Dicky] I'll tell ya
how crack works.
[inhaling deeply]
When it enters your lungs...
- [Little Dicky] I wanna watch, Daddy.
- Oh, my God. No, sweetie.
- You go back upstairs.
- But I wanna watch Daddy on TV.
I know, baby. You can't watch
Daddy right now, all right?
You go back upstairs
and go to bed, OK?
[Boo Boo] OK, yeah, there's my
boys right there. Check 'em out.
- What kind of snake's that? Python?
- Yeah, check it out, man.
- It's not gonna bite me or something?
- Nah, he's cool.
[prisoners laughing]
- It's been a while. I'll take
anything right now. -[prisoners laughing]
[Dicky] I never thought I'd kiss a
fuckin' snake. I always dreamed about it...
[laughter]
Do a lot of shit
when you're high, right?
[all murmuring]
[man on TV]
Dicky... put Lowell on the map.
He knocked
Sugar Ray Leonard down.
Yeah, he knocked him down,
but I don't think
it was a knockdown.
- I think he slipped.
- He knocked him down.
- He didn't slip.
- He slipped.
- Oh... and you're from Lowell.
- Yeah, come on.
- That's a fuckin' lie!
-They said he's in trouble with drugs.
What is this? Are you talking
shit about the family?
- Oh, no, no, no...
- I heard you say "Dicky, Micky..."
We're not like that. This is
not what Lowell is all about.
I thought he could
make a comeback
and make us proud,
but he didn't.
I don't know what
Dicky was thinking.
[woman 1] Very disappointing,
very disgusting.
[woman 2] You brought the city of
Lowell back 30 years. We're not happy.
-[Jimmy] Hello?
- Jimmy?
Hey, will you do me a favor?
Make sure Kasie's
not watching HBO?
Actually, we're watching it
right now, Mick,
but don't worry about it.
I got it...
I want her to see it.
Let her see who her uncle is.
- What?
-Who you are.
Who I am? What are
you talking about?
Kids need to know
the truth, Mick.
Laurie, turn it off, please.
She does not need to see this.
She doesn't need to see it.
- She's a kid.
- [dial tone]
When you smoke crack,
you know...
...you feel so much lighter.
You know, you feel young,
like when everything was
in front of you,
everything was just...
...everything was... just...
...it was in front of you,
you know?
And then...
...it fades and you
gotta get high again.
[HBO producer] Your part in the movie
is gonna end with you going to jail.
[prisoners chuckling]
What about little Dicky?
Who's gonna take care
of him, huh?
- [prisoners chuckling]
-[Dicky] You guys can't talk to 'em?
Oh, man...
Turn this shit off.
Turn this off, all right?
Turn it off.
Will you turn this off?
If you don't...
I'm turning it fuckin' off.
[all protesting]
Hey, hey, that is my life.
- My movie night!
- That's my fuckin' life out there.
- I wanna watch this. I don't care.
- I will fuck you up!
You fuckin' want some?
Don't fuckin' try me.
- [all clamoring]
- [Dicky] I still fuckin' got it, OK?
- You fuckin' want some?!
- [clamoring]
That's my son there,
and you're laughin' at him?!
That's my son.
He's crying. He needs me.
And I'm fuckin' stuck in here?
[O'Keefe] But you know what?
Dicky was a street kid.
Micky, you watching this?
What are they doing to us?
[O'Keefe continues
indistinctly]
Ma, I don't know
what to tell you.
You're pretending like you
don't know what's going on.
He's been doing this for years.
- [knocking at door]
- Yeah, I know it's horrible, Ma, but...
- [sighing]
- [knocking continues]
- What do you think?
-[Alice] You think they set him up?
What do you think he was doing?
[Alice] You know, gave him money,
gave him drugs for the movie. Right?
Micky... Micky?
-Shit. Micky...
- [hangs up]
[sniffling]
[prisoners chattering nearby]
[man speaks
indistinctly over PA]
[bells tolling nearby]
[# Red Hot Chili Peppers:
Strip My Mind]
- You got a new bag, huh?
- Yup.
- New bracket, too?
- What happened to the peanut?
- I don't know.
It's like a beach ball.
# Arthur J. did #
# Indicated #
# The boulevard will never be
so full of love and life again #
# Hot as Hades #
# Early '80s #
# Sing another song, make me
feel like I'm in love again #
# Oh, yeah #
# Oh #
# Please don't strip my mind #
# Leave something behind #
# Leave something behind ##
- Mick. Sal Lonano.
- Hey, Mick, how you doing?
You own a cab company, you're
a good businessman, right?
- Yeah, he's very organized.
- How's the hand?
It's good. You know,
it's getting better. Stronger.
Yeah, you know, I made a few calls
already. I talked to Buddy Tags.
Said he can set up
something local,
something
to start back with.
- Get your confidence back.
- [Sal] That's it.
You gotta get your
confidence back. That's all.
Hm.
Your dad wants Sal to manage
ya, and he wants me to train ya.
But I'll only do it
on one condition.
- No crazy-time nonsense.
- [Sal] It's how it's gotta be.
- No Dicky. No Alice.
- [Charlene] No Dicky. No Alice.
I get it, I get it.
I'm good, I understand.
Look, I appreciate
the opportunity.
I can't take the bullshit, Mick.
- No offense, Georgie.
- [George] None taken.
I'm gonna be the one who gets
his balls cut off, anyway.
[chuckles]
- Yeah. You laugh.
-[Alice] You...
- ...fuckin' traitor!
- What are you doing?
What the hell's
the matter with you?!
[yelping] Come on!
The pans hurt!
Do they hurt?!
I hope it hurts!
- Sal Lonano is a good man!
- A good man?!
He's a legitimate businessman,
for Chrissakes!
- Legitimate businessman?
- Yes. What?
[Alice] Oh, my God,
you know what that sounds like?
- He's a crook, George!
- He owns a taxi cab company!
- He's organized!
- Oh, my God. He's a cab driver.
He knows everything
about boxing, right?
I don't think so!
He's gonna steal your son's
money and rob him blind!
Why would you think that?
Why would you even think that?
- Why can't you trust anybody with...?
- I know people.
I know, George, you think I don't
know anything, but I know people.
- I know you know people.
- And that Sal Lonano
banana fucking thing,
we don't need that in our lives!
We haven't made one dollar
with these kids!
- You betrayed me!
- Oh, bullshit, I betrayed you.
- You always react the same way.
- He's a fuckin' crook!
What's Micky supposed to do?
Dicky's in jail!
We're not talking about
his trainer, sweetheart!
We're talking about
his manager, that's me!
But, Mom, maybe Micky
should try something different!
What are you doing opening
your mouth in my kitchen?
- You owe me $200.
- I said I was gonna pay you next week.
[Alice] I don't want
another word outta you.
That was last month
you told me two weeks.
You take sides against me in
my own house, you owe me money?
[Little Alice] And Ma's been
great to Micky, Sherri.
Really, I mean, who's gonna look out
for Micky better than his own mother?
It's that fuckin' girl,
Charlene. We gotta get rid of her.
Ma, we gotta get rid of her.
It's that girl, Charlene.
- She gotta go. - [George] You're
gonna get Charlene involved?
Is that what you're
telling me? Huh?
[Gail] I know where she lives.
[George] What are you
pickin' on her for?
[Gail] She lives in that
yellow house on Stevens Street.
[Alice] I'm gonna go talk to
Micky, sort this out for myself.
[George] Yeah, sure. You go handle it
with your vigilantes. All of you now.
This is wrong, Alice!
[up-tempo percussion plays]
I got it!
Get outta my way!
Get in the car!
- Come on, come on, come on, come on!
- [engine starting]
- Get in the car.
- [tires squealing]
[banging, clattering]
- Yeah, they're in there!
- Up there on the second floor.
- Micky!
- [chatter outside]
[Alice] Where the hell are you?
You up there? Come on down!
Where are you?
Holy shit, Micky, your mother
and your sisters are here.
No, don't.
Do not go out there. Please.
No, I'm not hiding from
your crazy fuckin' family.
Hi.
[Alice] Well, well,
well. Look at this.
Look at what?
- Why you hiding from us, Micky?
- He's not hiding.
Wasn't talking to you.
I was talking to my son.
What are you doing,
Mickster, huh?
I'm right here. I ain't
hiding from nobody, Alice.
You're not
helping yourself
with your father's
scumbag friend Lonano.
What are you gonna do, turn
your back on Dicky next? Huh?
All we ever wanted for you
was to be world champion.
Micky's a grown man.
He can think for himself.
- Shut your mouth.
- [sisters] Skank.
Don't call me skank.
I'll rip that nasty hair
right out of your
fuckin' head.
[Alice] I'm his mother.
And his manager.
You're not my manager anymore.
And I'm not waiting for Dicky, OK?
I'm not gettin' any younger.
Who's gonna look
after you, sweetheart?
I mean, come on. I know
you don't understand it,
but I had nine kids and I
love every one of you the same.
You got a funny way
of showing it,
letting him get beat up,
letting him get his hand broken.
- You're crazy.
- You fuckin' bar skank!
- What did I just say to you?
- Don't put your hands on her...
[screaming, clamoring]
[indistinct arguing]
- Get off of me!
- Stop it!
[Micky] Let her go!
Let her go!
- Fuck you, Charlene!
- Fuck you!
- Get the fuck outta here! Now!
- Fuck you, Charlene!
- Skank!
- Micky...
- Fuckin' bitch!
- [Alice] Oh, my God! Gail!
- What'd she do to your nose?
- [angry chattering]
What is happenin'?
What is happenin' to everybody?
I don't understand, sweetheart.
[tires squealing]
[# Traffic: Rock 'N' Roll Stew]
# The road's much too long
seems like I'm wastin' my time #
# Gone, gone, gone #
# I don't care
It's where I'm from #
# I'm on the road again #
# LA to London
is a mighty long time #
# Eight hours flying
can bring you down #
# Sitting near a suit
who's a red-neck going #
# His eyes are moving but
there's no life showing #
Why, uh... Why do you think
I spell my name with an E?
'Cause I don't.
- [Sal] No-E Micky Ward.
- Hey, somebody push the button.
- [grunting]
- [dings]
- Where we going? What's with the ring?
- Ring's across the street.
- The ring's across the street?
- Yeah.
Yeah, smaller venue. They got
no dressin' rooms over there.
- Yeah, but...
- Micky, It's just a start. Don't worry.
Hey. Good luck.
[audience cheering]
- [O'Keefe shouting indistinctly]
- [heavy punches]
- [O'Keefe] That's it!
- [crowd clamoring]
- Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
- [crowd cheering]
- [bell dinging]
- [cheering]
[# Aerosmith:
Back In The Saddle]
# I'm back #
# I'm back
in the saddle again #
# I'm back #
# I'm back
in the saddle again #
# Ridin' into town alone
by the light of the moon #
# I'm lookin'
for old Sukie Jones #
# She crazy horse saloon #
# Barkeep gimme a drink #
# That's when
she caught my eye #
# She turned
to give me a wink #
# That'd make a grown man cry #
# I'm back
in the saddle again #
# I'm back #
# I'm back
in the saddle again #
# I'm back... ##
[bell ringing]
[man on PA]
Visit for Dick Eklund.
[man] Dicky!
Eklund, you got a visitor!
[Dicky] Heard you won a bunch
of fights, Mick. That's good.
I know you know
what I been doing.
I'm sure Alice
and everybody else told you.
I just wanted to tell you
to your face myself.
I got new management.
Mickey O'Keefe's my trainer now.
It's all good.
Yeah. They got you
fightin' Alfonso Sanchez.
- On HBO.
- And you're proud of that?
- Fuckin' right.
- HBO is invested in the Mexican.
I didn't think they were gonna
be invested in me?
- I got a shot. I'm gonna take it.
- Wake up.
They don't care
if he kills you.
Mike Toma did it.
He's using you,
like a stepping-stone
for Sanchez.
- Why don't you see?
- Oh, I see.
How could I stand a chance without the
great Dick Eklund in my corner, right?
You didn't give a fuck
if I got killed by Mungin.
Now all of a sudden you're worried
Sanchez is gonna hurt me? Why?
'Cause you're stuck in here and can't
be the center of attention no more?
- You need it that bad?
- I've seen this Mexican fight.
He fights, hits, like
a fuckin' mule, all right?
Fifteen knockouts,
undefeated. You crazy?
And that taxi cab idiot,
Lonano, he went right for it.
He's a paper gangster,
he's using you to steal money.
Why can't you just shut up
and be happy for me?
I spent the last ten years of my life
in bad fights set up by you and Alice.
I finally got
a good thing going for me
and you can't be fuckin'
happy for me? Why?
What's your plan?
How you gonna fight Sanchez?
- I ain't here to talk about that.
- What's your plan?
- I am not here to talk about that.
Yes, you are.
You watch the fight
and you'll see the plan.
I can't watch it. They don't let us.
It's too fuckin' violent. I mean...
- [man] Two minutes, Dicky. - They'll let us
watch a stupid documentary about crack,
but I can't watch my own
brother fighting, you know?
Hey... Mick, what is it?
You scared?
You embarrassed because
you don't even have a plan?
I'm your brother. Just tell me.
Are you gonna shit on it
no matter what I say?
I'm not gonna shit on it.
Just tell me.
Go toe-to-toe. Overhand right
in the middle rounds.
He's weak against
the overhand right.
- Who came up with that? Fatty fuck O'Keefe?
- Fuck you, Dicky.
You gotta run against this guy.
Let him punch himself out.
Take him to the body,
right? Get inside.
Switch stances like you're gonna
work his right, hit him on the left.
You ain't me. All right?
You can't be me.
- Careful. Switch outside...
- You had a hard enough time
being you when you
had your fuckin' chance,
and that's
why you're in here.
I'll fight
Sanchez the way I fight.
I'm talking about the
way you fight, you moron!
Yeah, you know I'm right!
He knows I'm right. All right.
-[audience cheering]
- He knows I'm right.
[up-tempo intro music playing]
[announcer 1] Ward's record:
29 wins, seven losses
so far, 20 KOs.
He's been a little better since
he refocused himself on the sport,
as JB pointed out.
Now, here's Ward's opponent,
Alfonso Sanchez,
out of Tijuana, Mexico.
You see the record: 16 wins,
15 KOs, eight first-round KOs.
[announcer 2] There's Mike
Toma, the promoter of the fight,
who has a lot invested
in Sanchez.
And he says that Sanchez is
one of the most talented
young prospects
in the sport of boxing.
- [bell dings]
- [crowd clamoring]
[announcer 1] This is really one of
the saddest kinds of fights in boxing.
- Get out of the corner!
- Micky Ward is 31 years old,
he's here because he needs the
money, he's taking a beating...
[announcer 3] And my point is that he doesn't
really have to sit here and take this beating.
- He can do something about it.
- [announcer 2] Which is what?
Have his corner throw
in the towel?
- [announcer 3] Or fight back.
- Get back.
[crowd booing, jeering]
[announcer 1]
You can see his power.
Every time he hits
Ward, he backs him up.
- [announcer 2] How about taking
points away from him? - [booing]
[announcer 1] Larry, unless
the referee does, you can't.
[announcer 3] The referee should
just go ahead and stop this fight.
He knows that Micky doesn't want
to be here. I wouldn't even make...
He's fightin' scared, Dick.
Runnin' away, not hittin' back.
[Alice]
Oh, Jesus. He's gonna get hurt.
Doing that same old shit.
They never seen such
an embarrassing performance.
He's doing what I told him, Ma.
He's doing what I told him.
Don't worry about it.
- [announcer 1] Micky Ward, showing
nothing but respect. - [bell dinging]
What are you runnin' around for?
Stop running around!
Shut the fuck up, Sal!
Shut the fuck up!
I don't know what you're doing,
Micky. Want to fuckin' tell me?
'Cause I don't know
what you're doing.
We have lost all five rounds,
is that what you want?
[announcer 1] Dreadful. This
is dreadful, dreadful stuff.
You gotta show me something soon,
Mick, or I'm gonna stop the fight.
Now they're gonna
stop the fight, Micky.
He's gotta go inside, Ma.
He's gotta take it to the body.
He's gotta.
- [Charlene] Come on, get your punches up...
- Don't stop the fight.
- They're gonna stop this fight.
- Then you gotta do something, baby.
[O'Keefe] That's not what we talked about,
Micky. We had a plan and you're not doing it.
- Now, let's go.
- [bell dinging]
[announcer 1] All right, Micky.
You've lost the first five rounds.
What's the next
strategy gonna be?
Double right hand by Sanchez,
then a triple left hook.
A couple of the left hooks landed
flush on the cheek of Micky Ward.
- Ward tying Sanchez up.
- [indistinct]
- Very curious performance by Micky Ward.
- Come on, Micky, come on!
[announcer 3] Ward seems... trying to land
one big shot to change Sanchez's mind...
[announcer 1]
And he's beginning to open up.
Taking advantage of more and more
opportunities to get close to Ward
and throw against a fighter...
- [bell dinging]
- [referee] Time!
...who's not defending
himself by punching.
[announcer 3] Sanchez is gonna
try to end this fight.
[bell dings]
- What are you doing? Come on!
- That's it.
Good boy!
- [announcer 1] He's down on an uppercut!
- [crowd clamoring]
- Nicely thrown left uppercut inside.
- ...three, four, five...
[announcer 2] And right after Ward
threw a pretty good right hand.
Mick, you all right?
Come to me. Come to me.
[announcer 2] This is a fight
that should be stopped.
- Come on, head, body, head.
- Ugh.
[announcer 1]
This is not professional.
[announcer 3]
That's exactly what I'm saying.
- Punch him! You gotta punch! - Someone
should pay me to watch this. [chuckling]
Come on, man!
Head, body, head!
[announcer 3] That was
a good body shot by Ward.
[announcer 1] That was good.
Maybe it'll turn him around.
[announcer 3]
Maybe. I'm talking about if...
- [crowd screaming] - [announcer 1] Sanchez
drops like he's shot! Oh, my God!
The most unlikely
knockout you have ever seen.
[announcer 2] That was a kidney
shot, the kind of kidney shot...
- ...nine, ten!
- [bell dinging]
- [cheering] - [announcer 1] I still
don't believe what I just saw.
[cheering]
Oh, Micky won!
[announcer 1] Now, did Micky
Ward just make idiots of us all
with a spectacular piece
of strategy?
Take another look. Amazing.
A brilliant win in the career of
Micky Ward out of Lowell, Mass.
Unbelievable defeat
at the hands of Micky Ward,
who had all but given away the
first half-dozen rounds of the bout.
[announcer 3] I think what
Micky did was he recognized
that he'd hurt the guy
with the body shot.
Micky's a better fighter than that to
not be runnin' from that guy like that.
[announcer 1]
Theater of the unexpected.
Hey, you never know
what can happen, right?
Never give up in this game,
right? Never give up.
- [laughing]
- You can't make it up, folks.
[announcer 3] You hear what he said? He
said, "You can't give up in this game."
[announcer 2] Well, maybe Micky Ward
heard me say you should stop this fight
and he went out and stopped it.
- Right there. Right there.
- Yeah! [laughing] I can't believe it.
I'm lookin' over, and I'm thinkin'
to myself like they were thinkin':
This thing is over.
But I tell you what, if you
looked at the commentators,
they started to take their headsets
off before he was even counted out.
They just wanted
to get out of there.
Mick, Mick.
I just spoke to Mike Toma.
- He told me something very interesting.
- Holy shit, what?
He just told me,
had Sanchez won tonight,
he would've gotten
the title shot.
- Holy Christ, that's beautiful.
- Why? Why is that beautiful?
- A title shot. Mick gets the shot.
- Micky gets the shot!
- Are you kidding me?
- Are you sure about that?
I just spoke to the guy. Mike! Come
here, Mike. Look, tell these guys.
- Hey, Mike Toma. Thank you.
- Congratulations.
You're not a stepping-stone anymore.
I always knew you had the talent.
That was a hell of a strategy, wearing
him down and taking it to the body.
Thirty years in the business, I'd
never seen a knockout like that.
Larry Merchant was
writing your obituary,
and Sanchez drops
like he's shot with a gun.
- [all laugh]
- Where'd you get that?
That's the first thing
my brother taught me.
Tap 'em to the head,
ding 'em to the body.
- That's a hell of a body shot.
- Thank you.
- You ready for a title shot?
- I ain't gettin' no younger.
- [excited chattering]
- Thanks, Mr. Toma. Thank you.
- He's ready. You're ready, aren't ya?
- [excited chatter]
[Sal] Shea Neary in London
for the title.
[George] Are you kidding,
we got some celebrating to do.
- [Mike] Yeah, I think so.
- [George] Thank you so much.
- You're gonna have a great champ in my boy.
- Thank you, Mr. Toma.
- [all chattering, chuckling] - [Sal] It's
what your brother would've always wanted.
- He's not even gonna be there.
- [chatter continues indistinctly]
[buzzing]
- Hey! [laughing]
- Daddy!
- Come here, buddy.
- Daddy, Daddy!
[laughing] Good to see you! Ah!
That's a good hug!
That's a good hug! Ah, yeah!
- Sweetheart.
- Hey, Ma.
Oh, you look so good.
Oh, my God.
- You have clean teeth.
- I do! Look at my teeth!
- [chuckling] - I got new teeth.
Everything. How you think I look?
- [Little Dicky] Good.
- [Dicky] Yeah?
[indistinct chatter]
- [punching sounds]
- Cake and more cake.
- Ice cream? Huh?
- Ice cream and cake.
Ice cream and cake
and cake. Right?
Ice cream, cake and cake.
Ice cream, cake and cake...
[Dicky] Quacka!
Ma.
- They gave you some new teeth, huh?
- Yeah. [chuckles]
Hey, Georgie. What, they
let you outta the house now?
- [George chuckles] Yeah.
- Lettin' him outta the house, Ma?
[George] Hey, look, I want
you to meet Sal Lonano.
How you doing, Dicky?
Let's spar. Huh?
[indistinct]
Hey, Charlene.
[running footsteps]
[giggling] Welcome back!
Shh! It's supposed to be
a surprise. You're late.
- [Micky] Hey.
- Hey.
Mick, I can't even tell you, being in
this smelly-ass locker room. You know?
Being back with you,
this is what got me through.
- You look good. Your eyes are clear.
- Yeah. You know...
...Alice says prison might've
been the best thing for me.
Got me clean.
Got me clear. Up here.
It's a beautiful thing, Dick.
- I gotta talk to you about something.
- Yeah.
Look at this locker.
The old locker. Huh?
I love it. Fuckin' love it.
[kisses, chuckles]
I made a promise to them
I wouldn't work with you again.
Huh?
I had to. After everything
that happened, I'm sorry.
You stickin' to that?
I'm glad you're back.
You look good.
I don't know what else to say.
- Mick, you fuckin' kidding me?
- No, I'm not.
- [stammering] Oh, hey, Mick.
- Come on, come on!
You gotta... Ma. You gotta
do this at home. Please?
- What are you talkin' about?
What's the matter? - Mom, please?
- All right, girls. Let's pack it up.
- [overlapping chatter]
I know.
We'll see him at home.
[crashing]
[locker door squeaking]
- [sister 1] What the hell...?
- [Alice] Would you please pack it up?
- [sister 2] Why?
- [Alice] Let's get it put away.
If that's what Micky wants,
we're gonna put it away.
- There's your brother.
- [all] Dicky...
- How ya doing?
- Micky?
[hushed whispering]
That's nice. That's nice.
We've been working on it
for two weeks.
Sherri, come on, stop it.
- [sobbing]
- All right, girls, come on, let's go home.
It's not the time to do this,
obviously. Come on.
You stay here.
What the hell's going on?
- What's going on?
- We ain't gonna work together.
He don't want me
to work with him.
What're you talking about?
[Alice] That's not right.
Micky never would've won
Sanchez without Dicky.
That's fuckin' bullshit!
Take it back!
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Don't you
fuckin' talk to my mother that way.
- Fuck you!
Take 'em home.
Why don't you ask Micky?
If we're gonna train,
they gotta go.
They gotta go,
Mick, come on.
Ask him, George. Ask him if he would've
won Sanchez without his brother?
[Dicky] Hey, take him
outside, all right?
No, I wouldn't have won Sanchez
if it wasn't for Dicky.
- [Charlene] How can you say that
to O'Keefe? - [Micky] Because it's true.
I went with that game plan,
it wasn't working.
So I went back to what
I learned with Dicky.
And I wouldn't have won without
you, either, O'Keefe, OK?
I mean, you know that.
We worked hard.
You got me ready.
You got your confidence
and your focus from O'Keefe,
and from Sal and
your father and from me.
- Dicky's a junk bag.
- Hey.
He's a junk bag!
- Fuck you, Charlene.
- Fuck you.
- I'm eight months sober.
- Oh, yeah,
and I'm sure you're gonna need
something now that you're out.
"Oh, my back. Oh, my back."
- Fuck you always picking on me for?
- No, fuck you!
And what about O'Keefe?
We're in the same boat.
One day at a fucking time, right,
O'Keefe? You know what I mean?
What, it's all right
for him to be here?
Why am I the fuckin' problem?
I'm his blood, I'm his family!
- You are the problem!
- I'm the one fighting, OK?
Not you, not you, and not you.
- I know what I need.
- [Charlene] And you need Dicky?
I want Dicky back.
And I want you, Charlene.
And I want O'Keefe.
I want my family.
What's wrong with that?
It's not the deal we made, baby.
[Sal] She's right, Micky.
That's not the deal.
It wasn't the deal. Come on,
you can't do this to us.
- You sound like them now.
- I sound like them now?
- Yeah, you sound like them.
- You sound like them.
How could I do this to you?
"You can't do that to us.
He can't do that to us."
You sound like them.
You should fuckin' listen
to yourself.
You sound like them and maybe
this is where you belong.
That's the way
you love him?
- Charlene!
- Come on!
You wanted your
brother? Good luck.
- [George] O'Keefe, come on.
- Mickey.
[George] Mickey.
Come on, everything
happens for a reason.
You know? Maybe it's for
the best. God has a plan.
Wanna spar with your brother?
Dick Eklund, pride of Lowell!
[Alice] Watching
that for years, huh?
- [grunting]
- Micky, Micky!
[Alice] Whoa, hey!
What the hell are you doing?
- [groaning]
- Micky!
- Daddy! Daddy, Daddy!
- [Alice] For crying out loud!
Take that baby out of here.
I told you take him away
ten minutes ago!
Sweetheart, you all right?
You OK? Your back?
What are you doing?
What's the matter with you?
Can this be my fight,
Alice? Huh? Just once?
Maybe just this one time
not for Dicky? Huh?
I know you think
he's coming back.
He's 40 years old and doesn't have a
tooth in his head that's his fuckin' own.
[Dicky] I'll go
fuckin' ten rounds.
Let your brother talk
for a minute here, all right?
- What are you sayin', sweetheart?
- I'm Shea Neary...
Shut up before I bust your
fuckin' head open, Dicky.
- Hey, hey... - What are you gonna do?
Come on. I'm Shea Neary.
You want me to bust
your fuckin' head open?
Come on, come on!
George, please!
- Dicky!
- Please! What are you saying?
Tell me what you're saying.
This is supposed to be
my fight.
This is my shot at a title. I
won't get another one after this.
- Am I being selfish?
- No.
Am I saying, "Micky, Micky, Micky?"
You know what? If I am, I'm sorry.
I thought I was fightin'
for the championship.
And I thought you
were my mother, too.
I am your mother.
Yeah, Ma.
Mick, I'm sorry. I had no idea
you felt like that, all right?
If I made mistakes,
I'm gonna be better.
I don't wanna hurt you.
I am so sorry. I'm sorry.
- [crashing]
- [George] Dicky!
Stay with him.
[George] Dicky... Dicky!
- [George] Dicky!
- Gotta do something.
Dicky, wait, come on!
- Micky wants you! I want you!
- I gotta do something.
I know what that means.
Don't do this!
[sirens wailing in distance]
Hey, Chan.
- What's going on?
- Hey, Dicky.
Hey, Dicky's back!
- [all cheering]
- Hey!
- [all chattering]
- Look at you!
What's up, my boy, huh? How
you doing? Good to see you, man.
- You look good. Welcome back.
- Yeah, you're looking good.
- Great.
- Good to see ya.
- Welcome home.
- Hi, honey.
What's up, man?
You're looking good.
- Wanna head upstairs?
- Dicky's back.
- Hi, Dicky. We're gonna party.
- Go upstairs, man? Huh?
- Huh? Go upstairs, take a while? Huh?
- We missed you!
- Let's go, buddy.
- Come on, Dicky.
- Make for a little party for you...
- Hey, come back.
- What the fuck's that all about?
- What the hell was that?
[intercom buzzing]
Charlene? It's Dicky.
[Charlene] Get off my porch,
you piece of shit.
[buzzing]
- How fuckin' dare you...
-[buzzing]
- ...cocksucker...
- ...fuckin'...
-[buzzing]
[intermittent cursing
with buzzing]
- [window opening]
- You're a fuckin' asshole, Dicky.
- I want you off my fuckin' porch!
- Huh?
Why don't you just fuckin' come
down here and talk to me, huh?
Such an asshole, coming to my
fucking house. You piece of shit!
- Standing on my porch...
- Charlene...
It's not fuckin' lady-like
to be shoutin'
in the street like this.
You're such a fuckin'
cocksucker coming over here.
- [Dicky] Please?
- Oh, yeah, you think I fuckin' care?
- Come on, just fuckin'...
- Get off my fuckin' porch, Dicky!
[quietly] Would you just
fuckin' come down here...
and talk to me, huh?
[dog barking]
What kind of dog is that?
Is that a Cocker Spaniel?
All right, I know you
can't fuckin' stand me.
Really, what makes you say that?
I ain't got no use for
you, either. All right?
But my brother loves ya.
And you can't just
run away because of me.
He don't deserve that.
All right?
So I will quit
if you want me to quit.
- You're full of shit.
- I swear to God.
I will quit if it means
you'll come back, all right?
But I want you to
think about something.
Micky has a chance to do
something that I never did.
That in my time, I never had.
"Oh, yeah, my big chance
was with Sugar Ray Leonard.
I'm so great.
I'm the pride of fuckin' Lowell.
Oh, yeah, I fought Sugar Ray
Leonard." I've heard it.
I came here
to make things right.
- OK, let's make things right.
- Yeah.
Number one: You didn't
knock down Sugar Ray Leonard.
He tripped.
I was in the ring.
Don't you think I know what
really happened that day?
All right? What have you
ever done with your life?
- I like my life.
- Yeah, what you ever done with it?
- I like my life now, Dicky.
- What have you done with your life?
You're a college
dropout, Charlene.
You're just a little
bar girl. Your life sucks.
All right. I drank too much.
I worked in a lot of bars.
And I ruined a lot of opportunities, but
I'm trying to do something better here.
- And so is Micky.
- And so am I.
And he needs me. You heard him.
And I know he needs you.
What is that blue shit
on your arm?
It's icing.
OK. I'll see ya
in Micky's corner.
Otherwise,
go fuck yourself.
- It's a deal.
- All right? It's a deal.
[car approaches]
We worked it out
for you. Ask her.
Good. Go get O'Keefe back, too.
[Dicky] I will.
Hey, Mick...
You think I knocked down
Sugar Ray Leonard?
Went ten rounds. One of the best
ever and he couldn't hurt you.
You were my hero.
I was.
I'm sorry.
- You are?
- Mm-hm.
[# The Rolling Stones:
Can't You Hear Me Knocking]
[indistinct chatter]
# Can't you hear me knocking #
# On your window #
# On your door #
# Can't you hear me knocking #
# Down your dirty street #
[airplane taking off]
# Help me, baby #
# Ain't no stranger #
[music stops]
There's a press
conference downstairs.
Come on, let's go.
[Dicky in British accent]
Spot of tea, mate!
Neary: ten stone... six pound.
[light applause]
- Ward: ten stone... six pound.
- [light applause]
[man] Hey, Micky, Micky Ward!
We have a question over here.
[all chattering]
- How you been training?
- [Neary] I train, I train hard.
[man] Shea's 22 and 0.
He's never been knocked down.
- That's gonna change tomorrow.
- In fact, we expected
- a much better fighter.
- [low murmurs, chuckles]
I'm just grateful to be here
and have the opportunity.
Thank you guys for the shot.
Shea, who do you
respect as a fighter?
And who would you
like to fight next?
I plan on moving right
through Micky Ward tomorrow.
Moving on to other
great fighters, like Gatti.
Yeah, I believe Gatti and I
would make a great match.
- Are you scared, Mr. Ward?
- [reporters clamoring]
[cameras clicking]
[announcer] And now, ladies and
gentlemen, 12 rounds of boxing
for the WBU Welterweight
Championship of the World!
- [crowd cheering]
- [# Whitesnake: Here I Go Again]
I can't see!
[singing along]
# Here I go again on my own #
# Goin' down the only road
I've ever known #
# Like a drifter
I was born to walk alone #
- Hey, fellas, let's go.
- #I made up my mind#
[booing, jeering]
# I ain't wasting
no more time #
-[booing]
- # Here I go again on my own #
# Going down the only road
I've ever known #
# Like a drifter I was born
to walk alone #
- Don't listen to 'em, Mick.
- Wow.
# I made up my mind #
# I ain't wasting
no more time... ##
[announcer 1] And there is Micky
Ward of Lowell, Massachusetts,
entering the ring. It's his first
fight outside the United States.
Micky Ward:
30 wins, seven losses.
He's gotten better
recently, 20 KOs.
And now Ward awaits his
opponent, Shea Neary.
Neary regards himself
as the European Arturo Gatti.
- [indistinct] - Meaning that he
is a head-on, high-contact fighter
- [bell dinging]
- who throws 70 punches per round.
- [wild applause]
- Neary's from Liverpool and should have
- a huge following here tonight.
- [up-tempo music plays]
[indistinct]
[announcer 2] Accompanied by
Paint the Town Red by The Mahones.
[announcer 1] Neary is the current
Welterweight Champion of the World.
[announcer 2] He is a very tough
young man. Beyond dedicated.
Lives a Spartan existence.
And according to his promoters,
does nothing but eat,
drink, think, fantasize...
...dream of fighting.
[announcer 1] Shea Neary has had 22
professional fights and won them all.
Seventeen KOs.
Come out when you hear the bell.
Don't piss about. Shake hands.
Both of ya... shake hands!
[announcer 2] As close as we just
saw them in the middle of the ring,
- forehead to forehead,
- Did you see that?
that's how close
we expect them to be
for as long
as this fight goes on.
[announcer 3]
Ward is a long ways from home.
Don't coast
in a foreign country.
[announcer 1] Well,
the big challenge for Ward
is to get off to a faster start
than is customary for him.
Micky Ward, a notoriously
slow starter in big fights,
Shea Neary,
an ultra-fast starter.
- [bell dings] - And that's the
question that hovers over round one.
- [audience cheering]
- Will Ward be ready for the fight?
Already, Shea Neary starts
taking it to him on the ropes!
And Neary going to the body,
which is Ward's specialty.
- [announcer 2] Whoa! - [announcer 1] Neary
bangs Ward to the body.
- And a big uppercut by Neary.
- [announcer 3] Neary leads off with a good left jab.
- Come on, Micky!
- Keeps Ward off balance,
jabbing here and there.
[announcer 1] There's
a good left hook by Neary
as he stepped in on Ward.
Ward not able to deal
with him very well
when Neary stands
at range like this.
- Come on!
- That's it! Get him!
[announcer 1] And a left hook
lands up top from Micky Ward.
Neary digging his
own right hand to the body.
They trade shots at close range.
Ward, he's trying
to match Neary blow for blow
and now Neary starts to come on
and take the last
30 seconds of the round...
- How about that?
- [bell dinging]
Break!
[announcer 2] Tremendous barrage in
the first minute. Just look at this.
[announcer 3]
Unbelievable.
[announcer 1]
What a great round one!
[announcer 2] Ward is gonna
have to pick up the tempo
and beat him with
volumes of punching.
-[chatter]
- [announcer 3] No doubt, Neary is a better boxer.
[indistinct]
[announcer 2]
Four hard right hands...
...Neary has belted
in the last minute.
[announcer 1] Quicker than Ward,
more assertive than Ward,
surer of what he wants to do.
- They're standing and trading shots
at the center of the ring. - [bell dinging]
[announcer 3] Ward's gonna have to step it
up a little bit more than he is right now.
[announcer 1] Micky Ward's corner taking
a real deep look at what's going on now.
And his family at ringside well
aware he's stepping up in class.
[announcer 3] Ward has fallen to the
pedal. He's gotta be more aggressive.
He can't just try to wait
until everything is perfect.
[announcer 1] His dominance over Micky
Ward is increasing as the fight goes on
because his technical plan was the
right one and he's executing it.
[announcer 2] Punches
like these make it seem...
...that it's now Neary's fight.
[announcer 1] Ward hasn't been in this kind
of war with this strong of fighter as Neary.
[announcer 2] They are trying to
hurt each other with every punch.
They've tested each other's will, now
they're testing each other's skill.
[announcer 1] And Ward wobbled
there by a right cross from Neary!
Ward hurting now.
His legs are gone.
Neary goes to the body
as he tries to finish Micky.
[announcer 2]
Vicious body shots from Neary.
[announcer 1] And Ward still doesn't
even try to move off the ropes!
[announcer 2]
I don't know if he can, Jim.
He's waiting for Neary
to punch himself out.
- [announcer 1] Down goes Micky Ward! He may be out.
- [Dicky] That ain't fuckin' it!
- One... two...
- Come on! That's it!
- [Alice] That's my boy!
- [Dicky] Forward! Forward! Come on!
[bell dinging]
- [crowd clamoring]
- [announcer 1] Ward is out on his feet.
[man shouting] Loser!
Go back to America!
[announcer 1] This could
be it for Micky Ward.
Dicky, give him
the fuckin' stool.
Charlene, will you get
the fuck outta here.
- He needs to fuckin' sit down!
- Shh...
[announcer 3] His brother's got
Ward jumping to wake up his legs.
- [indistinct]
- I think this could be Ward's last chance
to turn this fight around.
[announcer 1] It's Micky Ward
against the aggressiveness
and clean punching
of Shea Neary.
[announcer 3] If you don't
have your defense up,
you can really get hurt.
He's making it very
difficult for Micky Ward.
I don't think he's gonna
get into it at this rate.
[announcer 1]
This is a survival mode...
Are you like me? Huh? Was just
good enough to fight Sugar Ray?
Never had to win, did I?
You gotta do more in there.
You gotta win a title.
For you, for me, for Lowell.
This is your time,
all right? You take it.
I had my time and I blew it.
You don't have to.
All right?
You fuckin' get out there,
and use all the shit
that you've been through,
all the shit we've gone through
over the fuckin' years
and you put it in that ring right now.
This is yours. This is fuckin' yours.
OK. Fuckin' head,
body, head, body.
Say it back to me.
Fuckin' say it back to me.
- Head, body, head, body.
Get in your mind this is
fucking yours. Fuckin' do it.
Stay off the fuckin' ropes.
[crowd clamoring]
[announcer 3] If I'm in
Micky Ward's corner tonight,
I thinking if he doesn't pick
things up this round and get going,
he'll just get
totally wiped out.
Off the ropes!
Get off the ropes, Mick!
[announcer 1] Once again, Ward against
the ropes as Neary is free to attack.
What are you doing?
Come on, Mick!
[announcer 3] Sometimes if you wanna win,
you gotta be something that you're not.
[Dicky] Come on!
Off the fuckin' ropes,
Mick, that ain't it!
[announcer 1]
Neary continues to pound away.
[shouting]
[Dicky] Don't take no abuse!
This is your time Micky!
- It's up to you!
- [announcer 1] Two big misses by Neary!
That's it! That's it!
Ward seemingly
getting his legs back.
He backs Neary off.
- Ward trades his way back.
- That's it!
Ward nods as if to say,
"Come on!"
"Come on, let's fight!"
Just imagine if
you bought a ticket.
Closer and closer
to Neary's ribcage.
This is becoming
Micky Ward's fight.
And a left hook to the body
and an uppercut lands
- and now he backs Neary off.
- Head, body, head fuckin' body!
Ward hurt Neary
with a body shot.
Ward hurts him again
with that left to the body.
Oh, and that one plants
Neary on his butt.
First time in
23 professional fights
- that Shea Neary has been down.
- This is it! This is it!
This is it, Micky!
Keep going! Don't look at me
for it! Take it to him!
- [Dicky] Come on, Micky, get in there!
- Ward lands a huge left hook!
As Micky Ward pounds away!
Goes to the body with the left
hook! Lands the uppercut again!
- [audience screaming]
- Neary down for the second time.
- Mickey Vann's gonna stop it right there.
- [bell dinging]
"Irish" Micky Ward with
a big eighth-round TKO!
[announcer 2]
He's done it again.
- [screaming, chatter]
- He's done it again.
[announcer 1] The grinding, gutty Micky
Ward pulls out another big victory!
You're the champion of the world, Mick!
You're the fuckin' champ of the world!
You fuckin' did it!
[indistinct]
Oh, you're the best!
- Oh, I love you!
- My boy's the champion of the world!
I love you!
[indistinct]
[audience cheering]
This town always said,
you're a fuckin' boxer, right?
He thought he was a piece of shit. He
put Lowell back on the map, you know?
- We.
- I tell ya...
- No, but hold on.
Who used to be
the pride of Lowell? Huh?
Right here.
Who's the pride of Lowell now?
Right there. That's how
it's meant to be, you know?
Handin' it down to him.
[voice breaking]
Nothin' better than that.
He did it. I gotta go.
[laughs] I gotta go.
[# Ben Harper: Glory & Consequence]
[laughing]
Oh, look at cabbage head.
Boo Boo! Quacka!
[quacking sound]
- What's up buddy?
- Boo, where's your teeth?
Oh, I'm under arrest!
Let's go, move it out!
- It's been real, ain't it?
- It's been real, it's been unreal.
It's been a great
experience. Um...
Just glad it's done, finally,
and thanks to everyone so much,
from the bottom of my heart.
Thanks so much,
all you Hollywood people.
Now you know what I mean when
I say I can't get a word in.
- I'm telling ya. He'll never get a word in.
- [laughing]
- All right, thank you.
- Thank you.
- [clapping]
- Peace, everybody.
# And every story has an end #
# Every battle has its glory #
# And its consequence #
# I'm more afraid of loving #
# Than I am of being scorned #
# Being scorned #
# I'm not as scared
of dying #
# As I am of growing old ##