ROME, SUMMER OF 1966
Can you help me? I have
to take the TV downstairs.
I'm studying.
It'll take a minute... Please.
No, I'm having an
exam in a few days.
Ask Nicola, he's in the
other room with Carlo.
Okay, I'll ask him.
"Natalino Sapegno,
History of..." Who's that?
He's my Italian teacher.
- Is he famous?
- You bet he is.
- And is he going to test you?
- No, his assistants will.
Assistants?
Do they know who you are?
Like they care, dad...
The "Messaggero" published
a composition of yours!
This Mr. Sapegno has
to test you personally.
When he sees
how smart you are,
maybe he'll help you win some
scholarship, so you can go abroad.
I can come with you
I'll speak to him.
What? You want
to speak to Mr. Sapegno?
Of course,
I'm not ashamed!
But I am.
Well, I was just trying to help.
When are you leaving to Norway?
After the exams.
I know a few people there.
I can give you their addresses, maybe
their daughters are your same age.
Ask them. They're
the experts there.
- Dad?
- The door.. Yes I know.
Okay boys, I have
a mission for you two.
That's great, we needed a break.
I'll leave the door open
as we'll be right back.
- Nicola, have you got the keys?
- Yes.
Then I better close it.
One can never know...
Mind the steps!
- Let me open the door.
- Where shall we put it?
Here on the luggage rack.
It would be tossed about otherwise.
- Here?
- Yes. Be careful.
- Careful!
- Okay.
- Go!
- Here!
- Come on!
- Here, wait...
- It needs tying up, right?
- Yes I'll take care of it.
- Will you?
- Yes.
- Bye.
Carlo, I wanted to
ask you for something,
because if I ask Nicola
he won't reply to me.
- Do you know Matteo well?
- Of course.
Tell me then,
what's wrong with him?
- What do you mean?
- I mean he's always angry.
- Come on, let's go study!
- We were talking!
You're always talking...
Oh, wait a minute, I've
got something for you.
I've had it in
the car for a week.
- Where did you get it?
- I traded for it.
What should I do with it?
You're a student in Medicine,
maybe you'll need it.
How are you, mate?
Quite well.
But in case of a turning point
in the situation, so to speak,
can I use your holiday home?
- The holiday home is a great idea!
- Don't even think about it!
What? That house is perfect!
Perfect? Last time you
used it you made such a mess
that my mother's still crying!
- Not again please!
- Yes again please. Enough!
By the way, I spoke
with my father.
- And?
- And he'll lend us the car!
- Great!
- This is good news!
Did you tell him we're
going to Cape North?
I told him it's an educational
journey around Europe.
So we'll leave
after the exams?
Yes, only we can't push
the engine over 4,000 revolutions.
So?
Are you coming to
Carlo's holiday home?
You and I?
- Yes.
- Alone?
Of course.
It's beautiful, the sand is golden,
it's full of "Tamarix aphilla",
and flying dolphins...
It's beautiful, and I love you.
- You're always kidding Nicola.
- No, I'm serious!
- I love you, I swear.
- Come on, let's dance.
Did you ask your
dad about that job?
You must be at the
clinic on Monday morning.
Do you have the address?
It's called "speech therapy"
You only have to take
our patient for a walk,
and chat with her to
help her feel "normal".
You don't have to
make friends with her,
it's just a therapy.
Giorgia has been
well for a while now,
so we need you only
twice a week. Follow me.
There she is.
You'll see it's easier
than walking a dog.
What's your name?
What's your name? What's your name?
Giorgia, don't speak to
people you don't know.
- What's your name?
- Matteo.
Mad Matteo,
madly mad Matteo...
- Watch out!
- Don't touch me!
I won't touch you,
but watch out.
Look left then right.
Go.
Do you like it here?
I come here often.
It soothes my nerves.
And there are no cars...
There's a beautiful place here.
Would you like to see it?
Would you?
When I've had enough of
studying at home I come here.
I like it here.
At this hour it's
almost desert too.
Shall we read something?
Yes. Trains.
Trains? Trains what?
What time they
leave or arrive...
Oh, the timetable.
There's no timetable here, sorry.
But there's a book I'd like to
read to you, a book of poems.
Wait, where's...
...American literature?
It's not easy to cover
the percentage of life..
She deals the cards
to catch you in weakness,
not in full strength.
She gives you
70 years to play.
If you can't in 70 years,
you can no more.
Leave the room if you lose.
Leave when
your time's over.
Only cowards stay
and hang on to the cards.
Hey, look out!
Mind the cars!
Oh my God!
Hey, careful!
What are you doing?
- Don't touch me!
- I'm not touching you. Fuck you!
I won't touch you but
you want to be run over!
Idiot, cockhead, shitface!
Listen, do you
know what death is?
- Asshole!
- No, you're an asshole!
- Fuck you!
- No fuck you!
Are you crazy?
Okay let's go now.
To the clinic. You don't
like me? You can stay there.
You only have to say it.
Here you are.
Come on!
So it's normal, but
what am I supposed to do?
Nothing, You don't
have to react.
If you stay quiet
she'll calm down.
- But, Professor...
- Call me by name, please...
Alright. But maybe I
did something wrong?
No, you didn't, my dear.
It's her disease's
fault, not yours.
But that's
what we're for.
Hey, is it ready?
Did you wash it?
I never ask them
to wash my car.
They like it.
It's their pastime.
But you can't
mortgage this house!
This is your children's house...
To mortgage a
house is a normal thing.
The problem is
that you're from Milan.
You are extraordinary people,
- you're intelligent...
- What's that supposed to mean?
And so you
lack imagination.
- ability to dream.
- Sure, imagination...
Chicca?
What are you doing
still up? Come here.
- How long have they been fighting?
- Since the film ended.
And did it and well?
Yes. He was a king
and he didn't know,
then he knew it and
married the princess.
- That's bad.
- Why?
Because then they'll
fight like mom and dad.
You must promise me
that when you grow old
you'll never get married.
I want to marry you.
And Nicola too.
You can't marry
your brothers,
especially two
of them together. So...
Let's put Alice to bed
and make them stop.
- ...if you have a head on your shoulders.
- Hey people...
- Will you stop it please?
- Hey, will you stop it?
What are you doing here?
Poor thing, you're still up.
How could she sleep
with all that noise?
Tell me,
what should I do?
Leave Matteo be,
don't involve him in this.
You and Nicola must
defend me against your father.
What? Matteo,
am I a bad father?
Yes, wanna know what
the good father did?
He mortgaged his house.
You mortgaged this house?
No, the Palace of Caserta.
Of course, I own this house here!
Did you understand?
If his job ends badly
we'll go to sleep under a bridge.
Under a bridge!
Matteo, that's cool!
Oh, finally someone
who loves adventure!
Sure, we'll live like
tramps under a bridge.
But who cares of
how his job ends?
You're insane too!
He's right, not insane!
Leave it all to me.
I'm the head of the family.
What does that mean?
It means I know when
I can invest money.
You have to beat
competition, understand?
And then, I can
smell a good deal.
You smell good deals?
I thought that you could smell
a fart!
Go, go...
What a pity I can't ask
for divorce in this country.
- Divorce? Like the American ladies?
- Yes like that.
Well, see you.
You're going out again?
Yes, Nicola and the others
are waiting for me.
- Where are you going?
- Around.
- Girls?
- Who knows...
Where is she?
With a client, I think.
Shall we wait here?
Yes this is her fire.
It's a bit embarrassing.
It's not. She'll be here soon.
Is that her?
Yes.
What's happening?
Hi Cati.
Hi Matteo.
Who was that?
Who are those?
My brother
and two friends.
Hi.
So, shall we go to your place?
Come in.
Can I leave the light on?
So the hens think
it's day and they'll eat.
It's okay.
Don't you get undressed?
Are you ashamed?
Understood.
I'll turn around.
Look, maybe it's better
if we do nothing.
- But I'll pay you all the same.
- Are you sick?
No, I'm not, but...
- I don't know. Maybe...
- Come on.
Listen, are you
Matteo's brother?
Yes, why?
Because you
two are different.
- You aren't like him.
- Really? Why, what's he like?
He's weird.
Well, anyway...
Let's do it quick or you'll
make me waste too much time.
No. Don't kiss my lips.
Hi Giorgia.
Why are you staying
here in the dark?
Don't you want to go out?
Everyone's in the garden.
Can I take some
pictures of you?
The light is perfect.
Come on, look at me.
Well?
Alright, I'll photograph your hands.
Your hands are pretty,
did you know that?
What's that?
What did they do to you?
Please read and
comment on this page.
It's a poem
by Sennuccio Del Bene.
I know, but what
does it suggest to you?
- Nothing.
- Nothing? Why?
Because it's empty.
Sennuccio Del Bene
is empty too.
Then give me an example
of a religious poet
you like in particular.
Il Beccaio.
Are you kidding me?
Il Beccaio, is a modest
imitator of Cecco Angiolieri,
and can't be considered as
one of the religious rhymers.
He curses his father
and his mother.
- Is that a religious poet?
- I think so.
Well, I don't, and I know
a little more than you.
What are you doing?
I got annoyed.
Yes those marks were
left by electrical discharges.
She was electroshocked.
- Where did you take the picture?
- Isn't the electroshock forbidden?
Unfortunately no.
Who's that girl?
I'll tell you later. Go study now.
Isn't your exam tomorrow?
Yes. Wish me good luck.
The teacher is a tough one.
I wish I got full marks like you.
Full marks...
Are you coming with Carlo
and Berto tomorrow?
So we can leave
as soon as I've failed?
No, come and take me from
"the hole". I'm going to sleep there.
With whom?
Hi Antonio.
Hey, most illustrious
one, why here so late?
Sorry, I forgot a book
in the hall upstairs.
- I can't move from here.
- Don't worry, I'll go get it.
If you wake them up,
you'll entertain them.
"Esposti Giorgia,
Pietracamela".
Giorgia?
Giorgia, wake up.
Wake up, Giorgia.
Don't be afraid, it's Matteo.
Listen to me carefully.
Now you take all your
stuff and we'll leave.
I'll take you away.
You deserved 28 or 29,
but I'm giving you 30
because of what I call
"sympathy quotient"
It's not much,
but it's enough
to make you get 30.
Someone disagrees with
this quotient thing of mine,
but I think that sympathy,
from the Greek word "sympazein"
which means "share the pathos",
or other people's sufferings,
is very important for a Doctor.
To others I apply the
"antipathy quotient".
It means I lower their marks.
Antipathy is the worst
thing for a Doctor.
I think you are praiseworthy,
congratulations.
But don't get big-headed.
You have to do
two more exams with me,
I can still tear you to pieces.
Who are those? Friends of yours?
Did you take the claque with you?
No. Well... we have
to leave together, so...
- They came here to...
- Are they in my class?
I can't remember them..
Ahem, no.
Carlo studies Economics,
Berto Philosophy.
Don't tell me the
story of their lives.
I'm just happy to know
they'll cause damage
somewhere else.
Economics, Philosophy. Wow!
As I said, you're promising.
And I may be wrong,
but I want to give
you a piece of advice.
If you're you somehow
ambitious, leave.
Leave Italy.
Leave Italy as
quickly as you can.
Do you want to be a surgeon?
I still don't know.
Whatever you decide,
go to study in
London or Paris.
Go to America if you can,
but leave this country.
Italy should be destroyed.
It's a beautiful
and useless place,
destined to die.
You mean the Doomsday
is about to come?
I wish.
We would be forced
to rebuild all if it did,
while everything remains
motionless instead,
in the hands of the dinosaurs.
Listen to me, go away.
Why are you staying though?
Me?
My dear, because I'm
one of the dinosaurs.
Move aside please.
Aside, aside, we're leaving!
I had thirty!
How can you have 30 at
your first exam! You're sick!
So, Matteo's in "the hole"?
- Yes.
- Drive faster!
I can't. 4,000
revolutions, remember?
- Yes but 4,000...
- Come on, 4,000!
4,000 my foot! Weeeeee!
Faster!
Giorgia?
Giorgia!
Wake up, it's time to go.
I made you some coffee.
Sugar?
One, two?
No sugar?
...I understand if
he was referring
to your specialisation,
But I don't think that going
abroad to find a job can...
So you think we'll
all find a job in Italy?
Yes, our yearly
growth is at 7%
and unemployment is at 3%.
- What does it mean?
- It means things are going well
because unemployment increases
when growth goes below 4%.
You mean that
will be begged to work?
No, that's a bit too much,
also because
within the next few years
plenty of people will graduate.
Inflation should
increase a little.
So to speak, natural
selection will take place.
Let's say that
out of 3 graduated people,
one won't find any job.
Basically the
dumbest of the three.
Hey now, why
don't you all go to...
I think we should take
the "Statale Appenninica".
Sure, so we'll need
20 days to reach Turin.
Okay but girls don't
hitchhike on the highway.
- He fixed his mind on that!
- On what?
- But where's Matteo?
- I have no idea.
You should
go and check.
Okay, I'll get
the keys and...
Oh, there he is, finally.
Who's that?
I don't know her.
He was supposed
to come alone?
I don't know anything.
Wait here, please.
We said no girlfriends!
Let's hear what he
has to say before.
Maybe she
isn't coming with us.
That girl looks strange.
There's something about her.
Who's she? The
girl in the pictures?
But what's the problem?
Nothing, it's
a delicate matter.
And?
See you at the Brennero.
- Did you go crazy?
- Are you joking?
We were supposed to be
at the Brennero by night.
- We'll be a day behind now.
- Calm down.
- We'll never get to Hamburg.
See you at the
customs in two days.
It's because of her?
Yes, because of her.
Did she run
away from home?
Kind of.
Where are you going?
We'll take you there.
No, we'll take care of it.
Okay then, good trip!
- You too.
- Good trip.
- See you.
- Don't go too fast, okay?
- I won't.
I don't know, when I saw
how bad she felt I thought...
You did the right thing.
And that matter of
the electroshock too...
You're right, it's horrible.
But we have to take
her somewhere now.
Her mom is dead.
Her dad lives in a place
called Pietracamela.
Pietracamela?
Where is it?
I don't know, maybe
in the Appennino.
We could take her
there, then leave.
Alright. Giorgia?
Come here.
See how strange she acts?
Yes, but why?
She's nuts!
No she isn't.
She looks intelligent.
Giorgia!
Do you remember me?
How are you, Giorgia?
My Bishop forgets me,
while you still love
Don Vito, don't you?
Look at you!
You're so pretty...
- Who are those?
- Hello.
- Nicola.
- Vito.
- Matteo, nice to meet you.
- What's the matter?
- We're looking for Giorgia's father.
He moved a few years ago.
- He lives in Ravenna now.
- In Ravenna?
Yes, he moved there
three or four years ago.
Are you from the Institute?
Yes, from Villa Quieta.
And so young... Good boys.
And how come
you brought her here?
- For summer holidays.
- For summer.
She was confirmed
like all the others,
because children are
all the same for me.
Aren't they, Giorgi'?
Do you remember...
Lord, I'm not worthy of you,
but just say a word
and my soul will be saved.
- She's so pretty.
- Very good!
As a child she knew
the Angel's prayer.
But the Word of God
was nothing serious for her.
So it is for many other people.
You're right.
What's your name again?
Matteo.
- And yours?
- Nicola.
Good boy, Nico'
Maybe it was her mother's death.
She died when Giorgia was a child,
and she kind
of became obsessed.
She cleaned everything,
over an over again.
She cleaned her room,
the kitchen, the stable...
Who knows why.
What time is the next
bus to Ravenna?
It's just left!
If you only said it earlier..
There's another one at 7 a.m.
which arrives
in the afternoon.
Tomorrow morning?
We must leave immediately.
Immediately?
That cannot be.
It's impossible.
What are we
going to do now?
You could stay at my place.
I have a kind of...
not a stable, a depot.
Better than a poke in the eye,
or a kick in the face! Isn't it?
For you madam,
here's the Royal Suite.
You can lay down
on this wonderful bed.
There's also a
fantastic séparé
so you can have your privacy,
separated from the two
heroes, Ajax and Achilles.
There's also a beautiful
blanket, by kind
concession of the clergy.
So if you're cold
you can put it on.
But I'm not
getting undressed.
I'm not.
That's fine.
You know what?
I won't get undressed too.
Okay, let's get
some sleep now.
Giorgia...
Tomorrow you'll sleep in a real
bed in your father's house.
I don't have a father. I don't.
Give me that! Thief!
Give me that, bastard asshole!
You're a thief! A thief!
Let go of it! It's mine!
Giorgia!
- Come inside!
- Leave me be!
- Leave you be?
Leave me be!
- Thief! Thief!
- Look...
- I'm not a thief!
- You are!
Sorry, I didn't know
it was yours.
- You're a thief!
- I found it on the floor!
Enough!
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, I took a noteb-
- But I didn't know it was hers!
- Go away!
You have to go away!
Leave it to me.
Giorgia, let's go
inside, it's raining.
Enough!
Come on, we're
getting wet here.
Let's go back inside, please.
Maybe you better
wear something dry.
I'll give you something mine.
Do you like it?
Put it on.
Are you ashamed?
You can go
behind the curtain.
Come on.
Next time you want to
shower, just let me know,
and I'll book you a
room at the Grand Hotel.
Done?
How long does it take?
The buttons...
- May I?
- Yes.
I'll help you.
Buttons are
the hardest thing.
Shoelaces too, but buttons
are really complicated.
Imagine if Don Vito
comes in now.
He would curse us
and we'd go to hell.
You have a beautiful smile.
You're good, see?
Let's sleep now.
Let's go to beddy-byes.
Shall I turn off the light?
- No. No no.
- Alright, lights on.
Good night.
What happened?
Nothing.
Good morning
madam. Excuse me...
- Good morning.
- Do you know where Mr. Saro lives?
He lives here,
he's my husband.
Where is he now?
What's wrong?
Nothing, it's
a personal matter.
Aren't you Giorgia?
You should have
been in the Institute.
And who are those?
Fatty...
Giorgia...
What are you doing here?
What happened?
We don't think the Institute
is the right place for her.
What?
She is ill-treated there.
And when she has a crisis
they electroshock her.
- Electroshock?
- Yes.
- And what's that?
- Electric discharges.
- Aren't they painful?
- They are.
I pay a lot of money
to the Institute
so she can
recover and be well...
Why don't you keep
her with you instead?
I can't, I have other children.
Then keep her in the
family with her siblings.
They aren't her siblings,
they're Rosa's kids.
Rosa loves you,
and they do as well,
but you don't get
along with them.
In fact
I put you in that clinic
hoping for you to feel well,
and recover your health.
Giorgia,
now these people will
take you back to the clinic.
Why don't you try
to take her with you?
They'll take you back
so you'll be fine.
Giorgia doesn't need a
doctor. She needs a father.
I am a father!
I love you Giorgia,
you know that.
Then show her you do.
Take her to your house.
I cannot do that!
Life's expensive nowadays,
I already spend
a lot for the clinic...
Money's nothing to do
with her. She needs love.
- We love her! But...
- She feels awful, I know that!
Hey I'm not forced
to speak about my family
- with two strangers!
- What kind of father are you?
- And who the hell are you?
- She's your daughter!
She's my daughter so
she's none of your business!
- None of my business?
- Hey calm down!
Calm down!
Stop it now!
Damn you!
- Where are we going now?
- I don't know.
You should think twice
before hitting her father!
- She can come with us.
- With us where?
To the appointment
with Carlo and Berto.
And what about the customs?
Where's her Passport?
You should use
your head sometimes!
Are you hungry?
No.
You don't eat or drink.
Do you live on air?
- And stop that-
- Leave her alone!
She cut herself.
Come on, get a towel!
- What if she cut her vein?
- Come on...
Maybe we should
take her to the ER.
There's no need for that.
Get a towel please.
This is the
Cheyenne method.
"Drooling Dew"
- What happened?
- Nothing, we broke a glass.
- Korea scored.
- Who cares?
In fact we
couldn't care less.
Less than nothing.
On the contrary,
I'm a fan of Korea.
Ko-re-a!
- Bye.
- Wait for me here then.
- What will you tell Giovanna?
I'll tell her that we got
a problem after leaving.
But what if she asks why
Carlo and Berto aren't with us?
Trust me, okay?
I don't trust my sister.
- She could send us to jail.
- That's why I'm going alone.
- What about us?
- Think of something.
There's a bar, have
something to drink...
I'll leave my bags
here, okay?
- See you.
- Bye.
Do you want
something to drink?
Okay, you're mad at me.
You don't speak to me...
Give me a sign then.
Say "yes" or "no".
Was that "yes"?
- Hello.
- Hello, can I help you?
What would you like?
Hey!
Giorgia?
You want to
listen to something?
What's your favourite?
Elvis? Sandy Show?
What's "Achi"?
Oh, "A chi", Fausto Leali.
Let me see...
Here.
B 3.
Your friend Berto
did something serious.
She is under her
father's jurisdiction
and he decides for her. There's
nothing I can do. It's the law.
But Berto thought she
would be killed in that clinic.
Then he could have
filed a complaint.
That's what
the Magistracy's for.
He seized a person,
not a knick-knack.
Do you ever deal
with such cases?
No, I'm dealing with that.
You won't believe me, but
thousands of people work there.
- So lots of problems?
- The usual job suits,
dismissals, diseases, accidents...
I've an embarrassing wide choice.
Plants never stop here.
They're on 24/7, all year.
That's why the sea and
the sky changed colour.
The Leadership says
it's all under control,
but last week
they distributed this.
Toothpaste?
Yes, but they advised
for teeth to be brushed
before meals, not
after. Understand?
Not really.
It means that the powder
on their teeth and gums is toxic.
And it causes
cancer in the long run.
Listen, it's not Berto's
problem but yours, right?
No, it's Matteo's instead.
He always gets in trouble.
No, I promise
you it's Berto's.
Why don't you call the
Psychiatric Hospital in Gorizia?
There are wonderful
doctors there.
They may be wonderful,
but it's still an asylum.
But their patients aren't
tied up or electroshocked.
What if we take her here?
I am forced to report
you to the local Attorney.
They come here, get the girl,
and take her back
to her father. Clear?
How long till the train leaves?
Half an hour.
Listen, why don't you go
and buy three "zatterini"?
- Me?
- Yes, you.
No, I can't.
Why? You've got
legs, haven't you?
- I'll do it.
- No, she will.
Come on, three "zatterini".
- I can't do it.
- You can, it's easy.
Hi miss.
- Three "zatterini".
Do you think we should
really take her to Gorizia?
I think so.
Giovanna said it's a good hospital.
And if we don't like the doctors,
she'll spend the
holidays with us.
In Sicily.
Here you are.
Your change.
Wait, miss. Your change.
- Hello.
- Hello guys.
- Two coffees please.
- Sure.
Miss, you left your change.
Take it.
He's asking you to
take your change...
- Do you know her?
- No, I've never seen her before.
Is anything wrong?
I don't know, she left
her change here.
- I called her, but...
- I see.
Are you with someone?
No, I'm alone.
Do you carry any documents?
She isn't answering.
Let's take her with us.
Come with us.
What about her bag?
I don't know..
What's going to happen to her?
I don't know.
Maybe she'll be taken
back to the Institute.
Is it possible that
there's nothing we can do?
Look, let's catch our train tomorrow.
Let's go on with our journey.
Alright.
Let's have some rest now.
Matteo, what are you doing?
My journey's over.
- Over? What do you mean?
- I'm going to Rome.
To Rome? Why?
What's wrong with you?
Have you gone crazy?
Remember the exam
I was supposed to take?
Well?
I failed it.
Did you?
Why didn't you tell me?
And what's this got to do with
the fact you're going back to Rome?
- Nothing.
- Then get off!
Come on, the
train's leaving! Get off!
And you left me
on that bench like an idiot!
Get off!
Bye.
What does "bye" mean?
Nicola...
Where's the recruitment?
What should I do
if I want to start military service?
What should you do?
You should look
for professional help.
Dear Matteo,
I'm sending this
letter to mom and dad
so that they
can give it to you.
Where are you?
Did you hear
from Carlo and Berto?
I never met them,
I travelled alone.
By the way here I am.
Norway is a wonderful place.
People are particularly striking.
Martin, for example, is American,
and he's a deserter.
He left America because he
didn't want to go to Vietnam,
Holy...
The world is holy.
The soul is holy.
The tongue, the cock,
and hand
and asshole are holy.
Who wrote that?
- A genius.
- What's their name?
Allen Ginsberg.
Savages...
I left my companions
and I'm heading north.
You won't believe me,
but I am in front of
a small wooden church
a few steps from
a stone which says that
the Polar Arctic Circle
Line passes through here.
Right now
my fellow students
are having lesson
with the old dinosaur,
but I don't feel guilty,
I don't feel like
I'm wasting my time.
Dear beast,
I've something
important to tell you.
I'll never shave
or a have a haircut again.
I'm sending you a picture
to show you how I look.
Pretty, aren't I?
What the hell are you doing?
...I don't like games, clear?
- Don't play with me!
- Calm down!
Don't break my balls!
- He's a weirdo.
- He's crazy!
- How are you?
- He hurt me.
My money's gone,
so I'll look for a job
in some local sawmill.
They pay workers well
and need workers all the time.
Girls are beautiful
here, serene...
without turning serious
as Italian girls do
when one pays
them a compliment.
Faster! Keep your butts down!
You wanna get killed?
You're a bunch of queers!
Faster, or you'll
do it again and again!
Come on, animals!
I'm gonna break your ass!
Nicola Carati.
- Long beard.
- But I...
- Shut up! Step forward!
- Remember
that you don't
represent only yourself.
You represent
the Army! Is it clear?
And another thing,
I want this to be clear:
No one plays games in here!
No bad jokes on
the recruits! Clear?
- Loosened tie.
- Step forward!
- Dirty shoes!
And you call that a rucksack?
- Sorry.
- Back to your place!
Step forward!
Please Lieutenant,
don't do this to me.
I have to call mom,
she's no one to help her.
Dad is sick, I was
the only one who worked.
- I need to know if...
- Attention!
- What are you doing?
- I don't want to go out!
Fine.
You won't go out tomorrow
and the day after tomorrow too!
The confined ones stay here.
All the others out!
Sometimes I think of Giorgia.
...of the fact we
couldn't protect her.
Maybe when I'm back
I'll become a Psychiatrist.
We must do something
for people like her.
They mustn't
be electroshocked.
You're great, Matteo.
You made fun of the Lieutenant.
But you're strange. You had
him confine you for three days.
And you could have
found a better excuse.
That's the truth.
I am unemployed,
I want to make a military career.
Didn't you say you're
the only one with a job?
That's the only lie I told.
- You should make a career here too.
- Are you nuts?
You can become a General.
Hurry up!
Faster!
Come on!
Nicola!
Attention!
Five minutes break
then we'll start. Stand at ease!
Dismiss!
Nicola!
Matteo!
- What's this military costume?
- I'm a military!
- What about University?
I left it. Luigi?
Luigi, come here.
He's my brother Nicola,
he sent me the postcards.
- Hi.
- I'm Nicola.
- Is that my brother for real?
- You don't look like each other.
Excuse me...
Excuse me.
Thanks.
- Professor, are there precious books?
- I'm still checking.
- I'll send someone to help you.
- Great, thank you.
Easy. Don't shake the water.
Watch out. Be careful.
Those are precious books.
- No need to hurry.
- It's slippery here.
- Carati, where are you?
- At your orders! I'm here.
- Is everything under control here?
- Yes, no problem sir.
- Then Pezzuco's following me.
- Alright.
- What was that?
- It's called "stecca". My God!
You never did military
service, did you?
I don't even want to!
Do you want
to be a tramp?
I saved lots of money
- working as a woodcutter.
- Good.
- I'm not going back to Rome.
- And what about University?
I'll enroll somewhere else.
After what
I saw around Europe
I can't keep on living
with mom and dad.
- When will you be done with the Army?
- Never.
- What do you mean?
- I'm making a career.
- Where?
- I want to be a Policeman.
- Are you kidding me?
- No.
- You'll be a policeman?
- I will.
You went nuts!
Come on, you believed that?
- You were kidding?
- Come on, Nicola...
Look!
Who knows what it used to be...
It's a miniated manuscript in Latin.
Let me get a torch.
"In 1126 A. D., the light..."
- No, "The first light."
- "The first light of day came..."
- I can't remember that verb.
- "Came and alighted"
"Came and alighted on
the head of the Blessed One."
What are you doing?
Why aren't you lined up?
Hurry up!
Did you hear him?
Such a jerk could be
your boss forever...
Faster! Faster!
He's right by the way.
We're wasting time.
Pass me the books.
- I can't believe it!
- Carlo! Berto!
- How long have you been here?
- Three days.
You're a tramp!
- You look like shit!
- I'm the "good savage"
- More like a woodcutter.
- Exactly!
You made us wait
in Bolzano for two days!
- Three days!
- You weren't there when I arrived.
- Liar!
- I called your mom.
- She said you were in Hamburg.
- Let's go get some food!
- I took two exams all alone.
- I failed three exams all alone!
- Let me see. "I think..."?
- "Therefore I am!"
- See, you're good!
- Why didn't you write at least?
It was a wild
place. No stamps.
Yeah sure...
What about
girls? No girls?
- Don't place it there.
- I was told to...
- No, their place is over there. follow me.
- Make up your minds...
...mind the step there,
or the bottles
will br- very good.
Our soldiers came
here to help us.
Give them some bread.
- And wine too.
- How cute.
Enough.
What are they doing?
Look at their coats...
Those are Lorenzo
the Magnificent's nieces.
- ...Covered with mud...
- He's amazing too.
Looks like he came
from a book by Chekov...
Remember Firs in
"The Cherry Orchard"?
- Who's Firs?
- The old hunchback...
Never mind.
No, I remember.
...give him some bread too.
...good. To these
young men now.
- Good morning misses.
- Are you mocking them?
- Just joking...
- Then it's fine.
Give them some wine
and bread too. Here.
Who are those pretty girls?
Marquis Riccobaldi's kids.
We were lucky.
Our house is on the hills,
so it wasn't damaged.
And so the Marquis
sent his daughters
...to say thank you all.
- How nice of him!
- Him? I'm the one who's carrying the cart!
Just kidding.
I've played the piano since I was 10.
- Now I'm a Maths' student in Turin.
- What's Maths got to do with the piano?
My mother chose
the piano, I chose Maths.
- But why Maths?
- Because I wanted to solve
the famous problem
of the jealous husbands.
What's that?
- You don't know it?
- No.
- There are three married couples.
- Married?
- Yes.
- How boring...
They have to cross a river.
They only have a boat
which can carry two people.
The jealous husbands don't want
their wives to remain
with the other men.
Of course.
Where's the riddle?
How do they cross the river?
It's easy. So...
Two wives go first.
One gets back
and takes her husband...
...to the other side.
Mind your own business.
She leaves him
there, gets back and...
- No.
- She leaves him there. No.
Two husbands go first...
It's the same, isn't it?
- I give up.
- It's easy you said?
- No, I'll solve it.
- Maybe another time.
- Okay.
- Once you've graduated,
...will you be a teacher or a pianist?
Not a teacher.
Not even a pianist, I think.
You know your business!
You must do both things.
Sure...
- Let's enrol in Turin.
- Why?
- Turin?
- He's crazy!
- Yes, he is.
- Berto, Let's go to Turin!
I won't graduate. Dad wants
me to work in his factory.
- Don't laugh.
- What about you, Carlo?
- Torino?
- Yes, Agnelli, the FIAT...
The chocolate... I don't know.
- Are you cold?
- Yes.
- What are you doing?
- I'm giving you this.
- Don't...
- Come on!
Berto, I think we
should go to sleep.
I'm not sleepy.
- Good night.
- Let's go.
- Bye.
- Good night.
- Did you send them away?
- I didn't.
Good night. Good night.
Can I be your guest in Turin?
You're crazy,
I don't even know you!
TURIN, FEBRUARY 1968
Nicola? Pull it a little...
Move it to the right.
No... Look at him!
No! Nicola?
I love you.
I love you like crazy.
Nicola, watch out!
Let go of them!
"Away, away the police!"
See you.
You brought the bike
in the house?
Are you afraid that
the "terroni" steal it?
- Shut up and make some food.
- Sure, honey!
- With your holy hands.
- So holy!
Where's Carlo?
- What?
- Here's "The voice of the Master".
One has to be informed
- as regards what they want too.
- You don't need papers for that.
- They want to fuck us.
- That's an elegant gesture.
From Oxford.
By the way don't call me
a "terrone" anymore okay?
- I am from Turin.
- Are you?
- Ouch!
- Look at him!
He can't even laugh.
It's easy for the police
to face you sissies...
Shut up.
They should come to the
factory. We'd kick their asses!
- Fast!
- Yeah, kick them...
- You can't because of the Labour Unions.
- Don't involve the Unions.
Who writes this bullshit? Your friends?
Did you read that?
We were given this yesterday.
Alright, but...
"We must destroy
the school, not change it."
- You got it wrong.
- Listen.
I don't want to destroy schools.
I want a right to study...
...for me who couldn't
study, and for my children.
You have no children!
- Learn to speak!
- But Vitale...
- It's true, you have no kids.
- I'm still young!
Don't you have to go to the
students' collective's meeting?
- Who makes me some coffee?
- I will. And you have a meeting
- at the factory, right?
- I'm going soon.
As long as you all leave.
- Are you in a haste?
- I have to study Anatomy.
- What?
- Anatomy.
(singing) Anatomy...
"Love me forever!"
Good morning Mr. Piero.
Hey, "Naples", you're so witty!
- Hi Giulia.
- Hi.
She's the Anatomy exam.
(singing) Anatomy...
- Ouch! My lip...
- Sorry, I forgot.
- You're frozen.
- No, I ran. I'm hot.
- It's so cold in here.
- The trick is to keep moving.
- You need to keep moving.
- Keep moving?
TURIN, SPRING OF 1974
There.
Please open up! I'm pregnant!
Open up please!
Open the door!
It's like heaven in here.
- Nice, isn't it?
- Would you live here?
Yes. Wouldn't you?
- You carry bricks in your pocket?
- You saw how hard they hit people...
What do you do then?
You throw bricks at them?
I don't, but if they
assault me I'll defend myself.
Weird... Someone opened
the door, but no one's showing.
You found a great
excuse... "Help!"
"Open up, I'm pregnant!"
Slow down! Slow down!
Stop at the crossing.
Hey!
First and Second turn right!
Third and Fourth turn left!
Slow down.
Slow down, I don't like it.
There's something wrong here.
Back!
Hurry up!
Away! Quick!
Go away!
Anyone missing?
Luigi!
Bastards!
Luigi! Luigi!
Luigi!
Gigi!
How are you?
How strange to meet again here.
Weren't you in Treviso?
I was, but they needed
help for the demonstration.
Nice idea!
Was it for self-defence?
If they hadn't stopped me
I would have killed him.
- Will you be tried now?
- I don't know.
- But I'll be transferred.
- Where to?
Bologna. I'm leaving tomorrow.
The boy you hurt will make it.
I don't give a damn.
Do you want to keep
behaving like that?
Let's start over.
Hi Matteo. How are you?
Wanna come to my place?
I'll show you the house.
What do you need
to get out of here?
Gotta ask for 70 permissions
to the Minister of the Interior?
Gotta lick the floor where
the Head of Police walked?
Gotta pray St. Michael,
patron Saint of the Police?
- I only need to sign some papers.
- Do it then!
This is the yard.
- Hello, "tota" Bianco.
- Hello.
"Tota" means "miss" in dialect.
I'll buy a cake.
- We gotta celebrate!
- What?
I'll tell you later.
- Ay, my good sire?
- Light of my life!
- You always forget the keys.
- Sorry love. He's Matteo.
- Hi.
Come in.
Thanks.
Gigi is paralysed.
You met him during
the flood in Firenze. Remember?
Of course. We look like
the same in our uniforms.
Is he a friend of yours?
- We're all friends.
- That's bad!
Really Why?
Because you're
on the wrong side.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
And which one's
the right side?
- The side of the poor?
- Exactly.
Luigi knows what to be
poor means. He is poor!
- Those who hit him aren't. Are you?
- That's nonsense!
- I don't hit innocents!
- But he's on the wheelchair, not you!
- I can't stay here anymore.
- Giulia, please.
Nice woman...
I see you made friends.
We're celebrating our
child's birth in September.
A child? Did you
choose its name?
Sara!
- What if it's a boy?
- Giulia says it's a girl. I trust her.
It's a nice name, from the Bible.
- Is she playing?
- Yes.
She doesn't seem
mean when she's playing.
She isn't mean.
- She thinks she's always right.
- Exactly like you...
Sleep.
- Nicola!
- Does the baby have to sleep with us?
- That's not good.
- Hush...
Sara, please go to
the other room, will you?
Cause daddy has a little
thing to do with mommy.
Go!
He could have come
to pick us at least!
Try to be kind, and don't say
that to have kids when
you have no job is crazy.
- Also because Nicola has one.
- Only for six more months.
- She works too.
- Yes, in a rubbish shop.
How can they buy clothes
and miniskirts for Sara?
Isn't it early for miniskirts?
And don't mention the fact
they aren't married.
No one gets
married anymore!
Why, you wouldn't
marry me today?
- You don't think it's good enough?
- What are you saying!
Ladder A
Hi!
- How are you?
- Fine. The journey?
- It was good.
- Open up please?
- What's that?
- An English baby-carriage.
- Thanks! It's beautiful!
- Here's the rest.
Put it there.
Hi.
This house is big.
- We were lucky to find it.
- Was it so coloured?
- No, I painted it.
- Congratulations!
She's sleeping.
Hi... she's so cute!
I'm grandma,
and he's grandpa.
Such a cute face...
She's got my
eyes and my chin.
- You wish!
- Let her grow and we'll see.
- She's bigger than the last time.
- She is.
If someone told me
I'd become grandpa...
Sara are you happy to have
such a young grandad?
- She's looking at me!
- You conquered her.
- Where's Nicola?
- At the Court.
What happened?
There's a trial against
a sick psychiatrist.
- Nicola's there to help.
- He must testify?
No, the patients will.
They were accepted as witnesses.
Let's hope that the Judge trusts them.
It would be the first time in Italy.
No, in the World!
Marino, when they say
"Swear to tell the truth"...
You all listen, because
you all will be asked for that.
You have to reply: "I do".
Marino, repeat please.
I do.
Good. otherwise
they won't listen to you.
When did you first
enter the mental hospital?
I was four...
No you were 8. You
must say that, okay?
Yes, I was 8, I liked
to dress like a girl.
- And they weren't supposed to shut you in.
- When I see the "Electrician",
- I'll break his bones!
- Calm down!
- You won't do that because you're good.
- Nicola!
You'll calm down.
Promise me, Aldo.
- Look me in the eye.
- Nicola?
- Will you stay calm?
- Nicola! Nicola!
- Yes, Mario?
- It looks like my cousin Ignazio.
That's true!
- Where did you find those?
- Behind the statue.
Don't pick up anything,
please. You all don't.
Who brought them in?
- Swear to tell the truth.
- They made us enter together.
They had us lay down
on the lined up beds.
- No!
- You must say "I do" first.
I do. Eight years old. 10 times
in the hospital. 10 times in the hospital.
The witness is playing
a part someone taught him!
Of course he needs
to calm down a little.
Mr. President...
- Mr. Levi, please say "I do".
- I do.
Please go ahead.
When the Electric Doctor
came into the room...
I closed my eyes, but I could
hear those besides me screaming.
Four nurses blocked
my hands and feet.
I felt a hand putting some
rubber stuff inside my mouth.
Then the first shock came.
Once I escaped from the hospital,
but they found me again.
They hit me hard then
tied me up to the bed again.
And then the Electrician
with his machine came in.
While
he shocked me, he shouted
"Tell me who helped you escape!"
I didn't want to tell him.
So I pressed
my jaws together...
so hard that I broke
all my upper teeth.
Giovanbattista,
are you listening?
Here's the record
of your last deposition.
Please repeat
what you know here.
Look at him.
Is that the man you referred to?
Can you speak?
You said...
"The doctor gave me
electromassages because I drank."
Did you say that?
"I had 5 in 5 days"
Is that true?
- Five of them is normal for alcoholics.
- Shut up! Shut up!
- You won't kill people anymore!
- Calm down.
If something like that happens
again I'll clear the courtroom.
I apologise for Aldo
and for all the others.
They're upset, it's not easy
for them to speak in tranquillity.
Giovanbattista can't speak at all.
I know silence is no evidence,
but it's all he has to give.
- I hope he gets eight life sentences.
- I'd be happy if he got a day.
It's a matter of principle.
Why did dad come to Turin?
He has a project and
is looking for a sponsor.
He says we should pass from
typing machines to don't know what,
processors, computers... I don't know.
I have to tell you something.
He doesn't know I found
them. He won't tell me about it.
But he seems worried.
I never searched
his drawers before.
You're a doctor.
Can you do something?
No mom. But the course of illness
can be slackened by some medicine.
It could take years before...
I know, I read
everything I could find.
I read the same
thing you said,
that nothing can be done.
What are you doing?
I'm writing some
notes for the trial.
You're a disaster,
you type with two fingers!
- Let me type.
- No, there's no need to.
Please!
I want to help.
"The lawyer said
that the treatments
weren't a punishment
and also stated
that homosexuality
is a disease
which needs curing."
Why, isn't it a disease?
No dad, it isn't.
- Are you sure?
- I am.
Okay then I believe you.
What a piece of crap!
Change the carriage at least!
It's good for me.
Cut it out.
But it's out of fashion,
a general change is needed.
I have an idea, I'm
looking for a sponsor.
As a matter of fact,
if you don't mind,
I'd like to stay in Turin for
a while, to look for this sponsor.
There are many
experts in mechanics here.
Of course dad, it's good
for you to get busy.
I thought you'd say
I'm crazy as you mom does...
No you aren't
crazy, you look ahead,
you already live in the future.
You aren't fit for this world.
And what about mom?
Is she staying too?
No, she's leaving.
It's already strange that she
left Francesca alone for 4 days.
Look,
one of these days I'd like
to go and see Giovanna in Milan.
- I'll take a train.
- No, I'll take you there.
- Don't bother, I can-
- It's fine, so I can also see Carlo.
- Do you remember Carlo?
- Of course I do.
Isn't he teaching in England?
Yes, he's only passing by.
So I can say hi to him.
I could tell him
about my project.
In England there are
Business Banks.
It's not like in Italy.
Maybe he knows someone.
Okay, dictate.
What, are you playing?
You can't play
with two six of flowers.
Take them back.
Sorry.
But I scored 40
points all the same.
You didn't. Count them.
- Come on.
- 3 times 6 makes 18, 20, 22...
- See, you didn't reach 40.
- I didn't. Sorry.
Adriana, listen.
Yes?
As regards that thing that
nowadays no one gets married,
I think that nowadays
I would marry you.
My little thing.
Did you find a house?
No.
There's a dormitory here,
but no one wants to sleep in it.
It's fine with me.
I don't like houses.
Why did you come here from
the Scientific Section in Bologna?
I didn't choose to.
They said you
need people here.
- But you could say "no".
- I never say "no" to orders.
What are you doing?
Drop it, won't you?
What have you got in there?
Books.
Books?
Yes, books.
You're a strange type.
I read your characteristic signs
and what did I find there?
Nothing
I found.
Apart from some mess.
Hot blooded, aren't you?
You're a fighter, right?
Why did you join the Police?
What were you looking for?
Rules.
And what do you make of them?
I follow them.
Do you?
Yes.
I do what I'm told to.
Then I mind
my own business.
Then you fit this place.
Sicily is the home of those
who mind their own business.
- What?
- He was shot in the head.
And there's a hole in his brain.
- You live nearby.
- Commissary, we're done.
Wait a minute, please.
- So you found the body?
- Yes.
- Early morning?
What were you
doing here so early?
I was pasturing the donkey.
- Oh, the donkey.
- Yes.
But the donkey found
the body, or you did?
- I did.
- Oh, you did.
- And you touched it?
- No.
Good boy, you didn't have to.
But you looked at him.
Who's that? Does he live here?
- Yes.
- So you knew him?
Did you know him or not?
- I didn't.
- You didn't?
If he lived here,
you had to know him.
Tell me the truth, come on.
Did you recognise him?
Did you know him?
- I did.
- Good boy. You knew him then.
And tell me, was he a good man?
He was. Those who knew
him knew he was good.
A good man... But why
do you say he was good,
when others say he wasn't?
How do I know?
I know nothing of nothing.
Right. After a certain point
you don't know anything anymore.
May the rats eat that bastard!
- Bastard...
- May he rest in peace.
- Bastard.
- May he rest in peace, yes.
Okay, I got it.
Did you see?
Please everyone show
the due respect to the Court.
Whatever the verdict is,
I don't want to hear
any noise or comment.
The Court,
according to Articles 483 and 488
of the code of criminal procedure,
finds the defendant guilty
of the crime he's accused of,
and sentences him
to 5 years' imprisonment,
and the payment of legal costs.
Order! Order!
I must say I like these colours
after getting used to them.
And these drawings are really nice.
Congratulations.
Listen...
- Can I ask you for something?
- Sure.
There's a piano in the other room,
why don't you ever play it?
I never play it because
I'm not good enough.
One can't be only a little good,
so I decided to stop playing.
I didn't ask you why you
don't play in front of an audience.
I meant why
don't you play it here?
At home, for yourself.
For myself?
What's wrong?
I'm done.
Why?
Because I made lots of mistakes.
I didn't notice them.
You didn't, but I did.
But you're playing for me
so they don't count.
Ahead with this Ravel, come on.
I like Ravel.
Do you ever ask her to play?
No.
Why?
Because I know
she doesn't want to.
That's not true, she
played the other day.
She did it for you.
It was a special thing.
You don't understand.
You're so smart and
yet you don't get it.
Women must be
told they're good,
that they're beautiful,
that they're the
best thing we have.
You should tell her:
"Giulia play for me".
"Play for the two of us".
You should behave
as I did with your mother.
What? You fight all the time!
Fights are good,
They're good to keep fit.
The 26 principles and
the 109 recommendations of the UN
approved in Stockholm 2 years ago,
are constantly
disregarded in Italy.
Above all by people like those
who are to be judged today,
and for whom I ask for
the maximum of the penalty.
I also ask for them to be
charged of the legal costs
and of the damage costs.
Because they willingly discharged
waste products to a river
damaging the environment
and the health of the citizens.
Think of this:
in the last ten years
1.870 billion dollars
a year were spent
for military purposes.
A year, understand?
Now, 50% of this money
was spent for bribes,
also in Italy. Wouldn't you
put them under arrest?
Give me the names.
- Tell her about public enterprises.
- What are you, a prompter?
No, she knows about those,
as the names are in the papers too.
But she has to read them.
Dad? What... Look.
- Old chopsticks.
- Dad?
- "Folk".
- Okay, okay...
Don't listen to him.
This is the crab's technique.
Sure, it's the calamari's.
I'll use the fork.
Will your banger
make it to the airport?
How dare you?
Take a taxi then.
Why are you
going to Cambridge?
There's much to do here too...
I know, I'll be back.
I'm studying for a Master.
Then I think I'll be
back next year. I wanted
to apply to the Bank of Italy.
Didn't I tell you he wants
to become a Governor?
He wants to sign the banknotes.
Let's drink to the future Governor.
Long live the Governor!
I know it sounds absurd,
but if you want him
to think he can make it,
you must believe it too.
Not just pretend.
- But he doesn't know we know.
- It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter,
your father can feel it.
he can feel everything,
he can feel it if you care.
- He can feel you all.
- Carlo, I'm a doctor.
I can't believe in miracles.
Then forget you're
a doctor for a while.
Okay, I understood.
You're my friend,
you want to help, I understood.
Thanks. Enough though.
- Sorry.
- Thanks. Thank you.
I think it's my plane.
Sorry about before.
No, I'm sorry.
I talked nonsense.
Try not to behave
like an asshole in England.
like an asshole here.
I didn't tell anyone.
Not even Nicola.
He would have started
with psychology,
with the fact that
you need to react,
all that bullshit, you know.
I told you... because I told you.
This is our secret.
You must promise me, because
I don't want anyone's pity.
But you must promise me
you'll have yourself cured,
and tested and so on.
I'll do everything.
Be patient with Matteo.
I don't know why,
but I've never understood him.
And I'm sorry for that.
Then there's Francesca...
and mom,
and Nicola.
Nicola is strong.
He isn't all the time.
He's like everyone else.
And last but not least
you have to take care of yourself.
You have to smile.
Be cheerful,
have fun.
Where's your husband?
Out for work?
We haven't seen
each other for a while.
There are some problems.
Another woman?
Not at all. There are
just some problems.
I think we'll ask for separation.
Separation? And you
weren't telling me?
- I'm sorry.
- I'm not.
It's better this way.
It is!
We'll find another one.
Are you looking for mystery?
Are you talking to me?
You must find the soul.
How can I find it?
You have to search for it,
look inside people.
PALERMO, SUMMER OF 1977
Can you look inside?
I can.
See that child?
Look at his hand.
He's confident.
He has a cockade on his shirt,
he's top of the form.
Maybe.
See that old lady?
Two wedding rings,
she's a widow.
And she feels lonely.
You aren't Sicilian.
Are you making fun of me?
Did you see the film "Stromboli"?
The one with Ingrid Bergman?
- Yes.
- That's where I live.
But I'll leave soon.
I applied for a job as a
librarian in Palermo.
I want to leave the island.
What about that? It's
a professional camera.
Are you an expert?
I'm an expert in libraries too.
Are you?
I am.
So if I got the job,
what library should I choose?
In Palermo I don't know,
but in Rome there's a beautiful
one in Villa Celli Montana.
Can I look for mystery?
Come on...
Sorry I have to go.
- Now?
- Yes.
- What's your name?
- Nicola.
- Mirella.
- Pleased to meet you. Sorry. Bye.
Bye Nicola.
- What happened?
- Someone was killed.
The Commissary wants
you to take some photos.
- I don't have the camera.
- I do.
Wow, you never forget
anything, do you?
Where did you find it?
Look at me!
That's too easy.
Look at daddy.
Look at me.
I hurt myself.
How many times must I say
Sara must be in bed at this hour?
Did the doctor prescribe that?
Daddy's a doctor!
He can decide!
What's wrong?
I'm tired.
I fought with Stefania.
I told her I'm done with the shop.
I've had enough of arguing all the time.
- You used to like arguing.
- I did once.
Maybe it's better this way,
so you can go back
to play the piano.
I sold it.
Someone will take
it away tomorrow.
Are you crazy?
Maybe I am.
Where have you been?
Do you control me?
I went to a meeting of the Collective.
Anything against that?
- Those are really good people...
- What do you mean?
There's nothing decent in this
country. Everything sucks.
And we do nothing about it.
Did you hear of that boy
who was killed in Bologna?
Yes, I did.
And when are we going
to make them cry too?
When are we going
Take off that thing!
You're ridiculous!
- Listen...
- Let go of me.
- You can't even stand me now?
- No!
I can't even stand you.
You only care for your hospital.
Everything's on my shoulders.
I don't agree.
I hate arguments!
I hate fighting couples!
Ladies and gentlemen?
Bobby can't sleep
with this noise.
You're right, love.
We'll all stay quiet now.
Dear Carlo,
I'm happy to hear of
your success in Cambridge.
Here things are
the same as usual.
It's not easy to work
inside the Institutions,
trying to change them little by little.
Giulia and I have got problems.
She became aggressive and hostile.
She's unsatisfied with
something I can't understand.
We've slept like brother
and sister for 6 months now.
Follow me, I'll show
you the dormitory.
Who sends these inspectors, I wonder...
The Minister of Health, madam.
True, the Minister of Health.
And who are you? A lawyer?
A judge? Please open up.
- I'm a psychiatrist.
- Good.
Here's the dormitory.
As you see it's clean
everything's tidy.
Where are the patients?
I sent them to a trip
to the Sanctuary of Europa,
because I care for them.
I want them to feel
well, to have fun.
To feel like normal people.
Where are you going?
There's nothing there.
There's just a basement.
- What's inside here?
- Nothing.
- Open the door.
- There's just a store.
- Don't!
- Marshal, please...
You must have a
search warrant first!
I want to call my lawyer first!
Come on!
Where are you going? See?
Are you happy now?
There's nothing here.
Only garbage.
Where are you going?
You can't do that!
- It's an empty room!
- Stand aside!
Marshal, please.
I protest! It's not fair!
Take her to the radio car,
and if she offers
resistance, handcuff her.
The door.
...water... water...
Call some ambulances.
Untie them and cover them.
Please Marshal...
Giorgia?
Now Giorgia put on the sweater.
Be good.
We'll give it to you and you'll
wear it by yourself, okay?
Here.
Let's do this,
I leave it here
and we'll turn around.
Please Giorgia.
It's okay, I'll manage it.
Thanks.
How are you?
Did you eat?
Do you want some?
Remember the journey
we took together?
Don Vito's village?
That time we slept in a hayloft.
Do you remember the soccer match?
Italy were losing and
we laughed and laughed...
Do you remember Matteo?
The orange.
It must drink or it'll die.
You're right.
I always forget it.
Sorry, I won't touch you.
But I'd like you to
come here every day,
to water the plant, or it'll die.
- The Judge? Did you call him?
- Yes.
- When?
- Two hours ago.
And he's still not here?
What? You're smoking
in a slaughterhouse?
- Please, put it out.
- Put it out!
We should leave...
Can we move it?
Move it? First the judge
comes and then we move it.
Always the same questions.
Our shift's over.
The shift you said?
There's a dead man here!
Enzo, what did I say?
Tell them to keep quiet.
- They don't want to!
- Force them!
Okay, go away everyone.
Please leave.
What? There's a child here!
Are you all nuts? Get out! Out!
Are you his dad?
Take him away!
Is the child bothering you?
Who do you think you are?
How dare you?
Do you think
it's a nice show?
There's a dead man
here! It's not a film.
Where were you
when he was shot?
I don't know! I don't
remember, I wasn't here!
He doesn't know! Like the
rest of you, nobody knows!
He died by himself!
And then show him to children
too, so they can learn.
- Go away.
- Don't touch my son!
- What are you teaching him?
- You won't touch him!
Here's an extraordinary permit.
I don't want to see
you for 2 weeks.
Go on holiday, go home,
do as you please,
but get lost.
I already have too
many problems here.
What do you want to prove?
Out of my sight!
Get lost!
- Carati, what happened?
- All's well.
- But will you be transferred?
- Nah.
Special leave.
That's how it works.
It could have been worse.
Oh, here you are.
It arrived this morning.
Dear Matteo,
I have good news.
I found Giorgia.
I think she suffered a lot,
but it seems as if
time stopped for her.
I was very excited
when I found her.
I remembered that summer
of many years ago,
when my life, yours, and
many others' changed.
And I thought
why don't you leave the
headquarter for a few days
and come to see her in Turin?
What took place in April
wasn't an isolated phenomenon,
it wasn't just an
outbreak of violence,
because it followed
50 days of fights at the FIAT,
fights which involved
a huge number of workers
and blocked the whole
production cycle,
showing how much
power the workers have
on a political and
organizational level.
I don't like it.
Too bureaucratic.
There's a difference
between desires and needs.
Needs are a serious matter.
Needs lead us to bring
it all up for discussion,
to risk everything,
to die and fight, if necessary.
For example the
need for communism...
- Hi.
Excuse me.
You came home
earlier today.
Yes, I did.
Hi Sara.
- Hi.
- Are you drawing?
Yes.
Let's go for a walk.
Hurray!
Enclosed space
is not good for a child.
And for people's brains.
The need for communism...
I need to drink, to eat...
Sara, when you
hear this bullshit...
You said a swearword!
Sometimes one has to.
When someone lies
to you at the kindergarten,
- what do you tell them?
- Shitty liar!
Good!
Now let's go out
for a nice walk.
- See ya'll!
It's cold outside,
so we take your coat with us.
Let's go take
a breath of air.
Out, out...
- Listen Giulia...
- I know, it's a problem I have to solve.
Hello. Luigi Pezzuco please.
Thanks.
I was lucky too, doctors
always tell me that
a few more millimetres
and I would have lost my arms too.
Everything works instead.
Almost everything.
I even met a woman. Patrizia.
Let me show you...
I have a picture of us which
someone took at a party.
It has to be here... Here it is!
She's beautiful. Congratulations!
We'll get married in September.
We also want to have children.
You wanna know how we do it?
Slowly, patiently. She likes it
all the same, she says.
- Of course.
- But this was only possible
thanks to your mother.
- My Mother?
- Matteo...
I have a few notebooks like this one.
Without your mother, this hand
wouldn't have recovered.
- Did she come here?
- Once in every week.
You didn't know?
- I did.
- And not only my hand recovered.
Also my brain. I had never
read poems before.
Listen:
"Ettore, you'll be
honoured with tears"
"shed where the holy blood you
poured for your country lies..."
What did I write here?
"Till the sun shines
on human misfortunes".
Doctor Carati?
What a surprise!
How are you?
- Fine. You?
- Fine.
- The beard?
- Sara says it stings.
- It stings?
- Yes so I shaved it.
- I have a present for her.
- Thanks. What's that?
- A doll, so you can play too.
- How nice!
- Did you pass through Rome?
- Yes, but didn't stop at home.
- What are those pictures?
- My patients made them.
I'm organising an exposition.
- Are you?
- Yes.
Did you know that mom
went to help Luigi,
- my colleague on the chair?
- Yes, I knew it.
- Who's that?
- My master, Franco Basaglia.
The one who wants
to set all the nuts free?
He has this strange feeling
that mentally ill people aren't
prisoners but human beings,
and that mental illness isn't
a crime to pay for. Weird guy, isn't he?
- How is dad?
- You should go see him.
I will.
I already made up my mind.
- Let's go see Giorgia.
- Sure. How is she?
Better.
Maybe we'll discharge her.
We do it as soon as possible,
and place them in small houses.
- What's wrong with them?
- Once they were all "schizophrenics"
- Which means nothing.
- It means they're like split in two..
Who isn't? Are you completely a
policeman? Am I completely a doctor?
The truth is we don't know
enough about the matter.
But one thing for sure they suffer
from the "mental hospital disease".
How do you cure them?
We open the departments.
- I'll wait in my study.
- You're leaving me?
- What can I tell her?
- Maybe she'll tell you something.
Hi Giorgia.
It's very good
to see you again.
Are you well?
You're right, it's
a stupid question.
What does it mean?
Nicola said you can go out.
Shall we go for an ice-cream?
We'll look for a juke-box too.
You used to like music.
I was also told you read.
You like books.
What do you read?
Which words can
reach your brain?
You can't hear me.
Sound! Air!
Attention! Nothing.
Nothing can reach you.
You're absent-minded.
Absent!
Like I didn't know already...
Do you remember that summer?
What were you like?
What was I like?
Madly mad Matteo...
Giorgia!
- Can she make it?
- She will, you'll see.
She reminded me...
Once, at that station...
- Yes?
- We listened to the juke-box.
- She turned around and looked at me.
- You were a bit in love with her...
- You were!
- We both were.
- What song was it?
- "A Chi" by Fausto Leali.
(singing) A chi!
A chi!
Nicola!
Your father...
Could you slow down?
Slow down, no one's after us.
You wanna drive?
- I just said to slow down.
- That's how I drive!
- Fuck off!
- Giulia, please...
I'm worried because
of Sara. Understand?
Understand?
Why don't you answer to her?
- She spoke to you!
- That's how I drive, Giulia.
Stop this fucking car!
Stop it!
Stop the car! Pull over!
Okay, calm down.
I'll stop it as soon as I can.
What the hell are you doing?
Turn around!
Turn around! Matteo!
Thanks for coming.
Hi.
Thanks.
- How's your mother?
- You can see it.
- Hi.
- Hi, I'm Francesca.
- Policemen are busy.
- But he said he would come.
He will, if he can. But why
don't you come with me to Milan?
- Francesca can make it.
- No, I have to stay because of my job.
I know the school
will be ruined without you,
but you have to
take care of yourself.
In fact I do.
Working helps me.
- Giulia? Coffee?
- I'll go make some.
No, I will.
- Anyone wants a coffee?
- Yes thanks.
Francesca, where's
the coffee machine?
Into the cupboard.
The other one.
Nicola says you'll be
Minister of Treasure in 10 years.
Does he?
I'm currently working
for the Bank of Italy.
- To be a Minister I should change career.
- You mean?
It means Ministers are politicians.
I'm only a technician.
You're modest. Nicola says
you're smarter than him.
And if he says so...
- Nicola is crazier than his patients.
- That's true.
You're so clumsy!
- What are you doing?
- I've just finished high school.
I'll study Literature.
I want to be an archaeologist
and see the world too.
It's a good thing.
I am a middle-distance racer.
I'm an excellent cook
and play the violin too.
Nothing else?
- I get easily bored.
- Are you getting bored now?
No, I'm making coffee,
making sweets with Sara,
- and chatting with the Bank of Italy.
- Good.
It's something...
- Aunt?
- I'm coming.
See how many
cookies I've made!
You're so good...
Want some more kneading?
- Can I have a cookie?
- Carlo, go away!
Francesca is good
with children. I'm not.
- I'm not good.
- There isn't a single way to be a mother.
I wasn't a good
mother to Matteo.
At least I wasn't
the mother he wanted.
No you were a great mother,
I can see it in Nicola.
Excuse me.
- I'll go get some milk.
- There's some in the fridge.
There are many
people. It's not enough.
- I'll go get some milk.
- I got it.
Can I get out of
this house for a while?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry love. Forgive me.
- You're late.
- There was trouble at home.
It's dangerous
for me to wait here.
I have a suitcase,
I have a suspicious air.
Have you got the keys?
They're inside, with the
money and the documents.
And the gun. Can you use it?
- No.
- You'll learn.
Let me pass! Let me pass!
Nicola, let me pass!
Let me pass!
- Let me pass!
- Did you think of your daughter?
Let me pass!
- Let me pass!
- Why?
Let me pass!
(Tv) "The group was accused
of being an armed band..."
"...with a paramilitary structure
and possession of firearms."
(Tv) "The DIGOS of Turin released
the identikit of five people..."
"...3 men and 2 women who
frequented the Red Brigades hideout..."
"...which was found in Turin,
in "Corso Bernardino Telesio".
(Tv) "One of the suspects
refused to answer..."
"...to the magistrates."
(Tv) "The defendants are
accused of trying to destroy..."
"...the State and its Institutions."
I want more.
Give me another piece of gazelle.
Sure, my little lion. Dad's
going to give it to you.
I want to quit fencing.
- I want to stop taking fencing lessons.
- What?
You asked me to, now you will!
- Where's mommy?
- Mom left. She left.
Sorry Sara.
I made a mistake.
Sara, please!
Let's make up.
Salute! One! Two! Three!
Four! Five! Six!
Down! On guard!
One step forward!
One step back!
Knee-bend! On guard!
One step forward!
One step back!
Today you're
a little uncoordinated.
Let's start over.
Arm in line. Look at me!
Arm in line! Position one!
Salute, away!
One! Two! Three! Four!
Five! Six! Down! On guard!
SPRING OF 1980
Will you, Tommaso...
- ...Carlo.
- Sorry?
Carlo Tommasi, not Tommaso Carli.
- Sorry. Will you, Carlo Carati...
- No, Carlo Tommasi.
- And Francesca Carati.
- There's also a male Carati.
It's me. I'm Nicola Carati, brother
of the bride Francesca Carati.
You are... sorry.
You're the brother of
the bride. Congratulations!
Then you should sit
where that crested girl is.
- In fact...
- I'm the best man. Carlo's my friend.
You're the best man
and SISTER of the bride!
- It's a coincidence.
- It's not illegal.
Let's start again.
Will you, Carlo Tommasi, marry...
Francesca Carati?
I will.
That's a good start!
Will you, Francesca Carati, marry...
- Carlo Tommasi?
- I will.
Will you exchange the rings?
- Careful...
- Sorry, it's my first marriage!
Mine too!
Long live the married couple!
Hurray!
Come to meet my girlfriends.
- No, Francesca!
- Only five minutes!
- They love blue eyes!
- Not again!
My brother Matteo.
Carlotta, Teresa...
Let me show you something...
- Sara!
- My niece Sara.
Give me a kiss.
It's a nice wedding.
- When will you get married?
- Who would ever want me?
You're a good catch!
Department of special bodywork!
- Working aristocracy!
- I was a good catch.
- What do you mean?
- I received this.
- You're fired?
- Almost: redundancy at zero hours.
- They sent 23,000 letters like this one.
- There's nothing you can do?
- We've been on strike for a month.
- You said you'd be safe.
Let's talk about it later.
It's Carlo's wedding.
Read this.
Do you study such things
at the Bank of Italy?
- More or less.
- So? What does it mean?
The FIAT is indebted
for 7,000 billion lire.
Other factories are in a worse
situation. They don't produce enough.
- They're not competitive.
- Then what?
- Workers can't win.
- It's his opinion.
- It isn't, unfortunately.
- But there are the Unions!
They can't do anything.
People are scared, selfish.
Carlo, they can't
fire him like in 1800!
Industries are
being re-organised.
They cut the expenses
to become competitive.
- Who cares!
- I know.
Should we pay
for their incapacity?
- Who cares if the system blows up?
- Come on, the system won't blow up.
If it did, it should be replaced
by something else. Any idea?
Me? You're the expert!
Enough with fighting!
This is a happy day!
Cut it out.
It's the "swan-song" of workers!
In a few years no one will remember us.
Don't worry doctor,
they won't have me!
I won't stay at home and cry.
I'll look for another job.
If I can't find it I'll invent one.
I can mend water taps, TVs, heaters.
Houses are full of so much stuff!
- Someone has to mend it! I will.
- Good!
At least I'll go live with him,
I'll wear a Napoleon's hat
and dance the tango!
I want to dance!
Let's go!
Come on, sissies!
Let's go to dance!
- Do you know "Anatomy"?
- What?
(singing) Anatomy!
- "Amado Mio"!
That one!
Mrs. Tommasi,
may I have this dance?
Be careful with my mother!
# Fixed and translated: lyliakar #
# Special thanks to Petrie,
BaalsEngeltje and matopotato #
# for their kindest collaboration #
He wants to be an acrobat.
TURIN, SUMMER OF 1982
He puts his hands on the
ground, springs up and "zac!"
He puts his feet against the wall
then he starts swinging them.
When I meet him I say
"Hello Mimmo"...
...and we shake feet.
- Balloons!
- I'll buy you one.
- What colour?
- Blue.
Yes, it's your favourite...
Hello. A blue balloon please.
- Are you happy that school is over?
- No.
Why? It's holiday time!
Where would
you like to go this year?
When will mom come back?
I don't know Sara.
Monica said dads
say that when moms die.
That's nonsense.
You believe Monica?
- If mom died would you tell me?
- Of course.
- Why did you set it free?
- If you told a lie, that was for mom.
(speakers) "The train will
arrive in a few minutes."
"We're sorry for the delay."
(Tv) Israeli troops have surrounded
the Palestinian quarters in Beirut."
"Barbara Melega."
"Roberta De Angelis."
"Paola Oriviello."
"United States of America."
"Celia Boback."
(Tv) "The balance deficit
has reached danger point."
"The Government has imposed
cuts in expenditure and new taxes."
"First soccer match of Italy
at the World Championship of 1982."
"The match against Poland
finished as a draw."
"Patrizio Peci on trial is finally
talking about the murder of Aldo Moro."
- Who's that?
- Your neighbour.
- I need a favour please.
- Just a moment.
- I'm sorry, I thought the Randis were in.
- No, they're out of town.
- I'm their guest.
- Are you a teacher too?
Yes.
I came here from
Udine for the exams.
My husband forgot the milk.
Do you have some?
The fridge is empty sorry,
I had no time to fill it up yet.
Never mind. I'll send
him to buy some.
As they say, "a forgetful head
makes a weary pair of heels".
- Welcome, by the way.
- Thanks.
Sara get inside!
- Her name's Sara too?
- Like your daughter?
No, like my niece.
- Is she a pest too?
- No... Yes!
No.
It was "Silver"!
"I heard a dozen words
and decided..."
"...I'd get stuck in there."
"I stayed there, shaking..."
"listening!"
She passed by in the morning.
About 7 a.m., no one
was here but me.
She came out of nowhere.
Who told her I work here?
You don't want
to know how she is?
I don't want
to know anything.
I didn't recognise her at first,
her hair's black now and...
Enough.
She wants to see her child.
From a distance. She won't
speak or get close to her.
Have a cigarette?
- Did you start smoking?
- No.
- What did you tell her?
- Nothing. You can't argue with her.
She made the date and left.
She didn't even ask how I am,
or why I'm a simple
manual worker now.
- When is the date?
- In two days, during the "final".
Which "final"?
The World Championship!
The soccer match!
(radio) "Header."
- They're listening to the match.
- Look, a hyena!
- "Hyena Ridens".
- They always laugh.
- Because they're witty?
No, they grind their teeth.
- A moose!
- Yes.
I've seen many in Norway.
- Look, a wild pig!
- No, it's a warthog.
(radio)
"3-1 at the 38th minute."
"His name was Fritz. He was
obedient and easy to lead."
"He lived in Stupinigi for 25 years."
"On 4th November 1847
he killed his guardian."
(Radio) "Causio enters as a substitute."
"It's just a device to
waste some time"
"as there's just a minute left till
the end of the World Championship."
Those are birds.
That's a hawk.
They were used to hunt,
they picked up preys.
It looks like a hen house.
- A pelican!
- A moose, look!
...and a giraffe, my favourite.
- Why is that?
- They stretch their neck to eat,
and look at the sky.
I like animals
which look at the sky.
- What's that?
- That's a sea cow.
- It looks like a seal.
- Yes, but it's a sea cow.
- How come you know so much?
- I'm reading the plates.
(radio) "Throw-in."
"Rossi looses the ball."
"40 seconds after the regular time."
"Muller kicks the ball"
"Scirea stops it. Bergomi...
Gentile... It's over!"
Yes!
We won.
Yes, we won.
AUTUMN 1983
What a cold!
Rome was supposed
to be sunny all the time!
You don't have a motorbike, do you?
I don't want confusion in the yard.
That's the kitchen
and this is the living-room.
It's bright.
The furniture is new.
There's the bedroom.
- It's perfect.
- The TV is new as well.
The removal company men
walked up to the fourth floor.
- I gave them a 20,000 lire tip.
- Sure. Here you are.
You can give it to me
at the end of the week.
Alright.
The owner of the house
wants her flowers
- to be watered every day.
- It's fine.
- I can do that if you want.
- No, I'll do that.
If you need anything,
please call me or my husband.
- We're in the porter's lodge.
- Okay.
- Have a nice day. Here's the key.
- See you.
All's well, Madam Marquise!
Let's go, colleague.
This way.
Hi.
The nightshift starts
tomorrow. It lasts 2 weeks,
then we have 3 days off.
Then the dayshift starts.
This is the Chief's office.
Pay attention.
That's your office and
here's the coffee machine.
This is your desk.
Those are wanted,
no political distinction.
We think they're all in town.
What if we meet
this one for example?
If she tries to reach
her pocket we'll shoot.
I'll shoot her even
if she stays still.
Just for precaution.
(Tv) "The car has been
found near there."
"It was stolen 10 days ago."
- It's sticky!
- Add some more flour to it.
(Tv) "His 20 year old daughter
has heard the shooting."
"The attorney has died
before reaching the hospital.
It's full of bubbles.
(Tv) "A man has called saying"
"the Red Brigades
forced him to call."
"...A new claim for
the terrorist attack..."
"Caccia was investigating
terrorism, traffic in drugs..."
"...and the mafia racket..."
I'd like to borrow this.
Hello.
Yes?
You're Nicola.
- The girl from Stromboli!
- I have a name.
Wait, don't tell me!
Give me a document
in the meantime.
I forgot it. Marcella!
- No, Mirella.
- True!
Sorry.
I'll record it using my name,
but bring it back in 15 days.
- What if I steal it?
- I'll look for you.
You don't know where
I live, or my last name...
I'll find you a second time.
Okay.
Did you come here
because we spoke about it?
Your advice was good,
it's a beautiful place.
It's lunch break. Wanna share
a sandwich and an apple?
I remember that day so clearly.
I even dream of you very often.
I told my boyfriend
and he got jealous.
I don't know why, I was
no longer sure you were real!
- Men are idiots.
- That's true.
Then if you tell him
you met me he'll kill you!
He's that sort of man,
yes, that's why I left him.
Apple?
Do you still take pictures?
Sometimes.
Remember when you told me
I had to look for mystery?
I liked that a lot.
I tried, but never managed it.
I can't photograph people inside.
You said that!
Did I? I don't remember.
- Don't you?
- I don't.
You changed my life
and you don't remember...
Apple, please...
I'll forgive you only
cause you're handsome.
Please don't keep the book
for more than 2 weeks.
Giovanna! Come in!
Let's go to the living-room...
- How did you know I was here?
- I read the list of...
...those assigned to the escorts.
- You left no address.
- Sit down.
- I didn't know you were in Rome.
- I'm staying at mom's for a while.
- There's lots of room there...
- How's she?
- Have a guess?
- Something to drink?
Do you think it's normal for you
to come here and not call her?
I'll make some coffee.
- I'm speaking to you.
- You're speaking like an elder sister!
- I already have a mother!
- To you it's as if she's dead!
How do you know?
You can only judge me!
We're not in the Court!
But what did we do to you?
Giovanna, wait! Giovanna!
Listen...
- Hi.
- What's your name?
- Matteo.
It's a beautiful name.
- What's yours?
- Lolita.
- Where are you from?
- Venezuela.
What's wrong? Are you sad?
What are you looking at?
- Your necklace.
- My necklace?
- Do you like it?
- Yes.
Here you are. For your girl.
I don't feel like I'm ready.
Maybe I...
My companions
are stronger than me.
I'm always scared,
maybe I'm not trained enough.
Maybe I should...
You don't have to be scared.
You'll make it.
Hello?
Hello.
- Francesca, listen to me.
- Yes.
I need to see you at once.
- At the Foro Romano in two hours.
- Okay.
Sara grew bigger. I wish I could
bring you a picture, but I was in a haste.
I was so nervous!
A few days ago Nicola took
her to watch "The Party".
Suddenly she asked him what
"a girl's period" is, in a loud voice.
And what did he do?
He explained it to her
in front of everyone.
Nicola cannot
see differences.
Young, old, crazy, sane
are all the same to him. Listen,
tell Carlo to ask for a transfer.
He must leave Italy.
Now.
- And go where?
- Wherever you want.
He's in danger.
The kids are small...
...and there's the house, and his job...
And I know him, he'll never leave.
- I have to go now.
- Wait!
Now you listen to me.
I'll try to speak to
Carlo and convince him,
but he'll say no.
He is your friend before being the father
of my children. You must do something.
- I can't.
- Tell them he's never alone.
Tell them it's too risky
for them to kill him. Save him!
Swear it!
You trust me?
I do.
Alright, I'll do my best.
- Is Nicola coming for the holidays?
- I think so.
- On New Year's Eve.
- I want to see Sara.
- Only once.
- What should I do?
- Take her to the Coliseum. I'll call you.
- Okay.
- Don't tell anyone.
- I won't.
What's your job?
I'm an engineer.
Every mother dreams
of having an engineer for a son!
Maybe that's why I became one.
So you make dams, bridges, buildings...
I often work abroad. I travel much.
- Do you like to travel?
- No.
- What would you like to do?
- I don't know.
- Maybe stay among books like you.
- Then come with me!
- Do you like chestnuts?
- Yes.
Chestnuts please.
- How much is it?
- 3,000.
That's a theft!
- You can go pick them up then!
- That's Rome...
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
- Wanna come to a place?
- Where?
Fingers here and thumb
behind, lift up your hand...
...swing your arm...
...and place your
left foot forwards.
- It's easy.
- So and so.
- Is it my turn?
- Yes.
- Put your fingers in the holes!
- No, I'll do as I prefer.
Enough said.
- But it won't go straightforward.
- Wait and you'll see.
- It's weak.
- Shut up.
Goal!
- It's called "strike".
- Strike!
- Get on.
- Thanks.
- You're all wet, sorry.
- Never mind.
- I'll make a phone call.
- Okay.
- You're all wet!
- I must leave tomorrow, sorry.
- There are problems at work.
- How long will you stay away?
A week. I'll be back on the 7th.
What will you do on the 7th?
I'll come and pick you.
What time?
When the library closes.
I found it under the seat.
I bought it the other day but I lost it.
- Who knows how it ended there.
- Is it for your girlfriend?
It's for you.
Then help me wear it.
I'll do your shift.
- Afternoon and evening?
- Yes.
You're a good friend!
I'm not sure this car could
have made it on the highway.
- Hey now!
- When will you change it?
Why should I? It's perfect!
- It's old and it sucks.
- No, it's beautiful and perfect.
- Why don't you buy a new one?
- My child's a consumerist...
- Are we poor?
- Why? Do you miss anything?
I wish we left for Christmas.
We'd have exchanged presents.
- We will on New Year's Eve.
- Who's coming?
- Granny, aunt Giovanna...
- Francesca?
Aunt Francesca,
Carlo, the kids...
- They had another kid.
- What's his name?
- Asdrubale Teofrasto Callimaco.
- Callimaco?
- No, Nabuccodonosor.
- You're making fun of me!
- His name's Michele.
- Michele?
"The journey started well.
The ship was good..."
"...to cross the Ocean."
"The crew was good too..."
"...and the Captain was skilled."
"Everything was going well."
"Then, one night Gino
was getting to his cabin..."
- "and he suddenly felt hungry."
- Let's not show ourselves.
- Look at them.
- Yes.
- They won't sleep tonight.
- Who cares, they're happy.
You're right.
- Lucky you!
- Why?
- You have a daughter.
- And?
We're much
better than you all.
- Stop it...
- If you had a son you'd be wilder.
- Really?
- Yes, but she tamed you.
- You have white hair!
- Only a couple!
- You're a charming 40 year old man.
- I'm only 37!
But women like mature men...
Lend me your finger...
How can you make it with 3 kids?
One's already too much for me...
I'm devastated but I love it.
Why is Carlo escorted?
These are hard times.
- Nicola?
- Yes?
Nothing. Michele woke up.
Can you open the door?
Why are you escorted?
"It was the winter
of our discontent..."
- "The accountant climbed up the stairs."
- "I was forced to wait for him..."
"There was also the crazy doctor!"
- How are you?
- Fine. Yourself?
I was thinking of places like
Denmark, Sweden or Holland.
Those countries look like glass boxes.
Citizens can look through them.
I dream of transparent banks,
and Stock Exchange.
This way politics and economics
would be transparent too.
Cute little thing...
Did he fall asleep?
- Have a look?
- Not yet.
What's wrong tonight, honey?
He's too excited, we arrived,
he saw new faces...
- Give him to me.
- No, he's about to fall asleep.
- Is he sleeping?
- Careful.
Give him to me.
Mind the duck.
- Francesca?
- She's sleeping.
She's exhausted.
Holidays are tiring for her.
As regards transparency...
- Do you think it's possible?
- Of course, in other countries it is.
But do you think
Italians like transparency?
I think it's an illusion.
- Shall we put him into his cradle?
- Yes.
Give him to me.
Don't whisper or
he won't fall asleep.
Kids like noise,
they're afraid of silence.
- He's sleeping.
- He'll wake up in half an hour.
Daddy's cute baby...
How cute you are...
You've always
been good with kids.
- Are you good with women too?
- Of course.
- Do you have anyone?
- Not a regular one.
- Do you have many women?
- Are you jealous?
I'll tell you a secret.
I married your sister
to stay close to you.
Indeed you look like a "queer".
- You too.
- Of course!
Who are your girlfriends?
You have a circle of
nurses and anaesthetists?
It's none of your business!
- Where do you see them?
- Outside.
- What about Sara?
- She doesn't know.
And none of them is somehow...
Of course.
But after a while
everything's over.
You didn't answer before.
Why are you escorted?
- Did you speak with Francesca?
- No.
Want some whisky?
So?
Looks like I'm a target.
That's why I'm escorted.
- But why you?
- Not only judges are targets,
or politicians and policemen.
The other day one of my
university fellow-students was shot.
They say "Hit one to educate 100"
They want to educate us!
- They want to terrify us.
- And so you're forced to live in an armour?
- Any suggestions?
- Ask for a transfer abroad.
The Governor wanted
to send me to New York.
And?
Drink that whisky
and tell me if you like it.
- Why didn't you accept?
- If we all leave
they'll win.
How did you find out you're a target?
Giulia met Francesca.
Giulia contacted us.
She also said she wants to see the kid.
31st DECEMBER 1983
There's no room here.
I'll let Francesca get off
then I'll follow you.
Okay.
- He's worked for me for a week.
- Six months ago another man
who was carrying cocaine
was arrested in your nightclub.
He was a customer. I'm clean.
I just care for them
to be wearing a jacket.
- He was arrested three times before.
- I don't check criminal records.
I respect my workers' privacy.
Nothing to say, Azi Mohamed?
No.
I'd like to go to my parents'
house. It's New Year's Eve.
I don't give a damn!
What?
- Someone's looking for you.
- Who's that?
A certain Mirella.
- Why did you say your name's Nicola?
- What are you doing here?
Why didn't you say
your name's Matteo?
- How did you find out?
- I asked some guy at the bowling.
You go there often.
He said you're a policeman.
I should be the detective here,
while everyone
investigates me, instead.
You, my sister... Everyone
wants to mind my own business.
- What do you want?
- I wanted to see you.
- I thought we were happy together.
- So what?
Nothing.
- But...
- What?
What?
I'm busy.
- Why do you act like that?
- I'm on duty.
I don't understand.
Why did you lie to me?
You've always lied to me!
- Why did you say your name's Nicola?
- I'll tell you, but not here.
- Fine. I'm leaving.
- Fine.
You like books cause you can
close them whenever you want.
Life is different,
you can't decide that.
You're wrong.
I've always decided. Also
not to see you anymore.
- That's not a choice.
- Good girl, you got it!
I'm an asshole, I suck.
You better lose me.
Now leave.
- You aren't like that.
- What the hell...
...do you want from me?
- Nicola...
- My name's Matteo!
Go away!
- Let's play "Merchant at the Fair"!
- Yes! - No!
- It's a good game.
- You're snobbish!
- We'll play it.
- Who plays the Merchant?
- You will, as you're impartial.
- No.
- You're a judge!
- Who plays the bidder?
- Carlo, he's into trade!
- No!
- Come on Carlo!
- Okay. Not because I'm a merchant,
but because I'm the only
good one here!
Read again and sign it.
You wait here, a colleague
will take you downstairs.
We're not done yet.
Sit down.
Sit down!
How much money will he give you
if you go to prison in his place?
- What?
- How much?
- This is a serious accusation!
- Shut up!
I won't!
I want to call my lawyer.
You can't treat me like that!
Does he give you the drugs?
You're a penniless wretch.
Where do you find the money?
Does he give it to you?
Does he?
What do you want?
Who are you?
- Don't try and fool me!
- That's not fair!
- I want my lawyer!
- You'll remember tonight forever!
Lawyer my foot!
That's not fair at all.
A friend of mine is a Deputy.
I'll have you transferred!
- And I'll break your teeth!
- Calm down!
How dare you!
What the hell are you doing?
Are you crazy?
I don't want to get
in trouble because of you.
But remember,
he's got nothing to do with it.
- It's 500 lire each. Take your change.
- Hurry up!
Here are some cards...
...which Agnelli himself would like
to have, and they're yours for 1,500 lire.
- 1,600!
- The doctor said 1,600.
- 2,000!
- Adriana offered 2,000.
- 2,500.
- Little Sara said 2,500.
- 2,800.
Where will you find the money?
I'll give him the money.
He got Giovanni Agnelli's cards!
- Who can it be?
- I'll get it.
- Who is it?
- Who can it be?
- Happy new year mom.
- I knew you'd come.
Come in.
Oh, oh...
- Look who's coming...
- Merry Christmas!
- How are you?
- How are you? Merry Christmas.
- Best wishes.
- Welcome.
By the way this isn't
a gambling house, officer.
- Merry Christmas.
- Little sister!
- Where's my change?
This is uncle's change.
- Where are the other two?
- They're sleeping.
- Sara!
- Hi.
- Remember me?
- Yes.
- You're the fast driver.
- And here are some cards
- for the fast driver...
- Okay.
Two cards for him.
I have some other cards here...
- Did I hear Orlandino speak?
- 6,500! - 6,500!
- 7,000.
- Don't go higher or Sara can't bet.
Mom!
I'll give Sara the money.
I can lend you a million.
It's not fair to lend money
secretly. How much was it?
- 10,000! - No.
- 8,300. - 8,300.
I heard something
which leaves no doubt.
10,000 one, 10,000 two...
10,000 three!
The grapes card.
- Who has the grapes?
- I don't.
He collapsed.
- Where are the others?
- Sleeping.
- Aren't you going to bed, Sara?
- No, I want to win.
Fair enough.
Remember that the grapes came out.
And as it's Christmas,
the Baby card came out too.
- Here it is.
- I'm out.
- Mom I have to call my office.
- Go to my bedroom.
- How many cards left?
- Nine.
Attention please.
It's an animal.
- Carlo!
- No.
- It starts with "Ca" though.
- Go ahead, I'll be right back.
- Camel.
- No.
- Canary.
- All's well?
- Yes.
- You still have my school-report!
- They're all full marks.
- You were so good.
- I was good.
What should I do with this?
- I'll put it in a drawer.
- No.
There are the kids.
I'll take care of it.
I'll leave you alone.
Mom I don't know
if I can stay till midnight.
- You know, my work...
- It's okay.
It was great to see you anyway.
- Shall I close the door?
- Yes please.
- Here's an animal again.
- What happened? - Nothing.
Adriana's just arrived
and has given me a zebra.
"I'm not in..."
- I'll go get some food.
- Who's taking your place?
Go the other way
or you'll wake up the kids.
So...
We have an animal which swims
into small lakes. It's the swan.
- Resist Sara!
- Sara has the swan.
Darn it!
Don't worry, you have other cards.
Two cards left.
An animal which... enough
It's an animal, a peacock.
Are you leaving?
- There's an emergency.
- Sure.
- Want some "torrone"?
- No thanks.
- Say bye-bye to mom at least.
- I have no time.
- It won't take long.
- No.
- Are you staying in Rome?
- Yes, for two days.
- See you.
- Will you call me?
- Yes.
- Promised?
Yes.
What's wrong?
- The first prize goes to the cat!
- Yeah! Hurray!
What do you say
when the cat comes out?
- Long live the Fair!
- Yes!
Long live the Fair, Sara!
"I'm not in, please leave a message..."
"...or call my office at 702254."
Matteo!
I need to call
the Police Headquarters...
(Tv) Let's drink to the new year!
"It's going to be
new year's day in a while."
"Let's see what's
happening elsewhere."
"So..."
"Get ready for the toast."
"I can see three beautiful girls."
(Tv) "Glasses ready!"
"Anyone missing?"
"Here we are."
- Happy new year!
- Happy new year everyone!
- Happy new year.
Happy new year!
This morning when the ambulance
and the police arrived
a beautiful girl came.
Her hair was dark.
Her eyes... I don't know.
It doesn't matter.
It was strange because your
brother never brought any girl in.
I used to say: "Such a
good-looking man with no girlfriends!"
Go ahead.
The girl asked me
about your brother.
I told her what happened
and she ran away.
- Maybe you know her.
- No.
He was so good, so kind,
a real gentleman!
- Thank you.
- I'm sorry.
Look, you'll think I'm crazy,
but I think your brother was pushed.
- Nonsense!
- Sorry.
- Take this lady downstairs.
- Officer please.
Doctor, is your brother
identifying the body for the report?
No, I am.
- Are you sure?
- Yes. Stay with mom.
- Okay.
- Stay with mom.
I will.
It's time to go.
All these books!
Get some bags,
let's take the books.
We can't take
all of them right now.
I'll do it tomorrow.
Only a few of them, please.
Okay.
Mom!
Please, stop!
Enough!
Calm down!
I was supposed to understand
But I didn't.
No, maybe I understood, but...
It was like with Giulia.
I could have stopped her.
He was in front of me as well
he turned around,
looked at me and I...
closed the door
and deleted everything.
There's nothing left in my mind.
The stairs of his house,
the saw-dust on the ground... Nothing.
The books on the floor, the porter...
I should have stopped them.
I loved them both,
but I couldn't chain them
to that love of mine.
That was my idea of freedom.
I thought that everyone
should be free to live as they wished.
What freedom is in death?
But did it happen?
Did it really happen?
Cause I don't believe it.
I realise what happened
only when I look at mom.
- I'm glad you can stay with her.
- I have to leave soon though.
- I asked for a transfer to Sicily.
- Sicily?
Yes, they need people and
no one wants to go there.
I still have a postcard you
sent me from Cape North in 1966.
It was in Norwegian,
and it said:
..."Everything is beautiful"
with three exclamation marks.
- Do you still believe that?
- Not to the exclamation marks.
Listen Giovanna.
Giulia is in Rome.
I'll meet her tomorrow.
She told Francesca
she wants to see Sara.
- I will go in her place.
- I don't want to listen.
Giulia wants to see Sara.
- Shut up!
- This time I won't!
The date is at the Coliseum,
tomorrow at 10.
And what am I
supposed to do?
Do you think it's easy for me
to ask you to arrest her
and bury her in a prison?
Should I wait
for her to kill someone?
for her to be killed?
Now!
Doctor Carati, Giorgia
wants to speak with you.
Tell her I can't.
Francesca!
Bring her here, please. I'll wait.
How shall I tell her?
How can I?
Cheer up! Come on!
Giorgia, I must tell you something.
A bad thing happened.
I had Giulia arrested.
I thought that
it was the best thing to do.
She made a bad choice, so I think
it's better this way.
Then there's another
bad thing I have to tell you.
Matteo...
Matteo is...
Matteo!
"You force my thought to wander
on the paths leading to the eternal void."
"And all the while these evil times
fleet by, bearing away the horde of cares..."
" consuming time and me.
And as I contemplate your peace..."
"...the soul of the warrior roaring
within me sleeps." Shall I comment on it?
Shall I comment on it?
The sonnet "To the Evening" is
one of Foscolo's most inspired ones.
It includes an alliterated line,
"...the soul of the warrior
roaring within me...".
which is full of "Rs"...
"...the soul of the warrior roaring
within me"
You can almost
hear the poet roar.
Back to your seat.
Go.
Adriana.
- How are your French lessons going?
- Well.
Thanks.
- Your wife was told you're here.
- She isn't my wife.
- But she wants to stay in her cell.
- Tell her the child is here too,
- and that I'm waiting for her.
- Alright.
Where's Sara?
With Giovanna.
I'll call her in a minute.
But I wanted to tell you
something before.
I won't leave you alone.
You're here but...
I can't hear you.
Remember when we argued
before Sara was born?
We said it was a mere formality,
but it isn't.
Giulia...
will you marry me?
Did you hear?
I want to marry you.
Giulia, please.
I want you to marry me.
I'm asking for your hand!
Giulia, please!
Look, I don't want you
to come here anymore...
- ...and don't bring Sara here.
- I'll call her now.
- I can't see her.
- You can.
I don't want to!
She wants to see you!
She was 4 when you left!
Now you must see her!
Please, Giulia!
- I can't make it!
- You can...
You can make it!
Come on!
Let's wait a minute, okay?
So she won't realize
that you cried.
Okay?
Okay.
Sara...
Sara, look at me.
You grew up.
Honey, look at me.
- But weren't you blonde before?
- I'll be blonde again soon.
HIGH SECURITY PRISON
Monfalco, you've got mail!
SPRING OF 1992
"My love, here's something
that only you can read."
Excuse me!
Send it back, I don't want it.
Fight.
Very well.
Sara!
Bravo!
Come on Sara!
Go!
Fight.
I won this medal
in a swimming race in 1964.
- Take it, so you'll have one too now.
- Are you kidding me?
I wanted my own medal.
I was supposed to win.
- I always beat that girl before.
- Come on, eat your food.
Tomorrow I'm going to Milan.
Will you go to sleep at Alessia's?
What are you going there for?
A psychiatric examination
to a prison inmate.
- Who's that?
- The manager of a public enterprise.
The Defence asked for his release
for health's problems.
- He said he's going crazy inside there.
- First they steal then they cry.
How do you know?
I think he deserved it. He should
have thought twice before.
- Why are you so mad at him?
- Because I hate
those who make others
pay for their own mistakes.
Why don't you ask me
what I'm thinking of?
Because I always know when
you're thinking about your mother.
The others had no children,
they were free. She wasn't!
- She knows that and she feels guilty.
- That's good!
- She didn't kill anyone.
- Only because you stopped her in time.
She doesn't want
to see me, or she can't...
That's fine, but what about you?
You write and she doesn't answer,
you go there and she doesn't want to see you.
This makes me angry!
- And what should I do?
- Find another woman!
My friends are
crazy for you.
- Don't you like Alessia, for example?
- Come on!
Well you're quite old after all,
you gained weight too...
You should be careful.
You're still in love with her.
I'm not.
You are, I read
the last letter you sent her.
- You shouldn't have.
- I didn't do it on purpose,
it was on the table.
But you still love her,
and I don't want you to.
I would like to be able
to take my own decisions.
You're right, sorry.
Tell me, was that a fight?
No, you and I cannot fight.
Why?
Because I love you too much.
- You don't say it often.
- I don't say many other things.
- Like?
- I want to go to Rome
and become a restorer.
I'll live with Francesca and Carlo.
- You should ask them, before.
- I already have.
Will you be sad if I go there?
Yes.
I know, but I'll leave all the same.
Idiot.
You cannot speak
or you don't want to?
The Court asked me to examine you
and your lawyer agrees.
Do you agree too?
Just say "yes" or "no".
I know you have a daughter.
I have one too.
When one is in prison they feel like
their children are ashamed of them.
But our children
are stronger than us.
They're too full
of life and curiosity...
to get depressed because
of their fathers' misfortunes...
or their mothers'.
Are you here to check if I'm crazy?
You lawyer would love that.
My wife and daughter
don't know the truth.
I found out myself yesterday.
You didn't know you
were doing illegal things?
You work in a Hospital...
...Hospitals are paid
commissions too, it's normal.
Yet you never noticed
anything, did you?
Maybe you suspected it,
but pretended not to see,
as millions of Italians do.
Then, one day a judge arrives
and says that
commissions are bribes,
and that political parties
can't be financed secretly
and that I am a thief.
Wow...
Now prisons aren't only
full of unlucky apple-thieves.
Now justice is done!
But they forget they
queued to give us money...
...in change for
favours and contracts.
Now they play the part of those
who wanna change the world.
Doctor, nothing's
actually happening.
They arrested a bunch of idiots
like me who were caught stealing,
while all the others
keep stealing undisturbed.
I didn't make Italy.
Well, you didn't as well,
our fathers
made this Italy here.
My father didn't.
Believe me.
I'm sure your father
was an honest man,
and you like to feel
honest too, don't you?
- Excuse me, can I have your catalogue?
- Of course.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
- Are the photos for sale?
- Almost all of them.
"Almost"?
Yes, the one in the poster
isn't, for example.
Where was he?
What was he doing?
Did you ask them?
No, those who took
the picture weren't there.
- Here's her name.
- "Mirella Utano".
Maybe they were for her.
What?
His eyes, maybe
they were for her.
Who is she?
When did she meet Matteo?
- What does she know about him?
- I don't know.
Maybe he saw him in the street
and took his picture.
No.
She spoke to him.
- You can keep the book.
- Thanks.
But I want you
to go and meet her.
- Who?
- Mirella.
- I want you to talk to her.
- Why should I?
Because I'm asking you.
I just do what's right, and this isn't.
Did you get offended?
Maybe you do everything I ask you?
I've asked you to get out of
here for a long time but you don't.
I asked you to go
and live with Elda and Gino.
- Did you do it?
- I'm fine here.
No, you only think
you are, but you aren't.
You have to go out
to understand that.
We're discharging
everyone but you.
You aren't a good man.
You aren't even skilled.
You used to be, now you aren't.
You were a good man,
now you aren't.
The famous European
law to abolish customs
wasn't understood
by us Italians.
(Tv) "People..."
"won't be able to pay taxes."
"It's not that
they don't want to..."
"They already paid too many!"
- Where's the Police Station please?
- Turn right at the end of the corridor.
Where did you want to go?
To the woman
who took the picture.
Why?
To speak with her.
I spoke to the police, everything's
settled. We can leave. Can we?
But I won't take you
back to the Institute.
Nicola, please...
- I can't.
- You can, instead.
- No.
- Yes!
You are already out.
You took Marcello's jacket.
He's still wondering where it is...
You took a streetcar
and came here all alone.
I won't take you back there.
That's the house.
- Are the others awake?
- I think so.
A bus will take a few
of them to work in a while.
- Do you think I can make it?
- You've already made it.
Thank you then.
Don't thank me. Matteo
made you leave the Hospital.
He gave us this present.
- Will you come to see me often?
- Not too often, but I will.
Smile, this is an important day.
Aren't you happy?
Go.
- Are you coming too?
- No.
Take your bag and buzz.
They'll open up. Come on!
- I want you to have it.
- But I gave it to you...
You can find the titles
at the end of the book.
Matteo's picture is number 7.
- Hi, Giampiero.
- Hi, Giorgia.
"Se..."
"...ven".
MATTEO, WHEN HE WAS NICOLA.
How can I contact her?
Alright.
Thanks anyways. Bye.
I was told she
doesn't live here in Milan.
Now she's in Palermo
for a report on the massacre.
- Which massacre?
- Judge Falcone was killed.
Judge Carati,
what happened exactly?
Where are you going?
- I need to speak with Judge Carati.
- That's impossible.
- I'm her brother, Nicola Carati.
- You can't see her.
Go away.
(Tv) "Here's Rosaria,
Vito Schifani's widow."
"She wants to speak."
"She gets closer
to Cardinal Pappalardo."
"Silence!"
"You must tell them
the Lord will punish them..."
- "...and they'll burn in Hell!"
- "Let's hope for them to change."
"You must tell them!"
"You said they'll change
too, they'll repent..."
- "...then they'll be forgiven."
- I haven't lost my hope, Father.
"People outside can
see the coffins now."
"They're all pressing
to pay tribute to them..."
"...to Giovanni Falcone,
Francesca Morvillo..."
"...Antonio Montinaro,
Vito Schifani, and Rocco Di Cillo."
You can wait here thanks.
Hi.
I knew you were in Palermo,
but these are terrible days.
I saw you this morning
but couldn't get close to you.
I'm tired.
We're all tired,
we're all so busy...
- I'd bury my head in the sand.
- You aren't like that...
- What are you doing in Palermo?
- I have to meet a person.
- Shall we have lunch together?
- I can't.
I only have half an hour left.
- How are mom and Francesca?
- I haven't been to Rome lately.
- What about Sara?
- She's really pretty.
She's always been.
What about you?
- And you?
- I'm the judge, I ask questions.
Hello?
Hi, thanks for calling me back.
Yes, tomorrow is perfect.
Where?
That's fine.
See you.
It's not as it seems...
We shall teach
respect to our children.
We shall
do our duty!
respect justice!
We shall fight
against immorality!
We shall never ask kindly
for our rights to be respected!
We shall fight
against the Mafia!
We shall remember
Giovanni Falcone!
all the victims of the Mafia!
We shall remember
them as our siblings!
We shall love them
like our siblings!
We shall defend that love
being a good example for others!
Sorry to make you wait,
but I must develop them now.
We'll speak
when I'm done.
Won't you get bored?
Thanks.
I took that picture here.
Right in this place.
It was different...
The towels were orange.
How long had you met him?
Five minutes.
He said his name was Nicola.
He never told me his real name,
I found out by myself.
I found out on the day...
...when...
I left the morning after,
I went back home.
I needed to stay
all alone for a while.
So you met him again in Rome?
Yes.
A few hours before he...
Sorry.
It's too hard..
For me too.
I still can't speak
about him with anyone.
I'm sorry.
I'm about to leave.
How can you live on an
island and be a reporter?
I only work
as much as I need.
When I'm needed,
as when important
things happen, like today.
- Are you going to Turin?
- Yes, returning home to my daughter.
- Do you have a daughter?
- Yes, Sara. She's 18.
She wants to be a restorer.
- She's a grown-up!
- Yes, she is!
Do you have children?
Yes, one.
He's about 8 and will be
in the third grade this year.
His name's Andrea and
he's as handsome as Matteo.
- Hello, can I help you?
- Thanks, sir. Don't bother...
- "Sir"?
- Nicola!
Mom, you look
like a poor oldie!
Because I am!
- What's this darkness?
- I can't stand the light.
It looks like a catacomb here.
- Giovanna used to draw the curtains.
- I'll do it.
- Let the light in.
- Don't make such a row.
It's a beautiful day.
- Please don't.
- Look at the sun.
Mom I have something
beautiful to tell you.
Something about Matteo.
One of those unpredictable
things he used to do.
When he was in Palermo he met
a woman, Mirella, and they had an affair.
- An affair?
- Yes, a love affair.
Mirella had a baby,
he was born after Matteo left us.
His name's Andrea. He'd love
to meet his granny.
- A baby?
- Yes mom.
We'll catch the train to Naples
and then the ferryboat to Sicily.
We'll be there
tomorrow morning.
- Wait a minute.
- What's wrong mom?
Want some water?
I can't... I'm not ready.
What does that mean?
- How do you know it's true?
- It is. I met the child.
Why didn't she tell us before?
Why didn't she write?
Why do you always have problems
when something good happens?
- Let's leave, mom.
- I can't.
Come on!
Sara wants to move to
Carlo and Francesca's place.
I know, we spoke about it.
Everybody knew it but me!
- Are you disappointed?
- No.
Sara needs to live in a
house where a mother is.
- Francesca is a good mother.
- Thanks honey.
- For what?
- For never being jealous of your siblings.
In fact I was jealous
of someone else.
- Of whom?
- Your students.
- My students?
- Yes.
You took them to see museums and to
our house, and checked their homework...
- I thought you loved them more than us.
- They lacked real families.
No one paid attention to them,
their parents never spoke to them.
And so you did that...
Yes, but maybe I should
have spoken with you more.
Come on mom, cheer up!
Don't speak Milanese,
you're so bad at it...
- How did you get used to Rome?
- It was love at first sight.
- It looks so decayed and ruined...
- Rotten and mephitic...
And its inhabitants
seem cynical and impolite,
but they're just full of irony.
- Do you know where I met your dad?
- No.
In Campo de' Fiori, at the market.
He was a costermonger.
He bought fruit and greens in Naples.
You know, one of his deals.
On his cart there was
a notice saying "Spanish oranges".
So I asked him if they
were really Spanish.
He replied: "Miss, can't
you hear the castanets?"
And what did you do?
I bought the oranges
and married him!
Andrea, they're here.
Hi.
- "Hi" and?
- Hi granny.
- Hi!
- Granny said "hi".
If you cry I'll hit you!
- I think they like each other.
- So do I.
By the way
I wanted to thank you.
- For what?
- For letting us come.
- I did nothing special.
- You could have said "no".
Come on...
- Where's your school?
- Over there.
- Will you attend middle school there too?
- No, in Lipari.
- Where's Lipari?
- There, but there's no volcano.
- Are you scared of volcanoes?
- No.
- What scares you?
- Nothing.
You're lucky. I'm
afraid of many things.
For example
I was afraid of coming here.
- Did the sea scare you?
- Yes.
- Why? You can't swim?
- No.
It's easy. I can teach you.
"He spoke about faith,
which never abandoned him..."
"not even when he was
on the verge of desperation."
"Of faith, which comes from
the knowledge of men and things."
"He spoke a long time,
as if he were speaking to himself..."
"...about his own courage and
energy under any circumstances."
Go ahead!
"His thoughts were so clear that
he never even changed his tone of voice."
These are pictures of Matteo.
I haven't been able
to look at them since...
I tried, sometimes.
My hands started shaking.
I want you to have them.
One day Andrea could be curious
to know what his father looked like
when he was a child.
Shall we look at them together?
- Bye.
- Thanks for everything.
See you soon.
- Let's go mom.
- Okay.
- I'll miss your eyes.
- If you cry I'll hit you!
- I'll hit you, you're annoying!
- Stay with us.
How?
There's a lot of room
here, and I'd love it.
- Andrea would as well, wouldn't you?
- Sure, granny. Stay!
Yes, stay.
- I don't have suitable clothes...
- You can buy some.
And I'll have Francesca
send you what you need.
- Should I stay then?
- Of course.
- Mom, can't you hear the castanets?
- Granny, can't you hear the castanets?
The accelerator
is on the right!
There are so many hats,
what should I do with them?
Alright, I'll keep them.
No, I didn't pack
the flowered dress.
Because... Wait a minute.
- You tell her.
- Thanks.
Hello? Yes granny.
I'm learning
the Roman dialect!
How are you?
Listen granny, as regards
the flowered dress...
Do you really need it?
You know, it's back in fashion...
- You'll look like an oldie wearing it.
- Viper!
Why do you want to look older?
It's perfect on me, instead.
- Francesca says it too.
- It's true, mom.
She looks... Remember that
picture of you and dad in Capri?
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
- Do I really look good?
- You look great!
I should wear high heels too,
but I can't walk in them.
Come on! The kids are
coming out of school!
- Can I drive?
- No.
- Please, only this time!
Thanks.
- I like this place.
- It's all ruined.
- But it's beautiful.
- They have to treat you well.
- I'll speak with the owner.
- Yes, please.
- When's the break finishing?
- Slavery's been over
- since Abraham Lincoln's times!
- "Desire to work, jump up at me!"
- "Speak less, work more!"
- Understood?
Teacher, you taught this kid well!
SPRING OF 1995
Let's go.
Observe a minute's silence
in front of this wonder.
Come on, don't
put on such faces!
This is a wonderful place.
- The landscape is beautiful.
- It is.
- What's that?
- That's clay.
It's a wreck!
Come on guys,
a little more imagination!
You don't have enough faith
or imagination. Follow me.
So, I need two or three
good ideas here.
Which ideas? Look
at those cracks!
- It needs new foundations.
- There are cracks in the frame!
That's why I called you,
Micavi Enterprises!
Okay, but you can't
lay foundations on clay!
I want sloping red bricks here.
Like in Piazza del Campo in Siena.
Of course!
- You're always complaining!
- Why? You're rich now!
- You're the owner!
- I'm rich in debts!
- Owners always complain.
- Stop it!
I'd like the windows there.
- I'd use aluminium for the windows.
- No way!
Aluminium window-frames?
Here I want the kitchen.
Look at this wonder!
Francesca wants it big.
Look at that fireplace.
Simply great!
Here I want a bathroom.
Here will be the nursery.
Every room must have a bath.
I count on that.
Here I want another studio,
or even... I don't know.
We'll think about it.
My only problem is I don't know
what to do with these pools.
- Shall I keep them?
- They aren't important.
But the floors need
loose stone foundations.
I want hand-made
terracotta tiles for the floors.
- Do you know how much it'll cost you?
- He wants it hand-made!
- Understood?
- Micavi...
I'm asking you officially.
Micavi Enterprises...
- Can you make it?
- Look at that!
God dam it...
If I can make it?
Depends... If you ask
me with respect...
...maybe I can do you a favour.
- Hurry up! I'm starving!
- We're coming!
He already speaks like a owner.
There's a boy who likes Sara...
I know, Francesca told me.
How is he? Did you see him?
- He comes home every day.
- Every day?
Yes.
He takes her to school
- and brings her back at night.
- At least he does!
- Yes.
- Fortunately!
Is he a good boy?
Trustworthy?
Yes, like you and I at his age.
Now I feel better! Thanks.
- Nicola will be a granny soon!
- Don't provoke me!
"Where shall I put granny..."
- Don't provoke me.
- Come on!
- We're starving.
- Let's light a fire.
Carlo, bring me some paper
- so we can light it.
- With my paper?
Just take it!
Hello?
Giulia, where are you?
No, she's at school.
Hello?
- Can I leave it here?
- Just for a minute.
Okay.
Thanks. I'll be right back.
Hi.
- Shall I call her?
- No.
- Are you coming home?
- No, I'm leaving at once.
- Who's that guy?
- Her boyfriend Mimmo.
I have to go.
Don't tell Sara you saw me.
- Why?
- Please.
I'll give you a lift.
- Stay here, please.
- Let me give you a lift...
Stay here. Really.
You don't have to stop his gestures,
or he'll think they make no sense,
while they make sense to him.
I'll try, even if that
seems impossible to me.
Nothing is impossible.
- I don't know what else I could do.
- Try to understand that sense.
- That's all.
- But it's like decrypting hieroglyphics!
In fact we did that little by little.
Let's have the usual meeting.
Can you call the others?
- Shall we wait for you inside?
- No, under that tree.
Okay kids. You have
to guess the animals.
My assistant Giacomo will mime.
It's not easy...
It's a particular animal.
- Giacomo is a great mime.
- It's a lizard!
It isn't a lizard, it crawls.
- It's a cobra!
- No.
- It's long! So it's a cobra!
- It crawls but it's not a cobra.
- It's a snail!
- No.
It isn't poisonous.
Let's say it has rings.
- A worm!
- No, it has rings so it's a?
- Ring snake!
- Correct! Giacomo is very good.
After becoming popular
in Munich, Paris and London,
our Giacomo will perform
as a mime again now.
This is difficult.
- It's a hare!
- It isn't.
- Shall I put it in your office?
- No, I'll check it here.
- Thanks.
- I've got mail.
The electricity bill,
a postcard from Giorgia...
Oh, there's a letter too.
But there's a mistake,
it's for Doctor Nicola Carati.
- Who's that?
- That's you!
Me?
- Yes, that's you!
- That's true, I always forget it.
Giacomo, will you read it?
- He can't read!
- He can,
and now he'll show you.
Let me open it up.
They used some special glue.
Here you are.
Read it.
Let everyone hear. Quiet
please, It's an important letter.
"Dear Ni-Nicola..."
"I w-wish..."
"...I never had to write..."
"t-this letter."
"Your m-mom..."
"...is d-dead."
"She didn't s-suffer."
"She f-fell asleep..."
"...slowly."
"I didn't write..."
"be-before because..."
"...she m-made me swear..."
"that w-when..."
"she died..."
"I didn't have to..."
"...d-disturb anyone."
"Kisses."
"S-see you s-soon."
"Mirella".
Very well, Giacomo.
You read very well.
Is my father buried near the sea?
- No.
- You must bring him here. There's the sea.
That's true.
I'll bring him here, I promise.
- How was he?
- He?
He was like Achilles. Did
granny tell you about Achilles?
- Yes.
- He was as brave and sad as him.
He knew the gods would take
him. You know how the gods are.
They send their favourite ones
here, then take them back.
But before that, they
make them leave a trace,
so we can't forget them.
That trace is you.
This morning when you
were checking the atlas,
you looked like him
when he was your age.
We checked an atlas too a long
time ago. We wanted to have a journey.
We wanted to go to a far away
place where there's only the sea.
- That place's name is Cape North.
- Where is it?
Over there.
- Did you reach it?
- I tried but I couldn't.
Your father wanted to,
but in the end he didn't.
The gods were calling him.
Yes, they were.
Why don't you stay
a few more days?
I can't, I have to leave tonight.
I need to check up
the kids tomorrow.
- But I don't want to leave.
- Then stay, I'll take you to France.
Or Greece or Africa. You can choose.
Choose!
- Shall we meet again in three years now?
- No.
It's good for me
to see you and Andrea.
SPRING OF 2000
- It's beautiful here.
- Beautiful? It's sublime!
- It's like heaven.
- We told him to buy a house here
- and he didn't want to...
- We had to insist!
- Look at that orchard! Is it new?
- Yes, there are palm-trees too.
- He put them in front of the house.
- But they're still small.
- You got rich with this project.
- What?
You never get rich
with your friends' money.
- I meant rich inside.
- That of course!
Giving without receiving...
They're making me crazy.
Your sister is worse than him.
Watch out when you
speak about my sister, or...!
She wants darker tiles
so they can match with...
- She's right.
- Very picky, though.
- Your car seems tired.
- It's old. Like us.
Carlo!
- Francesca?
- There's no one here.
Please notice...
- Notice that shape.
- It's an absolute wonder.
- The garden is my favourite.
- Look at that wonder...
Sara?
- So your daughter's getting married.
- Yes.
- Are you happy?
Did he ask
you for her hand?
Of course he did,
with respect too.
- I said yes because he's a good guy.
- Good.
- He should have his hair cut.
- You're right.
There's so much room!
That's great!
Look... great work
of a great artisan.
You remind me of Brunelleschi
or Leon Battista Alberti.
- Look.
- "One day all this will be yours."
- Thanks.
- Let's have a swim.
- A swim?
- Didn't you bring your bikini?
With this belly?
- Wear a one piece suit then.
- I only have a tanga, but it...
- I'm so glad you came here.
- We're happy too.
- This place is beautiful.
- In fact I wanted you to see it.
How are you?
- Fine thanks. How are you?
- Fine.
Are you happy that your
daughter is getting married?
Yes, very much.
- Are you happy?
- Yes.
Is everything okay?
- Good.
- I'll go to speak with your son.
- I'll leave you two alone.
- See you later.
- Yes.
- Bye.
So?
- How are you?
- Dunno.
Nice answer, short and concise.
- What's with that beard?
- Do I look good?
Does the girl you love like it?
- I don't know.
- Ask her.
What's she like?
- Is she pretty?
- Very much.
Did you tell her?
- It's not easy.
- I know.
You have to tell her all the same.
Tell her she's pretty,
and that you are as well.
What do you mean?
You are, we only have
to see if a beard fits you.
- Is she a witty girl?
- I don't think so.
- Let's switch to B plan then.
- Shall I jump on her?
Hey I can't say
that to my nephew!
- What's her name?
- Ermione.
- Ermione?
- Yes.
Then jump on her.
- I can't.
- I know.
- Let go of me!
- No way!
Here they are!
- Nice curls...
- Leave him be!
Okay, I will.
I have to talk to you.
Come.
What happened?
Sara, my love, I've worked in a
Record Office in Florence for a while now.
A few days ago I found a
1966 newspaper with a picture.
I thought you'd like to see
the way your parents were.
We were two cheerful people
who wanted you very much.
All the sad things came later,
and it was never your fault.
I'm trying to start over.
Away from everyone.
I don't want to bother
anyone with my presence.
I received it two days ago.
- Is that you with mom?
- Yes.
Florence, 1966.
What should I do?
It depends on
how strong you feel.
- Are you happy?
- Of course I am.
Then it's time
for you to be generous.
Bye.
- Bye.
Mom!
Giulia?
Mom...
- Mom, is there a bed in your place?
- There's mine, but it's small.
It doesn't matter,
I'd like to stay.
Okay.
- Hi, can you take a picture of us?
- Sure.
Squeeze up.
Good. Say "cheese".
- Done.
- Thanks.
Shall we look for something
nice for the new house?
We could go to...
There are many nice things here.
This could be a container
for bread, but I don't like it.
Those can be nice plates. No.
I want something special,
with more colours.
- What's that?
- It's a hat block.
- Can we have a look around?
- Of course.
Thanks.
That's the "Maestro" of
Santo Spirito. It was painted
by the sons of Domenico del
Mazziere, Agnolo and Donnino.
Donnino is more talented,
I think he painted the baby.
See how it...
This is wonderful, It's the "Maestro
della Conversazione" of Santo Spirito.
This is one of the best
works by Maso di Bianco.
It's my favourite work.
All those Madonnas with the Baby!
Why do you like them so much?
- Are you pregnant?
- I still haven't told anyone.
- What can I do for you?
- There is something.
- What?
- Play for me.
- Where?
- There's an organ here.
I haven't played
for so long... I can't do it.
And we're in a Church,
you need the authorisation.
Never mind then.
I only asked you for a thing
and you won't do it because
you need the authorisation.
You wanted to change the world
and now you need a permission to play.
Come on. Let's go to bed.
- Stirrup cup?
- No.
I'm in a coma.
I do not drink.
- Get up.
- Help me.
- Slowly.
- Careful.
Watch out!
- This way?
- No, that way.
By the way you...
...should understand something.
- Can I say it?
- Yes.
Then I'll say it.
Stop thinking of Matteo
as of an obstacle.
Otherwise you'll
end up hating him.
- What does that mean? Are you drunk?
- Yes. Goodnight.
However...
However.
It's too dark!
Don't worry.
- There was a door here?
- You built this house.
- So you won't come for the wedding?
- No.
I'll come to see you
when you have the baby.
- Promised?
- Yes.
Good.
Do you always wear those?
Sunglasses? Yes.
You're prettier
without them.
- Bye.
- Bye honey.
- Hi.
- Morning.
- Want some coffee?
- Yes please.
- Did you have breakfast?
- Yes. Milk?
Yes.
- Did you sleep in your clothes?
- I didn't sleep.
- Something worries you?
- No.
- Sara, maybe?
- Not at all.
That day on the boat,
I wanted to kiss you.
Me too.
NORWAY - SPRING OF 2003
Dear uncle. Or should I call you "dad"?
Dear Nicola,
we arrived at last!
I can almost recognise the places
you told me about when I was a child.
Maybe it's just my imagination.
It's good to do something
with the people you love,
even if sometimes I have
to do what Ermione wants.
Why? Come here!
Where are you going?
Come on! Please come here.
I convinced her to catch
a mail plane to Cape North.
She's scared but
we'll spare three days.
I look at the midnight
sun which goes down,
then stops without
sinking into the sea.
I think of my father,
of mom and you.
You always said that everything's
beautiful, and I think you're right.
Everything's really beautiful!
# Fixed and translated: lyliakar #
# Special thanks to Petrie,
BaalsEngeltje and matopotato #
# for their kindest collaboration #