Here I go!
Hm?
Makoto, throw the ball already!
Say, did you hear something just now?
Did you hear?
Hear what?
Huh?
Hey, Makoto!
Here goes!
There!
Whoa!
Ah, damn it.
Got it!
Yesterday...
My pudding...
I didn't get to eat it.
What's that about pudding?
Your sister probably ate it again.
And I especially saved it for later!
She shouldn't have eaten it... Stupid sister!
Uh-oh, there we go.
I did it again...
Big sis?
Big sis!
Huh?
Makoto! Makoto!
Up! Look up!
Up?
Ouch!
Get up already.
Why did you turn off my alarm?!
You did it yourself. I'm off!
Take care!
Today, July 13th, is known as NICE day.
Oh, no!
What does that mean?
From 7(NAna)-1(Ichi)-3(San), you get NICE(na-i-su).
You're finally up, Makoto?
Morning, Dad.
Mornin'.
I'm off.
Makoto, wait, wait, wait.
What?
Take these to Auntie Witch on the way back. Tell her they're from Grandma.
I don't want to carry this stuff to school!
And also...
Ask her when she's finally going to get married.
Good.
I'm off!
Take care.
Oh, Mako-chan, good morning!
Good morning!
Yeah... Sorry about the ruckus every morning.
Chiaki!
Oh, Makoto.
You should give yourself some more time to get to school.
Like you're one to talk!
Slept in again, I bet.
Shut up!
What's in the basket?
None of your business!
Why? Tell me!
Barely on time again?
You'd probably feel a lot better if you just came in late.
You're early, Kousuke. Did you forget to jerk off this morning?
Shut up! You guys are just too late.
I wasn't "barely on time". Look.
We're in luck today.
I'm in luck today.
What's that supposed to mean?
"When you're out of luck, nothing goes right". I thought that didn't apply to me.
Since I'm more lucky than not.
Okay, guess why the teacher was late.
A quiz?!
Yes, Hayakawa, correct!
Still, I'm more lucky than not.
I have good luck and intuition.
Thanks to that, my marks aren't too shabby.
I'm not exactly smart, but you couldn't call me stupid.
Five minutes left!
Couldn't call me stupid...
Five minutes left.
That was an exception.
[ Tempura ]
I'm not great with my hands, but I'm not clumsy enough to be laughed at.
I also don't make too many blunders that need to be erased from my memory.
What are you doing, stupid! The extinguisher!
Takase-kun, extinguisher!
Y-Yes!
That was also an exception.
Are you okay?
Singed my bangs a bit.
I'm usually pretty careful, so I've never been seriously injured.
The same goes for complex human relations...
H-Hey!
Aw geez!
What the heck is this!
Why you!
I don't think blood-type fortune telling matters here.
But it says extremely bad luck. Isn't that risky?
She's the one who gets to decide if it's risky or not.
[ Try harder ]
Try harder
Makoto.
What?
Did you decide between sciences or humanities?
Not yet. You?
Nope.
That's good.
Can't make up your mind right away, yeah?
Who knows what'll happen in the future?
It never ends...
Hey, Makoto!
How long are you gonna be?
Why don't you help then?
Yeah, right.
Hurry up!
What will Chiaki-kun go with?
Probably sciences. He can't read kanji.
He's amazing at math.
And only math.
And why are we talking about him?
Hey, the questionnaires are still here! Who's on duty today?
Who is it?
You, of course!
What a pain...
"Time waits for no-"
Huh?
Hm?
I thought someone was here...
A locked room mystery...
What's that...
You're such a moron. My stomach hurts!
You're laughing way too hard.
Yeah, you are.
But it's hilarious!
It's not.
Want to get a CT scan at our hospital?
I'm fine.
Be careful. Something might happen again.
It won't. I won't have it.
But stuff doesn't usually fall on its own, yeah?
It didn't fall on its own! Someone was there!
Someone?
Who?
You?...
Why would I knock you over?
So I'm the culprit now?
Then who?
Man, it's hot.
It's almost summer break. Hang in there.
That's right! Summer break! The three of us should go somewhere!
Like where?
Let's go to a night game.
We just went last month. You only have baseball in your head.
Where then?
Like the beach.
It's too hot.
Then fireworks. In yukatas!
I don't have one.
Kousuke, where do you want to go?
The library.
To study hard.
If you keep studying in this heat, you'll go crazy.
You guys slack too much.
We're not trying to get into med school or anything.
So what are you going to do?
A hotel tycoon.
Or maybe an oil magnate.
Be serious about it!
Say.
What are you going to do, Chiaki?
Me?
I'll...
You two should do some serious thinking.
Going home?
Gotta run some errands for Mom.
Don't be like that. You're leaving me alone with this guy?
Bye. See you.
Hey. Hey!
Come on.
The dwarves are about to pop up!
Sheesh.
Hey! Are you blind or something?!
I'm sorry!
If today...
If today were a normal day, there wouldn't have been any problems.
But...
I'd forgotten that today was an extremely unlucky day.
It's crazy... but I'm going to die.
This is it.
If I had known, I would have gotten up earlier.
I wouldn't have slept in. Wouldn't have been late.
Done a better job on my tempura.
Avoid being knocked over by stupid boys.
And today was supposed to be NICE day...
Hey! Are you blind or something?!
Apologize! Apologize this very instant!
I'm sorry!
Do you know why you've got eyes on the front of your head? To see where're you going! Got it?!
Yes! I'm very sorry.
Honestly, sheesh...
Mama, look!
Oh, it's already that late.
How...?
How?!
Yes.
Yoshiyama-san.
Don't be so anxious, she'll be here soon.
Makoto!
Auntie!
Auntie Witch!
Am I alive? I'm alive, right?
I don't look strange anywhere, right?!
Your bangs look strange.
That was a time leap.
Time leap?!
You were about to be hit by a train?
You were thrown off your bike?
But before you knew it, you'd gone back to a slightly earlier time.
Yes!
That's a time leap.
Time is irreversible, you know.
Irreversible?
You can't reverse the flow of time.
Which means that you were the one who went back in time.
You traveled through time and returned to the past.
Really?
It's not that rare. Many girls do it at your age.
No, no, no way. Never.
It happened to me, too.
For real?!
For example, on Sunday I would sleep in late.
And then I'd think, "I don't feel like doing anything today," you know?
And before I knew it, it was already night. That gave me a start!
Where did my precious Sunday go?
Listen seriously. I'm being serious here.
Aren't you glad you're alive?
Try to look a little happier?
Hey.
Help me here.
Yes.
Show me how you did it.
As if I could!
If you learn the trick, you can do it again.
I can't, I tell you!
But you actually leaped, didn't you?
Like this?
Yes. Hold it there.
What? Earthquake?
Big sis, no! Don't!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It was all my fault.
Why are you doing this? Because I ate your pudding?
Wh-Why what?
Big sis, don't die!
I won't.
Where are you going?
To the convenience store!
If you want pudding, I'll go buy it for you,
No need. Don't worry.
Are you mad?
I'm not.
You really aren't?
Yes, really.
Damn!
Awesome!
It's impossible to travel through time.
You can't just leap. No way.
I could never do something like that.
Here I...
...go!
Ouch, ouch!
Where am I?
Oh, back home.
Pudding...
My pudding's here. Which means...
Tuesday, July 12th.
Today, Japanese Standard Time...
Wasn't there some pudding?
Can I have it?
Isn't it your sister's?
She'll probably have something to eat with Kousuke-kun and Chiaki-kun.
I can? Yay!
No, you can't! It's mine!
Makoto?
You're home?
Ouch...
The pudding! Where is it?
Gone...
You saw?
Yeah, I saw!
Eh, what is it?
That girl just did an awesome jump.
She sure did.
And she disappeared for a moment.
How could she do that?
He's starting to tell tales again.
I'm not lying! I saw it!
Did I... leap?
Great!
This...
...is not a dream.
I can leap. I can!
I'm off!
Take care!
Take care.
What time is it?!
Why?
So, why is today, July 13th, known as NICE day?
Good morning!
Morning!
Mornin'.
Huh?
Barely on time again?
You'd probably feel a lot better if you just came in late.
You're early, Kousuke. Did you forget to jerk off this morn-
Stop babbling. Make sure you wake up early.
What? Why are you early today?
I'm done!
Takase-kun.
Let's switch groups.
Sure, but why?
Don't panic! Turn off the gas!
Takase-kun, extinguisher!
Y-Yes!
Takase, you jerk! I'll remember that!
Sorry...
Say, about Chiaki-kun...
I don't have time for that right now.
What?
Y-You okay?
[ Excellent! ]
Makoto, did you decide between sciences or humanities?
Maybe I should try going overseas.
What's that?
Like a student exchange or something?
What are you saying? You failed the English level 3!
Aw, come on. Time waits for no one!
Hey, Makoto!
Yo!
A melon soda and two colas.
Why karaoke instead of baseball?
We can do that after karaoke.
I refuse to follow a tight schedule.
Time waits for no one, time waits for no one...
Yes.
Your time is up in five minutes.
We'll be leaving then.
Time's up?
A melon soda and two colas.
Why karaoke instead of baseball?
What're you doing, Makoto?
Nothing.
Actually, I tripped.
Tripped how? And weren't you sitting here a second ago?!
Who cares. Sing on!
Time waits for no one, time waits for no one...
Yes.
Your time is up in five minutes.
We'll...
Yes, we'll be leaving then...
Not!
What're you doing, Makoto?
I tripped.
Tripped how? And weren't you sitting here a second ago?!
I'm not done yet! I'm gonna sing a hundred songs!
Ah, excuse me. A melon soda, a cola and a ginger ale.
I'm back...
What happened to your voice?
Karaoke.
How much did you sing to do that to your voice?
About ten hours.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm beat... What's for dinner?
Chicken stew.
Let's do teppanyaki or something!
We had it the day before yesterday.
Come on, teppanyaki!
Stop moaning. How about coming home earlier and helping?
W-What happened?
Nothing.
This is it! Let's dig in!
How do you catch my batted balls?! Damn!
Yeah, how do you catch them with that form?
Again?!
How can you read my pitches?!
There's nothing I can't read!
I can see it all!
One person will win every time!
À Tes Souhaits? That's quite a treat.
Don't worry. It's to show my appreciation for all the advice you've given.
Even if I use up my allowance...
...I can just return to the day I get my allowance!
This way, I haven't spent a penny!
Really, I can come and go as I please.
I can sleep all I want in the morning, I don't have to go back when I forget something...
...and I don't need to finish a buffet in 90 minutes!
Oh, if you ever miss a TV show, let me know. I'll tape it for you.
I'm glad.
Why?
Looks like you're not using it for anything important.
No way!
Time leaping is the best! I just can't quit.
Every day is so much fun! I can't stop laughing!
When you're enjoying yourself, doesn't that mean somebody else is suffering as a result?
Does it?
Who knows.
This is good.
It doesn't! It's fine. Whatever happens, I can just go back!
I can reset as many times as I want.
What's this? You've got extremely good luck today! You won't get another chance like this until next year!
You decided to do it today, right?
Break a leg!
What if she really does?
Senpai!
Me?
No.
Um, it's...
Kaho!
We're going!
Yeah!
What do they want?
Just go.
Stop throwing like a girl!
Throw with your shoulder. Your shoulder!
Hey.
You're late!
Sorry.
Um...
Those girls? Underclassmen from the volunteer club.
What'd they want?
Well...
They asked if we're dating.
We're not, right?
That's what I said.
And? What then?
I'm not really sure...
...but I guess I was asked out.
Way to go!
For real?!
So what'd you say?
"I can't".
How mean!
Hey now!
After she confessed?!
Why'd you turn her down?! I'd definitely date her!
Listen here...
Doesn't she look like the girl you liked in junior high?
She doesn't!
It'll be too late if you change your mind later!
Stop talking about it already.
Bye.
Yeah.
Hm? Where's your bike?
A little something...
Hop on the back.
You're giving me a ride? Lucky!
I wonder if he's really not interested.
When he says no, he means it.
I'm a bit relieved.
Why?
If he got a girlfriend, he would take good care about her.
That's how he is.
Then he couldn't play baseball.
You can't call catch playing baseball...
Somehow I thought the three of us would be together forever...
Kousuke would scold me for being late, and you would make fun of me for not catching the ball...
Makoto.
Want to...
...go out with me?
Stop.
Stop for a sec.
What's that?
What did you just say?
Let's go out.
Where did this come from?
From the "what if Kousuke got a girlfriend".
I'm... not that ugly, right?
You serious?
Serious.
W-W-Wait a minute!
What is it now?
Makoto?
What the hell are you doing?
Nothing.
It'll be too late if you change your mind later!
Stop talking about it already.
Bye.
Yeah.
Hm? Where's your bike?
Hop on the back.
That Kousuke beat me to it!
It's not like he actually got a girlfriend.
That's what you say now, but once he gets a girl, he'll put her first.
You can't be sure.
Damn, with him gone, we can only play catch.
Like I said, why don't hold off on the speculating until he actually gets a girlfriend?
Maybe it would be for the best.
In that case... want to go out?
Where did this-
That's what you say now, but once he gets a girl, he'll put her first.
B-By the way, my sister is such an idiot!
I'm talking about Kousuke!
Let's talk about my sister!
If Kousuke got a girlfriend...
My sister was-
Want to date me?!
It'll be too late if you change your mind later.
Stop talking about it already.
Huh? Makoto, get on.
I'm fine.
Hey, what's with you all of a sudden?
What's with her?
Must be your fault!
Why?!
I thought that you liked Chiaki-kun.
You think that you have to take care of him since he's a joker, right?
Well, I did say that before, but...
Why did you undo it? You could just go out with him.
No, no, no, no.
Why?
I totally can't imagine being anything but friends with Chiaki.
If it didn't work out, you could just go back to before you started going out.
You can do that, right?
There's no need for that.
It's also possible to fall in love after you've been confessed to.
That'll NEVER happen!
Yes... Because you undid it.
Poor Chiaki... He worked so hard to tell you how he felt.
But he has no idea, huh?
Chiaki-kun transferred to our school this spring, right?
He went through a bunch of schools, right?
Sounds like it.
Is it true that he returned from abroad?
Nope.
He's too dumb.
So it's not...
Totally.
I wonder if something happened at his previous school.
Why don't you ask him?
I don't know his e-mail.
You're in the same class!
You're such good friends with him.
I'm not gonna ask that.
And we're not that close.
Liar.
Nuh-uh, I tell you.
Stop it!
They're getting him back for the extinguisher.
Stop that!
Who is it?
It's Mamiya!
Not done yet?
See you, Takase!
Bye!
Man, you're dripping wet.
Takase-kun, are you all right?
Yesterday they splashed cola on me, so I returned the favor with some coffee milk.
If you do that, they'll keep bullying you, right?
Hey, Makoto!
Did you see yesterday's nighter? Saito puts on some mad pressure!
You looked away just now.
I didn't.
What are you up to?
Nothing.
Just spit it out. What are you up to?
I said nothing!
What's wrong?
Konno, you...
Why did you ask me to fry tempura that time?!
Ah, no... I couldn't have known that...
It's your fault, stupid!
Who's stupid? Keep complaining and I'll throw this!
Hey!
Yeah, throw it!
Sorry, it sorta slipped.
Stupid!
What a rude guy. Calling others stupid?
You call me stupid all the time.
In my case, it's a term of endearment.
Come on, where's the comeback? Don't leave me hangin'.
Isn't she out of sorts today? Don't you think, Hayakawa-san?
You are absolutely right.
Why so formal?
Ah, well, we haven't really talked much...
Makoto!
She's not here.
Why isn't she?
Did something happen?
No, nothing.
You probably pissed her off over something stupid.
Don't say she has huge feet or whatever. She's sensitive about it.
I said nothing happened!
Nothing!
Nothing, right?
Throw it already!
I can't throw while I'm thinking!
No good.
I don't get it!
Oh, it's from Yuri.
[ Today something really great happened! What should I do? ]
"Something really great happened."
Something great?
[ What, what happened? Tell me! ]
Yes.
Wait a second.
What was that...
Hurry up, or they'll be sold out.
Today I don't really feel too well...
No way. Wanna go to the nurse's office?
No, I'm fine.
Hey, hurry up! That's quite a sight!
Stop it, Takase!
You're the ones who didn't stop when I told you to!
We're sorry!
If you're sorry, then you shouldn't have done this in the first place!
This is dangerous.
Did anyone go tell the teachers?
Hey, look there!
Takase-kun, stop it! Takase-kun!
Konno!
You just gave me an order, didn't you?!
I-I didn't!
You did!
What?
Why? Damn, dammit!
Damn it all!
Stop it!
Takase!
S-S-Sto-
Chiaki!
Whoa, that was a really bad sound.
What year are you in?
Quickly, get a teacher!
Where's a teacher?
I'm not my fault! I... I...!
Yuri! Yuri?
Are you all right?!
Don't cry. It's not that serious.
What if it leaves a scar?
Then I'll do something about it.
Something?
I'll do something.
No boys.
Does it hurt?
Let me see.
No.
Just do it.
Thanks.
I'm sorry, really!
Why?
I mean, I'm sorry, really.
For real, who goes to a nighter on the first date!
Weren't the three of us supposed to go together? I was looking forward to it!
That's why I said I'm sorry!
Hayakawa-san was okay with a nighter.
So you're going out?
Of course.
You okay, Makoto?
For real?
I can't?
But yeah, Yuri-chan understands my hobbies.
Lucky you!
Hey, stupid! Look where you threw it!
I'm home.
Hm, where's dinner?
I'm making it right now.
Why?
Big sis ate everything.
Geez!
What is this? After he said he liked me!
I was about to die...
What is this?
Ninety?
Makoto!
Let me go!
We've been had.
Totally duped.
The world is full of lies.
Wait! Wait for me!
Hurry up!
We can only play catch like this.
I'm gonna drag Chiaki here tomorrow.
That would be unfair to Yuri.
If I tell him you're feeling lonely, he'll definitely come.
I'm not especially lonely.
He didn't go with Hayakawa because you turned him down?
I didn't turn him down!
Oh?
What's that "oh" for?!
Good grief.
Why don't you get a girlfriend?
If I get a girlfriend, you'll be all alone.
I thought you liked Kousuke-kun.
He's the one who always helps you when you're in trouble, right?
He's like that with everyone.
Go out with him.
How did you come to that solution?
You know... If it doesn't work out, you can just go back to before.
I'll never do that.
Why?
Playing with the feelings of others...
Is too cruel for you?
Isn't that what you've been doing because you wanted to try going back in time.
That's how you saw it?
I guess.
You're a witch.
You really are Auntie Witch.
This painting...
You noticed?
Yes, the one you've been restoring since forever.
It's a mysterious painting. If you look at it for a long time, you feel completely at peace.
We don't know its artist, or whether it even has any artistic value.
But... we learned one thing during the restoration.
This painting was drawn hundreds years ago in a time of war and famine.
Why did someone draw this painting when the world was on the verge of destruction?
What will you do, Konno? You're the only one who hasn't turned in a course plan yet.
Konno.
Konno!
Yes!
Don't get carried away just because you did well on the test.
Strange...
It was ninety the other day.
Yes, go ask her.
Um, but...
What?
W-W-Wait!
Whatwhatwhatwhat?
Konno-senpai, we're from the volunteer club.
We have a serious question to ask you.
I-It's nothing!
Lately, you and Kousuke-senpai...
...are together all the time, right?
Well...
Stop!
Are you going out, after all?
Are you?
Are you?!
It was back when I was still in junior high.
The volunteer club from Kuranose high school came to the retirement home where my grandma was.
Grandma really liked one of the members, and told me about him many times.
"He's a very kind and wonderful person," she would repeat again and again.
After hearing that so many times, I came to like him even though I'd never met him.
What a beautiful story.
After I entered high school, I learned that his name was Tsuda Kousuke.
So stuff like that really happens...
But, as you see, she's very shy.
So we were urging her to act.
The other day we finally got her to confess.
Oh, the other day.
Kousuke-senpai said...
"I already have someone I like."
"So I'm sorry but I can't go out with you."
Oh, um, well...
It wasn't anything like that.
"Someone who's usually stupid got better grades than me."
"I can't afford to slack off, so..."
"I'm very sorry, but..."
That "someone stupid" can't be... me?!
And then Kousuke-senpai said...
...that he's not going out with you!
But what is it with you two lately?
It's like the total opposite?!
Please explain yourself!
W-W-Wait a minute!
I got it. I got it!
I'll do something about it.
Something?
Something...?
Something!
Ouch!
What's with her?
Um, it's...
Kaho!
Um...
Kousuke!
Huh? Didn't you go to the field?
More importantly, her grandma said that she's really grateful for your help in retirement house.
Way to go, Kousuke! And then...
W-W-Why do you know my grandma?
How? I, ah, met her in the bowling alley...
She's confined to bed!
Ah, not there-
Call me when you're done talking.
W-Wait, Kousuke!
One more try!
Ouch!
Um, it's...
Kousuke!
Huh? Didn't you go-
Wait!
First of all, you're a coward! Don't be jealous of my good grades!
And that's got nothing to do with this, okay?
Why are you popping out of nowhere to brag? And it's got nothing to do with what?!
Like I said, my grades have nothing to do with Kaho-chan liking you!
Y-You're wrong.
You're wrong!
W-Wait, Kaho-chan!
You're wrong, she says.
Kousuke, wait!
What?!
I have to start with something more basic...
Big sis, why are you messing around so early?
Went back too far! And I'm late, to boot!
Makoto, the peaches!
Peaches!
Good grief.
Oh-oh, it's a headlock!
No good!
What was that?
Awesome.
Don't look. Carry on!
You all, get away.
Kaho!
I don't really get it, but she said to come to the courtyard.
Who did?
Where are we going? What do you want from me?
You'll know once we get there.
Makoto...
Later.
I give up, give up!
"Come to the courtyard"... for this?
No idea...
Fly!
There!
Ouch...
What the hell are you doing?
It hurts.
Oh, crap!
Can you stand?
Did you sprain it?
I'm fine.
No, you're not.
Kousuke-senpai!
Lean on me.
T-Thank you.
This is quite a development.
Could it be...?
It most certainly could be...
All right!
I feel like I did a good thing!
What is this feeling of happiness?
It changed again!
Ten?
Ten means...
One?
No one's here. Am I too early?
Here we go...
Excuse me! Can I ask something?
Yuri?
I thought someone was here...
Why?
I brought the questionnaires for you. Did you forget that you're on duty today?
Oh, right.
I knew it. Really, you should appreciate our friendship!
So, what was your question?
Ah, it's nothing.
I see.
Yuri...
You didn't see anyone on your way here?
Anyone?
No, never mind.
I see.
[ Looks like I got confessed to. Aren't you jealous? ]
Kousuke?
"Looks like I got confessed to."
[ I'm borrowing your bike. Tsuda Kousuke. ]
Sheesh, who do you think you need to thank for that?
[ your bike ]
No way...
Ma...
ko...
to... there.
Where's your house?
Past the station in the south district.
We better drop by a clinic.
Our home one is nearby.
By the way, Makoto...
...on the way here I met...
...Chiaki-kun.
Kousuke!
He went home.
Yeah, holding that first-year's hand.
Gone!
Kousuke?
It's me.
Look, Dad, can you treat a sprain?
No, it's not me.
Yeah, now.
Thank you.
Leave your message after-
Damn!
What should I do? Go back in time?
But it's not like anything happened yet...
E-Excuse me...
There wasn't a bike accident here?
No... I don't think so.
Thank you.
Accidents are scary.
Kousuke? Where are you? Kousuke?
Chiaki.
Kousuke went home.
Man, neither of you came to the field.
Sorry.
I'm waiting!
Say...
I've wanted to ask you something for a long time.
Is playing baseball with me fun?
What's that?
I like playing baseball with you.
You sure suck for someone who likes playing.
All you're good at is brute force.
Better than being good at nothing at all.
What are you laughing about?!
It just feels like we haven't really talked in a while.
What are you talking about? We've been talking since morning.
Oh, right.
You're right.
Do you miss me that much?
W-What? Stupid!
It's a joke! Man...
Look...
I also want to ask you something.
What?
It's a really stupid question though.
What is it?
Well...
Just say it, come on.
Are you time leaping?
You are, aren't you?
Hey, Makoto!
Makoto!
Look...
I also want to ask you something.
It's a really stupid question though.
Well...
W-W-Wait a minute.
Let's talk about my sister.
Why?
You know, she's so stupid...
Hey there! I'm trying to...
Never mind.
I'll be waiting.
How did he...?
Zero? So it really was the number of times I could time leap...
I wasted the last one on something stupid...
Oh, well. I know that Kousuke is fine now.
Yo, Makoto!
Let me borrow your bike a little longer.
Wait, Kousuke!
Ko-
Hey! Are you blind or something?!
Apologize! Hey!
Stop, Kousuke!
Kousuke!
Stop!
Kousuke, Kousuke!
Is she all right?
Hey, she's seriously hurt!
Call an ambulance!
How did she...
Stop, stop, stop!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
Stop, stop, stop, stop!
Stop...
Stop!
D-Did it stop?
So it really was you.
Chiaki?
What are you doing here?
Where's Kousuke?
Still home, I guess.
But he just...
Did... you do this?
You can leap?
You too?
If I told you that I came from the future...
...would you laugh?
In my era...
...they've developed a device which lets you go freely back and forth in time.
This thing here.
You use it to charge your body.
I used this thing to travel to this time.
But then, I managed to lose it somewhere.
I was frantic.
I looked all around and finally found it.
In the science room.
But it was all used up.
But I'm glad.
That an idiot got its charge.
I was up every night worrying about someone using it for bad things.
W-Why?
Because.
Because?
Because there was a painting I had to see.
No matter how far away it was... No matter where it was...
No matter how dangerous it would be...
[ A Picture of White Plum, Two Camellia and Chrysanthemum.
Currently in restoration. ]
I wanted to see it.
In my era, it was already destroyed in a fire.
Its whereabouts before this era are unknown.
The only confirmed record of its existence...
...was in this time, this place and this season.
You just want... to see it?
That's all I wanted.
I wanted to remember it for all my life.
But...
There's no point anymore.
None at all.
You can't go back anymore? Hey, what do you mean?
Like I said, I can't go back to my era.
But why?
To go back and snatch your bike that Kousuke was going to ride...
I used up my remaining charge.
W-What will you do?
There's nothing I can do.
Why did you use it?!
Shouldn't it have been saved for the right time?!
It was the right time.
You don't remember, but Kousuke and that girl died once at that crossing.
A certain someone was crying with guilt, so I had no choice.
I had to go back, but before I noticed, it was summer.
Being with you two...
...was too much fun.
It was the first time I ever saw a running river on the surface.
It was the first time I ever rode a bike.
It was the first time I ever knew how vast the sky was.
And above all...
...it was the first time I'd ever seen so many people in one place.
Say... Chiaki.
Could it be that...
...there was a connection between the painting...
...and the future you lived in?
Hey, tell me.
I like this era.
You have baseball.
There's no more baseball?!
Where are you looking, stupid?
Stop goofing around.
About that painting...
About that painting!
If you wait a bit longer, you can see it.
It's being restored right now...
Let's go together! The three of us including Kousuke.
I mean, summer break is about to start!
Hey, Chiaki. Chiaki!
Sorry, I can't.
I'm going to disappear tomorrow.
W-Why?
People in the past must not learn about time leaping.
I've violated that rule.
So...
I won't be seeing you again.
I'll keep quiet! I couldn't ever tell anyone.
Chiaki? Where are you?
Hey, Chiaki...
Chiaki...
You said that we'd go to a nighter together!
Sorry.
And you said that we'd go to a fireworks display!
Really sorry.
Don't you want to see me in a yukata?
Sorry, I kinda wanna see that.
Idiot!
Chiaki!
Chiaki, wait up! Chiaki!
Why did Chiaki-kun leave school?
I heard he got into debt, and the yakuza are after him!
Really? Wasn't it because his parents got divorced?
They say he's marrying an older girl.
I heard she got pregnant.
What, for real?!
Hey, what happened, Makoto?
He's not like that!
Sounds like he stabbed the guy with a box cutter.
I heard he beat him up with a bat.
Or slashed him up with a knife.
I said he's not like that!
Hey, Kousuke!
Hey! Kousuke!
What's going on...
Forget me... He didn't at least let you know?
Even though he liked you...
Did he say that?
It was plain to see.
You didn't notice?
Well, you've never been good with that stuff.
Maybe that's why he didn't tell you.
Kousuke.
I'm an awful person.
Someone told something important...
...but I undid it.
Why didn't I listen properly?
Makoto?
What are you talking about?
H-Hey!
Calmed down?
Actually...
I thought that you would stay friends with both Kousuke-kun and Chiaki-kun.
Graduate without dating either of them...
...and then end up dating someone totally different.
That's what I thought until yesterday.
But it's not like that, is it?
I first fell in love in high school.
We became really close as soon as we met.
It was like we'd known each other since childhood.
But it was over before we became adults.
Why?
The timing was probably bad.
What is he doing now?
I wonder.
He said he would definitely return one day.
Though I didn't plan on waiting for him.
And so much time has passed.
It didn't last long.
A blink of an eye.
But, Makoto...
...you're not like me, right?
If someone were late for an appointment...
...wouldn't you run out to meet him?
Makoto, watermelon!
Father!
What's with her? No food... Not even watermelon?
It's a broken heart.
No way!
Miyuki, that was uncalled for.
If someone were late for an appointment...
...wouldn't you run out to meet him?
Why?!
It should have been zero...
Could it be...
Makoto!
Big sis!
Don't do anything foolish, Makoto!
Makoto!
It's because Chiaki went back in time!
Then it should also apply to him!
Oh, Mako-chan.
Chiaki can also...!
Here I...
...go!
All right, no talking.
Who're you?
No talking!
I'm Tsuda, this is Konno.
This is a transfer student, Mamiya Chiaki-kun.
A girl?
Not a product of well-breeding, but let's get along.
Makoto, come here!
See ya, Makoto.
Did you hear that? He used your first name.
Makoto.
Let's go out.
From the "what if Kousuke got a girlfriend".
I'm... not that ugly, right?
Makoto?
Are you okay?
I wonder what Chiaki-kun does on his days off.
He can't play baseball all day long.
Yuri.
You know, I...
...have something I couldn't tell you.
What is it?
I...
...like Chiaki.
Sorry.
I see.
That's what I thought.
I passed him on my way here.
Go.
Makoto.
Time waits for no one.
Makoto!
Kousuke?
Where's Chiaki?
Got tired of waiting and went to the field.
He's quite annoyed. We better go quick.
You're leaving your girlfriend alone? After all my effort...
Girlfriend? Whose?
Oh, right! I went all the way back...
What are you talking about?
Um, that's...
Say, why don't you invite those girls to play with us?
Go and invite them!
What for?
Because it's more fun with more people.
Do you know them?
Sort of.
Also...
If you want to use my bike, it'll be 5000 yen.
Got it? Five thousand!
Hey, what do you mean?!
Say "Let's play baseball together", you hear me?
And also...
Thanks for waiting for me!
Makoto!
Look in front of you when you're running!
Sure!
You're late. Where's Kousuke?
He's not coming.
What's with him?
Where did you find it?
No... Do you know what is it?
I do.
Who told you?
You did.
I didn't!
I couldn't have!
You told me everything.
About the era you live in.
About this device.
Everything.
H-Hey.
Like I thought.
I'm glad.
Where are you from?
From the future.
You can leap?
Not anymore.
So I told you that?
And you believed me?
What a fool.
Maybe so.
Did you come just to say that?
Why did I talk... idiot.
The painting... you can see it back in the future.
It won't disappear or burn up.
It will still be there in your era.
I'll make sure of it.
I'm counting on you.
I had to go back, but before I noticed, it was summer.
Being with you two was too much fun.
That's not how you said it before.
Then what'd I say?
I'm not telling.
Why?
Come on, what did I say?
Not telling.
Tell me! I wanna know, yeah? Hey!
It's a couple!
A couple!
Getting it on!
Couple, couple!
Shut up, idiots!
Run away quick!
Give my regards to Kousuke.
And say I'm sorry I didn't do it myself.
And also...
Makoto.
What is it?
There's something I've wanted to say for a long time.
You...
Make sure you don't get hurt when you're racing around.
You know, you've got a short attention span.
Think some more before acting, okay?
What the heck.
That's all you have to say in the end?!
Idiot, I'm worried, you know.
Fine! Thank you so much for worrying about me!
So hurry up and go!
What are you mad about?
Go, I said!
See ya.
See ya!
Why is that?
I'll be waiting in the future.
I'll be right there. I'll run there.
Makoto.
Makoto!
Hey, Makoto!
Really, what's going on?
Forget me... He didn't at least let you know?
And he's leaving school to study abroad all of a sudden?
Don't make me laugh!
I'm sorry!
Kaho, it's okay.
He probably decided on what he wanted to do.
Did you hear something?
Not really.
Nothing.
There!
Sorry!
Kaho, you have no strength at all.
Good grief.
I also decided on what I'm going to do from now.
What?
Secret.
What's that?
Maybe later.
Konno-senpai!
Yeah!
There!
Nice throw!
Here I go!
There!