Oh, thank you, Arnold.
I can manage that.
But I still don't see why you couldn't
wait a couple of weeks.
Why go all the way up to Loki?
To hear Grace Makanga speak,
and she won't be coming to Nairobi.
I see.
Oh, sweetheart, don't bother
to see us off. It could be ages.
Okay, well
It's too hot to be standing around.
If you're sure.
Bye.
Bye, Arnold.
Let me take your bag for you.
Thank you.
Bye, sweetheart.
See you in, uh in a couple of days.
Sandy, he's here.
Hi. Come in. Oh, hi, Sandy.
You caught me skiving, I'm afraid.
How's Gloria? Well?
Gloria's fine.
You haven't heard from Tessa,
I suppose?
No, she's, uh, up north
with, um, Arnold Bluhm.
Look, old chap, do you think you could
stop doing that a moment?
Something wrong?
She didn't say anything
about returning by road?
From Loki?
Well, that wouldn't surprise me,
knowing Tessa. I mean, I hope not.
Dangerous country.
What is it, Sandy?
We're getting reports
of a white woman, black driver,
Found early this morning,
southern end of Lake Turkana,
Deadkilled, it seems.
You think it might be Tessa?
Seems they hired a car and driver
in Loki and then headed east.
They spent the night at Lodwar.
They shared a room, Justin.
The dead black isn't Arnold Bluhm.
Most terribly sorry.
And how sure are you?
It's not looking good.
It's...
Good of you to tell me, Sandy.
Can't have been easy.
Diplomacy, therefore,
as we've demonstrated,
Is the very map and marker
of civilization,
Pointing nations the safest way
through country...
Fraught with peril.
And that's it.
Uh, Sir Bernard Pellegrin has asked me
to convey his, uh, regrets...
That he's been unable to deliver
his lecture in person.
And I thank you on my own behalf
for your very kind attention.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Yeah? Yeah, sorry.
Excu Excuse me.
Sir, I've just got one question.
I just wondered whose map,
um, is Britain using...
When it completely ignores the United Nations
and decides to invade Iraq?
Or do you do you think...
It's more diplomatic to bend
to the will of a superpower...
Andand politely take part
in Vietnam, the sequel?
Well, uh, l I can't speak
for Sir Bernard
Oh, I thought that's
why you were here.
I mean, diplomats have
to go where they're sent.
So do Labradors.
Ooh.
- Ouch.
Well, I think that, no, Sir Bernard
would no doubt argue...
That when, um, peaceful means
are exhausted, then
Exhausted?
Mr. Quayle, they're not exactly
exhausted, are they?
I mean, they're just they're just
No, they are just lying
in the way of the tanks.
No, l-l-let's face it.
We've taken 60 years...
To build up this international organization
called the United Nations,
Which is meant to avoid wars,
- and now we just blow it up
because our car's running out of petrol.
- Sit down, Tessa, for Christ's sake.
- L I think
- Hold on a minute.
Let's see what he says.
I think the questioner
is making a valid point,
and that a nation's foreign policy...
- should not be determined
by narrow commercial interests.
- That's bullshit.
That's bullshit.
You have to take responsibility.
You are being paid to apologize
for this pathetic country of Britain,
And he can explain to us why we've burned
our diplomatic credentials...
And why we're killing, you know,
thousands of innocent people...
Just forjust for some barrels of oil...
And a photo opportunity
on the White House lawn.
Why?
Are you all right?
Yes, thanks.
You were courageous.
No. No, I was completely rude.
- It was just bad behavior, and l
- You were impassioned.
I'm so embarrassed. Sorry.
Please don't be embarrassed.
I'm really sorry.
And, uh, thanks very much.
You... tried to protect me.
Very feebly.
No, you wereyou were
You weren't feeble. I just
Anyway, it was a very dull lecture.
It was a dull lecture,
but even so I shouldn't have
Well, look, can l
can I buy you a coffee or
I owe you a drink. Come on.
All right.
You can buy me a drink.
I'm Justin, by the way.
Tessa. How do you do?
Pleased to meet you.
Yeah, yeah.
- You were quite scary,
but I don't blame you.
It was absolute bollocks,
So you're quite right to challenge
I'm rather nervous,
I have to confess.
Me too. This way.
Oh, do come in.
Yeah, please. Of course.
Thank you.
You lead the way.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Take a left.
All right.
Wriggle.
There we go.
Thank you.
For... this wonderful gift.
How very generous of me.
No, l
YouYou're so
You know what I mean.
I know what you mean.
I feel safe with you.
I can imagine when you were six.
You leading the revolution.
No. No, I was very conventional.
Here, Justin, put this on.
Mr. Quayle? Please.
Please.
Know this lady, sir?
Yes, I do. It's, uh
It's my wife, Tessa.
Sandy.
Come on.
Tessa.
My God, what a surprise.
How'd you get in?
Take me to Africa with you.
What? Roll you up in a rug?
Pack you in a tea chest?
Very funny.
I'd have to smuggle you in
as illicit goods.
I couldn't declare you.
Oh, listen. I could put you
in one of these plant boxes, and
You'd be very comfortable
wrapped up in a little piece of, uh
I could label you. "Tessa."
I'm serious.
Um, yeah, I can see you are.
And in whatwhat capacity
should I take you to Africa?
I don't mind. You can take me
as your mistress, lover, wife.
There's too much choice.
LWell, I'm
I'm flattered
that you would like
No. No.
Justin, please don't
say that sentence.
Sorry. Sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
That's really
Just yes or no?
Well, wewe hardly know
one another. I mean
You can learn me.
Learn you?
Mmm.
Yes or no?
Then l
Oh.
A gift.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
It's beautiful.
- Hey.
- Arnold.
That's so nice.
- Isn't it beautiful?
- Yeah.
They made it for me.
Hey, Mr. Bluhm.!
Careful.
Ooh. Take my hand.
What did you give her, Arnold?
Nevirapine. The government clinic
didn't have any again.
Jomo.
Yes, Mama Tessa?
Have you had your test yet?
No.
Jomo.
If she's H. I. V. Positive,
chances are you are too.
Look, Dr. Bluhm, I really must go.
We can talk about this later.
Thank you.
Take you 10 minutes.
- Woodrow is very particular about time.
I will be in trouble. Bye.
- I'll see you later.
Jesus!
You shouldn't be
wandering around in this heat.
Arnold, stop fussing.
You're as bad as Justin.
If you were my wife,
I'd tie you to the bed.
Then what would you do, Doctor?
That's another story.
Tell me what you'd do.
Hey!
All right.
Now, for the first time,
We are exploring a new territory.
This is a new discovery...
For the famous marine biologist
Jacques Cousteau.
You are a voyeur.
It's fantastic.
Now we are going down, down, down.
Oh, what do we have here?
Zoom.!
Wipe it.
I must keep this new discovery
for posterity...
And admire the new person inside.
You have to go wipe this.
Go and wipe it.
Wipe it right now.
No, I can't wipe it.
I'm completely inept with computers.
- I'm gonna keep it.
I'm sorry. I love it.
Will you see who that's from,
darling?
Sure.
What is it?
What?
The e-mail.
Oh, it's, um
It's just junk some ad.
- For?
- For the Nairobi Hilton.
Oh, my boobs hurt.
Would you, uh, mind, uh
Weekend package deal.
Two nights for the price of one.
Mmm. Two guests
for the price of one.
Sweetheart, would you come
and make yourself useful?
Yeah, I'm coming.
My darling. Sweetheart,
I'd like you to put this up
right in the middle.
Right?
Yeah.
So, um
Right there.
Mm-hmm.
What do you think?
I think it's gorgeous.
I think it's very tangled.
No, no, no.
I meant I meant
about a weekend at the Hilton.
Oh, no. It's a bit flashy
for my taste.
Is it?
Mm-hmm.
Oh. I wouldn't know.
L I've never been there.
Well, I have. I was there the other night
meeting someone with Arnold.
Oh, well, just a thought.
Sweetheart.
Were you just inviting me away
for a dirty weekend at the Hilton?
Mm-hmm.
Were you?
I would love to,
But maybe after... Arturo is born.
Oh, Tessa.
We're not calling him
Arturo, please.
Why not?
No. Not Not Arturo...
Or Giuseppe
All right. Then what about...
Garth Daddy's name?
No, no. Come on.
No, not Garth
or ditto Che or any
Che?
I just don't want any of these
mad, eccentric, hippieish
Che?
Alternative
Yes, your revolutionary half.
I think we should call him, in that case,
Che Muffin Quayle.
Muffin?
Yes, the Quayle genes.
Where do you get Muffin from?
No one's heard of muffins.
High tea by the jolly study fire...
While the starving mob
burns London.
Is that Is that how you see me?
No.
I see you buying the mob
fish and chips...
While you wait
for law and order to return.
And I love you the way you are.
What about Arnold?
As a name.
Hmm.
Be such a nice gesture.
Well, perhaps it'll be a girl.
Mmm. I think it's a boy.
I think it's a girl.
You'd better get dressed.
Move that tray.
Dry these glasses.
- Can you open your windows, please?
Please get out of the car.
Dr. Joshua Ngaba,
Kenya Health Ministry.
Sir Bernard Pellegrin,
head of F. C. O. Africa desk.
May I convey Her Majesty's
warmest greetings?
I thought that Arnold
was going up-country.
He is. Oh, don't worry.
He's not gonna take me.
I've already asked him.
Hmm.
Good. And, Tessa
Yes?
I'd be happier
if you stayed out of Kibera,
At least until
the baby's born anyway.
Um, just you wait until
I'm single again.
Hello, Tim. How are you?
Hi.
Are you struggling through
without Maude tonight?
One of her party headaches.
I take mine standing up.
Oh, how manly of you.
Isn't it just?
Hello, Arnold.
Tessa.
Hello, Ghita, darling.
Ooh, what a lovely sari.
Interesting guests, Mr. Donohue.
This is Kenya, Dr. Bluhm.
Seems only fair to invite the odd native.
Mmm. The health minister's turn,
was it?
So it seems.
Who's that he's talking to?
I have no idea.
Thought your spies
knew everything, Tim.
Only God knows everything.
He works for Mossad.
You've met Dr. Ngaba, have you?
Yes, at the opening
of a new state-of-the-art clinic...
Without autoclaves
for sterilizing.
Mmm.
Probably converted them
into a Mercedes.
Hmm.
I've never met an alchemist before.
Tessa, darling.
Ah, Tessa.
Hello, Porter.
May I introduce Tessa Quayle,
Dr. Ngaba,
The wife of our representative
for aid effectiveness?
Pleasure to meet you.
How do you do?
And this is Dr. Bluhm
from Mdecins dans I'univers.
Good evening.
Dr. Bluhm and I have met.
Yes, it was at the opening for the clinic
that didn't have the sterilizing equipment.
We never met, Dr. Ngaba,
but I know your work.
Do you know Sir Kenneth Curtiss,
Chief Executive ofThreeBees?
- Yes, also by reputation.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
Company here in Kenya.
We're very proud ofhim.
And which of the bees are you?
You were going to show us
the garden room, Porter.
There is just one thing
that I'd like to thank Dr. Ngaba for
The free nevirapine.
He's, uh, persuaded the manufacturers
to donate it to H. I. V. -positive mothers.
It's a wonderful thing.
Shall we?
The problem is,
it isn't actually reaching them.
Some, but not all.
So we've been wondering,
is that a standard cock-up, Dr. Ngaba,
Or or were the pills converted
into the limo that you arrived in?
I think that's probably enough.
If you'll come through here, Doctor.
Justin.
Excuse me.
You've gotta do something about Tessa.
Well, what would you
like me to do, Sandy?
Well, she's embarrassing our guests.
Her and that bloody Bluhm.
There'll be hell to pay,
I can tell you.
Well, the the squall
seems to have passed.
If you can't control her,
you should keep her locked up.
You're wanted on the veranda,
Mr. Woodrow.
Yes.
Are so big here, they'll be best
towards the back of the border.
Hey, sexy.
You look divine.
Sandy, I think you're a pervert.
Stop looking at me like that.
We're to have a baby in a week.
Can I come and visit you
in the hospital?
You want to visit me in Uhuru?
Uhuru? Tessa, you're not
having it there.
Oh, Sandy, come on. Kibera women
have their babies there every day.
It's perfectly safe.
No, it's not. It's madness.
Just Can I just choose
Wait a minute. That looks a good one.
Shall we run away?
Yeah, come on then.
Take me for lunch.
- I'm fine. Thank you.
How are you?
I'm fine. Thank you. How are you?
I'm fine. Thank you.
How are you?
I'm fine. How are you?
- Look, near the car.
- Jomo is getting a test.
Of course. You told him to.
It was a suggestion,
not an order.
- What are they carrying
in those littlejars?
- It's probably saliva.
But that's not how you test
for H. I. V. Here, is it?
They're also testing for T. B.
Why?
When they test for H. I. V.,
they also test for T. B. Free here.
- What, just for free?
- A small extra service to humanity.
They're a drug company,
Arnold. Come on.
No drug company does
something for nothing.
Is there... something
you're not telling me
Arnold?
Hello, Sandy.
I'm so sorry, Tessa.
Gloria sends her sympathies.
What can one say?
It was a boy.
- Did Justin already tell you that?
- Tessa. Tessa.
This one was born healthy though.
Weren't you,
my beautiful, beautiful darling?
His name is Baraka.
It means blessing.
I... don't quite see.
Who the mother is?
Her name is Wanza Kilulu.
She's 15, and she's dying.
Kioko's 12.
He walked 40 kilometers
just to keep the flies off
his sister and her baby.
Perhaps that's the blessing.
Darling, please don't.
Please sit here, Mr. Woodrow.
I'll wait outside.
Thank you.
Kioko, here you are.
You sweetheart.
- Justin, my darling, could you please
go and get me a fresh bottle of water?
- Hmm? Sure.
Now, Sandy?
Yes?
If I tell you something,
Will you listen to me?
Not here, Tessa.
No, Sandy,
if I tell you that that
That that girl over there
was being murdered,
would you believe me?
Tessa, you're tired.
You're feverish.
No. No, I'm not.
Now we haven't got all of the evidence yet,
but when we get it,
If I bring it to you, will youwill you
actually do something for once?
What you need is rest.
Now what I'm I'm talking about
are coincidences.
Tessa, you've got to stop involving yourself
in matters that don't concern you.
You're embarrassing the High Commission,
and you're not doing Justin's career any good.
Justin doesn't know what I do.
That doesn't surprise me.
Sandy, you've got to promise me...
That you're going to act
on what we tell you.
We?
Me and Arnold.
Please?
All right. I promise.
Within reason.
Uh, there's a man.
She's raving mad.
You've got to get her to a proper clinic.
With white doctors,
Mr. Woodrow?
For Christ's sake, Justin,
she's your wife.
Yes, she's my wife.
You see, she's dead.
What did you give her?
It doesn't matter.
Dr. Lorbeer, you have got to stop
testing on patients with H. I. V.
- It Look at me.
- I have to go.
Justin, stop the car.
Stop, stop, stop.
Why? What is it?
Tessa.
It's 40 kilometers to Miluri.
It's gonna take them all night.
We can't involve ourselves
in their lives, Tessa.
Why?
Be reasonable.
There are millions of people.
They all need help.
That's what the agencies
are here for.
Yeah, but these are three people
that we can help.
Please.
Justin.
I'm sorry, Tessa.
I have to put you first.
I have to get you home.
Probably got enough
there now, Mustafa.
Yeah?
I think.
Just the flowers this time, please.
You can spare the weeds.
The pest must eat too, bwana.
Yes, I know. If only they would.
They can eat the weeds.
Look, you should be wearing gloves
with that, you know?
And there's a mask
if you want it.
Okay.
It's an outrageous thing. It's almost as if
it's a it's a marriage of convenience
Shh.
Tessa.
And the only thing it's gonna produce
is dead offspring.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
- What the fuck is that?
- What?
I said, what the fuck is that?
Tessa, it's pesticide.
It It's just unbelievable.
Would you just get that thing
out of this house?
Well, if you feel that strongly about it,
yes, Tessa anything.
It would help if you might explain to me
what's upsetting her.
I mean, this doesn't kill people, does it?
Unless they swallow it?
No.
What? Then can you tell me
why she's so
You have to trust her, Justin.
It's hard, you know,
when shewe don't talk about
- Does she blame me for losing the baby?
- Of course not. Give her time.
Tell her I'll be back later.
Wherever there are drug companies...
Testing their drugs on people
who they think are expendable,
You'll find organizations like ours
trying to fight back.
Of course, the problem is that they have
millions to spend on P. R...
While we work with volunteers
and a few donated computers.
If you're gonna dig deeper,
then most of us have Web sites.
Check out Oxfam, M. S. F.,
Health Action International
Put it in here.
Just mind the roses, please, Mustafa.
Hi, Birgit.
Sorry. More questions.
Tessa never sleeps.
Always time for you, Tessa.
Take care of yourself, Tessa, okay?
I'm very tired. I'm sorry.
I can't translate that word to you.
So you'd better ask that kind,
nice husband of yours
Okay. See you, Tessa.
Hi.
It's bloody awful weather.
You really shouldn't have waited up.
Good. Then I think
you should go to bed.
I'm safe home now, sweetheart.
No, you're drenched.
Look, take those wet things off.
Tessa, come to bed
with me, please.
Yeah, l
I will, but there's, um, something
I have to do first. It's important.
Tessa,
Whatever it is
that you and Arnold are doing,
I'd like it to stop.
Wow.
Who have you been talking to?
No one. These are
my concerns, all right?
- I'm thinking of your health.
- No. No, you're not.
They've asked you to rein me in,
and you're doing it.
It's just unbelievable.
What the hell are you talking about?
I hope you know me better than that.
Your life is your own.
That was always our agreement.
No. No, no. The agreement was...
That my work was gonna be my own.
That's what makes me who I am.
I mean, if you stop me from doing my work,
then I am nothing. I'm just nobody. L
I'm not trying to stop you
doing anything.
Please.
I'm sorry.
I'm just tired. That's all.
Very tired.
Then come to bed.
Hmm?
Will you get me up for breakfast?
I've got to finish my report.
Just smash it like that.
Oh.! Right.
Now if you just put those there.
You want probably to break them up
into smaller pieces.
A bit more vermilion.
Oh, you're just very blas,
aren't you?
You know, just through feel.
No, I wouldn't No.
I wouldn't call it a parasite, no.
You're gonna be late for your match.
Quick, quick, quick, quick!
Kenny, I can't discuss this on the phone.
wouldn't even give me an appointment.
Time was you buggers couldn't get
your tongues far enough up my arse.
What's changed?
Hi.
If I find out that this has got
anything to do with that bitch
Come to my office.
L I've got to go, Kenny. Bye.
Having trouble with ThreeBees, Sandy?
Just Kenny being Kenny.
Oh. Nothing to do
with my report then?
Oh, he's just ranting.
Oh, Sandy, you promised me
you were gonna do something.
I sent your report to London.
Really?
Yes.
To Pellegrin?
And?
There was no official response.
Well, what was there then?
Well, just a personal letter. That's all.
Saying?
It's private.
What do you mean,
it's private?
That's the most ridiculous thing
I've ever heard.
I sent him an official document.
I gonna have to call Pellegrin
and ask him.
No, no. Don't do that, Tessa.
Why?
It's serious.
You know me well enough to know
that I'm not gonna take no
for an answer. Come on.
Tessa,
I'm supposed to keep an eye on you.
What?
Report where you are,
What you're doing.
Trust me, Tessa.
This is something
that you should not pursue.
I say that as a friend
who cares deeply for you.
Sandy?
Oh, Tessa.
Hi, Gloria.
Been wondering
where you'd got to.
Darling, you know,
we really have to leave now.
Match starts in half an hour.
Harry's got a cricket match.
That is, you're still coming, right?
Yes, of course.
You're not too busy, no?
One sec.
Right. Okay.
Justin's waiting for you in the car.
All right. Tell him
I'll be right down.
Sandy, what do you think of me?
I think you're beautiful.
Do you?
Yes.
Really?
Well, you can have me
if you show me the letter.
Ooh.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
When?
Um, when I get back from Loki.
Tessa,
If anyone ever found out
I'd shown you the letter,
I'd be ruined.
No one's gonna know, Sandy.
Put it back in the drawer.
Lock the drawer.
Put the key back.
Read it at once.
Promise?
Promise.
My continent, Africa, is staggering...
Under the weight of not one,
but three plagues.
Yet still the governments
of the U. S. A. And Europe,
At the behest of the pharmaceutical companies
that seem to control them,
Drag their feet and continue
to give us endless reasons...
Why we should buy your branded drugs
at five, 10, 20 times the price.
Sweetheart, don't bother
to see us off. It could be ages.
Okay, well, if you're sure.
It's too hot to be
standing around.
Bye, Arnold.
Let me take your bag for you.
Thank you.
Bye, sweetheart.
See you in, uh in a couple of days.
Tessa.
Tessa?
Yeah.
Inside a car and had been mutilated.
Turn it off, will you?
Certainly. Sorry.
Mr. Quayle.!
- Mustafa.
Mmm.
Tessa's family.
- Yes.
Police were here, bwana.
When?
This morning. They took away
Mama Tessa's things.
Better make a list
of what's missing.
Mustafa.
See? I told you.
They took away the CD's,
the diskettes, the computer.
They came here and took the
the files, the papers.
Just didn't want to touch anything
so that you can come
and see for yourself what they did.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you, Mustafa.
Dypraxa?
Huh.
Darling Tessa, you have hurt me
more than you know.
Trusting you to be honorable,
I afforded you, against all the rules,
An opportunity that you have abused
in the worst way.
I beg you, for the sake of my career,
to return what you took.
If you will not, then at least save
what is left of me...
By chucking in your ridiculous sham
of a marriage, as I will mine,
And bolting with me
to the end of the earth.
I love you, I love you...
And I love you.
Sandy.
I'm sorry to have been
so long, Sandy.
Seems they've been in here too.
Anything missing
in the bedroom?
Her laptop's gone
and her disks and all her files.
Yes. It's a mess.
What's in that?
Oh, uh, her will,
Amongst other things.
Oh.
Seems she wanted
to be buried in Africa.
Oh.
Darling Tessa. Hmm.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
Could someone please explain
what they're doing, please?
Look, Justin, it it's just concrete.
It's to keep the grave robbers out.
Tessa expressed a wish to lie...
In African soil,
not in bloody concrete.
Nothing can grow in concrete.
Kindly tell them to leave,
please, Ghita.
And you too, please, gentlemen.
Thank you. It was kind of you to come.
Hello.
Kioko. It's Kioko?
Yes.
You're Wanza's brother.
Justin.
Yes.
You brought a card for Tessa?
You walked here?
Did you walk?
Thank you.
You'll always protect me, won't you?
Yeah. Of course.
Of course I'll protect you.
And I'm gonna protect you.
Justin?
Hi. You're a million miles away.
Yes, I was. Um, I'm taking refuge
in my nasturtium seeds.
Listen, you knowyou know
that I'm here for you, don't you?
Yes, I do. Thank you, Ghita.
You're a good friend.
I, uh I'm afraid I wanted
to ask you a question.
Rather a delicate question.
LWell, maybe it's indelicate.
Um
Anything.
What do you think that Arnold and Tessa
were doing at Lake Turkana?
Oh, I see.
You know, they did spend
enough time together to give everyone
the impression that they were
Come on, Justin.
You know what this place is like.
If you can't have sex, you have
other people's sex real or imagined.
Who's this?
It's Claude.
Arnold's boyfriend.
I'd never have guessed.
It's illegal here.
You don't shout about it.
Ah, well.
Wish she could've told me.
Perhaps she didn't think
you needed to know.
Tessa Quayle I have,
but I have no Wanza Kilulu.
Are you sure that is the right name?
Uh, yes, Wanza Kilulu, and, uh, there was
a white doctor attending to her,
And he was there when she died.
Perhaps he conducted the postmortem.
Maybe you have a record of the postmortem.
If I have no patient's record,
how can I have a postmortem record?
And we don't have
European doctors working here.
Right, but her name is definitely
Wanza Kilulu,
And I remember that she was
Well, if she does not appear
in my records here
I'm sorry. She does not
I don't think she was
Yes. No, I understand.
I mean, I'm not mad here.
She was in the bed.
Okay, fine, yeah. I'm sorry.
You want money?
Fifty.
Fifty. Fifty.
Sorry.
He helped my wife,
and I'm trying to find him.
I think he lives here,
but I have no idea where he is.
It's a family. You don't know him?
Kioko Kilulu.
Kioko Kilulu?
Yes, a name. Do you know?
Who is it? Who is it?
It's a family, from here.
He's a young boy, about 12. No?
Kioko?
Kioko, hello.
Hello.
Do Do you remember me?
I've been looking for you.
No trouble.
You're not in trouble.
I just want to talk to you.
Is this the clinic
where Wanza was treated?
I cannot help you without
Next.
Can I help you?
WhyWhy was that lady
turned away?
She refuses treatment.
But she seemed to want
to have treatment.
She's a T. B. Patient
who discontinued her treatment.
Her card was canceled.
Isn't that all the more reason
to inoculate her child?
This is diphtheria vaccine.
What is your business here, please?
My name is Quayle.
I'm from the British High Commission.
Do you see any of your countrymen
here, Mr. Quayle?
Uh, excuse me one
May I see your card, Kioko?
I see. This is in Wanza's name.
That's the family
It's a family medical card, right?
Yes.
And what does "I. C."mean?
It means informed consent.
It means they consented to treatment
and have family medical entitlement.
And that treatment is Dypraxa?
But if they don't give consent,
then they lose the right to medical care?
It's not much of a choice, is it?
I suppose they're not even informed
that they're testing a new drug?
- I don't make the rules, Mr. Quayle.
- Mr. Quayle?
Yes?
Will you please
come with us?
Kioko, there's your card.
Thank you.
Why is the child
being questioned?
It's okay.
Why did you come to talk to this boy?
He attended my wife's funeral,
so I came to thank him.
For a diplomat,
you're not a very good liar.
Well, I haven't risen very high.
We know about your wife,
Mr. Quayle.
He was her lover this, uh, Bluhm.
So people are pleased to tell me.
These men you hired to kill them
They rape and kill her,
and they let him go.
Where did you find them?
Well, perhaps I asked a policeman.
Can you tell me what
I'm doing here, please?
We've been asked to... keep you here.
Right. Help us help you.
I'm sorry. Could you explain?
I have not acquired a taste
for Kenyan tea, I'm afraid.
Look, we're trying to help you.
You help us, we help you.
If you give us something small,
we can always say we didn't find you.
Don't you believe I have the power
to let you go?
Can I help you?
Yes.
My name is Woodrow,
Acting Head of Mission
for Her Majesty's government.
This is Detective Inspector Deasey
of Scotland Yard.
Mr. Deasey will be inquiring
into the death of Mr. Quayle's wife.
If you have any questions,
ask them of him.
Is that clear?
You weren't mistreated?
No.
You know whose territory you are in, Mr.
What did you say your name was?
And your name is?
Right.
The, uhThe boy Kioko
who I came to see
What have you done with him?
He ran away.
I hope nothing's happened to him.
Where's your car, Justin?
It's near the market.
Is that the official thinking then
that Arnold killed Tessa?
I'm afraid that's looking likely.
Do you think
that he was her lover?
I'm afraid that's looking likely too.
What were they doing
up at Lake Turkana?
Romantic setting.
Sorry to have to say it, old chap.
But why suspect Bluhm then?
I mean, there may have been others
Other lovers.
If she was an unfaithful wife,
why stop at Arnold?
I wouldn't listen to rumor,
Unless you've evidence?
Yes, evidence.
That's always the problem.
Justin,
Be a good chap
and leave this to us.
There are proper channels
for these things.
Ghita, hi. Thanks for coming.
So why did you want to meet here?
Something that we shouldn't
be seen talking about?
Dypraxa.
I know that Tessa and Arnold
wrote a report
on the ThreeBees trials,
And I need to know
what happened to it.
What makes you think I know?
Because they trusted you,
and so do I.
Help me, please, Ghita.
All I know is that Tessa
gave Sandy a copy.
Sandy? Why him?
Sandy was a compromise
semiofficial.
Arnold wanted to go public with it.
Tessa wouldn't.
Because?
Because she wanted to do it your way,
through channels.
But, Justin, I wouldn't bother
looking for it.
If it threatens British commercial interests,
it would've been shredded.
She could've brought it to me.
She didn't want
to get you involved.
Why?
Ghita, why didn't she
want me involved?
To protect you.
Do you know if she showed
the report to anyone else?
Kenny Curtiss.
Time of the month, Kenny?
Fuck off.
Might help if you took
the fucking flag out.
Well, get closer to the fucking hole,
and maybe I will.
Interesting man you got there, Crick.
Must be the only white caddy in Africa.
Look, KDH are waiting for me
to default on my Dypraxa commitments,
And I have a cash flow problem.
What are you lot going to do about it?
We never promised
to protect you commercially.
You protect me?
That's fucking rich.
A word or two from me
in the right black ear,
a couple of cases of Krug,
And you'd be on the next plane
back home.
I mean, I spend more money
on champagne in a year
than your shop's annual fucking budget.
Oh, there you go
Cause of your cash-flow problem.
You're in my eyeline, old chap.
You're what passes forJames Bond
around here.
Get Her Majesty's secret service
to pull a few strings.
It's what you spies do, isn't it?
Is it?
Never really sure what it is we do.
Don't even think about
bullying me, old man.
I'm not a member of your gentlemen's club.
I don't have to play by the rules.
So it seems.
Call that one in, shall we?
Mr. Curtiss, I'm sorry
to disturb your game.
My name is Justin Quayle
from the High Commission.
I believe you knew my wife, Tessa.
Justin. Didn't know
you were a member here.
Yes, I met her
at one of your parties.
She came to see you, I think.
She gave you a report
that she had written on Dypraxa.
Justin, I really don't think
this is the time or the place
I hope you didn't find her too troublesome,
because she could be a terrier
when she had a scent.
Huh, sounds like you're
describing a bitch.
I'm sorry about your loss,
But I don't remember
being given any report.
Well, that's odd,
because she noted it in her diary.
Then you know more than I do.
Didn't know, uh
Didn't know Tessa kept a diary.
Well, I think Tessa was right then, Tim.
You don't know everything.
I know where you're going
on Tuesday.
Next, please.
Sorry about the weather.
It's hardly your fault.
Oh, dear. We've had some forgeries
on the diplomatics.
I'm gonna have to keep this,
I'm afraid, sir.
- What?
- The F. C. O. Will issue you
with a new one in a few days.
What if I want to travel with it?
Just two, three days at the most.
Are you saying that's a forgery?
It does happen, sir,
even on diplomatics.
But that was issued to me a year ago
by the diplomatic office
Sir, the F. C. O. Will take care of that.
It's just here on the right.
Good afternoon, sir.
Good afternoon.
Let me take that for you.
Oh, I'd rather keep it with me.
Uh, club rule, Justin.
I'm sorry.
No No luggage in the, uh
in the dining room.
Could you just tuck it into your cubbyhole,
please, Jimmy? Thank you.
Certainly, sir. Thank you, sir.
My dear fellow, what a dreadful time
you've had. Welcome home.
Thank you, Bernard.
Any, uh, plans,
or is it too soon?
Plans?
Well, holiday, visiting friends,
The million things you've always wanted
Mmm.
You're on indefinite sick leave.
Enjoy it.
I hear the, uh the snow's
very good at Chamonix.
I don't have a passport, Bernard.
They took mine at the airport.
Oh, of course, yes.
You missed the, um
You missed the recall.
Mmm. The sole meunire's
not bad here,
If if you like sole.
Otherwise have it grilled.
Grilled'll be fine.
Um, no starters, I think.
You've been cleared, by the way.
Thought we'd get that bit
of unpleasantness dealt with first.
Cleared for what?
Um, of what.
Uh, murder most foul.
Seems you didn't hire
contract killers
in a den of vice after all.
Deasey is satisfied
it was a crime of passion
by our dark medical horse.
It's just a question now
of finding Bluhm.
Arnold Bluhm is gay,
Bernard.
Gay men don't rape
their women friends.
Well, I've known one or two
very savage queens in my time.
Do you no good to go poking around
under rocks, Justin.
Some very nasty things
live under rocks,
Especially in foreign gardens.
Advice of a friend.
What is it that I'm not
to look into, Bernard?
Quayles have always made
reliable foreign service men.
Shouldn't be surprised
if you've still got a small
Head of Mission in your knapsack.
Challenging post.
More challenging than
dealing with Kenny Curtiss?
He's a crude sort of chap, our Kenny,
but he flies the flag for us.
He got up dear Tessa's nose, I fear.
- Yes, she wrote a report about it.
- About Kenny?
No, about Dypraxa.
Ah, that.
She expected some action to be taken,
but none was, was it?
She tell you about the letter,
or did you find it among her things?
Tucked into her diary,
perhaps?
What letter is that, Bernard?
Ramblings of an aging fart.
Senility setting in early, alas.
Naughty of her to take it though.
Very naughty indeed.
Yes, I found that.
Be grateful to have it back.
Written under stress, you understand.
Regrettable things said. Wouldn't
want it falling into the wrong hands.
Sorry, Bernard.
Are we talking about the same letter?
What's yours about?
Undying love.
Ah.
What's yours?
They're not so good grilled.
You should've had the meunire.
Ladies and gentlemen
Ladies and gentlemen,
please keep all your belongings
with you at all times.
It's good to see you, Ham.
Sorry about the blubbing.
It's those bloody Latin genes,
you know.
It's the same old Ham.
Oh, no. No, not anymore.
God, I loved her rotten.
And she loved you rotten.
First cousins can be closer
than siblings.
I still don't understand why I let you
talk me out of going to the funeral.
It was the wrong crowd for you, Ham.
We'll have a private memorial service here.
You can blub
all your way through it.
Don't think I won't.
Hire the Abbey.
You can afford it now.
Can I?
Tess left you bloody well off.
Want to know what you're worth?
Not particularly.
Oh, I've got the keys to the Chelsea house.
Thought you might want to stay there
while you're in London.
No, I'd rather not.
Well, it's all yours.
That and her African women's charity.
Said it would get you
out of the garden.
When did she say that?
Two weeks before she died.
Look, I am ravenous.
Have you had lunch?
Yes, I have. A very civilized lunch
with Bernard Pellegrin...
Who expressed an interest
in Tessa's diary.
But Tess never kept a diary.
She hated the things.
You and I know that.
Pellegrin must have been disinformed.
Tess thought she was being watched.
Didn't stop her e-mailing twice a day.
More inquiries than Google.
Look at him.
The boy is two-thirds machine.
I'm telling you, it's scary.
Mind of a computer.
Appetite of a waste disposal.
And what's the other third?
Oh, Manzini, unquestionably.
Those e-mails from Tess
Guido helped me with them.
Company stuff. Boring.
Mm. Ownership, franchises,
that sort of thing.
I'm trying to find out
who brokered the marriage.
What marriage?
KDH and ThreeBees.
KDH make Dypraxa.
ThreeBees test it.
It's a marriage of convenience, of course.
Both in it for what they can get out of it.
That phrase about the marriage
Is that Tess's phrase or yours?
Oh, hers. Hers.
Producing dead offspring.
Oh, this is so good!
Why don't you try some.
It looks disgusting.
I can get that stuff
through her mirror server.
Well, how do you do that?
All you need is the password. Duh.
Yeah, but I don't have her password.
Come on, Jus.
Five letters. Three guesses.
- I have no idea.
- My name Guido.
She used the one for the "l"
and the zero for the "O."
- I set it up for her.
- Wait, wait.
- Give him a chance to read it.
- Lightning tour. I'm printing as I go.
What's Hippo?
German German Pharma Watch.
Keep an eye on what
the drug companies are up to.
Copy that.
KDH. Can we open that?
Sure. No problem.
A new plague is sweeping the world.
In the 21 st century, multi-resistant
T. B. Will kill one in three.
- But now there is hope.
- It's huge, isn't it?
KDH is developing a revolutionary
treatment for T. B. Sufferers.
It's global.
We call it Dypraxa.
You will call it life.
And I call it a blockbuster.
Karel Delacourt Hudson.
The world is our clinic.
It's gonna sell like hotcakes.
- Can you magnify that photograph?
- Magnify it? He can send it out
for doughnuts.
Is it possible to zoom in on it?
Yeah, sure.
It's Pellegrin.
Why is he there?
There's a personal file.
Do you mind if I open it?
No, sure. Go ahead.
Ti amo.
So you'd better ask that kind,
nice husband of yours to translate.
He's got very delicate little ears.
He's dreaming
about his favorite things.
He's dreaming about...
A world without any weeds.
Justin Quayle,
it's time to get up.
Go away.
You're very annoying.
Time to get up, Justin.
Get up.
This is really just not fair.
It's time to get up.
Tessa, just let me sleep.
There's gardening to be done.
Weeds to be pulled out.
Good morning.
Come back to bed.
Oh, sweetheart.
Moral dilemma, Ham.
And the person that I most
want to tell can't be told.
I had a creepy love letter today.
It's not your fault.
From a five-star creep.
You've got to move on, huh?
I've cold-bloodedly led on.
I stole something from him.
And worse,
I made him a vile promise...
That I have absolutely
no intention ofkeeping.
Oh, do come in.
Yeah, please. Of course.
Thank you.
You lead the way.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Take a left.
I really hate to think how
it would hurtJustin ifhe knew.
I've violated his code, Ham,
In the most cynical way.
And the end
thatjustifies my means?
I need this creep to help me
blackmail Her Majesty's government.
Please tell me I'm not a ruthless bitch.
Please tell me thatJustin
would understand ifhe knew.
If you give me the wrong answer,
then I will push you into the Tiber...
Like I did when we were 16.
Ciao, my darling.
Thank you.
For this wonderful gift.
How very generous of me.
No, l
Here, Justin, put this on.
I like it here.
This is where you work from?
Mm.
Amnesty.
Won't make any difference.
That's the official line
of the Foreign Office.
I thought you were like that.
I thought you were one of those
privileged revolutionaries.
- My lady.
- Am I?
These plants If they were children,
you'd be prosecuted.
I do water them.
When I remember.
You say you're all into saving lives
around the world,
But you let your poor plants die.
I say put people first.
Why don't you water them?
You're being cruel.
I feel safe with you.
I can imagine when you were six.
You leading the revolution.
Ham? Hi. It's Justin.
Listen.
Do you still represent that
dodgy client in Amsterdam?
Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry. I only just got it.
Directions for use.
No air travel, no credit cards.
Never say your name on the phone,
or the computers will kick in.
Dodgy client adds,
"Welcome to my world."
Well, I don't want his world.
No choice, old chum.
Actually, I'm getting
a bit paranoid myself.
Look, suppose I posited
that all this was just coincidence
Tess killed by bandits,
pure and simple...
And that you're being
as paranoid as she was.
Ham.
Thanks for trying, Ham.
I have to finish what she started.
Well, look, look. I've got the address
of Aunt Claudia, the old bat in Rome.
If you need to contact me,
you'd better do it through her.
She adored Tess.
I failed her, Ham.
I lost my faith in her.
No, she forgives you.
She loved you rotten too,
you know.
You think?
Oh, yeah.
Thank you.
It seems our erstwhile colleague
has disappeared.
Four days ago he lunched
in London with Pellegrin,
Who describes him as overwrought,
after which he visited his wife's lawyer...
Before going off our radar.
The poor man seems
to have convinced himself...
There was a conspiracy against Tessa
in which we are all complicit.
Lfhe has left the U. K.,
he did so without a passport.
Therefore, any contact from Justin
must be reported to me immediately.
In his own best interest.
No point asking if you've
heard from him, I suppose?
No, no, Tim, none at all.
Birgit, why are ThreeBees spending
$70 million testing Dypraxa for KDH?
I mean, is the African market
worth that much?
Tessa, you have to understand
the scale of this.
There is a T. B. Epidemic coming.
It will affect the entire world.
Or, put into the language that stock
exchanges all over the world understand,
If the T. B. Market performs as forecast,
Billions and billions of dollars
are waiting to be earned.
And the boy to earn them is Dypraxa.
Lf, of course,
the preliminary trials in Africa...
Have not thrown up
any disturbing side effects.
Ich suche Birgit.
Ich bin Justin Quayle,
Tessa Quayle's Ehemann.
- Michael Adams.
Okay, Herr Adams.
She collects Karl at 3:00
from the kindergarten at Bahnhofstrasse.
Karl, here.
Birgit.
You sent this to my wife.
Justin.
I need to talk to you.
Our computers
were stolen last night.
Yes, I know.
They have never gone
this far before.
I can't be seen with you.
Sorry. I've Karl to think of.
Is there some safe place
we could talk?
Nowhere. Nowhere safe.
Nowhere?
Please. Just... a few questions.
Okay, let's talk here.
With these people.
All right.
Okay. My bike's across the street.
Ask your questions before we get to it.
Is it a scam?
Scam?
Dypraxa.
Does it cure T. B.?
Yes, it cures.
But it can also kill, you know,
because they haven't got
the formula right.
Right. So why don't they work on that?
It's cheaper to fix the trials.
Exclude the patients that
have side effects, you know.
To go back to the lab would
cost them time two years
Millions of dollars, and other companies
would have time to produce their own cures.
Okay, next question.
You said to Tessa in your e-mails
that the Kenyan government
had approved the trials.
Somebody bribed them.
Who?
ThreeBees, Lorbeer.
We don't know.
But $50,000 in the right hands,
and you can test battery acid
as skin lotion.
My bike's there.
Stop! Stop!
- Stop!
Who is Lorbeer?
Birgit, is it a company?
A white coat.
He invented Dypraxa.
When patients started to die,
Lorbeerjumped clear.
Is that why Tessa went to Lokichogio?
Is that where Lorbeer is?
Disappeared.
Murdered?
We've gotta go. I'm sorry.
Where can I find him?
Birgit? Where?
Go back to Africa.
Lorbeer's still there.
Tessa, why didn't you tell me?
I could have helped you.
It is my sad duty to inform you
that Dr. Bluhm has been found.
I'll spare you the details.
Suffice to say, the poor fellow...
Seems to have been tortured to death
on the same day Tessa was killed.
Which would seem to exonerate him.
Seem? So what's the new theory?
That he tortured himself to death?
That'd save you looking
for anyone else, wouldn't it?
Moving on.
What is the purpose of your visit?
I'm seeing a friend.
Welcome to Kenya, Mr. Black.
Thank you.
Has anyone seen
ThreeBees' share price lately?
Does that mean he won't be able
to contribute to tombola?
Hardly Kenny's fault if someone
put the word out on him.
Wish I'd know that's all it took.
I'd have done it sooner.
I expect he'll land on his feet.
Give him a life peerage.
Henceforth you shall be known as
Lord fucking Curtiss of fucking Kenya.
Whoever you are, I don't
take kindly to being blackmailed.
Christ. How did you get here?
Safari tour. Via Paris.
Hunting me now, Justin?
You're the one on the run.
I loved her.
I'm not ashamed of it.
Nor should you be...
if it were true.
It's not for you to tell me
how I felt.
If you've read that, you'll see
that I let her read something
she shouldn't.
Yeah. A letter from Pellegrin.
She trusted you.
What do you want for that?
I want to know why Pellegrin
suppressed Tessa's report.
It was him, wasn't it?
Don't try and play detective.
ThreeBees, KDH, Dypraxa.
What's the story on that axis of evil?
KDH is Swiss-Canadian.
So why are we involved?
Curtiss is one of us.
He's British.
Christ, Justin, stop bleeding
for bloody Africa
and show some loyalty.
That plant KDH built in Wales
could have gone to France.
Fifteen hundred jobs
in a depressed region.
We owed them.
They needed help
with the Dypraxa trials.
KDH needed
an investment partner here.
Curtiss and ThreeBees
served us both.
And Tessa wanted what?
Pressure on Kenny...
To stop the tests,
redesign the bloody drug.
Three years' delay,
millions of dollars.
Or?
We're not paid
to be bleeding hearts.
You know that, Justin.
We're not killing people
who wouldn't be dead otherwise.
Look at the death rate.
Not that anybody's counting.
But you were
a bleeding heart, Sandy.
Tessa was your salvation,
wasn't she, from all this?
You loved her. Remember?
Pellegrin said the report
was too damaging...
And she had to be stopped.
Oh, yes. She was stopped.
I betrayed her.
We all did.
You did it by... growing flowers.
How did you betray her, Sandy?
They wanted to know
what she was up to.
I'm the one who told them
she was going to Loki.
- Who did you tell?
- Pellegrin.
But God knows who he told.
Ghita, get in the car.
Get in the car!
- Go!
Get in.
Listen, fuckhead,
if I wanted you dead,
I would've brought Crick with me.
I wanna show you something.
Show me from there.
Don't mess me about.
I'm doing you a favor.
How did you know where I'd be?
I've still got a friend or two, you know?
We're marked men, Quayle.
They've called in my fucking bank loans.
I'm finished.
They want you silenced.
And they want another country's flag
flying over my pharma division.
So, you've been asking
about Wanza Kilulu.
She's under there,
covered in quicklime.
Her and 62 others
who never officially existed.
Dypraxa?
Yeah.
Is that where I'm going?
Not on my agenda.
Then why are you
showing me this?
Let's just say
if I'm going to the wall,
I want a trophy.
That's what you lot do,
isn't it? Heads on walls.
I think I'll have Pellegrin's
fucking head on mine.
So, now you know where it is.
I'm not taking any fucking questions.
What about Lorbeer?
That Bible-thumping bullshitter,
he's doing his penance in the Sudan.
Jesus the healer.
You don't know where I'm going?
You get one guess.
I'm gonna surprise you, Tess.
- I love this man.
- Hello.
I wish you had shared
just a few things.
I love you.
I love you too.
Who did you think it was?
Fuck you, Donohue.
This is bandit country.
Did you tell Curtiss where I'd be?
Ghita's car?
Well, Ghita's
my only friend here, Tim.
I wouldn't want her
to get into trouble.
She won't.
You do have another friend,
believe it or not.
You won't find what
you're looking for in Loki.
Let's be honest
with each other, shall we?
That's a a late career change
for you, Tim.
There's something else
we have in common, you and I.
We'll both be dead by Christmas.
There's a contract out on you.
Same people who did for Tessa,
I shouldn't wonder.
Mine's cancer.
My pain is controllable.
I knew that you were ill.
I'm sorry. I didn't realize.
Yeah. Sandy tell you?
He fingered Tessa.
He said he'd made a phone call.
He didn't know they'd kill her.
Silly sod was besotted with her.
But that's the way it works
with corporate murder.
Boss gets wind of something,
calls in his head of security,
Who talks to someone,
who talks to a friend of someone.
Finishes up with an answering machine
in a rented office,
A couple of sensitive gentlemen
in a blue pickup truck.
They will never know
who ordered the hit.
I can get you out of Kenya.
It's one of the few things
we still do well.
Drop it now, and it's over.
I'll make sure word
gets to the right people.
Go home... and live.
But I don't have a home, Tim.
Tessa was my home.
Know about Bluhm?
What about Bluhm?
Let me tell you
what you're facing.
They dragged him into the desert,
cut out his tongue,
Chopped offhis manly apparatus
and stuffed them where his tongue had been.
Then they crucified the poor bugger.
Pathologist's opinion is
he was still alive when they nailed him up.
Of course, you might be lucky.
It might be in their interest
to make yours look like suicide.
Which it is.
Balance of mind disturbed.
No fuss, no inquiry.
Nothing.
Right.
Well, thank you for the warning.
You've been very kind.
I was afraid you'd say that.
In case you meet any bandits.
I, uh I wondered
if you could help me.
Yes, sir?
Thank you for agreeing
to take me, Mr.
Please. I can't hear you.
Please put these on.
I said thank you
for taking me, Mr. Andika.
Jonah. No formalities up here.
Do you know about
Southern Sudan, Mr. Black?
The place we're going to
is a food camp,
But on the way we must drop
to some villages.
We'rejust about to do a live run.
Take a look.
His name is Brandt,
this man you want to see.
He works at the clinic up there.
He's a good man,
but he pushes God with the pills.
Don't get him started.
Better strap yourself in.
We're landing on the surface of the moon.
Hi. Uh, Robert Black,
freelance journalist.
I'm looking for Dr. Brandt.
Dr. Brandt? Yeah, he's just here.
He's traveling over from the village.
Thank you.
- Dr. Brandt?
- I'll see you over by the tent.
My name is Robert Black.
I'm a freelancejournalist.
Uh-huh.
I'm told that you're the man to talk to.
I don't know
about that, Mr. Black.
But I can tell you what's
happening around here, yeah?
Good.
Meet my self-appointed
assistant, Abuk.
Abuk.
Hello. How are you?
I'm very well.
Follow me. Come this way.
Youse need to go
all to the medical center,
quickly as possible.
I only give the food
to the women, Mr. Black.
The women make the homes.
The men make the wars... and hooch.
Adam was God's first draft.
He got it right with Eve.
You tell that
to your readers, Mr. Black.
It's a philosophy
that I learned from my wife.
Cherish her, man. Cherish her.
One of God's finest creations.
Now I'll show you
what the devil's up to.
Our treatment center.
Pretty crude, isn't it?
Well, I've seen hospitals
little better. In Nairobi.
So have I. Gharan, what surprises
have they got in store for us this month?
Have you checked those things?
Ja? Should be 40 boxes.
Free medicines, Mr. Black.
Most of them well beyond
their sell-by date.
The drug companies donate them.
It's a tax break for them.
Disposable drugs
for disposable patients.
Out here they have
absolutely no shelf life.
Safest thing to do
is incinerate them.
Big pharmaceuticals are right up there
with the arms dealers.
This is how the world
fucks Africa, Mr. Black.
Blood on their hands?
It's how they expiate their guilt.
Pharmaceuticals,
the aid agencies, everybody.
This whole machine
is driven by guilt.
Is it?
And now you will sample
my goat stew. Come with me.
So tell me, Robert,
Do you believe an individual
can redeem himselfby good acts?
Abuk.
I do, yes.
Maybe the redemption
is in the struggle, huh?
God has your head.
The devil has your balls.
So which particular devil had yours?
Oh, you don't want to know
about that, Robert.
What's your paper
really interested in?
In the big
pharmaceutical companies.
African guinea pigs.
Cheap trials for unsound drugs.
Uninformed consent extorted
with threats against children.
Who are you?
Christ!
Payoffs, cover-ups.
You were in Nairobi.
At the hospital.
Unmarked graves.
I knew I'd seen you
somewhere before.
Murder.
You're the husband.
That's right, Dr. Lorbeer.
Markus.! Markus.!
Something's going on out there.
Why did my wife come here?
SheThey had written this report.
Sixteen pages of inspired guesswork.
I was supposed to provide
the missing clinical data.
Testify on tape.
And did you?
This could be a raid.
Tribesman. Nasty.
They steal cattle, food, children.
- I think maybe we should leave.
- Did you testify on tape?
She was a very persuasive woman,
your wife, Mr. Quayle.
And, no, I do not have the tape.
They took the tape.
But you kept a copy
of the report, yes?
Yes, I did. You're welcome to it.
Level four alert!
They're leaving in five minutes.
If you don't want to die, my friend,
you'd better come with me to the airstrip.
Hurry.
- We can still make it.
- What were Tessa and Bluhm
doing at Lake Turkana?
Are you crazy?
We've got to get out of here, man.
I mean, these people,
they kill anybody. Sorry.
Have you lost your senses?
- There was something else!
There was a letter!
Look, you're a lunatic.
Do you know what you're doing?
You're killing us both.
We'll take our chances with them.
No!
- Get down!
Abuk!
Abuk.! You okay?
Come with us, quick. Run.
Run.
Wait. Wait!
Be careful!
Abuk, be careful!
Here!
Hurry on up!
Where have you guys been?
Sorry about that, Jonah.
- I'm sorry. I can't take the girl.
- I'm not leaving her.
- We're only allowed to evacuate aid workers.
- Well, to hell with what's allowed.
I'll How much do you want for her?
- Look, there's $800.
- Don't embarrass me.
You can't buy this. The rules
are made for good reason, please.
This is a child's life!
There are no rules to cover that!
Look, there are thousands
of them out there.
I can't make an exception
for this one child.
Yes, but this is one we can help! Here.
Abuk.! Abuk.! Abuk.!
Listen, that's the way it is here.
Keep your money.
Strap yourself in, and let's go.
What What'll happen to her?
She might make it to a refugee camp...
if she's lucky.
This is what you came for,
I believe.
Your wife would have made that tape public,
Mr. Quayle, with my voice on it.
That letter was my insurance policy.
But how did they know
where to find her?
They were on their way to Marsabit,
taking the whole rotten package
to Grace Makanga.
Makanga would have put it
in front of the U. N.
But someone knew exactly
where Tessa and Arnold would be.
That was me.
I radioed Nairobi.
KDH security man name of Crick.
God, Christ, man.
I didn't know they
were gonna be murdered.
My oath to God.
Crick's going to know
that you were up here.
Going to be very interested
to know where you're headed.
What do I tell him?
He'll know.
He's been there before.
Mr. Andika?
Yeah?
I'd like to apologize
if I embarrassed you earlier.
It's all right.
Do you think that it would be possible
to land the plane here?
Lake Turkana? It's possible,
but you don't wanna go there.
It'sThere's nothing there
but crocodiles.
Let me take you back to Loki.
Well, l I wouldn't be alone for long.
Please. I'd be, um I'd be grateful.
I have one more favor
to ask you, I'm sorry.
Do you think you could post
that envelope for me?
It's quite urgent.
Ah, Rome.
If we have lost in Justin and Tessa...
Two valued friends,
The diplomatic community
has lost a true gentleman
Courteous, self-effacing,
Large ofheart.
That he chose to take his own life
in the same remote spot...
Where Tessa met her tragic death...
Is a sad reflection
ofhis tormented state of mind...
But also typical ofhis discretion.
He would not have had us troubled.
He would not have had us inconvenienced.
Nothing in his life became him...
Like the leaving it.
I have, uh, chosen a text I know
Justin and Tessa would approve.
It's an epistle.
Noncanonical.
"My Dear Sandy:
Your naivet is beyond belief.
"Knowing our arrangements
with KDH and ThreeBees,
"you send me
this half-baked report...
"by some bleeding heart
diplomatic wife and her black lover...
"and ask me to take action.
"The only action required,
apart from shredding the thing,
"is to keep a tighter rein
on your resident harlot.
"I want to know what she does,
where she goes, whom she meets.
"The issue here is deniability.
"If nobody told us
Dypraxa was causing deaths,
"we can't be held responsible.
"But, my dear Sandy,
should it ever become known...
"that we've closed our eyes to the deaths,
"none of us would survive the scandal.
"I still have great hopes of you.
My love to Gloria.
Yours Sincerely, Bernard."
This way, sir.
What do you have to say, sir?
It was a bizarre sort of suicide.
His body bore no fewer
than eight bullet wounds...
From three different guns,
None of which was the one
found in his hand.
So who has got away with murder?
Not, of course, the British government.
They merely covered up,
as one does, the offensive corpses.
Though not literally. That was done
by person or persons unknown.
So who has committed murder?
Not, of course, the highly respectable firm
of KDH Pharmaceutical,
Which has enjoyed
record profits this quarter...
And has now licensed ZimbaMed of Harare...
To continue testing Dypraxa in Africa.
No, there are no murders in Africa.
Only regrettable deaths.
And from those deaths
we derive the benefits of civilization,
Benefits we can afford so easily...
Because those lives
were bought so cheaply.
I know all your secrets, Tess.
I think I understand you now.
You want me to come home.
But I am home.
Mr. Quayle.
Tess.