All hands on deck.
Be advised.
All good. All good.
How'd you pull that off, Cole?
Just a roughneck who got lucky.
I see that.
Hey, Mom. What are you doing?
Thinking. Avoiding the dishes...
- Nice out.
- It's beautiful.
Yeah, it is.
How are you doing?
Just thinking about next fall.
About leaving.
What's gonna happen to me.
Just the rest of my life. No big deal.
You know, there are whole civilizations
that used to believe
they could see their destiny
in the stars.
You feel that kick?
Mom, are you OK?
Man that ramp!
Blowout preventer!
Hit the blowout preventer!
Hey, buddy! Hey, come here.
We're gonna get you out of here.
Hey! Hey!
Get him up the deck.
Go!
That's an...
You're the company's
hero, Mr. Cole.
Those two men you saved
are gonna be just fine.
If your vitals stay stable,
you can go home tonight.
It's incredible. You were in the
water almost four hours.
No evidence of hypothermia.
The fall alone should have killed you.
It's a miracle
that you're alive, Mr. Cole.
There's just no other
word for it.
Is there anyone we can call
to come get you or...?
Uh, no. I'm good.
When I was young,
I looked for a shape to things.
A reason or a design.
So much of what happened to me,
though, felt like an accident.
So I guess I lost faith
in all that.
When I survived my fall,
I began to wonder
if there wasn't some purpose to
my life.
Maybe I was on a
destined path...
...even if I couldn't
see it yet.
Go, go, go, go, go!
You're looking good
in there, Michael Phelps.
Hey, hey, have you
decided on a major yet?
- Not really.
- He's thinking about finance.
- What?
- I didn't say anything.
Look, it's tough out there
and it's getting tougher.
Finance makes the most sense.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, grab me a Bud?
- Yeah.
All I said was he's thinking
about it.
Here.
You know, Pop, honestly the only thing
I'm thinking about is the beach
and what girls on the beach will
or will not be wearing this summer.
- Reynolds' residence.
- Amanda Collier, please.
Amanda Reynolds now,
but Amanda Collier.
Yeah, you found her.
Amanda,
my name is Morgan Dupree
and I'm the estate attorney
for Tuck Hostetler.
Oh, God.
- Hello?
- Dawson Cole, please.
Yeah, this is he.
My name is Morgan Dupree.
I'm the estate attorney
for Tuck Hostetler.
I'm afraid I have some bad news.
Mr. Hostetler died
in his sleep last night.
He was 92.
Look, I'm sorry about
your friend. I really am.
But we've got stuff
going on here.
I got to be at Tulane on Saturday
for the Sigma Nu thing.
Monday night we've got the dinner
with the guy from Chase and his wife.
Next time someone I know dies,
I'll call your secretary first.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Amanda?
Dawson?
Hey, Amanda.
Hi.
Man, I'm sorry I'm all
messed up.
How did you find out?
I got a call from a lawyer.
Something in Tuck's will.
I'm supposed to meet
with him tomorrow.
- 10:00am?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, me too.
- Oh.
It's been a long time.
Twenty years.
Well, 21, but I mean,
who's counting?
You look amazing.
I gotta go. I'm late.
Meeting my mom.
I'm gonna meet her.
- Oh, all right.
- At her house.
Yeah.
- Good to see you.
- Yeah, you too.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- Yeah, the lawyer.
- The lawyer.
It's 10:00am.
That's right. OK.
Hey, Dawson.
Hey, Dawson?
- Food's here.
- Thanks, April.
- How you feeling?
- She was throwing up a lot.
But I'm not now, so that's good.
- She's so pretty.
- She sure is.
You OK?
It's going to be tough, but...
her parents are really good to us.
They don't judge us.
They just want a Bible name
for the kid.
What do you
think about Aaron?
I think it's better than Moses.
I know it's crazy
and we're young, but...
the other day when I felt
that little heartbeat...
I don't know. It made
me feel happy.
That's good, Bobby.
That's real good.
It would just start I think...
But it's not...
Just try again.
Try again.
- I'm sorry. Tell them I'm sorry.
- April, it's fine, OK?
Put it in neutral. We'll push you
out of the way. Come on, Bobby.
What's the matter?
You forget how to drive?
Your dad take your
learner's permit?
Come on! Move your car!
You guys wanna get out
and help us push
or you just gonna sit there
and keep honking?
- It won't happen again.
- Yeah, sorry.
Thank you. Ma'am.
- Hey, we could be friends.
- What? Let's go!
Will you boys grow up!
Where are you going?
Over to the right, April.
Hi.
All right. Good.
OK.
- Should I call a tow truck?
- No, it's all right. I got it.
I'm sorry about my friends.
They try to be funny but only
succeed at being idiots.
- Amanda, let's go.
- Yeah, come on, let's get out of here.
- OK!
- Come on!
- Amanda.
- Seriously.
It's all right.
You don't have to wait around.
Oh. OK.
- Thanks for your help.
- Yeah. Anytime.
Amanda! You're wasting
your time.
Thank you.
Later!
I don't want you
to take this the wrong way
'cause you're my cousin and I
love you, but you are a jackass.
Did you not see the beautiful girl who
just pushed a car to try to talk to you?
She was being nice, all right?
She's nice.
- Yeah, she is. She's also hot.
- She is hot.
Start her up.
She'll be fine now.
- Thanks, Dawson.
- Go on. It's all right.
See you later.
I turn the key and
nothing happens.
What do you think?
Karmic payback for being
party to the honking?
I think the universe
dispenses swift justice.
He speaks.
He's sort of funny.
- Hey, Amanda.
- Hey.
- Try it now.
- OK.
Thank you.
Your battery got disconnected.
It's not major. It happens.
All right.
Are you actually
about to say something else?
My cousin thinks you were trying
to talk to me the other day.
I was.
- He thinks I blew it.
- You did.
You don't know how to flirt,
do you?
Guess not.
Well, what are you gonna do
about it?
OK. This isn't working.
OK, I'll tell you what. Uh...
I want you to think about it
and, uh...
...meet me at Squeals
Saturday night at 6:00... maybe?
- Is that a yes?
- Yeah.
OK. Maybe you'll figure out
how to flirt with me by then.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
♪ I know a place
where I can go ♪
♪ When I'm alone ♪
♪ Into your arms
Whoa into your arms I can go ♪
♪ I know a place
that's safe and warm ♪
♪ Into your arms
Whoa into your arms ♪
♪ I can go... ♪
Where you runnin' off to,
Dawson?
I expect you to say hello.
Hello.
- You're cute.
- He is cute.
Looks like his daddy.
Come on in here. Sit down. Let's play
a hand of cards or something.
No, I'm... I got stuff to do.
I got homework.
He thinks he's smarter than us.
Abee, why don't you take that stupid
goddamn hat off in the house.
- Yes, sir.
- Is that true?
- You think you're smarter than us?
- No, sir.
- You too good for this family?
That's good.
'Cause this is where you belong.
Here.
Why don't you go out back
and tune up the Merc.
We got a delivery upriver tomorrow
night and you're going with us.
I can't go tomorrow night.
I got something to do.
You didn't listen to a goddamn
thing I said, did you?
- I'm not...
- I'm not what?
Hey, hey, come on, Pop.
Let's play some cards.
I swear to God, Dawson,
you are a slow fucking learner!
That's a bad thing to be.
You still got someplace
to be Saturday night?
Yes, sir.
- Hit him again, Papa.
- Ted, shut the hell up!
You wanna hit me?
You hit me,
you see where that'll get you.
Hormones.
That's what his problem is.
You are either the worst car thief
in the history of the world...
...or you have a story to tell.
- What's your name?
- Dawson Cole.
- Tommy Cole's boy?
- Yes, sir.
Well, that is unfortunate.
- What happened to your eye?
- I just ran into a tree.
A tree with a mean right cross.
You got any place to stay?
Friends? Anything like that?
No, sir.
Shit.
Where you going?
That cot over yonder ought to be
more comfortable than this car.
Water out of the hose is good
to drink.
If there's any trouble, anything
goes missing, anything like that,
the next one to wake you up will be
a sheriff's deputy. You understand that?
- Yes, sir.
- Do you understand that?
Yes, sir.
All right, then.
Shit!
Good night, Amanda.
♪ Little Miss, Little Miss,
Little Miss can't be wrong ♪
Where is he?
- I decided not to come.
- Mm, yeah, I got that.
I didn't know how to get a hold
of you.
Oh, I was at Squeals. You could
have gotten a hold of me there.
Do you live out here?
Is this some kind of game
you're playing?
Huh? With your friends? A little science
experiment you got going on? What is it?
- That's crazy.
- That's crazy, is it?
Or maybe you just like strays.
Or maybe I like smart guys who
haven't had it handed to them.
Right.
God, you just don't get it,
do you?
I guess I don't.
You know, I just wanted a date.
I wanted to go somewhere and maybe
have some coffee or some ice cream.
Come on, you know, you ask me
questions, I ask you questions.
And if we just so happen
to like the answer, Dawson,
then maybe we'll go on
another one.
And if we don't, then we won't.
But God, I mean, if that's just
too much to ask, then fine.
Forget it. I'm exhausted.
I'm done.
This is why I didn't want to
go out in public.
Well, then take me
somewhere private.
So what're you
gonna do after high school?
Uh...
OK, I'll go first.
I'm going to Tulane in the fall.
Double majoring in child
psychology and public policy.
I'm hoping to intern
at a law firm while I'm there.
And then after law school,
I'd like to work for a non-profit.
Maybe in another country,
that deals with children's issues.
- You wanna work with children?
- Mm-hm.
You wanna have a family
of your own?
Yeah, I would.
I'd like to have a little girl.
Maybe name her Bea.
That's a real nice name.
It's really beautiful out here.
I've never seen so many stars.
I've always loved the stars.
I feel closer to them up here.
When I was a kid,
I built my own telescope.
- Wow.
- No, it's pretty easy.
Yeah, for you, maybe.
Humans have always
looked to the stars.
Instruct their way of life,
consult them.
You were gone
for a while.
Yeah, my dad made me
quit school when I was 16.
He said he needed me
around the home.
How do you feel
about that?
I don't know. I guess
I didn't like it much.
It was a hell of a fight to
come back.
Is it weird to be there now?
Kind of.
I mean, I just
wanna finish, get out.
Where do you want to
go to college?
Do you think everyone goes
to college?
People who build
their own telescopes usually do.
I don't know, it's just...
it's not something I can do
right now.
Is it something you want to do?
- Why do you care?
- Why won't you answer?
You are gonna be
a really good lawyer someday.
Do you want to go,
yes or no?
No.
You're a bad liar.
I like that.
I'd like to do this
again sometime.
I'd even shower and show up.
How about that?
- You promise?
- Yeah, I promise.
I guess I wanted to do that.
I wanted to do that, too.
Good to know.
I wouldn't mind doing
that again.
Then do it.
Now first thing that Tuck
stipulated was for me to apologize
on his behalf for
any inconvenience.
He asked that I pass on
his gratitude
for your being here
and your friendship always.
His words.
He would like you
to spread his ashes together,
outside the cottage
of Vandemere.
There is to be no funeral,
no reception,
nor store-bought bouquets.
Not a dime is to be
spent on frivolities.
- Again...
- His words.
That's right.
He asks that you pack up his things
and he would like you to go through it,
and take whatever you want.
He left instructions that his assets
be liquidated and that the proceeds be
donated to the American
Pediatric Cancer Society.
The only asset not to be sold
is the cottage at Vandemere,
which he left to you both.
Now, typically, in situations
like this,
one party will buy the
other out,
unless you're interested
in joint ownership.
- We're not.
- No. No.
When he was in the hospital,
he wrote these. Mm-hm.
Excuse me. He would
like you to read them on your own.
Well, you still living
around here?
- Baton Rouge.
- Yeah?
- I see you got married.
- 18 years.
Nice. You guys got kids?
- Two.
- Boys? Girls?
You know, we don't have to do this.
Ask the questions, tell our stories,
pretend to want to know
about each other's lives.
Well, I do want to know.
We're not here for a reunion.
We're here for Tuck, so...
How about this? You go to the house
today and I'll come out tomorrow.
And we'll meet out at
Vandemere tomorrow afternoon.
We'll say our goodbyes.
- Does that work for you?
- Yeah.
Bye.
I'm sorry.
You remember that thistle problem
I had in the garden last year.
Thistle is one tough weed.
You can't pull it or mow it.
You have to dig it out by the root.
While I was digging,
I got to thinking about you and Dawson.
You have wounds that
have never healed.
You've lived with them so long,
you don't even know they're there anymore.
Pain has deep roots.
The only way to dig it out is to
forgive him and forgive yourself.
- Don't you get bored out here?
- Completely.
When are you gonna let me
get my hands dirty?
You want
to get your hands dirty?
Absolutely.
What? This dirty?
No. Dawson,
you're not gonna do...
'Cause I'm the grease monster
from the bayou!
Stop it!
Dawson! Don't!
You're gonna get me all dirty,
you little punk!
You gotta leave!
You gotta get out of here.
- What?
- No, please, just get out of here now.
- Who's that?
- Get out of here, please! Leave!
- Dawson! You're hurting me!
- Leave!
- Don't ask any questions. Get out! Now!
- Why do I have to go?
- Go, go, go! Go, please!
- OK, Dawson.
- OK.
- Go!
OK!
Time to come home, Dawson.
You didn't introduce us
to your girlfriend.
That's that Collier girl, Pop.
You know her.
- Collier girl.
- Yes, sir.
All right, get your stuff,
put it in the truck.
- You're coming home with us.
- No, I'm not.
I ain't gonna tell you again,
boy.
I have had it with you, Dawson!
You're all puffed up,
you're thinking that you're special.
Well, let me ask you something?
Do you really believe that that girl
is gonna have anything to do with
a white trash piece of shit like you?
No. Come on.
Get your stuff, put it
in the truck and let's go.
You touch him again,
the next one will kill you.
Now, I've come here for my boy
and I ain't leaving without him, so...
I guess you're gonna
have to shoot me.
All right.
That windshield is gonna
cost you about $1,000.
And those floods run about
$500 each.
Do you want me to keep going?
Go on now.
This is nice.
What you've done here.
Your wife plant these?
Get in the truck, Ted.
If I stay, they'll come back.
I just shot up a $17,000
pick-up truck.
About broke my heart to do it.
They'll be back
whether you're here or not.
Not safe for you to sleep out here
anymore. I'll fix you a place inside.
Well, come on.
Dawson...
- What are you doing?
- I had to see you.
- Well, come in.
- That's not a good idea.
- I need to talk to you.
- OK.
- Wait, what are you doing?
- I mean, if you're not gonna come in.
- My parents think you're dangerous.
- They're right.
Sooner or later, I'm gonna have
to pay for what happened today
and I can't have you standing
next to me when I do, OK?
- I can't have you getting hurt.
- I'm not gonna get hurt.
You hang around with me
long enough and you will.
I don't care! I don't care!
I mean, Dawson, do you want this?
Do you want me?
I do.
All right.
- Just give me one second.
- Sure thing.
You work here?
No, sir. Just picking up
some stuff for my uncles.
You look a lot like
an old friend of mine.
- People tell me I look like my dad.
- Yeah?
Bobby Cole?
You knew him?
Goddamn it, Aaron. How many
times I gotta tell you that you...
Well, as I live and breathe.
Man 2: The Prodigal Son returns.
You might wanna stay away from
that shit. Good talking to you.
It's been a long time,
Dawson!
About 20 years?
Thank you.
- You know who that is, Aaron?
- That's Dawson Cole.
I thought maybe you'd
need a hand.
Hey. I thought you might
want this.
You can take it.
I just didn't want to pack things away
if you might want to keep 'em.
It's OK. I don't want much.
I'll make my own box.
OK.
- What? What is it?
- Nothing.
Is there something you
want to say?
No.
I guess I just want to know
if you're happy.
You want facts?
I... went to Tulane, as planned.
Got pregnant sophomore year,
not planned.
Got married, moved to Baton Rouge.
Bought a house.
Had another baby. Did some volunteer
work. Bought a bigger house.
Law school?
I didn't finish college.
I had so many plans
and I don't know what happened.
Life?
I guess. Anyway.
Am I happy?
Being a mother makes me happy.
Look what I found.
Oh, wow.
I forgot he had this.
She's a real beauty.
Thanks.
So if you're not going to college,
then why do you study so much?
Oh, wait, I know why.
Because you are going to college.
You'll definitely get in.
You'll probably get a scholarship.
- Grab the stuff from the back, please?
- I got it.
All right, these are
applications.
- I know what they are. I've seen them.
- All right. Well, get started on them.
- There's a problem.
- Already? You haven't even started yet.
They want a home address.
You live with Tuck.
Why don't you ask him?
- No, don't ask Tuck, please.
- Why?
He's private. He won't like you snooping
around and stuff... Amanda!
- OK!
- Amanda.
- Tuck?
- In here.
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
Wow, you look handsome.
Here, I got you these.
They're chocolate covered pralines.
I hope you like them.
- Can I ask you a couple questions?
- OK.
- Do you have an onion?
- I do.
Good. 'Cause we forgot one.
Second thing, we were just going over
Dawson's college applications
and we were wondering, can we use
your address as his home address?
- That'll be fine.
- Great.
Let's get cooking.
- Maybe you should set the table.
- Maybe I should set the table.
Wow, those are beautiful.
Yeah, they came in real good this year.
It was a wet spring.
- These are my wife's favorite.
- Oh, yeah?
How long were y'all married?
We're still married.
We're just on different schedules.
She had a stroke
four years ago this May.
I'm sorry.
There's still times that
I'll step outside there at night
and have a little chat
with Clara.
Ain't that foolish?
All I'm saying is when two cars
break down on consecutive days,
that bring two people together
that fall in love, that's destiny.
Destiny? No, Destiny is the name
the fortunate give to their fortunes.
What is that supposed to mean?
That means that people
never call bad things destiny.
You are absolutely impossible.
Why can't you just agree
with anything that I have
to say, Dawson? Why?
- Tuck, please help me out here.
- Come on, Tuck.
- What?
- What do you think?
I never did believe
in any of that stuff.
But I will tell you one
thing now.
Uh, back in the war,
I was in the Navy,
I'm serving aboard a destroyer.
And at the Leyte Gulf, we...
we took a Jap torpedo.
Blew me right off the deck.
Broke my back.
There I am bobbing around in
the water like a fishing cork,
all hell breaking loose
all around me and l...
I started singing.
This old Irving Berlin song.
What'll I do with just a photograph
to tell my troubles to?
What'll I do? What'll I do?
What'll I do?
Well, after a few verses of this,
this calm just, poof,
came over me and I knew right
then I was gonna be all right.
That I was gonna go home,
that I was gonna...
I was gonna hold my wife again.
Well, a few years pass by, we built
that little cottage at Vandemere and...
...I walked outside one day and Clara
was out there in the garden singing...
What'll I do?
Now, she saw the look on my face
and so I told her the story.
And then she told me hers.
It seems like right about that
same time, she'd had a dream.
A dream where I was
singing to her.
And you care to take a guess
at the name of the song?
Come on. Get out of here, Tuck.
Well, now, I don't know exactly
what you'd call that, but
whatever you call it,
it got me home.
Would you dance with me?
- You can dance?
- No.
But I figured you'd make me
learn sooner or later.
I guess you have a good point.
- Now, don't step on my feet.
- I'll try not to.
Hey, look at me.
Dawson?
I'd like to talk to you.
Four years after Jared was born,
Frank and I had another child.
A wonderful little girl.
She was so full of joy.
Tuck loved her.
"She shines with her own light,"
he said.
He was right about that.
She was diagnosed with leukemia a few
weeks after that picture was taken.
She'd just turned two.
And I remember that day.
You know, it was just a day.
And you want so much
to go back to just a
not-so-special day like that,
you know.
But you never can.
I can't imagine how difficult
that must have been for your family.
We both started drinking
too much.
I quit. He never did.
I wish I'd have been
there for you.
Yeah.
That didn't happen.
That's life.
What was her name?
Bea. Her name was Bea.
Bea.
You've gotten better at that.
Yeah, 20 years later,
I can chop an onion.
- Sorry.
I bet you're the smartest guy
on the rig, huh?
Well, of course I am.
Yeah, you know, I got pretty good
at computer, actually,
and the boss wanted me
to go back to school,
get certified as an
IT specialist.
And let me guess.
You don't want to do that.
- I like my job.
- But you might like the new one more.
I don't know why you don't
go to college and get the piece...
Piece of paper.
- Well, I don't.
- Yeah, that's her.
That's the girl who
just wouldn't let me settle.
Yeah, well, I haven't
seen much of her lately, so...
Yeah, but there she is.
To her.
Does it ever
get lonely out there?
I mean,
are you asking me if I'm single?
Are you?
Well, I've had, you know,
relationships, I guess.
And things...
I mean, nothing...
Yeah, no, not right now.
You ever been in love?
With you.
That was 20 years ago.
Twenty-one.
Well, what do you want me to say,
you set a high bar.
Seriously?
Are you saying that
I'm the reason that you're alone?
Don't ask questions
if you don't want any answers.
That's ridiculous.
I mean, honest to God.
What? Why are you laughing?
I don't know. I guess I just...
I miss this.
I miss... you getting all mad at me.
I'm not mad.
You're being a little pushy.
I'm not pushy.
You just care so much, Amanda.
You just can't help yourself.
I should go.
- What?
- This is dangerous.
We've had wine...
...and somehow you have gotten
better looking, which is so annoying.
Couldn't you have gotten bald
or fat or something? Jesus!
You know, it seems a little silly to
take two cars to Vandemere tomorrow.
I have a confession to make.
OK.
It wasn't destiny when
my car broke down at school.
I disconnected the battery myself
so you could save me.
- I know.
- What?
I know. I knew the minute I saw
your battery line yanked out.
Oh, my God!
Why didn't you tell me?
How often is the mechanic
the hero of the story?
Oh, I gotta go to Vandemere.
Tuck's been putting it off for weeks.
Now his back's out,
he's worried about the garden.
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's OK.
You go take care of
Tuck's garden.
He needs you. I just want you.
- Maybe next weekend.
- Can't wait.
- Be good.
- I will.
- Don't wreck.
- I won't.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
I love you.
All right.
I told you I couldn't wait.
Well?
♪ I put my faith
in your promise ♪
♪ That you'd be here soon ♪
♪ Don't doubt it, darlin' ♪
♪ The stars may be falling ♪
♪ I'm still coming for you ♪
♪ I can hear you whisper ♪
♪ Every doubt screams
where are you ♪
♪ And every moment waiting ♪
♪ Makes the day harder
to get through ♪
Are you sure about this?
I'm sure.
Just kiss me.
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ Hold just a little longer ♪
- Good morning.
♪ I can swear I feel you ♪
♪ Every time
I lay my head down ♪
♪ Nothing but restless ♪
♪ Sleepless, long nights now ♪
Eat. Dig in.
♪ The stars may be falling ♪
"...and you think good days
are preparing for you.
Do not believe it.
It can never be so.
Nothing can bring you peace
but yourself."
- Pull it.
- I am!
You're such a jerk. No, no!
Stop it!
- Come here!
- No!
Whoo!
♪ Hold just a little longer ♪
It's cold!
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ Hold just a little longer ♪
♪ Hold ♪
♪ On ♪
What happened here?
That was for talking back.
That was for not answering.
That was for disrespect.
I don't remember what
that was for.
Hey.
It's OK. They don't
hurt anymore.
We need a song.
In case one of us
gets deployed in World War lll?
No, I'm serious.
Something we can keep forever.
Then pick one.
There's nothing romantic
about picking one.
Here.
First song that comes on
clearly.
We're in the middle of nowhere.
You're not gonna get anything.
Even if you do get something, it's gonna
be a public broadcast on fly fishing.
- Why are you always right?
- I guess it's just a gift.
- Look at you.
- I've been practicing.
- With who?
- Tuck.
♪ Sweet Jane... ♪
Dawson!
So, Dawson, tell me,
what are your plans for the future?
Well, I hope to go to
college next year, sir.
He is going to college.
He got a 4.0 and 1520 on his SATs.
Well, that's good, son.
Where did you apply?
I applied to Tulane,
Loyola and LSU.
I mean, I'll probably end up at LSU.
It's the most realistic.
Yeah, and it's not too far
from New Orleans,
that way we could
still see each other, right?
I take it you know
a few things about cars.
- Yeah, a little, I guess.
- I got a bunch of them in the back.
Yeah, Amanda said you
have a collection.
- How many cars you own?
- Too many.
A few. Would you like to
see them?
- Recognize that one?
- It's a '71 Oldsmobile 442.
You know why they call it that?
Yeah, a four barrel carb,
four speed gear box, dual exhaust.
It's a beautiful car, sir.
Smart boy. I can see why she
likes you.
Go on. Take a look underneath.
Yeah. I know you want to.
I'd love to.
Wow.
Say, have you given any thought
to how you'll pay for college?
There's... There's scholarships,
financial aid, loans, stuff like that.
Tuition's a killer. And you need money
for books, room and board.
It's expensive.
It can be prohibitive for kids like you.
"Kids like me?"
You're a nice guy, Dawson.
I'd like to help you, if you'll let me.
Well, how's that, sir?
Well... four years of school,
say...
$15,000 a year for tuition.
Another five to live
comfortably.
You want to give me $80,000?
If you'll let me.
Just stay away from Amanda,
right?
You'll come out debt-free.
With a real chance
to make something of yourself.
This isn't personal, son.
I just want what's best
for my daughter,
and I can't have her
anywhere near your family.
It's gonna end anyway.
This way, you get something out
of it.
- I don't want your money.
- What's that?
- You think about it.
I don't have to.
You know what you can do
with that 80 grand, sir?
Shove it up your ass.
You think about it.
I'm sorry.
My dad's an asshole.
He's right,
though.
You got a big life ahead of you.
You're gonna do great things.
I don't want to get in the way
of that.
Dawson, what would you risk for
me?
Everything.
Then let me love you like that.
Please.
OK. OK.
How much did he offer?
There's not enough money
in the world.
Well, I mean, if he was gonna throw in
that Cobra, I'd have to think about it.
You're so mean.
- Nice car.
- Tuck's policy.
All rebuilds
must be test driven...
Before they're returned.
Are you gonna
let me drive?
- You learned how to drive a stick?
- Yes.
- Really?
- Kind of.
- All right.
- Kind of?
- Mm-hm.
God help me.
All right. Easy on the clutch. Easy.
All right. Go to first gear. Up.
There we go. Now, slow.
Slowly let the clutch out.
- OK, there you go. Slow down!
- Whooo!
♪ I'm fallin'
I'm fallin' ♪
♪ Just lay me down ♪
♪ And steal my heart tonight ♪
♪ So hold me now ♪
♪ I'm fallin'
I'm fallin' ♪'
♪ To you ♪
God, it used to be so beautiful.
I just... this is how
we're supposed to do this?
I mean, yeah, I don't know.
This is where he
scattered Clara's ashes, so...
- Right.
- Seems all right to me.
Well, we should say something.
Not like a...
...a long winded eulogy
or anything like that. Just...
- No, no, he'd hate that.
- Right. No fuss.
- No.
- OK.
We love you.
We do.
Oh! Oh, shit. Oh!
- Just scatter it.
- Yeah?
Yeah, just...
Oh! OK. Well, maybe we throw it.
- That was much better.
- Yeah. OK. Here.
- To Tuck.
- Sure you don't want another one?
- No. Nah, I'd better not.
- When are you going home?
- Tomorrow.
Last time I was out,
there was this explosion.
Wait, that was your rig?
You were on it?
Yeah, I fell 100 feet into
the water.
I still have no idea why I
didn't drown.
I wasn't wearing a vest.
Doctors couldn't figure it out either.
- God, you were lucky.
- Maybe.
I saw you.
I had, like, a...
It wasn't a dream.
You were there with me.
And it was strange 'cause
I hadn't seen you in so long.
And then I get out of the hospital
and I get this call about Tuck.
Then I come here and
I see you.
And it's like...
I don't know. Just strange.
I'm glad you're OK.
What are you gonna do,
Amanda?
What do you mean?
If you're unhappy.
Wait.
You got all this advice
for me, you know?
What are you gonna do?
You know what this feels like
to me?
Fate. That's what it feels like
to me.
I'm trying to get my head around it
since it all happened.
Why the hell am I still here?
And maybe it's 'cause of this, you know?
Maybe it's a chance
to see you again and...
a chance to tell you how sorry
I am.
And tell you how much I still
love you.
You want me to fall back
in love with you?
How do I do that
if I haven't ever stopped?
- Tuck?
- Yeah.
I... I got you something.
It's not much at all, but...
...I didn't want you to have to worry
about a dry spring anymore.
Yeah.
She'll need one of these.
Tuck, no one's ever treated me
like you have.
No one's ever shown me
- this kind of dignity and respect.
- Your tie is crooked.
- How about a smile, Tuck?
- This is a smile.
Oh, shoot.
Whoo!
Get down there!
Get on down there!
- Come on, g-up, mule.
- Smile pretty.
Oh, oh. Oh, no, no, no, no.
Wake up, you gotta wake up.
I want you to see this.
Now, look at that.
- There it go! There goes the squash.
- Whoo!
Just about ready to pick.
Let me ask you something.
Those pretty tulips right there,
all those flowers.
Not the tulips.
Did you and your wife plant those?
Come on, you get a good look.
Get a good look.
Hey, I forgot Amanda's flower thing.
Can we turn around?
- Oh, yeah, it's just right there.
- Yeah.
Mayhall can't even tie his shoe.
It's Tuck! Stop! Stop, stop, stop, stop!
Get out, get out!
Tuck! Tuck!
Call 911! Go, now!
Bobby, you go help!
Go help, go help, go help!
Tuck! Tuck, what happened?
I ran into a tree.
Bobby, you stay with him.
You help him.
Tuck.
Someone's on their way, Tuck.
OK? You're gonna be OK.
- Dawson! What are you gonna do?
- Go on, stop him now.
- Dawson, don't do this!
- Just talk to me!
Give me the gun.
- Just give him the gun, Dawson!
- Get out of the truck, Bobby.
Don't do this. It's what
he wants.
- Get out of the truck, Bobby!
- No!
- Bobby! No!
- Stay with Tuck. Stay here with Tuck.
- It's gonna be OK.
- Bobby!
Dawson.
- Stay here.
Cool down, cool down,
cool down!
Just think!
Dawson, come on.
Turn the car around. Come on!
Stop! This is stupid.
Dawson, you don't want
to do this.
Told you he'd come back.
- Stay back, Bobby.
- Dawson.
- Stay there!
- Uh-oh.
You know, the last person
that pointed that rifle at me,
he had an accident.
He tripped down his
wheelchair ramp.
Look at him.
Look at you,
you're all dressed to kill.
Is that what you are?
You're a killer now?
What are you gonna do?
You're gonna kill all three of us?
No. Just you.
Why don't you go on and
do it then?
- Put down the gun, Dawson!
- Oh, he will.
Don't worry, Bobby.
I know this one.
He ain't no killer.
You're not a killer, son. Here.
You ain't nothing.
- Hell, no.
- Ted! Hey, Ted!
Get up!
I gotta tell ya.
I didn't see that coming.
Yeah, Papa!
Come on, hit him!
Get up, Papa!
You got this.
Dawson, that's enough!
You're gonna kill him. Come on!
Come on, Dawson.
Dawson, look out!
Bobby. Bobby!
Bobby, Bobby, Bobby, no, no.
Bob, Bob, look at me, look at me.
Look at me, Bobby!
Bobby...
I'm so sorry!
Bobby was getting out.
He was gonna be a dad.
Tuck, he was gonna be
such a good dad.
He's the only family I ever had.
Look at me, son.
I said look at me.
The DA doesn't want you.
He wants Tommy.
If you help them,
then they will help you.
I killed him, Tuck.
I deserve to be here.
Yeah, you showed up there
with a loaded gun
and...
...you're gonna have to
do some time for that.
But, son, there is a reason
that you are here.
You have a life to live.
And you're gonna fight back and
you're gonna keep fighting back.
'Cause no matter what you think,
you are not just your father's son.
Dawson, you are not
like them other boys.
You're a good boy.
And you're
my boy.
You hear me?
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
This is the DEA.
We have the house surrounded.
Ted!
Do you see any of those individuals
present in the courtroom at this time?
I do.
Can you point out
Abee Cole at this time?
Can you also point out
Theodore "Ted" Cole at this time?
Yes.
Can you also point out Thomas
"Tommy" Cole at this time, please?
- Hey.
I brought you some books
and things.
Thanks.
You just let me know if I need
to bring anything else for you
and I'll bring it next time,
all right?
- There can't be a next time.
- What do you mean?
I got eight years.
I mean, it's, what, four before
I'm even eligible for parole?
- I'll wait.
- No.
No, I can't let you do that.
You don't get to make
that choice.
If this was the last time
you're gonna see me...
...what would you say?
- Please don't do this.
I'd say thank you.
- I'm not walking away.
- I'd say I love you.
- Dawson.
- I always will.
Dawson, please don't do this.
Please.
I love you.
Wait, Dawson! Dawson!
Dawson! Dawson!
- Ma'am, I need you to come with me.
- OK.
- Please.
- Oh, God.
- Please come with me. Come with me.
- Right this way.
- OK.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Brentwood,
please come to the front.
He's not taking any visitors.
Collier.
I'm sorry, Miss Collier.
He doesn't want to see you.
OK.
- Man. Back again, huh?
- Yeah.
I went every day for a
month,
and then every week for a year.
Did they tell you that I came?
They told me.
I guess maybe I hoped
they didn't.
Do you even know that I went
when Frank and I started dating?
I told him I was going
to see my parents.
They told me every time.
- And you didn't want to see me?
- That's the only thing I did want.
I never stopped loving you,
Amanda. Not once.
- Then why didn't you?!
- Because I...
- I know this doesn't make sense...
- It doesn't.
All right, Amanda. Listen to me.
I wanted to do something good.
And I wanted to save you
from some of the pain.
You didn't save me
from anything.
I lived with the pain every day
of my life, Dawson, and I blame you.
I blame you for thinking you knew
what was best for me
- when it was you that was best for me.
- I know.
I couldn't have you
wait for me.
- There was so much you wanted to do.
- But I wanted to do it with you.
And I would have waited
for as long as it took.
- I didn't deserve you, Amanda.
- Oh, deserve me?
Jesus, Dawson.
Don't you understand?
When I had Jared,
and I know this is wrong,
but do you know that when I had him
I wanted to tell you.
And when I lost Bea...
I wanted you to hold me.
And when I was alone
at night, I wanted...
I wanted you and I cried for you
and I hated you
and I hated you because...
because I would have chosen you
no matter what,
and you took that away from me.
- I made a mistake.
- Yes, you did.
I did. I hurt you.
But see, I still love you.
I still love you.
Do you remember
the last time we
were here and I turned
on the radio?
- "Sweet Jane."
- Yeah.
God, I knew a song
would come in and then it did.
- Clear as day.
- I know.
As if it was cued up for us.
You know, I used to feel that
way about everything.
I'd just blindly trust
in life to work out.
And then it would.
I don't feel that way anymore.
What?
Where you going?
Anymore, I don't like
to leave things to chance.
Wow.
You're not stepping on
my feet anymore.
Well, not yet.
Would you do one thing for me?
Would you forgive yourself?
You're a good man, Dawson.
Believe it.
That shirt looks a lot better
on you.
It's so cold.
Do you remember it being so cold?
Nah, don't be a baby.
- I'm not a baby.
- Come here.
Lie back.
- Happy?
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry.
- That's OK.
Hi, Jared. Yeah, I'm doing OK.
How are you?
Are his parents going?
I just don't want you to get in the car,
you know, if anyone's been drinking.
I know, but Mike can
barely drive if he's sober.
All right, well,
just ask your dad.
I miss you, too.
All right, I'll see you
in a couple of days.
OK, be careful. Bye.
- Sorry. It's Jared.
- It's OK.
We can't do this, can we?
I know you, Amanda.
I know your heart.
You're the girl who came every day
for a month and every week for a year.
You have a husband.
And you have a son
that you love very much.
You won't give up easy.
These past few days
have been so good.
A chance to see you
and to talk to you.
To heal a little.
To love you again.
People spend their whole life looking
for that and they never find it.
But we did.
We're the lucky ones.
No matter what happens, Amanda,
I want you to know
how grateful I am.
'Cause at the end of it all...
...I get to say I know what it's like
to have loved someone.
Truly love someone
because I've loved you.
I have to go back.
And I don't know how
I'm gonna say goodbye to you.
I'll always be here.
And I'll always love you.
I'm gonna trust in the stars.
Hello?
Hey. I'm home.
- You just get back?
- I did.
How was it?
Nice... Sad.
How's your mom?
She missed us at Easter.
- It's a busy time of year.
- I said.
- I got to, uh...
- I'll get dinner started.
Wow.
Cheers.
Sorry.
Hello, Chas.
Uh-huh. Right, pal. No.
Brooksie already told me
you shot eight over par, so...
Eat.
...you're busted.
What the hell
are you doing out there, man?
I saw you hacking away like it
was a...
Oh, yeah, OK, no.
Blame it on the partner, that's good.
Is that what you said about me
last week, you son of a bitch?
Dawson, over the years
I've come to know Amanda pretty well.
She's got a lot of good
inside her.
A lot of pain, too...
...about the past, about you.
I got you together here because I don't
want either of you living with regret.
You two were meant to
love each other.
You needed a chance to
remember that.
I'm not saying you're gonna be
together. I don't know that.
And if it doesn't work out,
you'll miss her so much
you'll barely be able to move.
You'll feel you have
no purpose...
...no reason to go on.
But there's nothing to do
but wait.
Wait and it'll get clear to you.
You'll get on with your life
and gifts will come into it.
I was lost when Clara died.
Then one day this kid
walks into my garage.
I want you to know the gift you
were to me. I thank you for it.
I knew you were back.
I saw the flowers on
Bobby's grave.
I haven't had a chance
to do that in a while, April.
We've been getting the money.
You don't have to send that.
You don't owe us anything.
How'd you know it was me?
Who else would it be?
Who else would send cash
through the mail?
I figured if I wrote you a check with
my name on it, you wouldn't cash it.
We told him to get out
of the truck.
We both did.
It wasn't your fault.
It's just something that
lives in my head, you know?
I play it over and over.
Look at me. Look at me!
Dawson, you didn't kill him.
They killed him.
And now it's Aaron.
What do you mean?
Ted and Abee started coming around
when he was about 14.
They took him out. Eased him in.
You know, girls and cars
and booze and...
So he's been
hanging around out there?
All the time.
He didn't get in any real trouble until
your father took him under his wing.
And how he's running errands for them
and making deliveries.
He's a good kid.
He's not like them.
He's like his dad.
He just doesn't know it.
What are you doing here?
Aaron. I want you to
come with me.
Why the hell would I do that?
Dawson.
They told me you were here.
What a surprise.
It's not even my birthday.
What line of bullshit
is he feeding you, son?
He lives here now, with family.
This is no family. It never was.
Well, not to you, maybe.
But you never figured that blood
counted for much, did you?
I'll tell you what I do know.
There was never an ounce
of love in this house.
Oh... love.
You're a weak piece of shit, Dawson.
You know that?
You always were, you always
will be.
- I'm weak?
- Mm.
You were my father and you
treated me like an animal.
I tried to make a man
out of you.
But you didn't appreciate
a goddamn thing I gave you.
And what did you give me?
These?
You are weak.
And you're not worth it.
And I'm not gonna let you
ruin another person's life
like you tried to ruin mine.
I'm taking the boy, if he'll go.
And there's nothing
you can do to stop me,
because you're just a scared
old man
who doesn't want to go
back to prison.
Don't get in my way.
It's all right.
Amanda!
Yes?
I didn't know you were there.
Did you see my golf glove?
- Can I talk to you?
- Nothing is where I left it.
- Jesus, Frank.
- What?
What do you want to talk about?
Us.
Come on, Amanda, I'm 20 minutes
late for my tee time with Hal.
I can't do marriage counseling.
- I've lied to you, Frank.
- About what?
For a long time I have lied.
But I want to tell you the truth.
OK.
I saw someone this weekend.
Someone I fell in love with
a long time ago.
What, you mean, the guy,
the kid...
- Dawson.
- Cole?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
I'm still in love with him.
I didn't know I was going to see him.
I didn't expect to.
But I'm glad I did because it made me
realize how completely lost
- I have been.
- You sound a little crazy.
I don't expect you
to understand.
When I lost him,
I lost who I was.
- Right.
- I lied to you, Frank.
I have lied to you
and I have lied to myself.
And I've tried to
make it work. We both have.
But I can't do it anymore.
So what? You want me to stop drinking?
Is that what you want?
What I want is to stop sleepwalking
through my life.
Then stop!
I mean, just listen to yourself.
Get over it.
No.
Look, this is my life, too.
You don't just get to choose.
Yes, I do.
And I am done pretending.
OK. Good.
- What are you doing?
- Does it matter?
Hi, it's me, it's Amanda.
I was hoping maybe we
could talk.
A lot of things have changed
since I last saw you.
And well, I just...
I want to say I love you.
I do, Dawson.
And I always have.
All right, call me if you
have a moment.
Hello?
Yes, this is his mother.
Frank, it's the fourth time I've called.
Jared's at Delta West.
I need you to come
as soon as you get this.
Mrs. Reynolds?
- How's my son?
- Post-op.
We went in, had a look around.
He's stable for now.
- All right, what happened?
- His car hit a tree,
- he was thrown from the vehicle.
- Oh, my God.
The blunt trauma from the accident has
resulted in serious damage to his heart.
- What does that mean?
- Amanda!
- Sorry. I was...
- Wait, Frank.
What's happened?
- Frank, just listen!
- What's going on? Where's my son?
It means one of the valves
of his heart is torn.
It's my determination
that we can't repair it.
What does that mean,
exactly?
He needs a transplant
and very soon.
Doctor, I have lost one
child already. I cannot lose another.
I understand.
Hi, it's me, it's Amanda.
I was hoping maybe we
could talk.
A lot of things have changed
since I last saw you.
I wanted to say I love you.
I do, Dawson.
Come on!
Abee! Abee!
Ted!
Oh, hell! Where is he?
What's going on? What happened?
They're prepping him for surgery.
They found a heart.
He's got a chance now.
Amanda.
Dawson.
What are you doing here?
Mom. I overslept.
I gotta get back to the hospital.
Jared's all right, sweetheart.
I just spoke with Frank.
All right. Let me get dressed.
You'll come with me, right?
Jared will want to see you.
Amanda.
Yeah, Ted and Abee. Both down.
All right, thanks, sheriff.
No, I can bring 'em down.
That's all right.
I got nothing but time.
I can bring 'em to you.
That sounds good.
- Dawson Cole!
- You got it.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, God!
I commend the soul
of Dawson Cole to God.
Amen.
Children's Legal Defense Fund.
Yes, of course, hold please.
- Hi, doll. Your ex called.
- Thanks, Jamie.
- Hey. So what'd you figure out?
- Hey.
Well, after weighing everything
that we discussed,
it is my recommendation that
we go all the way back to 1959.
We can look at the UN's declarations
of the rights of the child
and we can structure
our argument from there.
Good. Thank God for paralegals.
But if we do that, we have to
make sure that we
keep in mind the 1976...
Sorry, it's my son.
Well, we are the
Children's Defense Fund.
- Hi, Jared.
- Hey, Mom.
- Everything OK?
- Uh, yeah.
Why wouldn't it be?
Well, this is your third phone call
in two days. That's a record for you.
Very funny.
No, I'm actually calling because there's
something that I wanted you to know.
You remember how Dr. Charbonneau
told me that if I waited a year
I could file a request to find out
who donated my heart?
Yeah. Did you decide
to go ahead with it?
Well, actually, I did go ahead
with it.
Oh.
And I got the information yesterday.
So, here, give me one second.
Yeah, it says he was 39 years
old when he died.
Get this, he was actually
from St. Olivia,
so I thought that maybe you
knew him.
Dawson Cole.
Mom, you there?
Yeah. I'm here.
So, did you know him?
Yes. I knew Dawson.
Great, so when I'm home for Spring Break
maybe you can tell me a bit about him.
- I would love that.
- Oh, hey, Mom, I gotta go.
I'm meeting this girl for lunch.
She's in my English class.
- OK.
- I'm totally loving it here.
All right, I love you, Mom. Bye.
Everything all right?
Yes. It is.
Good.
So, like I was saying,
if we start in 1959, we can...
Dear Amanda,
when I was young,
I looked for a shape to things.
A reason or a design.
So much of what happened to me,
though, felt like an accident.
So I guess I lost faith
in all that.
When I survived my fall,
I began to wonder...
...if there wasn't some
purpose to my life.
Maybe I was on a destined path,
even if I couldn't see it yet.
When I saw you again, I believe
we'd been given a second chance.
That the universe
had decided to give us that.
You have commitments,
I understand,
and you want to keep them.
I can only love you more
for that.
I hope to see you again someday,
but if I don't...
...just know that these last days
have been the best of my life.
I love who I am
when I'm with you, Amanda.
You are my dearest friend,
my deepest love.
You are the very best of me.
Forever, Dawson.
♪ I remember thinking
'bout forever ♪
♪ Sitting there
with you by the river ♪
♪ We danced
in the headlights ♪
♪ And fell
for the first time ♪
♪ I remember telling you
I loved you ♪
♪ The Northern star
rising above you ♪
♪ And in that moment ♪
♪ I thought every dream
would come true ♪
♪ Oh, but some
just never do ♪
♪ Love comes in circles ♪
♪ And love takes
its own time ♪
♪ Bending and breaking ♪
♪ Not taking
a straight line ♪
♪ I never knew another love
timeless and true ♪
♪ Oh, but I did, yeah
I did with you ♪
♪ Oh, I did
♪ Through the years
I just kept on believing ♪
♪ Had to be a plan
or a reason ♪
♪ But Heaven was silent ♪
♪ And life just kept
moving along ♪
♪ 'Til my heart knew
the moment was gone ♪
♪ Love comes in circles ♪
♪ And love
takes its own time ♪
♪ Bending and breaking ♪
♪ Not taking a straight line ♪
♪ I never knew another love
timeless and true ♪
♪ Oh, but I did
yeah, I did with you ♪
♪ Love is the reason why ♪
♪ Miracles never die ♪
♪ They just live on and on ♪
- ♪ Like a song ♪
♪ In the hearts of the ones
you leave behind ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ Love comes in circles ♪
♪ And love
takes its own time ♪
♪ Bending and breaking ♪
♪ Not taking
a straight line ♪
♪ I never knew another love
timeless and true ♪
♪ Oh, but I did
yeah, I did with you ♪
♪ Oh, I did
♪ I just don't know
what to do when you cry ♪
♪ On my shoulder ♪
♪ I could make a joke ♪
♪ On that's about how
we're getting older ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Or I could hold you close ♪
♪ And say everything
will be all right ♪
♪ Or I could give you
a little time ♪
♪ And just say good night ♪
♪ Say good night ♪
♪ I'm a crossroad ♪
♪ I feel you down low ♪
♪ But I just don't know ♪
♪ Should I stay or go ♪
♪ I'm at a crossroad ♪
♪ I know you want me ♪
♪ But I just can't see ♪
♪ Maybe I'm crazy, baby ♪
♪ I just don't know
what to do ♪
♪ When you say
you're gonna leave me ♪
♪ My heart says, "Run" ♪
♪ But my head says ♪
♪ "Heart, don't deceive me" ♪
♪ I'm at a crossroad ♪
♪ I feel you down low ♪
♪ But I just don't know ♪
♪ Should I stay or go ♪
♪ I'm at a crossroad ♪
♪ I know you want me ♪
♪ But I just can't see ♪
♪ Maybe I'm crazy, baby ♪
♪ I'm at a fork in the road ♪
♪ Don't know
which way to go ♪
♪ Both roads
sound good to me ♪
♪ This decision
is bittersweet ♪
♪ I just don't know
what to do when you say ♪
♪ That you need me ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ So all I know is that I ♪
♪ Can't let you
bleed me dry ♪
♪ I'm at a crossroad ♪
♪ I feel you down low ♪
♪ But I just don't know ♪
♪ Should I stay or go ♪
♪ I'm at a crossroad ♪
♪ I know you want me ♪
♪ But I just can't see ♪
♪ Maybe I'm crazy ♪
♪ I'm at a fork in the road ♪