Couldn't you have talked sooner?
-So, he's talked, has he?
-Does he know where Alì's hidden?
I reckon so. Let's go see.
Give him some coffee.
-Did you make him sing, Marc?
-Yeah.
Come on, drink up. It'll do you good.
Buck up.
Come on, stand up.
Don't crowd him. Give him room.
At ease.
-Is it true?
-I reckon so.
-3, Rue des Abderames.
-Dress him.
Come on, it's all over now.
I assure you.
Can you stand?
Leave him alone.
Put it on.
It's for your own good.
They'll not recognize you like this
in the Kasbah.
Come on, then you can go.
And we'll look after you.
Here's a cap.
-Now you're nationalised.
-Idiot.
Let's go.
No!
Pig-head, let's not start again!
Behave or you'll make me look a fool.
Alì la Pointe,
the house is surrounded.
It's useless.
Surrender!
Let the boy and the girl come out.
Then you, and the other.
Leave your weapons there.
No tricks now.
We've got you covered.
You wouldn't have time. Understand?
Can you hear me?
Listen,
you're the last.
There's no one else left.
The organisation's finished.
Everyone's dead, or in prison.
You'll have a proper trial.
Surrender!
National Liberation Front (FLN).
Communiquè N.1 .
The time has arrived to emerge
from the long night,
and from the misery we have suffered
under 130 years
of colonial oppression.
The battle draws nigh.
The aim is independence.
To avoid a bloody conflict,
we propose honourable discussions
with the French recognizing our right
to self-government.
Algerians, unite!
Be prepared!
The National Liberation Front
calls you to arms.
The king loses, the queen wins.
Place your bets.
This one wins, this one loses.
The king loses, the queen wins.
Place your bets! Watch!
Watch! The king loses, the queen wins.
Where's the king? Place your bets!
-Yes, that one!
-You've lost.
Yes, that one!
Get the rat! Kill him!
Stop it! Leave him alone!
Get back to the Kasbah!
Kill the rat!
Murderer!
Omar Alì, alias Alì la Pointe.
Born in Miliana on the 1st March 1930.
Educational standard: illiterate.
Occupation: labourer, farm hand,
boxer, presently unemployed.
Previous record:
1942 - Orano Juvenile Court:
reformatory for vandalism.
1944 - two years' reformatory
for theft.
1 949 - Algiers Assizes -
8 months for living off immoral
earnings and resisting arrest.
Persistent offender.
They're going to execute an Algerian.
A patriot. Come on, all together.
Yell: Long Live Algeria!
Here he is.
Silence.
Five months later.
-Beat it!
-Men have two faces.
-They've sent you?
-You're displeased?
It's all written here.
Come here.
-Can you read?
-Of course.
-Read it.
-Here?
There's a Moorish cafè
at 40, Rue Randon.
Madjebri, the owner,
is a police informer.
Every day at five a French cop
stops by a moment,
and picks up information
pretending to have a cup of tea.
Kill the cop.
Not Madjebri?
It says the cop.
Okay.
At the corner under the clock,
you'll see a girl with a basket.
When the cop comes out,
you both follow him.
At the right moment
she'll give you a gun,
and you shoot.
Immediately. In the back.
Wait, what do you think you're doing?
Stop!
I give the orders now.
Put your arms up!
Look brothers! See our masters now.
Louse! Scum!
Now, explain.
Let's get clear first.
Who sent the letter?
-He's waiting.
-Let's go, if we can make it.
Move. You go first, I'll follow.
-I had to know if you were a spy.
-With an empty gun?
Let's suppose you were a spy.
The FLN contact you in prison,
you pretend to be for the cause
and the French let you go.
-Shooting at me?
-It could be fixed.
You escape, go to the address you
received in prison and get to know me.
-What's your name?
-Kader. Saari Kader.
To join the organisation
you had to do a job.
I could have told you
to kill the barman.
But he's an Algerian and the police
would have let you kill him even though he's a stool.
And you could have spied on us.
That's why I said to kill the cop.
Because the French
wouldn't have allowed it.
If you were one of them,
you wouldn't have done it.
-I didn't.
-You couldn't.
-You tried, that's the important thing.
-And nearly got caught.
Now, now... you're exaggerating.
Your orders were, shoot in the back.
Don't grumble.
Why didn't you let me kill him?
We're not ready yet.
We need a safe hide-out.
There's the Kasbah. It's still not safe.
Too many drunks, whores, junkies.
People who talk too much, ready
to sell us out, they're uncommitted.
We must convince them
or eliminate them.
Clean up the Kasbah.
Then think about the French.
April 1 956.
FLN Communiquè N. 24.
Brothers of the Kasbah,
the Colonial Administration is
responsible not only for our misery,
but also for our brothers' vices
which make them lose their dignity.
Corruption and degradation
are the weapons of colonialism.
The FLN calls on the people to prepare
physically and morally
so as to gain independence.
To this end,
the FLN has decided to prohibit:
gambling,
the sale and use of drugs,
alcoholic drinks,
prostitution and pimping.
Offenders will be punished,
those who persist will be put to death.
Opium is prohibited.
-Alì la Pointe!
-Have you seen Hacène le Bonois?
Not today.
-Have you seen Hacène?
-No.
Margot? Margot?
What's the matter?
-Come here.
-I'm coming.
-Have you seen Hacène le Bonois?
-No.
Tell him I'm looking for him.
Alì la Pointe,
I've not seen you for ages.
I thought you were in prison.
-Is Hacène here?
-He went out early.
-You know what the boss is like.
-I want to see him.
I'm around.
-My boy, where've you been hiding.
-Stand still!
-Don't move your hands.
-I don't carry arms.
-I know.
-Are you afraid of these?
-Don't move.
-Why are you afraid?
We're friends.
You could say I raised you.
-Isn't that so, Alì?
-That's true.
-What's happened to you?
-You're condemned to death.
So that's what it's come to.
I could die of laughter.
-What are they paying you?
-Nothing.
They've told you twice.
This is the last time.
-Decide.
-What?
-To turn over a new leaf.
Try to convince me.
Stop! Take a good look.
No one does what he likes now,
in the Kasbah.
Not even Hacène, still less you lot.
Now, beat it.
And tell the rest.
Go!
June 10th 1956
-Good morning.
You stay outside and keep watch.
Sit down.
Let's hurry up with the formalities,
you know why.
One day, weddings
will be in the open again.
It is very sad that a day like this
should not be in the tradition
with the whole quarter celebrating.
But to be first to desert
the offices of the French,
to be married by the FLN,
takes courage.
It's a conscious act of war.
Let's start, Mahmoud e Fathia.
Sign here.
Here.
Congratulations.
Best wishes.
Make yourselves comfortable.
June 20th 1956, 10:32
Quiet. Speak quietly.
Listen,
they want to talk to the inspector.
Come on.
You stay here, else it'll be like before.
But, Sir, in Paris you can't imagine
what's happening here.
The Government must be made to act.
The press must move.
The police?
They're beset
by a thousand difficulties.
Exactly.
They're hamstrung.
No!
Democratic methods, quibbles...
meanwhile they're being shot at.
The magistrature favours
a formal enquiry.
Yes, sir.
You must move.
But the press...
Is conditioning public opinion back to normal?
But couldn't you... Okay, as you wish.
They'll slaughter the lot of us!
Well... 3:00 p.m.:
patrol fired on.
Three soldiers wounded.
Location: Rue Lanciani.
3:30 p.m.:
shots fired at territorial guards.
Location: intersection of main road
and Laquière Avenue.
Excuse me a moment.
Do you know,
these Paris types want us
to continue to talk of... reconciliation
of our Moslem brothers.
What do you say?
That Paris doesn't give two hoots.
That the Government's senile.
The Governor of Algiers decrees: Art. 1
The purchase of medicines
suitable for treating gun wounds
must be authorised by the Prefecture.
Art. 2
Hospitals and nursing homes
must inform the police
about all patients admitted
for treatment.
The Algiers Prefecture communicates
that there have been dozens
of outrages in the city
and it is presumed that
the culprits come from the Kasbah,
or can easily and quickly find refuge
in the Arab quarters.
So, to restore order,
the Prefect has decided
that military control posts
shall be set up around the Kasbah
where citizens may have to show their
papers on request and be searched.
Queue up!
Papers.
-And you?
-But I'm French.
Stop!
Enough! Let her through.
What a job!
July 20th, 1 1 :20
What do you want?
I'm going swimming.
-You again?
-I go this way.
Come here.
Now, beat it.
They kill and run away,
it's the same story!
They should be exterminated
without pity.
It's the Government's fault.
What does it care!
He was very young.
Murderers! Murderers! Murderers!
Enough! Let's finish it!
Here's one!
Where are you running to?
Black rat!
He's escaping. Grab him!
It's him! I saw him!
Murderer! Murderer!
Culprit Lahidan Bualem
labourer, married with three children,
living at 8 Rue de Thèbes.
-How many today?
-Seven incidents, three dead.
A copy for the teletype,
the foreign press and one for you.
Thanks. See you tomorrow.
Goodbye.
Tell me,
-where's Rue de Thèbes?
-In the upper Kasbah I believe.
-Goodnight mummy, goodnight daddy!
-Goodnight.
-Fatma,
-Yes, madam?
why are they still up?
-Goodnight mummy!
-Goodnight.
-We must go now.
-Don't go to the club,
play poker here.
-At least another cognac.
-No, thanks.
They're waiting for us, we're late.
Goodnight all. Hurry up.
-Bye-bye.
-Goodnight.
To Rue de Thèbes.
Halt!
-Good evening.
-Can we go in?
You can't enter the Kasbah
at this time. It's quite impossible.
Press! They're with me.
-Go ahead then.
-Let's go, brothers!
Alì!
Alì, Alì!
Alì, Alì, Alì!
Alì, stop!
-Kader says you must stop.
-Why?
-Kader is trying to stop the people.
-Beat it.
They'll kill us all.
-Stop!
-Go away!
Stay calm or they'll kill us all!
Leave it to the organisation.
You stand guard. You come in.
-Okay like this?
-Perfect.
What's wrong?
I'll take my son.
Okay,
but go by the Divan checkpoint.
There's more traffic
and they're not so careful.
The air-line agency.
Cafeteria in Rue Michelet.
Milk bar in Rue d'Isly.
They're short-time-fuse bombs,
so they'll be set outside the Kasbah
at 3 Rue del Porto.
But take care,
from that moment, move!
You'll have 25 minutes.
Now, go. Goodbye and good luck.
Good luck.
Fathia, God bless you.
Halt!
Okay, go.
-Your papers.
-I've forgotten them.
Over there then, move.
I've got them at home. Leave me!
-Give me a break.!
-I have to go to work.
Get back!
It's late.
Keep calm or else
no one'll go through today.
Excuse me.
-Excuse me, may I pass?
-Go on.
-Good morning, madam.
-Good morning.
And you?
Beg pardon, madam.
Come on, move.
Halt!
Wait.
Okay,move on.
Next one.
Go on.
Please, madam.
What's in there?
I'll be gone an hour.
He's a very good boy.
Be good. Thank you, thank you.
-Going to the sea, miss?
-How did you guess?
The bag, the towel...
-Alone?
-No, with friends.
Next Sunday I'll be free. How about it?
-We'll see.
-See you next Sunday.
Good luck.
-Good luck.
-An amarena.
-Please, have a seat.
-No, thank you.
-Please, miss, have a seat.
Going already, miss? Cheerio.
Attention please, flight 432 for Paris
will be delayed twenty minutes.
Seems like a gas explosion.
Must be close, towards the port.
A fire. Look, firemen.
Come on, let's dance.
Another!
Murderers! Murderers! Murderers!
Criminals!
January 10th 1957
Mr. Lefevre, the Inspector General
of the Administration,
has taken drastic steps
to ensure law and order
and to protect people and property.
In particular to bring
the 10th Para Division into Algiers
from antiguerrilla operations
on the Kabir plateau.
The Commander will take over
responsibility for law
and order in Algiers using
all civil and military measures
necessary for the job.
Surname: Mathieu.
Christian name: Philippe.
Born in Rennes on the 3rd May 1 906.
Rank: Lieutenant-Colonial.
School: Polytechnic.
Degree in Engineering.
Campaigns: World War II,
Resistance Movement in Italy,
Indo-China war and Algeria war.
The average during the last months
is 4,2 incidents per day
including individual attacks
and explosions.
The problem, as usual, is:
1st - the enemy;
2nd - how to destroy him.
There are 80.000 Arabs in the Kasbah.
All against us?
No, for sure.
There's only a minority
which rules by violence.
This is the enemy
to isolate and destroy.
Draw the curtains.
It moves on the surface and below.
Using well-tried revolutionary tactics
and original techniques.
It's an unknown,
unrecognisable enemy.
It blends with the others.
It is everywhere.
In the alleys of the Kasbah in the
European quarter, where people work.
These shots were taken by the police
with cameras hidden at checkpoints.
They thought them to be useful.
They are useful to show the
uselessness of certain methods
or at least, their shortcomings.
I've chosen these films
because they were taken in the hours
preceding recent incidents.
Amongst these Arabs, men and women,
are those responsible.
But which? How to recognise them?
Not from their papers, that's for sure.
If anyone has them in order,
it's the terrorist.
Watch the film.
The operator had his doubts
about the basket,
and keeps it in the field.
Perhaps the bomb was there,
in a false bottom. Who knows?
We'll never know.
That's enough.
We have no information,
apart from that on the structure
of the organisation.
Let's start from there.
It's an organisation like a pyramid,
with sectors themselves
formed by a series of triangles.
At the apex of the pyramid
is the Chief of Staff.
The military boss,
responsible to the political bureau,
nominates the person
responsible for one sector: N. 1 .
Number one selects the other two
and so triangle one is formed.
Number two and number three,
each select two men.
And so on.
Because of this structure,
each member only knows three
members of the organisation.
The one who chose him.
And the two he chose.
Contact is only by writing.
So we don't know our enemy.
In practice,
they don't know each other, either.
If we know him we can eliminate him.
The military angle is secondary.
It's the police side that matters.
Yes, the word's not to your liking.
But, it's the only one which sums up
what we have to do.
We must make investigations which
run through the entire pyramid.
The basis of our job is information,
the method, the interrogation.
Interrogation conducted so as to get
an answer, always.
In this situation, false sentiment
leads to ridicule and impotence.
I am certain that all sections
will act accordingly.
However it doesn't depend just on us.
We must have the Kasbah available,
screen it, question everyone.
But we're up against a mass
of laws and regulations.
It's like being in a holiday resort,
not a battlefield.
We've asked for carte blanche,
but we haven't got it.
We need the opportunity
that will legalise our actions.
We ourselves must create
this opening.
Unless our adversaries do it for us.
As I believe.
God bless you.
To all combatants,
after two years' bitter struggle,
the Algerian people has its victory.
The United Nations will debate
the Algerian question,
starting on Monday 28th January.
The FLN proclaims a general strike.
For the entire period there will be
no armed action or incidents.
Combatants are mobilised
for the success of the strike.
Le Monde! General strike!
The 8-day strike.
My money?
Strike!
Brothers, Algerians,
there is great hope for us.
The next few days will decide
our future and our freedom.
The colonists will tell the UN that
the FLN does not represent our people.
Our reply will be our support
of the general strike.
Don't move during these 8 days,
don't leave the Kasbah.
Lodge in your own houses the poor,
the beggars,
who have no houses,
stock up with food and water.
See? No one's coming out tonight.
They seem happy.
Rats in a trap we hope.
-Think the strike will be 100°/o?
-Certainly.
A name, Mathieu.
-A name?
-A name for this operation.
Off the cuff, it's difficult.
Champagne, eh?
Champagne? Champagne?
Operation Champagne. Yes, fine.
They're beggars,
unemployed, homeless.
They're staying with these families
during the strike,
clear of police sweeps and reprisals.
But I wouldn't have thought
they'd have been brought here.
-It's a mistake.
-Why?
Because you're here.
You'd better change house.
-Don't you trust them?
-You never know.
You 're the boss.
If the decision had been up to me,
you wouldn't have been in Algiers.
-Why? Isn't it prudent?
-No, it isn't.
Go with Ben M'Hidi
to the Maison des Arbres.
Isn't he sleeping here?
There are too many new faces around.
Here we are.
Look at this for a hide-out.
Seems like a wall.
A bit of dirt and it'll be perfect.
-Look inside.
-No, it's late.
This is a family of old fighters,
you'll be okay.
Hurry up.
The terrace is the shortest way.
You'll be safe with Alì.
All right, you can come.
Fine. They're waiting.
-What do you think about the strike?
-It'll succeed.
Yes, I reckon so too.
It's well organised.
-But the French?
-Obviously they'll try to break it.
They'll do more.
We've given them the chance.
Understand what I mean?
They'll no longer be groping.
Every workman, shopkeeper who
strikes will be a recognisable enemy,
a confessed offender,
and they can pass to the offensive.
-Have you thought of this?
-No.
Kader says you weren't in favour
of the strike.
No, nor my men.
Why?
Because they say
we mustn't use arms.
You don't win wars with outrages.
Neither wars nor revolutions.
But later,
the people themselves must move.
That's the reason behind the need
to strike.
To mobilise all the Algerians,
to count them.
-Assess our strength.
-Of course.
To let the UN see, no?
Yes, the UN too.
I don't know whether this'll be
of much use,
but at least the UN
can see our strength.
You know,
it's difficult to start a revolution.
Even more difficult to continue it.
Very difficult to win it.
But the real difficulties come later.
When we've won.
Ah, well, there's still a lot to do.
-You are not tired?
-No.
Wake up! Wake up!
To all vehicles, speed up the sweep.
Truck No.1 : El Biar worksite.
No.2: Gasworks.
No.3: Port, Goods Quay.
Attention! Political affairs personnel,
arrange for suspects to be sent
in to H.Q.
That one.
You, here.
What's your name?
-Why are you striking?
-I was at home.
Why have you gone on strike?
Did they force you?
-Let's have the truth!
-No.
So you went on strike: are you FLN?
Speak up. Are you scared to talk?
It doesn't matter. This one for H.Q. too.
You, there. Stop!
Move! To work!
Talk about a strike!
12 hours' work today!
A whole 12 hours!
4th day, the strike continues
with the full support of the people.
All's quiet. Quiet, are you deaf?
The city's dead quiet. In the Moslem
areas and in the Kasbah...
Cheerio, I'll call you later.
Mathieu's here.
Colonel.
-Colonel, a statement please.
-What do you want to know?
-Any news?
-There's a meeting with the Prefect.
-What's now?
-It's nothing.
Just an initial assessment.
Go around.
You'll see with your own eyes.
-The strike's successful.
-It's not achieved its aim.
-Revolt?
-Revolt.
But the strike
was just a demonstration.
Do you believe the FLN?
A general strike
is a good argument at the UN.
The UN's not here.
Bombs make more noise.
That's what I'd use in their place,
I assure you.
-Armed revolt, what's that exactly?
-It'd be armed revolt.
It's an inevitable step.
First terrorism, then revolt.
Same as, guerrilla tactics, then war
proper that's the deciding factor.
-Dien Bien Phu?
-Exactly, but in Indo-China they won.
And here?
-It depends on you.
-It depends on us?
-You want us to enlist?
-No,
there's no lack of soldiers.
You only have to write. And write well.
-What's lacking?
-Political will,
which is sometimes present,
but at time is not enough.
-What's Paris saying?
-There's another article by Sartre.
Why are the Sartres always
on the other side?
-Would you like a Sartre?
-No. But even less so as an enemy.
One, two, three, four, inside.
Come on.
-What's happening?
-They're dancing.
Let's have you.
From the start, then you can go.
First name?
-Sid Ahmed.
-Surname?
Sail.
-District?
-Second.
-Be more precise.
-District No.2,
the Kasbah, Algiers West.
-Which Group?
-Third Group.
-What was your job?
-Responsible for the Sixth Squad.
Ahmed Sail,
Sixth Squad.
Stay there! Don't move!
Sixth day of strike.
Look lively,
there's work to do tomorrow.
People of the Kasbah,
Algerians, listen.
The FLN want to stop you
from working.
They make you shut your shops.
Rebel against their orders.
France is your country.
She has given you
civilisation and wealth.
Schools, roads and hospitals.
Algerians return to work.
Algerians, listen...
My husband was at the port,
isn't he with you?
Ramid Fouad! Who's seen him?
Bel Casel | . Bel Casel| !
My son!
Algerians, brothers!
Take courage.
Algeria will be free!
Brothers, resist.
Don't listen to what they say.
Algeria will be free.
February 5th 1957
Last day of strike.
Open the shops!
Don't you want to sell?
Pull!
The UN Assembly has decided that
there will be no direct UN intervention
on the Algerian question as none
of the motions received a majority.
The UN however expresses the hope
that in a spirit of co-operation
a peaceful and democratic solution
will be found
in keeping with the principles
of the UN Charter.
Very good.
Now let's go to bed.
The end of the strike changes nothing,
orders are the same.
Keep the boys on duty.
We must stay in the Kasbah
24 hours a day.
We must stay in there ready to act.
-Any of you ever had a taenia?
-No.
It's a worm that grows to infinity.
You can kill thousands of segments,
but if the head remains,
it immediately reproduces.
The FLN's the same.
The head is the General Staff:
four people.
If this is not eliminated,
we'll always be at square one.
I found these in the police files.
I had them enlarged.
Ramel.
Si Mourad.
Kader.
Alì la Pointe.
We'll print a thousand
to give to our boys.
You can come out.
Good.
There were ten this time.
-Parachutists?
-Yes.
-Did they come here specifically?
-By chance.
They only asked a few questions.
Attention! Attention!
Inhabitants of the Kasbah,
the terrorist Ben Amin
was executed this morning.
Qrara Normendine was arrested.
Boussalem Alì was arrested.
Bel Kasel Maussà was arrested.
Inhabitants of the Kasbah,
the FLN lost.
Rebel against
the few remaining terrorists
who are involving you
in a useless and bloody struggle.
People of the Kasbah,
the terrorist Ben Amin has been executed.
Work with us
for a free and peaceful Algeria.
People of the Kasbah,
the FLN has lost the battle.
Rebel against
the few remaining terrorists
who are involving you
in a useless and bloody struggle.
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
Cheer up.
... the terrorist Ben Amin
was executed this morning.
Qrara Normendine was arrested.
Boussalem Alì was arrested.
We'll split up,
that will improve our chances.
We must change hide-outs
continuously,
and never stay in one place.
Meanwhile, renew lost contacts.
Replace arrested brothers.
Reorganise.
-Yes, make ourselves felt.
-As soon as possible.
Immediately. The people are down.
-Leave it to me.
-No. None of us.
Whilst we're here,
the FLN's in the Kasbah,
else there'll be nothing.
Nothing comes out of nothing.
But we must do something.
We'll do something,
as soon as we remake contacts.
-How do we move?
-We'll change methods.
Who're you?
Quick, hide us, we're being followed.
Where, my boy? The house is small.
-They'd find you.
-In the well.
God look after you.
The well's nearly dry.
They've gone. They've turned
the corner, the others are far off.
Thanks.
We're making contact
with the 2nd and the 5th sectors.
The 1st and 6th
have had too many losses.
The 3rd and the 4th are reorganising.
Two sectors are enough
to start moving.
February 25th 1 957
Murderers! Murderers!
Blackface bastard!
You're just like them!
Get back! What're you doing!
Are you mad!
Get back!
Don't be like them, it's a child!
Well? They kill our children!
March 4th 1957
Mr. Ben M'Hidi, isn't it a filthy thing
to use women's baskets
to carry explosives for killing people?
Doesn't it seem even filthier to drop
napalm bombs on defenceless villages
wreaking even greater havoc?
It would be better if we too had planes.
Give me the bombers
and you can have the baskets.
Mr. Williams wants to know whether,
according to you,
the FLN still has the possibility
of beating the French Forces.
The FLN has more possibility
of beating the French Forces
than they have of stopping history.
Colonel Mathieu said that you were
arrested by chance. By mistake.
I understand that the paras
were looking for someone
less important than you.
Could you say why you were in that flat
in Rue Debussy?
I can only say
I'd rather not have been there.
That's enough, gentlemen.
That's all for now.
-Show over?
-Correct.
Before it backfires.
Closed for having taken part
in the strike.
People of the Kasbah,
the rebellion is petering out.
... was executed just now.
Kassem Moussu of FLN Sector 2
has been arrested.
People of the Kasbah,
the FLN terrorists are false friends.
Abandon them.
Count on the protection
of the French Army.
Denounce terrorists and agitators.
Work with us to bring back
peace and prosperity.
Colonel Mathieu, the spokesman of the
Resident Minister Morlin states that
Ben M'Hidi hung himself in his cell,
tearing up his shirt to make a rope
which he tied
to the bars of the window.
In an earlier statement
the same spokesman said that
because the prisoner said he would
escape on the first possible occasion,
it was thought advisable to keep him
permanently bound hand and foot.
According to you, Colonel
is a man in this condition capable
of ripping up his shirt
making a rope and tying it
to the window bars?
You should ask the spokesman
about that.
I didn't make the statements.
For my part, I appreciated Ben M'Hidi's
moral strength intelligence
and the way he stuck to his ideals.
And so, even though I recognise
that he was dangerous,
I pay homage to his memory.
Colonel, there's been talk recently
of the paras' successes,
and of the methods they're said to use.
Could you say something on this?
The successes result
from these methods.
The one presupposes the other.
I feel that in being excessively careful
my colleagues keep asking
round-about questions
to which you can only reply
in a round-about way.
It would be better to call a spade
a spade.
If it's torture, let's speak of torture.
I understand. You have no questions?
The questions have been asked.
We would like answers.
Let us be exact.
The word torture does not appear
in our orders.
We ask questions as in any police
operation against an unknown gang.
The FLN asks its members
to keep silent for 24 hours,
if they are captured.
Then they can talk.
That's the time required
to render any information useless.
How should we question suspects?
Like the courts,
and take a few months over it?
The legal way has its drawbacks.
Is it legal to blow up public places?
When you asked Ben M'Hidi,
what did he say?
Believe me, it's a vicious circle.
We could talk for hours
without reaching a conclusion.
The problem is quite different.
The FLN want to kick us out of Algeria,
and we want to stay.
Even though we have different ideas,
I think we all want to stay.
When the rebellion started
there were no nuances.
All the papers, even those of the left
wanted it suffocated.
We're here for that.
We are neither mad, nor sadists.
They call us fascists, they forget
what we did in the resistance.
They say Nazis, but some of us
survived Buchenwald.
We are soldiers.
Our duty is to win.
Thus, to be quite clear,
I'll ask you a question myself.
Must France stay in Algeria?
If the answer's still yes,
you must accept all that this entails.
He's a doctor.
-Stabbed.
-Blast!
No more ammo!
Look there.
Crush them!
Kill them! Kill them!
August 26th 1957
Don't play the hero. It's not necessary.
-The megaphone.
-Right.
Ramel! Si Mourad!
Be reasonable.
I wouldn't like to be in your place
when we get you.
You know we'll get you.
Give yourselves up!
I promise you'll not be touched,
and you'll have a fair trial.
Do you hear?
-Who's speaking?
-Mathieu.
Colonel Mathieu.
We don't trust you, come closer.
-Show yourself.
-I don't trust you,
stand, so that we can see you.
With your hands in view.
Okay, but the promise about the trial
I want it in writing.
A written declaration,
then we'll surrender.
How shall I pass it?
We'll lower a basket.
Fair enough, I'll write it.
-That one?
-At this point.
-Ready, Colonel?
-Yes, but first let's see you.
60, 59,
58, 57,
56, 55,
54, 53, 52...
We can see them. You can come.
Here's the note.
You know I keep my word.
You go.
Swine! He's done us.
-7, 6, 5...
-Get a move on, blackface!
Now you'll see how we get a move on.
2, 1
September 24th 1957
Burn everything, you never know.
Who's Fathia?
-You?
-I am.
Go up and tell him to surrender,
or I'll blow the lot up.
-Understand?
-Yes.
Convince him, if you value your house.
Stop, or he'll kill you.
Kader, Fathia's coming up!
Don't shoot.
Go now.
Kader, it's Fathia.
They say, if you don't come down,
they'll blow up the house.
-You can save yourselves.
-Tell the Colonel
to blow up what he likes. Now, go.
-Kader!
-Go!
-Well?
-He says: blow it up.
Go with the others.
Put the plastic on the ceiling
under the hide-out, with a long fuse.
You give covering fire while they work.
Clear the house and check the rooms.
It's quite pointless to die like this.
Mathieu! If you give me your word,
not to touch the others in this house,
we'll come down.
If you'd made me blow it up,
I'd have been disappointed.
Why?
Your photograph and your record
have been on my table for months.
I feel I know you.
You don't seem the type
for empty gestures.
You're happy to have me alive.
-Certainly.
-I've made a mistake.
I've given you
an unexpected advantage.
No, but the satisfaction
of having guessed right
is no longer an advantage.
The game's over.
The FLN's lost.
What has she said?
That there's still Alì.
-Mahmoud.
-I'm coming now.
Be back right away.
Come on, go to sleep.
There'll just be us tomorrow.
Mahmoud, Hassiba, me...
and you.
No one else will come.
You get out of the truck, first place
the bomb and then return quietly.
Then Hassiba will go down,
then Mahmoud.
Then me.
We'll plant them all,
so they'll know we're still here.
Wake up.
Wake up,
you'll see some fireworks today.
It's nearly time.
-Hassiba.
-I'm ready.
-There was a truck.
-I heard it.
But if it's been Sadek
he'd be here now.
-How's your wife?
-The same.
Inside!
Get out!
What're you waiting for?
-Ready?
-Yes.
-Has he replied?
-Silence.
-I thought so.
-I've cleared the house.
We're blowing you up.
Let the others out.
The boy. He'll only go to reformatory.
Why let him die?
Let's go.
He's still here?
I'll give you 30 seconds.
What do you hope for?
You've already lost.
30 seconds from now.
Who wants can go out.
-What are you doing?
-I'll not bargain.
You four go down when I signal.
Attention!
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Sir.
-Well?
-Ready.
Get back.
-Ready?
-Yes.
Take photos and make a report.
Now the taenia's without a head.
-It's finished in Algiers.
-No more talk of the FLN for a time.
For always.
They're good folks.
We lived together for 130 years,
we could continue.
-There's not only Algiers.
-Right, nor just Algeria.
That's true, but let's be content
with Algiers.
Things are easier in the mountains.
-Goodbye, Sir.
-Goodbye.
Anyway, we'll be meeting
this afternoon for the report.
-Goodbye.
December 1 1th 1960
It is not known why,
but after two years of relative quiet,
apart from guerrilla war
just in the mountains,
trouble has broken out again.
I've phoned Lausanne. Lausanne!
I spoke with an FLN in exile,
but he knows nothing.
Their flags appeared for the first time
this morning.
Green and white flags
with the crescent and the star.
They must've sewn them on overnight.
Flags, in a manner of speaking,
made from sheets, shirts, or rags.
But they're flags.
The situation's very tense today.
Despite pressure from extremists,
it seems the Government's ordered
arms not to be used,
except in the last resort.
In the afternoon there were attempts
to break through
towards the European quarter,
with some deaths.
But calm has now returned
even thought from the Kasbah we continue to hear incomprehensible cries.
Rhythmic, nightmarish.
The surprising unanimity
of these demonstrations
has had a marked effect
on French public opinion.
According to news from Paris,
the more sensitive political groups
are beginning to look for a new line
on relations with Algeria.
December 21st 1960
Last day of demonstration.
Break it up!
Return to your homes!
What do you hope for?
Another two years must pass,
with numerous deaths.
Then, on the 2nd July 1962,
independence is obtained
and the Algerian nation is born.