Hyah! Huh!
Get in there now!
Get in! Get in!
Get in there, Dude!
Get in now!
Hyah! Come on! Huh!
All right! Huh!
Huh!
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa!
Got room for one more?
Who the hell are you?!
And what happened to them?
Name's Major Marquis Warren
former U.S. Cavalry.
Currently a servant of the court.
Trying to bring a couple
no-goods into market.
Got the paperwork on 'em in my pocket.
You takin' 'em into Red Rock?
Figure that's where you headed, right?
I am.
That damn blasted blizzard
has been on our ass for the last three hours.
There ain't no way we gonna make
it all the way to Red Rock
Fore it catches us.
So you hightailin' it halfway
to Minnie's Haberdashery?
You know I am.
May I come aboard?
Well, smoke
if it up to me, yes.
But it ain't up to me.
Who's it up to?
Fella in the wagon.
Fella in the wagon ain't partial to company?
Fella in the wagon he paid for a private trip
and I'm here to tell you
he paid a pretty penny for privacy.
So if you want to go to Minnie's with us
you gonna have to talk to him.
Well
that's what I'll do.
Hold it, black fella.
Fore you approach you take them two guns of yours
and you lay 'em on that rock over yonder.
Then you raise both your
hands way above your hat.
Then you approach.
Molasses-like.
Real trustin' fella, huh?
Not so much.
Put 'em down.
Come on ahead.
I said way above your hat, goddamn it!
Now come forward.
That's far enough.
Well, I'll be dogged.
You a black fella I know.
Colonel somethin'-or-other Warren, right?
Major Marquis Warren.
I know you, too.
We, uh, shared a steak dinner
once upon a time in Chattanooga.
You John Ruth The Hangman.
That'd be me.
How long's that been?
Since that steak?
Oh!..eight months.
So why don't you explain to me
what a African bounty hunter's doin'
wanderin' around in the snow
in the middle of Wyoming?
Trying to get a couple of bounties in to Red Rock.
So you still in business?
You know I am.
Happened to your horse?
Circumstances caused us to have
to take the long way round.
My horse couldn't make it.
Mm.
You don't know nothin' bout this filly here.
Nope.
Don't even know her name?
Well, I guess that makes
this one fortuitous wagon.
I sure as hell hope so.
Major Marquis Warren this here's Daisy Domergue.
Domergue, to you this is Major Warren.
Howdy, nigger.
She's a pepper, ain't she?
Now, girl, don't you know
the darkies don't like
being called niggers no more?
They find it offensive.
I been called worse.
Now, that I can believe.
You never heard of her, huh?
Should I?
Well, she ain't no John Wilkes Booth
but maybe you might heard tell
about the price on her head.
How much?
$10,000.
Damn.
What'd she do, kill Lily Langtry?
Not quite.
That ten thousand's practically in my pocket.
It's why I ain't too anxious
to be handin' out rides
especially to professionals open for business.
I can certainly appreciate that.
But I ain't got no designs on her.
One of my fellas over there is worth $4,000
another one's worth $3,000 and one of 'em's worth $1,000.
That's damn sure good enough for me.
Well...let me see their paperwork.
Like I said, molasses-like.
Back off.
Look, I sure hate to interrupt you all
but we got a cold damn blizzard
that's hot on our ass
that we're tryin' to beat to shelter!
I realize that!
Now, shut your mouth
and hold them damn horses while I think!
Okay, boy, we'll give it a try.
But you leave them two pistols
over yonder with the driver.
Hey, uh, you ain't really gonna let that nigger
ride in here, is ya?
I mean, maybe up there with O.B., but...
How ya like the sound of them bells, bitch?
They real pretty, ain't they?
You open up your trashy mouth again
I'll knock out them front teeth for ya.
You got it?
Yeah.
Let me hear ya say, 'I got it.
I got it.
Uh, I'm gonna need a hand tyin'
these fellas up on the roof.
Give O.B. $50 when we get to Red Rock.
He'll help ya.
Well, I agree with O.B.
This storm got me concerned.
We get goin' a lot quicker you helped out, too.
Goddamn it to hell I'm already regrettin' this.
Now, I can't likely help you
tie fellas to the roof
with my wrist cuffed to hers.
And my wrist is gonna stay cuffed to hers
and she ain't never gonna leave my goddamn side
till I personally put her in the Red Rock jail!
Now, do you got that?!
Yeah, I got it.
Good.
Get in, Dude!
Hut! Get in!
Go on! Hut!
Come on!
Dude, Coconut, giddyup.
Yah!
Hut!
Giddyup!
Yah! Cimarron!
Leche! Get in!
So, what happened to your horse?
Get in!
He was kinda old.
I done had him for a bit.
When the weather took
a turn for the worse
well, he done what he could
but he couldn't make it.
Get in!
That's too bad.
Yeah, it is.
Me and ol' Lash done rode
a lot of miles together.
Could say he was my best friend
if I considered stupid animals
friends, which I don't.
Nevertheless, I'm gonna miss him.
Leche! Ha!
Who's this Daisy Domergue?
A no damn good murdering bitch, that's who.
Come on, boys! Get up!
I see you ain't got mixed emotions
about bringing a woman to a rope.
By 'woman', you mean her?
No, I do not have mixed emotions.
Get in! Ha!
So you taking her into Red Rock to hang.
You bet.
You gonna wait round to watch it?
Oh, you know I am.
Come on! I want to hear her neck snap
with my own two ears.
Get up, boys!
You never wait to watch 'em hang?
Get up!
My bounties never hang
cause I never bring 'em in alive.
Never?
Never ever.
Ha! Get up! Yah!
We talked about this in Chattanooga.
Bringing desperate men in alive's
a good way to get yourself dead.
Get in there!
Can't catch me sleeping
if I don't close my eyes.
I don't want to work that hard.
No one said the job is supposed to be easy.
No one said it's supposed
to be that hard, neither.
Get up, boys! Ha!
But that, little lady
is why they call him 'The Hangman.
When the handbill says 'Dead or Alive'
the rest of us shoot ya in the back
from up on top of a perch somewhere
bring ya in dead over a saddle.
Get in!
But when John Ruth The Hangman catches ya
you don't die from no bullet in the back.
Mm-mm.
When The Hangman catches you, you hang.
Ha!
You overrate him, nigger.
I give ya he got guts but in the brains department
he like a man who took a high dive in a low well.
Now, Daisy
I want us to work out a signal
system of communication.
When I elbow you real hard in
the face, that means 'shut up.
You got it?
I got it.
Get in there!
Come on now, boys, get in!
* Hey, little apple blossom *
* What seems to be the problem? *
* All the ones you tell your troubles to *
* They don't really care for you *
* Come and tell me what you're thinking *
* 'Cause just when the boat is sinking *
* A little light is blinking *
* And I will come and rescue you *
* Lots of girls walk around in tears *
* But that's not for you *
* You've been looking all around for years *
* For someone to tell your troubles to *
Ha!
* Come and sit with me and talk a while *
* Let me see your pretty little smile *
* Put your troubles in a little pile *
* And I will sort them out for you, all right. *
Hyah!
Get in!
Get in there!
Mm.
Giddyup!
I, uh...I know we only met
each other the once before
and, uh, I don't mean to
unduly imply intimacy, get up!
But, well Yah!
You still got it?
Do I still got what?
Get in, now!
The Lincoln letter.
Mm. Course.
Get up, boys!
Got it on ya?
Mm-hmm.
Come on!
Where?
Right here.
Come on, boys! Get up!
Look, I know you got to be
real careful with it and all
and I can imagine you probably
don't like taking it
in and out of the envelope all that often
but, uh Get up!
If you wouldn't mind,
I'd sure appreciate seeing that again.
Get in, boys!
Ha! Giddyup!
You're right.
I don't like taking it in and out
of the envelope that much.
I...Yeah.
But Get in!
Seeing's how you saved my life and all
I suppose I could let you read it again.
Get in! Ha!
Get in there!
Get up now!
Get in!
Giddyup!
Huh!
Get in, now!
Get in!
Ole Mary Todd's calling,
so I guess it must be time for bed.
Ole Mary Todd.
Ha!
Get in!
Well, that Get up, boys!
That gets me.
Yeah, it gets me, too.
Get in! Get in!
You know what this is, tramp?
Hmm?
It's a letter from Lincoln.
Letter from Lincoln to him.
Get in there!
Yeah.
They shared a correspondence during the war.
They was pen pals.
And this is just one of the letters.
Get up!
What the
Hyah!
O.B.!
Stop!
Whoa!
Easy.
All the stupid
Like to rip my goddamn arm off!
I didn't drag her stinking ass
up this goddamn mountain
just for you to break her neck
on the outskirts of town!
You the one handed her my goddamn letter!
I didn't give it to her
I give it to you!
That nigger like to bust my jaw.
You ruin that letter of his
that nigger gonna stomp your ass to death.
And when he do, I'm gonna sit
back on that wagon wheel
watch and laugh!
How is it?
Well, she ain't help it none.
But it's all right.
Is that the way niggers treat their ladies?
You ain't no goddamn lady!
Hey, Mr.Ruth!
What?
There's another fella on
foot up here on the road.
Hey!
What?!
I said there's another fella
on foot, up here on the road.
Hey! Hey!
Considering there's a blizzard going on
whole lot of fellas walking around
wouldn't you say, Major?
Well, seeing as how I'm half of them fellas
uh, yeah, seems to be a lot of us.
This changes things, son.
$8,000 a lot of money for a nigger.
With a partner, 18's a whole lot better.
You really think I'm in cahoots
with that fella, or her?!
Put them on.
Oh, I...I ain't wearing no handcuffs.
You put those on, or you can stop
worrying about this whole thing right now!
Hey!
Hand your weapons to the driver.
Little jumpy, ain't you?
Never mind the jokes.
Just do it.
If you say so.
I do.
Okay.
I done done it.
O.B., you got 'em?
I got 'em.
Okay, fella.
You keep holding that lantern in that one hand
and you keep that other hand where I can see it.
Walk over there where I can
get a good look at ya.
Well, I'll be a goddamn dog in a manger.
Is that you, Chris Mannix?
I'm sorry, friend, do we know each other?
Not quite.
You know this fella?
Only by reputation.
Like I said, friend, you got me
at a bit of a disadvantage.
Keeping you at a disadvantage
is an advantage I intend to keep.
Uh, whoever you are, mister you sure sound tough
when you talking to a desperate
man knee-deep in snow.
I...I...I don't want no trouble.
I just want a ride.
I...I'm freezing to death!
Who is this joker?
You heard of the rebel renegade Erskine Mannix?
Mannix's Marauders?
That's them.
Scourge of South Carolina, Mannix's Marauders.
It's Erskine's youngest boy, Chris.
Brings you in my path, Chris Mannix?
Well, Mr.Face, I was riding to Red Rock
my horse stepped in a gopher hole in the snow
fucked up his leg, had to put 'er down.
You got business in Red Rock?
Yes, I do.
What?
I'm the new sheriff.
Horseshit.
Fraid not.
Where's your star?
Well, I ain't the sheriff yet.
Now, once I get there, they swear me in.
But, uh, that ain't happened yet.
And-and that's when you get your star.
You got anything that can
back any of this up?
Yeah. When we get to Red Rock.
And-and from the look of those
three frozen fuckers up there
I...I figure you a bounty hunter
open for business.
And-and I figure you taking
them three dead bodies
into Red Rock to get paid?
Three dead.
One alive.
Who's that?
Daisy Domergue.
Who the fuck is Daisy Domergue?
Not a goddamn thing to nobody
except me and the hangman.
The hangman?
Well, I'll be double-dog damned.
You're 'The Hangman' Bob Ruth!
It's John.
And you!
You're the nigger with the head!
Major Marquis!
My Lord, is that really the real head
of Major Marquis looking at me now?
Yeah, it's really me and it's really my head.
So what's going on?
Uh, y'all having a bounty hunter's picnic?
Never mind.
Uh, you taking them three dead bodies
and-and hurrying to Red Rock
to get paid, ain't you?
Yeah.
Well, the man in Red Rock's
supposed to pay you is me, the new sheriff.
So if y'all want to get paid
y'all need to get me to Red Rock.
Well, excuse me for finding it hard to believe
a town electing you to do
anything except drop dead.
So I'm supposed to freeze to death
cause you find something hard to believe?
No, I suppose not.
Put them on and come inside.
No.
Then you'll freeze.
Then you'll hang.
How so?
Stagecoach driver, could you
come down here and join us?
I got to hold these horses.
I can hear you just fine from up here.
Well, you just heard me tell this fella
I'm the new sheriff of Red Rock, right?
Yeah.
Red Rock is my town now.
And I'm gonna enter my town
in bounty hunter's chains?
No, sir!
Sorry, bushwhackers
I ain't entering Red Rock
that way.
Now, when you finally get to Red Rock
you gonna realize every Goddamn
thing I said was right.
And I expect you, O.B.
to tell the townsfolk
of Red Rock
that John Ruth let their
new sheriff freeze to death.
Ain't no bounty on my head, bushwhacker.
You let me die, that's murder.
Hold out your hands.
O.B.!
Give the major back his iron.
One thing I know for sure
this nigger-hating son of a gun
ain't partnered up with you.
Now, I'll help you protect your $8,000
you help me protect my ten.
Deal?
Well, ain't love grand?
Y'all want to lie on the ground
and make snow angels together?
Hut!
Come on!
Hyah!
Well, I'll tell you what, Bob.
The name's John.
When we get to Red Rock Hyah!
I'll buy you and Major Marquis there
dinner and booze.
Get in!
My way of saying thanks.
I don't drink with rebel renegades
and I damn sure don't break bread with them.
Well, Mr.Ruth Get up, boys!
You sound like you got
a axe to grind against the Cause.
The Cause' of a renegade army?
Get in!
Bunch of losers gone loco.
You bet I do.
Get up there! Hyah!
You wrapped yourselves up in a rebel flag
as an excuse to kill and steal.
And this ought to interest you, Warren.
Imparticular, emancipated blacks.
Sounds like my kind of fella.
Sound to me you been reading
a lot of newspapers printed in Washington, D.C.
Get in! Huh!
Anywho, I'm just trying
to let y'all know how grateful I am.
I was a goner.
And y'all saved me.
You want to show me how grateful you are?
Get in there!
Shut up.
Goddamn it, Daisy.
It's coming.
Get in there, Cimarron!
Here.
Last piece.
Get in!
Get in, now!
Hyah!
Does he know
Does he know how famous you once was?
I don't think so.
Giddyup!
Black Eye.
Do you know who he is?
Get in!
Do I know about the $30,000 reward
the Confederacy put on the
head of Major Marquis?
Come on now, boys!
Get in!
Yeah.
Ah, them hillbillies
went nigger head-hunting.
Get in!
They just never did get 'em
the right nigger head, did they?
No, they didn't.
But it wasn't for lack of trying.
Get in, boys! Ha! Get on!
Them peckerwoods left their homes and families
and come up this snowy mountain
looking for me and fortune.
Ha! Get up!
Ain't none of 'em found fortune.
The ones you ain't never heard of no more
they found me.
Now, it didn't stay $30,000
the length of the war.
Once passions cooled
it dropped down to eight, then five.
Get up, boys! Ha!
But I bet even when it was 5,000
you had your share of country boys coming to call.
Mm, you know I did.
Why'd they have
a reward on you?
Confederates took exception to
my capacity for killing 'em.
Get up, now!
And after I broke out of Wellenbeck
well, the South took
my continued existence
as a personal affront.
Get up!
And the Cause put a reward on my head.
Hmm.
Get in there!
What's, uh, Wellenbeck?
You ain't never heard
of Wellenbeck prisoner of war camp, West Virginia?
No, reb, I ain't never heard of it.
Hyah!
Did you bust out?
Oh
Major Marquis did more than bust out.
Major Marquis had a bright idea.
Get in, now!
So bright, you got to wonder
why nobody never thought about it before.
Tell John Ruth your bright idea.
Well, the whole damn place
was just made out of kindling.
Get in!
So I burnt it down.
Get in! Hyah!
There was a rookie regiment
spending overnight in the camp.
47 men burnt to a crisp.
Southern youth, farmer's sons Get up!
Cream of the crop.
And I say, 'Let 'em burn.
I'm supposed to apologize
for killing Johnny Reb?
You joined the war to keep niggers in chains.
I joined the war to kill
white Southern crackers.
Ha! Get up!
And that means killing 'em any way I can.
Get in!
Shoot 'em, stab 'em
drown 'em, burn 'em
drop a big ol' rock on their head.
Whatever it took to put
white Southern crackers
in the ground, get up!
That's what I joined the war to do.
And that's what I did.
To answer your question, John Ruth
when Major Marquis burned 47 men alive
for no more reason than to give
a nigger a run for the trees
that's when the South put a reward
on the head of Major Marquis.
And I made them trees, Mannix.
Get in!
You best believe I ain't looked back
till I crossed the Northern line.
Oh, but you had a surprise waiting for you
on the Northern side, didn't you?
See, once they started pulling out
all them burnt bodies at Wellenbeck
seems not all them boys were rebs.
Why, you burn up some of your own boys
didn't you, Major?
How many burnt prisoners
they end up finding?
Wasn't the final Yankee death count
something like 37?
Giddyup!
That's the thing about war, Mannix.
People die.
Oh!
So you gonna chalk it up
to 'war is hell', huh?
Well, admittedly, that is a hard argument to argue with.
But if memory serves
your side didn't look at it that way.
I think they thought 37 white men
for one nigger
wasn't so hot a trade.
I do believe they accused you Giddyup!
Of being a kill-crazy nigger
who only joined the war
to kill white folks
and the whole blue and gray of it all
really didn't matter that much to you.
Ha! Get up!
And that's why they drummed your black ass
out of the cavalry with a
yellow stripe down your back.
Get in!
Isn't it, Major?
Horseshit!
If he'd have did all that, the cavalry
would've shot him.
Get in!
Well, I didn't say they could prove it.
Get up!
But they sure did
think it out loud, didn't they, Major?
Hyah! Get up, boys!
But Warren's war record was stellar
and that's what saved his ass.
Hyah!
Now, you killed yourself your share
of redskins in your day didn't you, Black Major?
Cavalry tends to look kindly on that.
I'll tell you what the cavalry
didn't look kindly on.
Giddyup!
Mannix's Marauders
that's what.
Get in! Hyah!
And the fact that Erskine Mannix's little boy
would talk about anybody else's behavior
during war time makes me want to horse-laugh.
Hyah!
Don't you say anything about my daddy.
What he fought for was dignity in defeat Get up there!
And against the unconditional surrender.
We weren't foreign barbarians
pounding on the city walls.
Ha!
We were your brothers.
Get up, now!
We deserved dignity in defeat.
Just how many nigger towns did y'all sack
in your fight for dignity in defeat?
Oh, my fair share, Black Major.
Cause when niggers are scared, huh!
That's when white folks are safe.
You gonna talk that hateful nigger talk
you can ride up top with O.B.
No.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You done got me talking politics.
I didn't want to.
Like I said, y'all I'm just happy to be alive.
Get in, now!
Ha! Get up!
I think I'll scoot over here
right by this window
and let this beautiful carriage rock me to sleep.
And dream about how lucky I am.
Get up, now!
Ha!
Hyah! Get in!
Get in there!
Get in, hyah!
Get in!
Get in there, Leche!
Get in there!
Whoa, whoa, easy.
Whoa! Whoa!
What the hell is going on?
We weren't expecting another stage tonight!
Yeah, I can see you already
got another one up in here.
Just got through putting the horses away.
Well, this ain't the normal line
but we are stuck on the wrong side of a blizzard
so it looks like you're stuck with us.
Are Minnie and Sweet Dave inside?
They ain't here.
I'm running the place while they're gone.
Where's Minnie and Sweet Dave?
He says they ain't here.
He's looking after the place while they're gone.
Who are you?
I'm Bob.
Well, whoever you are help O.B. with the horses.
Come on.
Get 'em out of this cold 'fore
that blizzard hits us.
Whoa! You all right?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Esperate, esperate, esperate!
I just put those other horses away.
You need it done fast you need to help.
I got two of my best men on it.
You heard him, freeloaders.
Get to work!
All right, you two, unhook the leaders.
Come on, let's go.
Open up!
You have to kick it open!
Ya got to kick it open!
What?
Kick it open!
Shut that door.
There's a goddamn blizzard out there!
You have to stop, close the door!
You got to nail it shut.
You have to, you have to nail it shut!
Hold it shut!
There's a hammer and nails by the door!
You have to nail it shut!
There's a hammer and nails by the door.
Give me a hammer.
Yeah.
You need, you need two pieces of wood!
You need two pieces of wood!
One ain't good enough!
Two pieces of wood!
The fuckin' thing is busted!
Not just one piece of wood!
Give me another piece of wood.
Yeah. All right.
I need a nail.
Here.
Jesus.
That door's a son of a gun.
Who's the idiot who broke that
that Mexican fella?
Oh, good heavens!
A woman?
Out in this white hell?
You must be frozen solid, poor thing.
Looks like Minnie's got her a full house.
When did you fellas arrive?
Ah.
About 40 minutes ago.
That cowboy fella in the corner
that your driver?
No, no, he's a passenger.
The driver lit out.
Said he was going to spend the blizzard
shacked up with a friend.
Lucky devil.
Jesus Christ, that's awful!
Christ Almighty
what'd that Mexican fella do soak his old socks in a pot?
Yes, uh...I...I think we all felt the same way
but were a little too polite to say something.
He don't have that problem.
Shit.
Where's the well water?
Uh, over there.
So, all three of you fellas headed to Red Rock
when the blizzard stopped you, huh?
Yes. All three of us were on
that stagecoach out there.
Coffee beans.
Uh, over there.
Get your hand out of there.
New sheriff of Red Rock's
travelin' with us.
Ah, sheriff of Red Rock, that'll be the day.
He's a goddamn sheriff I'm a monkey's uncle.
Good.
Then you can share bananas
with your nigger friend in the stable.
So
the new sheriff of Red Rock
is traveling with you?
Oh, he's lying.
He ain't sheriff of nothin.
He's a Southern renegade.
He's just talking hisself
out of freezing to death is all.
What the fuck I tell you about talking, huh?
I'll bust you in the mouth
right in front of these people.
I don't give a fuck!
You never gave your name, sir.
John Ruth.
Are you a lawman?
I'm taking her to the law.
So you're a bounty hunter?
That's right, buster.
Do you have a warrant?
Yeah, course I do.
May I see it?
Why?
Ah! You're supposed to produce it upon request.
How am I supposed to know
you're not a villain
kidnapping this woman
without a warrant in your possession?
What's your name, buster?
Well, it certainly isn't Buster.
It's Oswaldo Mobray.
Oswaldo?
Yes.
Well
I got my warrant, Oswaldo.
I take it you're Daisy Domergue?
That's her.
Yeah.
I see.
Uh, it says here 'Dead or Alive.
Yeah. It does.
Well, transporting a desperate
hostile prisoner such as her
sounds like hard work.
Wouldn't transporting her be easier
if she were dead?
Well, no one said the job
was supposed to be easy.
And why is her hanging proper
so important to you?
Let's just say I don't like
cheatin' the hangman.
He got to make a living, too.
Well, I appreciate that.
Allow me to properly
introduce myself.
I'm Oswaldo Mobray
the hangman in these parts.
La-di-da.
Ah.
Looks like I brought you a customer.
Yeah, so it would appear.
You ever spent two days or more
locked up with one of your customers before?
I can't say I have.
Don't talk to my prisoner.
I talk to my prisoner, that's it.
You got it?
I got it.
Jolly good.
You got anything in here
besides coffee
that can help warm us up?
Well, the bar is open.
Follow moi.
Line, O.B.!
Oh, whoa.
Oh!
Whoa!
Hey.
Whoa, Ace, whoa.
You're all right, you're all right.
Come on, goddamn it.
I'm cold!
I'll feed and water the horses.
You go inside and get some hot coffee.
Got some stew cooking.
Should be done soon.
Now, look.
No matter how bad this blizzard gets
we still got to feed these horses
and take a squat from time to time.
So me and Chris better lay out a line
from the stable to the front door
and from the front door to the shithouse.
Okay?
Good idea.
Come on, Chris.
I'll give you a hand.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Go inside. Get warm.
You're doin' stable work
in a goddamn blizzard.
I offer to help, you say no?
You're right, amigo.
Muchas gracias.
All right. Follow me.
We're gonna drop one every ten paces
from here to the door.
Yeah!
All right!
Now, you're wanted for murder.
For the sake of my analogy
let's just assume that you did it.
Now, John Ruth wants to take
you back to Red Rock
to stand trial for murder.
And if you're found guilty
the people of Red Rock
will hang you in the town square.
And, as the hangman
I will perform the execution.
And if all those things
end up taking place
that's what civilized society
calls justice.
However
if the relatives and the loved ones
of the person you murdered
were outside that door right now
and after busting down that door
they drug you out into the snow
and hung you up by the neck
that would be frontier justice.
Now, the good part
about frontier justice
is it's very thirst-quenching.
The bad part is it's
apt to be wrong as right.
Well, not in your case.
In your case, you'd have it coming.
But other people, maybe not so much.
But ultimately, what's the real difference
between the two?
The real difference is me.
The hangman.
To me, it doesn't matter what you did.
When I hang you, I'll get no
satisfaction from your death.
It's my job.
I hang you in Red Rock.
I move on to the next town.
I hang someone else there.
The man who pulls the lever
that breaks your neck
will be a dispassionate man.
And that dispassion is the
very essence of justice.
For justice delivered without dispassion
is always in danger
of not being justice.
Amen.
No offense, cowboy fella.
Just gettin' your attention.
Yeah, well
you got it.
What you writin', friend?
Only thing I'm qualified to write about.
What's that?
My life story.
You're writing your life story?
You bet I am.
Am I in it?
You just entered.
Well, you like writing stories so much
why don't you tell me the
story that brings you here?
Who's asking?
I am. John Ruth.
I'm bringing in this one
to Red Rock to hang.
And ain't no way I'm spending
a couple of nights
under a roof with somebody
I don't know who they are
and I don't know who you are.
So, who are you?
Joe Gage.
What?
That's my name.
Joe Gage.
Okay, Joe Gage.
Why you going to Red Rock?
I ain't, I ain't, I ain't going to Red Rock.
Where you going?
About nine miles outside of Red Rock.
What's there?
My mother.
Your mother?
Listen, I'm just a cowpuncher.
I just, uh, got back from a long drive, and
and I wasn't just an ass
in a saddle this time.
I was a partner.
First time in my life
I made a pretty penny.
And, uh
figured I'd come home
and spend time with my mother
for Christmas.
Now, that's funny.
Cause you don't look like
the coming-home-for-Christmas
type.
Yeah, well
you know, looks can be deceiving.
Because I definitely am a
coming-home-for-Christmas-to-spend-time-with-Mother type.
Christmas with Mother, I mean, uh
it's a wonderful thing.
Now, is that, uh
good enough for you
John Ruth?
For now.
You steer clear of my prisoner.
Hello, old-timer.
General.
You, sir, are a hyena.
I have no wish to speak to you.
I've been called worse.
Fair enough, General.
Sorry to bother you.
Hey!
You gotta kick it open!
Gotta kick it open!
What?
Kick it open!
That latch, you gotta kick it open!
You gotta kick it open!
Jesus Christ!
Close it!
Close the door!
What?
Close it!
The goddamn door!
It doesn't have a latch.
Close it!
It's already cold enough in here!
Doesn't have a latch.
You gotta hammer up a board.
You gotta nail it shut!
The hammer and nails by the door.
There's a hammer and nails right there!
Ah, God!
Hold this here, Chris.
Here! Here.
Watch your fingers.
Yeah.
Really nail it in!
You need two pieces of wood.
You got to hammer another one.
One ain't good enough!
It's gonna blow right open!
Now, goddamn it!
Gonna open if you don't ham...!
Shut up!
Ah, got it!
Son of a bitch!
Jesus Christ.
That's door's a whore.
Oh!
I get it, 'Haberdashery.
That was a joke.
How's the coffee?
Now? Pretty good, if I do say so myself.
Thank you.
Ooh!
Ha! Navajo!
Guess who he is.
Buffalo Bill?
Hardly.
No. I'm
Oswaldo Mobray.
I'm the
He's the hangman of Red Rock.
Oh, you are?
Yes, I am.
Well!
Uh, good to meet you, uh.
Yeah.
Mr...?
Uh, Mobray.
Mobray.
Yeah.
I'm Chris Mannix.
The new sheriff in Red Rock.
Really?
Pfft, horseshit!
Pay no attention to him.
Horseshit!
Fella warmin' himself
by that potbelly stove
is a hell of a driver named O.B.
Ah.
That's the only thing
you've said that's the truth.
You comin' into Red Rock
to hang Lance Lawson?
Precisely.
Do you have the execution orders on you?
In my bag.
May I see 'em?
Of course.
Who's, uh, who's Lance Lawson?
He's a fella been sittin' in the Red Rock jail
about a month now.
He's the fella who shot the fella
who was sheriff 'fore me.
Precisely.
Thank you.
What did she mean when she said
The bounty hunter's nigger friend in the stable'?
He's got a nigger bounty hunter
friend in the stable.
But all that just to guard her?
Uh, I don't think that was
the original idea, but
that's the idea now.
Oh! Mm.
Want a little snake bite in your coffee?
Yeah.
Five of you?
Well, well, well, looks like Minnie's Haberdashery
is about to get cozy for the next few days.
Yes, it does.
Here.
Ah!Ah.
Are you the chap with the Lincoln letter?
The Lincoln what?
Yes. The letter from Abraham Lincoln.
President Abraham Lincoln?
Yes. Weren't you pen pals?
With the president?
Well, I'm sorry, I heard that somebody in your party
had a letter from Abraham Lincoln.
I assumed it was you.
Not him!
Black fella in the stable.
The nigger
in the stable has a letter
from Abraham Lincoln?
Yeah.
The nigger in the stable has
a letter from Abraham Lincoln?
What'd you say your name was again?
Bob.
Warren.
Minnie and Sweet Dave in there?
Minnie and Sweet Dave went
to visit her mother
on the north side of the mountain.
What?
Yeah.
Minnie ain't here?
Yes, they're visiting her mother.
Her mother?
Yes.
Hmm.
Never knew Minnie had a mother.
Well, everybody's got a mother.
Yeah, I suppose.
And she left you in charge?
Si.
That sure don't sound like Minnie.
Are you calling me a liar?
Well, not yet I ain't.
Just sounds peculiar is all.
What sounds peculiar?
Well, first off Minnie never struck me
as the sentimental type.
And secondly, I can't imagine
Sweet Dave lifting his fat ass
out his chair long enough
to fetch well water
unless Minnie was laying a
frying pan upside his head
let alone take a trip to the north side.
Well, that sounds a whole lot
like you're calling me a liar mi negro amigo.
Yeah, it do sound a whole
lot like that, don't it?
But I still ain't done it yet.
Minnie still serve food?
Do you consider stew food?
Yes.
Then we serve food.
She still stinking up the place
with Old Quail pipe tobacco?
Minnie doesn't smoke a pipe.
She rolls her own.
Red Apple Tobacco.
But, mi negro amigo I think you already know this.
Yeah, I do, Senor Bob.
Just seeing if you do.
Come on!
Fill 'er up, O.B.
Yeah.
Goddamn it.
Thank you.
Well, cut my legs off
and call me Shorty.
Is that General Sanford Smithers I see?
You got a good eye, son.
Ha-ha! Well, I'll be double-dog damned!
General Sandy 'Don't Give a Damn' Smithers?
Captain Chris Mannix, Mannix's Marauders.
Erskine's boy?
Yes, sir.
Uh...may I sit down, sir?
Well, according to the Yankees it's a free country.
General Sandy Smithers.
Ha-ha!
Boy
oh, boy
did my daddy talk about you!
I heard you gave those
Blue Bellies sweet hell.
Me and my boys did our part.
Just like Erskine and his boys
did their part.
Hell yeah, we did.
Yankee sons of bitches.
I never knew your father, son.
But I always respected
his resolve.
Well, thank you for saying that, General.
Your respect would have
meant the world to him.
Can I get you some coffee?
That'd be nice.
Well, how about a blanket?
That'd be even nicer.
Hell, you know what?
You can have mine.
Here we go, General.
Ha-ha! So what brings you
out Wyoming way, sir?
If you don't mind my askin.
My boy.
Oh, you got a boy that lives in Red Rock?
My son.
Chester Charles Smithers.
He died out here a few years back.
Oh, forgive me, sir.
There's no forgiveness needed, son.
Like I said, it was a few years back.
It was after he'd served his service.
He came out here to the hills of Wyoming
to make his fortune.
Never to be heard from again.
I bought him a symbolic plot
in the Red Rock cemetery.
And I'm here to advise a
stone maker on his headstone.
Was he a goner for sure?
No chance he could be livin' the cold life
out in the woods?
It's a rough life but folks can learn it.
If he'd have done what he came out here to do
he'd have come home.
Hold it. Close it, close it!
You have to hold it closed
while I nail it shut.
Well, who's the idiot
broke the damn door?
Oh, j-j-j
just fucking hold it closed!
Orale, cabron!
Hold it closed.
Okay.
One more.
Keep holding, keep holding
my negro amigo.
We need two pieces of wood.
Orale, cabron!
All right.
There you go, motherfucker!
Lot of hats, Senor Bob.
Huh?
Considering Minnie's 'no hats indoors' policy
which, if I remember correctly
was one of them Bar of Iron rules.
Kind of rule she'd want
kept up in her absence.
You seem to have a laissez-faire attitude
when it come to the hats.
I'm guilty.
I have a laissez-faire attitude about the hats.
How about we forget
about the hats today
considering there is a blizzard going on and on?
We'll make tomorrow 'No Hat Day'!
A large black dog.
* Now take my tip *
* Before you ship to join *
His name was Henry, I believe.
* The iron gang *
Labrador.
* Don't be too gay *
* In Botany Bay *
* Or else you'll surely hang *
* Or else you'll hang, you'll hang, said he...*
You know, my daddy
I...I said that my-my daddy
always said that Davis
A plum tree.
Was a courageous man
but he should've put the capital
in Montgomery and not Richmond.
Yes, sir.
I agree with that.
The army in northern Virginia would've been used
in a very different way.
I said the army
of north Virginia would've been
used in a very different way!
* They'll flog the poaching out of you *
* Out there in Botany Bay *
Shut up!
O.B.
Do you know that nigger, sir?
I don't know that nigger.
But I know he's a nigger and that's all I need to know.
Well
that nigger just ain't any nigger.
That nigger, he
General Sanford Smithers?
Battle of Baton Rouge?
Inform the nigger
in the cavalry officer's uniform
that I had a division of Confederates
under my command
in Baton Rouge.
Major Nigger, General Smithers
wishes me to inform you
I heard him, hillbilly.
Inform this old cracker that
I was in Baton Rouge also.
On the other side.
Oh, that's interesting.
Uh, General Smithers
he said that he was also in
Baton Rouge on the other si
Captain Mannix
tell the nigger
that I don't acknowledge niggers
in Northern uniforms.
You captured a whole colored command
that day
but not one colored trooper
made it to a camp, did they?
We didn't have the time
or the food
nor the inclination
to care for Northern horses
and least of all
Northern niggers!
So we shot 'em where they stood!
Gentlemen.
I knowAmericans aren't apt
to let a little thing like unconditional surrender
get in the way of a good war.
But I strongly suggest we don't restage
the Battle of Baton Rouge
during a blizzard in Minnie's Haberdashery.
Now, uh
my Nubian friend
while I realize passions are high
that was a while ago.
And if you shoot this unarmed old man
I guarantee I will hang you by the neck
until you are dead once we arrive in Red Rock.
I damn well guarantee that, too.
Yeah, Warren
that's the problem with old men.
You can kick 'em down the stairs
and say it's a accident but you can't just shoot 'em.
Uh, gentlemen...since we may be
trapped here
close together-like
for a few days
may I suggest a possible solution?
We divide Minnie's in half.
The Northern side
and the Southern side.
With the dinner table
operating as a
neutral territory.
We could say that the fireplace
side of the room acts as a
a symbolic representative of
Georgia.
While the bar
represents
Philadelphia!
Long as the bar's Philadelphia
I agree.
We still got that deal we
talked about in the wagon?
Thank you.
I help you protect your $8,000
you help me protect my ten?
Yeah, I suppose.
One of them fellas
is not what he says he is.
What is he?
In cahoots with this one, that's what he is.
One of them, maybe even two of them
is here to see Domergue goes free.
To accomplish that goal they'll kill everybody in here.
They got 'em a couple of days
so all they got to do is sit tight
and wait for a window of opportunity.
And that's when they strike.
Huh, bitch?
If you say so, John.
Are you sure you
ain't just being paranoid?
Our best bet is this duplicitous fella
ain't as cool a customer as Daisy here.
He won't have the leather patience it takes
to just sit here and...wait.
Waiting for an opportunity
and knowing it's the right one isn't so easy.
He can't handle it
he'll stop waitin.
Try and create his opportunity
and that's when Mr.Jumpy reveals himself.
Now, what you got to say about all this?
What do I got to say?
About John Ruth's ravings?
He's absolutely right.
Me and one of them fellas is in cahoots.
We're just waiting for everybody to go to sleep.
That's when we're gonna kill y'all.
Okay, everybody.
Hear this.
This here is Daisy Domergue.
She's wanted dead or alive for murder.
$10,000.
That money's mine, boys.
Don't want to share it
and I ain't gonna lose it.
When that sun comes out
I'm taking this woman
into Red Rock to hang.
Now
is there anybody here
committed to stoppin' me
from doing that?
Really?
Nobody got a problem with this?
Well
I guess that's very fortunate for me.
However
I hope you all understand
I can't just
take your word.
Circumstances force me to
take
precautions.
When you say
precautions'
why do I feel that you mean me?
Because I'm gonna take your gun, son.
You are?
Yes, I am.
Nothing personal.
Just mine?
Hangman's got himself a gun, too.
I'll be dealing with his gun
after I deal with yours.
I feel kind of
naked without it.
Oh, I still got mine.
I'll protect you.
A bastard's work is never done.
Huh, John Ruth?
That's right, Joe Gage.
Now, give me the gun.
If you want it
you're gonna have to come and take
Calm down.
Take your hand away from your gun.
Blink if you're calm.
He blink?
He blinked.
Blink if you're gonna remain calm.
Take his pistol.
I'm real sorry about this, son.
Like I said
nothing personal, just
a precaution.
Pretty sneaky.
Afraid the same applies to you, too
Mr...Mobray.
Ah, precautions must be taken
because life is too sweet to lose.
Hand me that little bucket.
O.B.
Go to the outhouse.
Take this bucket and dump it down the shithole.
Why do I got to go outside?
Well, your jacket's already on
and I sorta kinda trust you.
Grab the other cup.
Yeah, I got it.
After you, Major.
Okay.
I'm gonna cut you loose while we eat.
Don't get any ideas.
I ain't goin' soft on ya.
Lift your ass even one inch off that seat
and I'll put a bullet right
in your goddamn throat.
Come here.
Oh!
So, Domergue
I suppose this blizzard
counts as a stroke of luck
far as you're concerned.
You don't hear me complainin', do ya?
No, I sure don't.
Well, how 'bout you, Oswaldo?
How 'bout me what?
Look
considering all the things
I done for money
I ain't one to judge, but
don't you feel just the least little bad
about hangin' a woman?
Well, until they invent a
trigger a woman can't pull
if you're a hangman you're going to hang women.
Well, hell, Ozzie, I guess
I ain't never looked at it like that before.
When it comes to some of them
mean bastards out there
it's the only thing does the job.
You really only need
to hang mean bastards.
But mean bastards, you need to hang.
You goddamn son of a bitch!
I almost died out there!
I ain't ever...going out in that shit
ever, ever again!
You okay, O.B.?
I'm fine.
I'll be fine.
I just need to get warm.
You want some stew, O.B.?
Stew?
Later.
Oh, yeah.
That's nice.
So
how you doing, Black Major?
I ain't in the mood, Chris Mannix.
Leave me be from your horseshit.
John Ruth says you got a Lincoln letter.
I told you, jackass, go hee-haw someplace else.
That's right, John.
You did say that, didn't you?
Yeah, I did.
So
you got a letter from Abraham Lincoln?
Yes.
The...Abraham Lincoln?
Abraham Lincoln?
The President of the United States?
Yes.
OfAmerica?
Wrote you a letter
personally?
Yes.
Personally, as in 'Dear Major Warren'?
No, personally, as in 'Dear Marquis.
Dear Marquis'?
Abraham Lincoln
the President of the United States ofAmerica?
Yes.
May I see it?
No, you may not.
But the way John tells it
you weren't just some random nigger soldier
picked from a pile of letters.
Way John tells it
y'all had a correspondence.
Yes.
The way John tells it
y'all was practically pen pals.
Yes.
And a pen pal's
practically a friend.
John Ruth
you really think a nigger
drummed out of the cavalry with
a yellow stripe down his back
was practically friends
with the President of the United States ofAmerica?
John Ruth, I hate to be the one to break it to you
but ain't nobody in Minnie's
Haberdashery ever corresponded
with Abraham Lincoln.
Least of all
that nigger there!
Was all that horseshit?
Course it was.
Good one, Warren!
Talk that sass, nigger!
Talk that sass!
Well, I guess it's true what
they say about you people.
Can't trust a fuckin' word
comes out of your mouth.
What's the matter, John Ruth?
I hurt your feelings?
As a matter of fact
you did.
I...I know
I'm the only black son of a
bitch you ever conversed with
so I'm gonna cut you some slack.
But you got no idea what it's like
being a black man facin' down America.
Only time black folks is safe
is when white folks is disarmed.
And this letter had the desired effect
of disarmin' white folks.
Call it what you want.
I call it a dirty fuckin' trick.
You want to know why I lie
about somethin' like that, white man?
Got me on that stagecoach, didn't it?
Well, I'll tell you like
the good Lord told John.
A letter from Abraham Lincoln wouldn't have had
that kind of effect on me.
I might let a whore piss on it.
I spit on it.
Good for you, sister!
Warren.
Goddamn it, you leave that old man alone.
Stand down, you son of a bitch.
I shared a battlefield with this man.
Or would you deny me that, too?
I suppose you were there.
May I join you?
Yes, you may.
Damn it.
So, how's life since the war?
Got both my legs.
Both my arms.
I can't complain.
Got a woman?
Fever took her start of this last winter.
Mm.
What was her name?
Betsy.
Georgia gal?
Augusta.
Atlanta boy, Augusta girl.
I used to raise Kentucky horses.
And her pa was the owner of the breedership
where I bought most of my ponies.
Goddamn it.
I made a good deal on her.
Took the stake he gave me
and bought a bunch of peach orchards.
Set myself up pretty well.
Did a hell of a lot better
than either one of my no-good
brothers, that's for damn sure.
Hmm.
Yeah, your boy come up
here a few years back.
He spoke highly of his mama, too.
You knew my boy?
Did I know him?
Yep.
Yeah, I knew him.
You did not know my boy.
Suit yourself.
Did you know my son?
I know the day he died.
Do you?
No.
Do you want to know what day that was?
Yes.
The day
he met me.
He come up here
to do a little
nigger head-huntin.
By then, the reward was, oh
$5,000 and braggin' rights.
But to battle-hard rebs
$5,000 just to cut off a nigger's head?
That's good money.
So them Johnnies climbed this mountain
lookin' for fortune.
There wasn't no fortune to be found.
All they found
was me.
All them crackers come up
here sang a different tune
when they found theyself at
the mercy of a nigger's gun.
Let's just forget it.
I'll go my way, you go your'n.
That's your boy Chester talkin.
You're a goddamn lie!
If you just let me go home
to my family, I...I swear
I'll never set foot in Wyoming again.
That's what they all said.
Beggin' for his life
your boy told me
his whole life story.
And you
was in that story, General.
And when I knew me I had
the son
of the Bloody Nigger Killer of Baton Rouge
I knew me I was gonna have some fun.
You shut your lyin' nigger lips up!
General Smithers, don't you listen to him.
He didn't know your boy.
He just heard tell why you're here, is all.
It was cold the day I killed your boy.
And I don't mean
snowy-mountain-Wyoming cold, uh-uh.
It was colder than that.
And on that cold day, with your boy
at the business end of my gun barrel
I made him strip
right down to his bare ass.
Then I told him to start walkin.
I walked his naked ass
for two hours
Fore the cold collapsed him.
You never even knew my boy?
No, he didn't!
He's just a sneaky nigger
trying to get you to go for that gun.
Then he commenced to beggin' again.
But this time he wasn't beggin' to go home.
Ah, he knew he'd never see his home again.
He wasn't beggin' for his life, neither
cause he knew that was long gone.
All he wanted
was a blanket.
Now, don't judge your boy too harshly, General.
You ain't never been cold
as your boy was that day.
You'd be surprised
what a man that cold
would do for a blanket.
You want to know what your boy did?
I pulled my big black pecker
out of my pants
and I made him crawl through the snow
on all fours over to it.
Then I grabbed me a handful
of that black hair
at the back of his head
and I stuck my big black johnson
right down his goddamn throat.
And it was full of blood so it was warm.
Oh, you bet your sweet ass it was warm.
And Chester Charles Smithers
sucked on that warm black dingus
for long as he could!
You're startin' to see pictures, ain't ya?
Your boy
black dude's dingus in his mouth
him sh-sh-shakin', him cryin'
me laughin'
and him not understandin.
But you understand don't you, Sandy?
I never did give your boy that blanket
even after all he did
and he did everything I asked.
No blanket.
That blanket was just a heart-breakin' liar's promise.
Kind of like those uniforms
the Union issued those colored troops
that you chose not to acknowledge.
So what you gonna do old man? Hmm?
You gonna spend the next two, three days
ignorin' the nigger that killed your boy?
Ignorin' how I made him suffer?
Ignoring how I made him
lick...all over my johnson?
Oh, the dumbest thing your boy ever did
was to let me know
he was your boy.
About 15 minutes has past
since we last left our characters.
Joe Gage volunteered to take
Smither's dead body outside.
Straws were drawn to see who'd help him.
O.B. lost.
Chris, John Ruth and Oswaldo
had a vigorous debate
about the legality of the self-defense murder
that just transpired.
Major Marquis Warren who was supremely confident
about the legality of what just transpired
ignored them sat at the table by himself
and drank brandy.
Captain Chris Mannix donned
the dead general's coat
and joined Oswaldo in lighting
the candles and lanterns.
Hey, Ozzie!
Now, you got the right idea.
Let's light this place up.
John Ruth held the door closed
waiting for Joe Gage and O.B. to return.
Bob enjoyed a Manzana Roja.
Domergue, however hasn't moved from her spot
at the community dinner table
since John Ruth uncuffed her.
John Ruth.
Yeah.
Can I play that guitar over there?
Let's go back a bit.
Your boy, black dude's dingus in his mouth.
15 minutes ago, Major Warren
shot General Smithers in front of everybody.
But about 40 seconds before that
something equally as important happened
but not everybody saw it.
While Major Warren was captivating the crowd
with tales of black dicks in white mouths
somebody
poisoned the coffee.
He did everything I asked.
No blanket.
And the only one to see him do it
was Domergue.
That's why this chapter is called
Domergue's Got a Secret.
John Ruth.
Yeah.
Can I play that guitar over there?
You come back with anything else but a guitar
my pistol plays a tune.
Domergue's Death March.
You got it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I got it.
* Listen for a moment, lads *
* And hear me tell my tale *
* O'er the sea from England shore *
* I was condemned to sail *
* Jury found me guilty, sir *
* And said the judge, said he *
* For life, Jim Jones *
* I sentence you across the stormy sea *
* Have no chance of mischief there *
* Remember what I say *
* They'll flog the poaching out of you *
* Out there in Botany Bay *
* Waves were high upon the sea *
* The winds approaching gales *
* I'd rather drowned in misery *
* Than come
to New South Wales *
* The waves were high upon the sea *
* When the pirates came along *
* But the soldiers on our convict ship *
* Were full 500 strong *
* They opened fire and somehow drove *
* That pirate ship away *
* I'd rather join that pirate ship *
* Than gone to Botany Bay *
* And one dark night *
* When everything is quiet in the town *
* I'll kill you bastards one and all *
* I'll gun the floggers down *
* Give them all a little shock *
* Remember what I say *
* Yet regret they sent Jim Jones *
* In chains to Botany Bay. *
That's the one you like to
sing in the stagecoach, huh?
Yeah.
It's kinda pretty.
Got another verse to it?
Yeah, lots.
Well, go ahead, sing it.
Whatever you say, John.
* Now day and night the irons clang *
* And like poor galley slaves *
* We toil and toil and when we die *
* Must fill dishonored graves *
* By and by I'll break my chains *
* And to the bush I'll go *
* And you'll be dead behind me, John *
* When I get to Mexico. *
Give me that guitar.
Music time's over!
Wha...Hey!
Whoa! Whoa, whoa!
Whoa!
Turn around!
John, no!
No, no, no, no, no!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Shut up!
When you get to hell, John
tell 'em Daisy sent ya.
Mannix, the coffee!
Oh, my God!
Oh! Aah!
Give me that fucking gun.
Don't test me, bitch.
Everybody!
Get your backsides up
against that back wall over yonder.
Well, goddamn it!
Get or don't get, Joe Gage.
It's up to you.
I'm gettin.
Then get!
You, too, Senor Bob.
Everybody turn around
and put your hands on that wall.
Move them damn snowshoes!
Everybody keep your mouths shut.
Do like I say.
You open your mouth
you gonna get a bullet.
Move a little sudden
a little strange
you gonna get a bullet.
Not a warnin', not a question.
A bullet.
You got that?
Let me hear you say 'I got it!'
I got it.
We have it.
Chris Mannix come over here on this side.
Come on.
Take this gun out my holster.
Point it at them.
Now, like I said
anybody does anything
and I mean anything
you kill 'em.
So
you finally decided I'm tellin' the truth
about bein' the sheriff of Red Rock, huh?
I don't know about all that.
But I know you ain't the killer
poisoned that coffee
cause you almost drunk it
your own damn self.
One of them is.
Aah!
Ow!
Give me the key.
Give me the key!
You motherfucking black bastard!
You're gonna die on this mountain
and I'm gonna fucking laugh when you do!
What'd I say 'bout talkin'?
Bastard.
Meant it, didn't I?
And you need to understand
you just killed the only man here
committed to gettin' you to Red Rock alive.
Now, one of y'all
is workin' with her.
Or two of y'all is workin' with her.
Or all y'all is.
But only one of you
poisoned the coffee.
Now, what charms this bitch got
make a man brave a blizzard
kill in cold blood?
I'm sure I don't know.
But John Ruth's tryin' to hang your woman.
So you kill him.
Okay.
Maybe.
But O.B. wasn't hangin' nobody.
He damn sure wasn't.
But he sure enough layin' over there dead
now, though, ain't he?
He damn sure is you sons of bitches.
Just like any one of us
would've drunk that coffee.
Like me, goddamn it.
Now, those of y'all with
your hands on the wall
don't practice in poison
need to think about that.
Think about how it could've been you
rollin' around here on this floor.
And how the man standin' next to you
would be responsible.
And I know who I got my money on.
Oh, that's right, Joe Gage.
I'm lookin' at you.
Not so fast, Chris.
We'll get there.
Let's slow it down.
Let's slow it way down.
Who made the coffee?
He did.
Yeah, he did, didn't he?
Yeah, he did didn't he?
But it's the stew that's got me thinkin.
Now, how long you said Minnie been gone?
A week?
Si.
See
my mama used to make stew
and it always tasted the same
no matter the meat.
And there was another fellow on the plantation
Uncle Charly.
He made stew, too.
And like my mama
I ate his stew from the time
I was a whipper
till I was a full-grown man.
No matter the meat
it always tasted like Uncle Charly's stew.
Now, I ain't had Minnie's stew
in six months so I ain't no expert.
But that damn sure is
Minnie's stew.
So if Minnie is on the north side
visitin' her mama for a week
how'd she make the stew this mornin'?
Hmm.
And this
this is Sweet Dave's chair.
When I sat in it earlier
I couldn't believe it.
Nobody sits in Sweet Dave's chair.
Uh, this may be Minnie's place
but this is damn sure
Sweet Dave's chair.
And if he went to the north side
I'm pretty goddamn sure
this chair be goin' with him.
What's in the chair?
Just what I thought.
Sweet Dave's goddamn blood.
Hoo!
Hoo-hoo-hoo!
So, are you actually accusing me of murder?
Way I see it, Senor Bob
is whoever is workin' with her
ain't who they say they is.
And if it's you
that means Minnie and her man
ain't at her mama's.
They layin' out back there dead somewhere.
Or if it's you little British man
the real Oswaldo Mobray layin'
in a ditch somewhere
and you just a English fella
passin' off his papers.
Or we go by my theory
which is the ugliest guy
did it.
Which makes it you, Joe Gage.
So I take it you deduced
the coffee was poisoned
while you were murdering the old man?
Yes.
Well, mi negro amigo
during that whole incident
I was sitting on that side of the room
playing 'Silent Night' on the piano.
Oh, I ain't say you poisoned the coffee.
I said you didn't make the stew.
My theory is
you workin' with the man
who poisoned the coffee
and both of y'all murdered Minnie
Sweet Dave and whoever else
picked this bad-luck day
to visit Minnie's Haberdashery this mornin.
And at some point y'all intended
to bushwhack John Ruth
and free Daisy.
But you didn't count on the blizzard
and you didn't count on the two of us.
Hmm.
That's far as I got.
How am I doing?
You're a real imaginative nigger
ain't you?
So, do you intend to murder me
based on a far-fetched nigger theory
or can you prove it, cabron?
It ain't so far-fetched Senor Bob.
And it's a little bit more than a theory.
How long you say you been workin' for Minnie?
Four months.
Mmm.
See, if you'd have been here
two and a half years ago
you'd know 'bout that sign
used to hang up over the bar.
Minnie mention that to you?
No.
You want to know what that sign said, Senor Bob?
No dogs or Mexicans allowed.
Now, Minnie hung that sign up
the day she opened this haberdashery.
And it hung over that bar every day
till she took it down a little over two years ago.
You know why she took it down?
She started lettin' in dogs.
Now, Minnie liked just about everybody
but she sure don't
like Mexicans.
So when you tell me
Minnie went to the north side
to visit her mama
well, I find that highly unlikely.
But okay, maybe.
But when you tell me
Minnie Mink took the haberdashery
the most precious thing
to her in the whole world
and left it in the hands
of a goddamn Mexican?
Well, that's what I meant in the barn
when I said that sure don't sound like Minnie.
Now I am calling you a liar
Senor Bob.
And if you lyin'
which you are
then you killed Minnie.
And Sweet Dave.
Four measly bullets
and there goes Senor Bob.
But that still
don't get us no closer
to which one of y'all
poisoned the coffee, though.
Do it, Chris?
No, it sure don't.
Now, one of y'all poisoned this coffee
to free Daisy.
If I don't hear a confession
from one of you motherfuckers
quick, fast and in a hurry
I'm gonna pour this whole pot of coffee
down that bitch's Goddamn throat.
Okay! Time's up.
Stop!
All right, I did it.
It was me.
I poisoned the coffee.
I fuckin' knew it!
Oh!
You gonna die now you murderin' bastard!
Major Warren please let me send this ugly
son of a bitch to hell.
You killed O.B.
He was worth ten of you.
Warren, can I kill him?
Say adios to your huevos.
Major Warren!
I ain't got no gun
Sheriff.
Roy!
Good boy.
Get up!
Get up there!
Packer, Roy, get up!
Get up!
Get up there! Get up!
Get up there!
Get up!
Go!
Go! Go! Go!
Go! Go!
Go!
Get up. Get up.
Hyah! Get up! Get up!
Get up!
Get up! Get up!
Whoa!
Easy.
Whoa! Hey, Charly, my boy.
How the hell are you?
Hiya, Ed.
Hiya, Judy.
Yeah!
Ah.
How many you got?
Full house today, friend.
Got one in there waitin.
Well, he's gonna have to keep on waitin.
We ain't got no room.
Well, you need to tell Minnie.
Cause he been here two days
and Minnie wants him
out of here.
Well, I can't give him
a seat I don't have.
Listen, why don't you take
the passengers inside
and introduce 'em to Minnie
warm yourself up and drink some coffee.
Yeah.
Here we are, everybody.
Minnie's Haberdashery.
Step outside you and your friends
can stretch your legs.
When you're ready step on inside
get warm by the fire get some coffee in you.
I'll introduce you to Minnie.
Hiya, Minnie!
Now, Minnie I'm not tryin' to tell you
how to run your business
but I would think coffee
would be the first thing you'd make.
Hmm.
Come on in, everybody.
Don't be shy.
Hats!
Everybody, this is Minnie
and this is her place.
Behind me, pluckin' that chicken, is Gemma.
Ah.
Lovely smile, that Gemma.
Now, the fella in the uniform I don't know
but the one he's playing
chess with is Sweet Dave.
Hiya, Dave.
Hey, Judy.
And, Minnie
these are the passengers.
Well, that's not good enough.
Go on, take away them rags
let's see some faces let's hear some names.
Oswaldo Mobray, madam.
Joe Gage.
Bob.
And I'm Jody.
It's a pleasant surprise to
find such a warm sanctuary
in the middle of such a cold hell.
Well, make yourself comfortable.
Get warm by the fire.
Uh, we're just gonna go warm ourselves
by the stove if that's all right.
Oh, stove, fireplace, whatever.
Just get warm.
Oh, and Judy said somethin'
about the best coffee in the world.
Ah, yes. I do believe Judy did say something
Well, I don't know about all that
but I tell you what it is.
It's hot, it's strong and it's good.
And in this here snow
it sure enough warms your ass up.
You don't need to sell it Minnie,
you need to make it.
And you need to get
your ass out there
and help Charly with them
bags and get Ed in here.
Yes, ma'am.
But fix that coffee.
I'll fix you!
I don't know, some old man.
Well, I don't know what I'm supposed to do about it.
I'm just telling you what she said.
Anyway, she sent me out here to help Charly.
She wants to talk to you.
Charly, you got a hold of these fellas?
Got 'em, Ed.
Miss Minnie would you roll me a cigarette?
Sure, honey.
I smoke Red Apple tobacco.
That all right?
That's my favorite.
Don't mind me, gentlemen.
I'm just watching.
You play?
You know, I must have had
at least 12 people
teach me that goddamn game.
Just never could keep
the moves in my head.
But if I'm not disturbing
I'd like to watch.
Hell no! I like whippin'
this old man's ass in front of a audience.
You ain't whippin' shit!
Merci beaucoup Mademoiselle Minnie.
Oh, that's real nice.
What is that?
That's French.
You speak French?
Oui.
Oui'? What does that mean?
It means 'yes.
Oui, yes.
Hey, hey, Dave ask me if my ass is fat.
What?
Ask me if my ass is fat.
It is.
I said ask me.
Why?
Just do it!
Is your ass fat?
Oui.
Look at that, y'all I can speak French.
Are you the, uh
jelly bean salesman around here?
How many peppermint sticks
I get for a nickel?
Five.
All right.
Here you go.
Thank you, sugar.
Okay.
Uh, allow me to assist you, madam.
I'm bringing in your bags
in case anybody wants to change
your clothes before Red Rock.
Oh!
Peppermint stick?
Thanks.
So why do they call you 'Six-Horse Judy' anyway?
Cause I'm the only Judy you've ever seen
that can drive a six-horse team.
Oh, yeah!
Kind of a stupid question.
Do you mind holding this for me?
Ah!
Rock steady, madam.
Rock steady.
You got a very sweet
little accent.
Where's that from, England?
I take exception to that.
New Zealand.
Careful, madam. Precarious.
Is that anywhere near uh, Old Zealand?
Mmm.
Auckland?
What the fuck's an Auckland?
It's where I'm from.
It's our biggest city.
Coffee!
Mm-hmm.
Coffee's ready.
Well, it's about damn time!
Best coffee on the mountain.
Oh, I don't know about all that.
Stagecoach drivers like it passengers not so much.
Most find it a mite too strong.
Can't be too strong on this mountain.
Thank you.
Well?
What do you think?
Shit, fuck!
Shit!
Yep.
Mmm, si.
He adds something.
Not much, but something.
What you think, Pete?
Well, I must admit
he does make the setup more convincing.
Hmm.
Okay.
I'll talk to the old man.
You three collect the bodies
and chuck 'em in that well out there.
And then start unhitchin' the horses
and gettin' 'em in the barn
and gettin' 'em fed.
Well, hang on!
I mean puttin' the horses away
that's easy enough
but draggin' these fat bastards
up and down the mountain
that's fuckin' impossible, mate.
Okay.
Well, this is a store so there's gotta be
a wheelbarrow around here somewhere.
Start with the horses
and as soon as I get through
with this old hickory tree
I'll come out and help you, okay?
Hey, Pete grab my coat, will ya?
* Now *
* You're all *
* Alone *
* Feelin' *
* That nobody wants you *
* And you're looking *
* For someone *
* To hold your hand *
* Someone *
* Who understands *
* Now *
* You're by yourself *
* And you're feelin' *
* The world close *
* In on you *
* And you're askin'...*
Look.
I just started workin' here.
Whatever Minnie did to make y'all mad
I had nothin' to do with it.
* Someone...*
Hmm.
Well, old man.
If you
was a cat
what just happened here
would count as one of your nine lives.
Do you realize how close you came
to being tossed on a pile of niggers?
Yes.
Yeah.
And when it comes to that pile of niggers
that we buildin' out back
won't take nothin' to make you general of it.
You believe that?
I expect no less.
Not so fast, old man.
You might have a way out of this yet.
Later today
dirty
son of a gun
is gonna come in here
and he's gonna have my sister with him.
And he is gonna have her in chains.
He's taking her to Red Rock to be hung.
Do you know why?
No.
$10,000.
That's why.
Now, when he gets here
I'm gonna kill that fella
and turn my sister loose.
Now, do you have any reason
why you would want to interfere
with me saving my sister
from a hangman's rope?
No.
You don't?
No, I don't.
You sure you don't?
I mean, we did just kill
Minnie and Sweet Dave.
Now, you and Sweet Dave looked
mighty chummy over here.
I just met these people!
I don't give a damn about them!
Or you. Or your sister.
Or any other son of a bitch
in Wyoming, for that matter.
That is a good answer
old man.
Now, when they get here
you just sit your ass in this chair
and you don't do nothin.
You don't say nothin.
Hello.
Thank you.
Good night.
That's about it.
Maybe your name.
But that's it.
Hello.
Thank you.
Good night.
And maybe my name.
Maybe your name.
Mm-hmm, be a, be a old man.
Be dotty.
Go to sleep.
And don't you say nothin'
and I mean nothin'
to that bounty hunter
that's got my sister.
Do you understand?
Yes.
When it's safe, I'll kill him
free my sister
and leave you be.
Deal?
Deal.
Thank you.
During the next four hours
Jody and the boys chucked
the bodies down the well
put away the horses
tidied up around Minnie's
stashed weapons
for further use
and waited for John Ruth and
Daisy's stage to arrive.
All right, boys.
This is it.
Let's get ready.
Now, remember
it doesn't matter if we have four men or 40
we are still gonna be facing John Ruth
chained to my sister
with a pistol pointed at her belly.
Now, killin' that fella
Fore he kills my sister
ain't gonna be easy
but you better believe that's
exactly what we gonna do.
So the name of the game here is patience.
Trapped here for two or three days
at some point he will close his eyes.
And that's when you blow
the top of his head off.
Remember, old man.
If my sister don't make it
off of this mountain alive
neither do you.
I'll do my best.
Whoa, whoa, easy.
Whoa! Whoa!
Good luck, mate.
What the hell is going on?
We weren't expecting
another stage tonight!
Yeah, I can see you.
Here.
Already got another one up in here.
No.
Just got through puttin' the horses away!
Well, this ain't the normal line.
But we are stuck on the
wrong side of a blizzard
so it looks like you're stuck with us.
Now you gotta do another one.
Are Minnie and Sweet Dave inside?
They ain't here!
I'm running the place while they're gone.
Where's Minnie and Sweet Dave?
He says they ain't here.
He's looking after the place
while they're gone.
Who are you?
I'm Bob.
Well, whoever you are help
O.B. with the horses.
Get 'em out of this cold 'fore
that blizzard hits us.
Whoa! You all right?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Esperate, esperate, esperate!
I just put those other horses away.
You need it done fast you need to help.
I got two of my best men on it.
You heard him, freeloaders.
Get to work.
All right, you two unhook the leaders.
Come on, let's go!
Open up!
You have to kick it open!
Ya gotta kick it open!
What?
Kick it open!
How you doin', old boy?
They shot my nuts off.
I'm freezin' burnin' up the same time.
Bleedin' like a stuck pig.
I think I'm gonna die.
And these motherfuckers did it.
That's how I'm doin.
How you doin'?
Well, my leg hurts really bad.
But I think, if I put all
my weight on my right foot
I was just bein' sarcastic.
I don't give a fuck about your leg.
Huh.
Now, you just
make yourself comfortable.
Don't worry about my comfort.
Shit, I can't feel my ass no more.
Worry about these owl hoots
and that bushwhackin' nut
shooter in the basement.
All right!
You...fella in the basement!
You either give up by the
time I count to three
or I shoot Domergue in the head.
One!
Two!
No, no, no, no don't shoot her in the head!
I'm coming up.
Hold on now you bushwhackin' sack shooter!
You just open the door.
We tell you when to come up.
Now throw out your pistol.
Toward the bed.
Bet he got another.
Now throw out your other pistol.
I ain't got another pistol!
Well, you better shit another
pistol out your ass
cause if you don't throw one up here
in the next two seconds
we gonna kill this bitch.
See?
Told you.
Now, with your hands
where we can see 'em
slowly come on up.
How you doing, dummy?
Better now I see your ugly face.
How you like that?!
You bushwhackin' castrator!
What are you doing?!
He was giving up!
It took him too long so I done it for him.
Joe Gage, get your ass over
here and shut this trap door.
I'm sorry, honey.
May I sit in a chair?
Yes, you may.
Keep your hands flat on that table.
And don't move 'em.
Mannix!
You sure picked the wrong time
to turn into a nigger lover.
Don't you see that nigger and John Ruth
put you smack dab in the middle of danger?
You're about to be murdered
in some nigger named Minnie's house
and you don't even know why!
Okay...bitch.
I'll bite.
Why?
I'm working with all three of them fellas.
But not 'cause they got
butterflies in their belly
about me, but because
we're all gang members.
The Jody Domingre Gang.
That fella y'all just killed in the basement
was Jody Domingre!
My brother!
Well, who the hell is Jody Domingre?
You want to tell him bounty man?
He was a big bad cat worth $50,000.
And every member of his gang
was worth at least ten.
Which finally explains
why you worth ten.
And what's gonna happen when
that sun comes out, nigger?
So is my brother's 15 men
coming straight here for us.
Tell him, Grouch!
Jody got 15 men waiting in Red Rock.
We couldn't kill John Ruth
and free Daisy here
their job was to sack
the town kill John Ruth
and free Daisy there.
Now, with my brother dead
I'm in charge of this gang.
Right, boys?
That's right, Daisy.
Oh, yeah.
And, Chris, I am telling you
you ain't done anything yet
that we can't forgive.
So, let's make a deal.
No deals, bitch.
You gonna let that nigger
speak for you, Chris?!
Hold it, Warren.
Seeing as how she ain't
got nothing to sell
I'm kinda curious about her sales pitch.
Humor me.
All right...bitch.
What's...your...deal?
Easy.
Take your gun shoot that nigger dead.
Then we sit here all nice-like
for the next two days.
When the snow melts, we go to
Mexico, you go on to Red Rock
get that star pinned on your chest.
Hey, Pete.
How much can we pay him?
Well, we could give him Marco.
Bob's real name is Marco the Mexican.
He's worth $12,000.
That's Marco the Mexican?
Precisely, yeah.
Shit.
Now that I blowed his face off,
Marco ain't worth a peso.
Oh!
Oh, sh...Oh, sh
Well, then, if I die
in the next two days
which is more than likely you can have me.
Under the name of English Pete Hicox
I got a federal bounty
of $15,000 on my head.
It's all yours, Chris.
You keep talking, Pete
you gonna talk yourself to death.
Joe Gage, who you be?
Grouch Douglass.
You heard of him?
Yeah, I heard of Grouch Douglass.
He worth ten, just like Daisy.
Well, remind me
why we wouldn't just
kill all y'all, cash in.
Oh, you can kill us all but
you'll never spend a cent
of that bounty money
and you'll never leave this mountain alive.
Cause when that snow melts
the rest of Jody's gang
all 15 of 'em that are waiting
in Red Rock, are coming here.
Now, l...let's say you shoot us all.
If you really want all that
Domingre Gang bounty money
you still got to get all
our corpses into Red Rock.
And that ain't gonna be so easy.
Cause I...I doubt you can
drive a four-horse team.
And that wagon out there is
too heavy for a two-horse team.
So that means you're gonna have to lead
a string of horsesinto Red Rock.
And with that deep snow after a blizzard
you ain't gonna be able to get
away with any more than
say, one body per horse.
So that's you leading a string
of four horses into Red Rock.
And with all them horses in that snow
and you all by your lonesome
you're gonna be a mite poky.
And you're gonna run smack
dab into the Domingre Gang.
And again, Grouch how many is that?
15 killers strong.
And when those 15 killers come across you
in possession of all our dead bodies
they ain't just gonna
kill you and that nigger!
They gonna go back to Red Rock
and kill every son of a bitch in that town!
You really the sheriff of Red Rock?
You want to save the town?
Then shoot that nigger dead!
Jesus Christ!
Oh, ho, ho!
You believe in Jesus now huh, bitch?
Well, good 'cause you about to meet him.
Anybody else want to make a deal?
Huh?!
The deal still stands, Chris.
You ain't done nothing we can't forgive.
It's all still on that nigger.
You shoot him dead take my body
sit out in the snow
with Daisy and Grou
You cunt!
Mannix
give me my pistol.
Give it here!
So, you were saying
we sit here all nice and friendly like
for the next two days.
Then the snow melts you leave here
meet up with your gang and
hightail it to Mexico.
That's the deal, right?
Yeah.
And I get Oswaldo and Joe Gage?
But Jody's worth $50,000.
What about his body?
You gonna make a deal
with this diabolical bitch?
I ain't saying I'm gonna make a deal with her.
We just talking.
Calm down!
So what about Jody's body and the $50,000?
You're getting greedy, reb.
No deal.
We're taking Jody's body back with us.
He got children.
So I kill Warren and we all friends?
Yeah.
No deal, tramp.
Chris!
You're making the biggest
mistake of your life!
When our boys get here
in a couple of days
they're gonna cut your nuts off!
And there won't be a stick
left in that town unburnt!
Well, I guess I should be
plumb scared right now, huh?
If you had any brains you would be!
You see
here's the problem, Daisy.
In order for me to be
scared of your threats
I got to believe in those
15 extra gang members
waiting it out in Red Rock.
And boy, oh, boy, I sure don't.
What I believe is
Joe Gage or Grouch Douglass or
whatever the fuck his name was
poisoned the coffee.
And you watched him do it.
And you watched me pour a cup
and you didn't say shit!
And
I believe you are what you've always been
a lying bitch who will do anything
to cheat the rope waiting
for her in Red Rock
including shitting out
15 extra gang members
whenever you need be.
Oh, oh!
And
I believe, when it comes to what's left
of the Jody Domingre Gang I'm looking at 'em.
Right here, right now
dead on this motherfucking floor!
Goddamn right.
Then you're gonna die
on this mountain, Chris.
Cause my brother leads an army of men.
Horseshit!
My daddy led an army.
He led a renegade army
fighting for a lost cause!
My daddy held up to 400 men
together after the war
with nothing but their
respect in his command!
Your brother's just an owl hoot
who led a gang of killers!
I don't feel so good.
Oh, shit.
Ha!
You still alive, white boy?
Fuck!
Mannix!
Oh! Fuck!
Hey, boy!
Get up!
Chris Mannix!
If your ass ain't nailed to the floor,
wake the fuck up!
Wake up, white boy!
I ain't dead yet you black bastard.
Chris Mannix I may have misjudged you.
Now we've come to the part of the story
where I blow your goddamn head off.
No! No, no, don't shoot her!
Why the hell not?
John Ruth.
Now, John Ruth was one mighty, mighty bastard.
But the last thing that
bastard did 'fore he died
was save your life.
We gonna die, white boy.
We ain't got no say in that.
But there is one thing left
we do have a say in.
And that's how we kill this bitch.
And I say shooting's too good for her.
John Ruth could've shot her
anywhere anytime along the way.
But John Ruth was The Hangman.
And when The Hangman catches you
you don't die by no bullet.
When The Hangman catches you you hang.
You only need to hang mean bastards...
Mm-hmm.
...but mean bastards you need to hang.
As my first and final act
as the sheriff of Red Rock
I sentence you, Domergue
to hang by the neck until death!
Hang on, Daisy.
I want to watch.
Now, that was a nice dance.
Oh!
That sure was pretty.
Shit!
Hey.
Can I see that Lincoln letter?
Dear Marquis
I hope this letter finds you
in good health and stead.
I'm doing fine
although I wish there were more hours in a day.
There's just so much to do.
Times are changing slowly but surely
and it's men like you that
will make a difference.
Your military success is a credit not only to you
but your race as well.
I'm very proud every time I hear news of you.
We still have a long way to go
but hand in hand I know we will get there.
I just want to let you know
you're in my thoughts.
Hopefully, our paths will cross in the future.
Until then I remain your friend.
Ole Mary Todd's calling
so I guess it must be time for bed.
Respectfully, Abraham Lincoln.
Ole Mary Todd.
That's a nice touch.
Yeah.
Thanks.