>>>>
EnCoded By nItRo & UpLoaded By XpoZ
**xpoztorrent.blogspot.com**
(GLASS SPEAKING PAWNEE)
It's okay, son...
I know you want this to be over.
I'm right here.
I will be right here...
But, you don't give up.
You hear me?
As long as you can still
grab a breath, you fight.
You breathe... keep breathing.
(GLASS CLICKS TONGUE)
GLASS: Hawk.
- (GUNS COCKING)
- (GLASS CLICKS TONGUE)
(GLASS SPEAKING PAWNEE)
Ah, shit.
Goddamn sumbitches.
The sumbitch got shit for brains.
(GRUMBLING)
You seen Coulter?
TRAPPER: Nope.
Listen up!
When them plews is cleaned,
I want you to hoop 'em up real tight.
Remember, we're not doing
no 15-pelt bales!
We're going 30-pelt bales!
HENRY: Fitzgerald!
Cap'n.
Where are we with the haul?
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking, whatever it is
they're hunting out there...
I hope it don't need another shot.
Make sure we're ready to head out by dawn.
Been done by this morning.
I'd have liked to be out by how,
but the men are too tired.
We're only a few days from the fort.
We're trapped out.
All we have to worry about
is fresh meat for the boys.
Well, you, uh, seen Coulter?
(JIM PANTING)
JIM: Hey, we took down an elk. A big one.
We need help to haul the meat back.
Let me know when it's on the spit.
I'll help you with it then.
Come on, I need your help.
We needed help when we were
loading them bales.
I been eating this damn
beaver meat so long...
I'm starting to miss my wife's cooking.
I'm starting to miss your wife.
Shut up.
COULTER: Help!
Help.
- TRAPPER 1: Is that Coulter?
- (MEN CLAMORING)
You go get the Captain.
STUBBY BILL: Jesus Christ.
TRAPPER 2: Anybody see them?
TRAPPER 3: Stay quiet.
TRAPPER 4: Watch the ridge.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
(HAWK SPEAKING PAWNEE)
What was that?
Pa?
Let's go.
(MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(MAN SHUSHING)
- (HORSES WHINNYING)
- (ARIKARA WARRIORS WHOOPING)
They got Thomas.
I can't see 'em. I can't see 'em.
HENRY: Get down!
We're surrounded! They're everywhere!
HENRY: Stay here! Stay here!
(PAUL GROANING)
Paul, no!
(PAUL SCREAMING)
They want us out in the open.
Nobody move! Stay where you are!
They want the pelts.
We got to get on that boat
right now or we'll lose it all.
(ARIKARA WARRIORS WHOOPING)
(SHOUTING IN PAWNEE)
Get to the boat! To the boat, son! Move!
Move, move!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Leave the furs!
Leave the furs! To the boat!
(YELLING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(ARIKARA WARRIOR 1 GROANING)
Hawk!
(ARIKARA WARRIOR 2 WHOOPING)
(SHOUTING IN ARIKARA)
(GROANING)
Grab some pelts! Come on, grab the pelts!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Grab the pelts! Grab the pelts!
DAVE: Give this to my little girl.
You're coming with us. I'll get help.
GLASS: Leave the furs! Leave the pelts!
Willman!
Lean on me. Just keep going.
(GROANS)
Get to the boat!
(ARIKARA WARRIORS WHOOPING)
(YELLING)
Fucking savage!
Get on the fucking boat!
(GROANING)
Help!
HENRY: Cut the rope! Cut the rope!
Wait for Amos!
No! We go now!
Fire the cannon!
AMOS: Don't leave! Wait!
(ARIKARA ELDER CHANTING)
My daughter, Powaqa, is not here.
Collect all the pelts we can carry.
We'll trade pelts with the French
for horses and keep searching for her.
HENRY: ...and dust becomes flour
and when the morning is clear...
this child of God will meet
Jesus Christ himself. Amen.
(MURPHY BREATHING SHAKILY)
HENRY: You ready?
Hold still.
(MURPHY SCREAMING)
ANDERSON: Where did you learn that?
My father was a doctor. Bridger!
FITZGERALD: Captain, we got a swarm of tree
niggers out here waiting to finish the job.
Tell me you got some kind of plan.
Glass?
Missouri's no good.
Not while the Ree's running it.
We got to get off this boat.
Oh, you want to get off the boat?
Then what do we do, huh?
Take our furs and sit out there amongst
the Ree like a bunch of ducks?
Only safe thing to do is track
a new course back up on land.
That'll add weeks to the trip.
Better than floating
where they can get eyes on us.
They got eyes on you right now, son.
What I'm saying is we stay on the boat.
Chart a course toward the fort
and take our chances on the water.
Glass knows this territory best.
It's his job to get us home safe.
- Get us home safe?
- Yeah.
FITZGERALD: Need I remind you
we already lost 32 men?
It's 33 now. They were my men, Fitzgerald.
I know how many I lost.
We do like Glass says.
That's the end of it.
GLASS: We have to set the boat loose.
If the Ree are tracking us,
they'll find it downriver.
Best course is to hike inland to
the Grand and follow it to Fort Kiowa.
ANDERSON: On foot?
It'll be winter before we get there.
Yeah, unless we come across a post,
trade for some horses.
Ain't no posts that far over!
Captain, losing this boat
is a goddamn mistake.
The Ree ain't that stupid.
We keep it, we can lay it up
around Arrow's Peak.
Quit acting like you know
what you're talking about.
Ain't nobody talking to you.
Who'd listen to you anyway?
Can't find your way
out of your breeches to take a shit.
All I'm saying is Camp Rhulen
is just up the way.
We can hole up there.
We walk.
Yeah, I'm sure we will.
Wish my dad was a doctor.
Then he could've bought me
a captain's job.
What do we do, eh?
Pray these pelts ain't rotten
if we ever get back here?
HENRY: Make sure to mark this place.
We're leaving a fortune under these rocks.
Glass, chart a course.
Tightest you can that
gets us around the Ree.
FITZGERALD: This ain't right.
We all know these furs ain't gonna
be here by the time we come back.
There's no way we can haul them
all the way to the fort.
Arikara are all through the territory.
We'll want our hands free.
We're gonna lose those pelts.
You rather keep the pelts or your life?
Life?
What life you talking about?
I ain't got no life.
I just got living and the only way
I get that is through these pelts.
Fuck!
Ain't no way I'm going home
after six months
working my ass off like a mule...
risking my neck, men dying, and for what?
Damn near lost everything.
Job's been fucked from the start!
There's the one been fucking us.
You wonder how the Ree
got the dead drop on us...
when Mr. Glass was supposed
to look out for that very thing?
All them Pawnee buddies of his.
Pawnee's as much against
the Ree as the rest of us.
Yeah?
Well, what about
his little half-breed son?
What kind of savage
you think his mama was?
Oh, lay off the boy, Fitz.
All I'm saying is...
a savage... is savage.
Hey, Glass...
is it true what they say
about you shooting a lieutenant
while living with them savages?
Twenty-one dead soldiers
and 40 dead feathernecks.
But you and your boy
the only ones to walk out alive.
Kind of a miracle.
HENRY: Shut up, Fitzgerald.
FITZGERALD: Is that what you did?
Shot one of your own
to save this little dog here?
Shut up!
Why? Was he playing with
this little boy's mama, huh?
Did he kill her?
Hey, you can quit polishing that rifle
when I'm talking to you.
I'm working on it.
You can work on it
when I'm done talking to you.
Look at me.
HENRY: That's enough!
You're forgetting your place, boy.
As far as I can tell, my place is here
on the smart end of this rifle.
HENRY: You move along, Fitzgerald.
That's an order!
Listen!
There's only a couple hours of light left.
We got to stash these pelts
and get rid of the boat.
- Let's go!
- (ALL AGREEING)
(SPEAKING PAWNEE)
I told you to be invisible, son.
At least he...
If you want to survive,
keep your mouth shut.
- At least he heard me...
- They don't hear your voice!
They just see the color of your face.
You understand?
Yes.
You have to listen to me, son.
You have to listen.
(GLASS GRUNTS)
HENRY: Beckett!
Weston!
JONES: Why are they not jumping?
STUBBY BILL:
It looks like they changed their minds.
FITZGERALD: Smart sumbitches.
Smart.
(GRUNTS)
I ought to be on that boat.
They did the right thing.
(MEN LAUGHING)
(BOTH SPEAKING PAWNEE)
It's time to move.
Get up.
We're headed out.
I'm coming.
It's better you lay down.
When the rest of the men are ready
you send them to me.
I'm going west.
You are my son.
(WARRIOR 1 SPEAKING ARIKARA)
There are only two here.
(ELK DOG SPEAKING ARIKARA)
Powaqa is not here.
(WARRIOR 1 SPEAKING ARIKARA)
The others probably took her.
They went north.
(ELK DOG SPEAKING ARIKARA)
We'll pick up their tracks on the mountain.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
HENRY: Was it the right decision?
Leaving the boat?
The Ree own that river.
They would've flanked us.
We stay east of the Grand through
the mountains, we cut a week off our trip.
Lands are bone dry up there.
Nothing for the Ree to hunt.
HENRY: Except us.
GLASS: Except us.
Is it true what Fitzgerald said?
Is that why you came out here
to the edge of the world?
Glass?
I do like the quiet.
Your boy...
he's seen a lot.
He got a mother
you need to get him back to?
(FITZGERALD BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CUTTING HAIR)
(RUSTLING)
(COCKS GUN)
(BEAR BELLOWING)
(BEAR SNORTING)
(GLASS YELLS)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(BELLOWING)
(GROANING)
(GLASS PANTING)
(STRAINING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(SCREAMING)
(BELLOWS)
(GRUNTING)
(CUB BELLOWING)
(HAWK YELLING)
JIM: Mr. Glass!
There are cubs here!
We got cubs here!
Christ Almighty.
He's down here!
ANDERSON: Keep your eyes open.
There's bears around.
JIM: I need your help now!
HENRY: Oh, my God.
(GLASS WHEEZING)
Get me rags now!
Give me rags before he bleeds out. Rags.
Prepare the kit. Bridger! You hold that.
(GRUNTING)
Easy. Oh, my God.
ANDERSON: Got to give him credit
for taking that grizz down with him.
He shouldn't have shot.
The place is crawling with tree niggers.
HENRY: That's enough! That's enough!
We're still in Ree territory.
He's one of our own men.
(CONTINUES WHEEZING)
Scout a circle around us. North and west.
Take those two with you.
Bill, Fryman, you take south and east.
Watch for anyone
that might've heard that shot.
We have to stitch him up.
What about me? Captain?
You just stay here.
Hold it down.
JIM: I'm so sorry, Mr. Glass.
HENRY: Bridger, press down here.
JIM: He's bleeding down here, too.
(GLASS SCREAMING)
ANDERSON: They're torturing the bastard.
The proper thing to do would be
to finish him off quick.
Unless he has a chance of pulling through.
(SCOFFS)
Pulling through?
You saw what that grizz did to him.
- He'll be dead inside an hour.
- Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, we all will be if he don't quit
wailing like that.
Toward you and twist it into place.
I'll hold him. Go.
- Pa.
- HENRY: Hold him. Go.
Go!
Now!
He passed out.
I'll take advantage
and stitch up his neck.
Water.
Bridger, tell the others
- we'll camp here tonight.
- (SPEAKING PAWNEE)
I'm right here.
I'll be right here...
(MEN LAUGHING)
(MEN SPEAKING FRENCH)
Toussaint, he's here.
I thought he wouldn't make it.
I'm glad you made it here.
We need horses and rifles.
We bring you many pelts.
No horses... just what we agreed.
Take all the pelts you want.
We need horses and rifles.
I need a woman with big tits...
Who can cook.
We can't give you any horses.
What's he saying?
I don't know, something about horses.
Bring us something to drink... some whisky.
Tell him to stop asking about the horses.
Always good doing business with you.
Horses.
No horses.
All we can trade are guns and ammunition.
Tell him if he asks about horses again,
there is no deal.
Where did you get these? The Americans?
They're already branded.
I'll only be able to get half price for them.
Get him away from there.
I said no horses.
We'll take these three horses.
I'm not going to say it again.
They aren't part of the deal.
Now tell your man to step away.
We had an agreement, you have to honor it.
(IN FRENCH) You stand there
and talk to me about honor?
I told you he speaks French.
Those pelts are stolen.
You all have stolen everything from us.
Everything!
The land.
The animals.
Two white men snuck into our village,
and took my daughter, Powaqa.
We leave you these pelts
because honor demands it.
I take your horses to find my daughter.
You are free to try and stop me.
Business is business.
Prepare five horses for them.
HENRY: I want everybody up
at the crack of dawn.
Carrying Glass will be hard...
so we need to get ahead
as far as possible.
We'll divide into two groups.
Fitzgerald, Jones, Fryman,
you take the east side of the river.
Anderson, you scout up front.
That claw don't belong to you.
It ain't for me.
(WHEEZING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(MEN ARGUING)
Stop!
(HAWK SPEAKING PAWNEE)
(COUGHING)
HENRY: Don't let him down!
Don't let him down!
ANDERSON: Watch it.
- JONES: How we gonna make it up this?
- FITZGERALD: Slow down.
ANDERSON: It's killing us, Captain!
(ALL GRUNTING)
HENRY: Lift it, Bridger!
FITZGERALD: Goddamn it, keep it steady.
JIM: Lift it up higher.
HAWK: I am.
HENRY: And heave!
(ALL GROAN)
JONES: I'll go up and pull.
(ALL GRUNTING)
(ALL EXCLAIM)
My foot!
Enough of this shit!
We'll never make it across
like this, Captain.
- He's burning up.
- (COUGHING)
(ALL PANTING)
Cap'n, you ain't doing us
nor him no favors...
by letting him go on suffering like this.
Captain, it's all the same up here.
We're gonna have to go back.
Find another way.
(GLASS WHEEZING)
Glass. Hugh.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Lay that rag over his eyes, Mr. Bridger.
HAWK: What?
- HENRY: Lay the rag over his eyes.
- HAWK: Wait!
HENRY: I'm sorry, Hugh.
JIM: Sir, I can't do that.
HAWK: How do we get back without him?
Only he knows the way.
- HENRY: Lay the rag over his eyes.
- JIM: I can't.
Wait! How do we get back...
(SPEAKING PAWNEE)
HENRY: Lay it over his eyes!
Step back.
HAWK: Bridger, stop! Bridger, Henry.
Henry! Henry, please.
Captain. Captain. Please. Please leave...
(HAWK SPEAKING PAWNEE)
(GLASS CONTINUES WHEEZING)
There's a $70 bonus from the Rocky
Mountain Fur Company to the two men...
that stay with Glass to see this through.
HAWK: I'll stay!
Me, too. Money or not, I'll stay.
I'll need a third.
Sorry, Captain.
I have a family. I'm not crazy.
Captain, three men
can't hold off a party of Ree,
much less some boys.
Besides, $70 ain't gonna buy
nobody a new set of ears.
A hundred, then.
This man is the only reason
we're still alive.
We were 45 men when this started.
Now we're ten. Almost nine.
HAWK:
He's my father. He can have my share.
JIM: Mine, too. He can have my share also.
All right.
If Mr. Bridger feels the same way,
I'll lag behind with them.
- You?
- Yep.
You already lost my share of the pelts
so I got no choice but to make it up
by some other means.
Sticking around for another day or two
don't make no difference.
$300... at least I get to
go home with something.
Glass is to be cared
for until, understood?
Yeah. You have my word. I understand.
HENRY: You boys get him down off this
slope and somewhere safe before dark.
Fitzgerald.
Glass is to be cared for
as long as necessary.
And a proper burial when it's time.
He's earned it.
I understand.
You hurt yourself?
ANDERSON: I'll be fine.
(GLASS WHEEZING)
(HAWK SPEAKING PAWNEE)
Can you hear that wind, father?
Remember what mother used to say
about the wind?
The wind cannot defeat
a tree with strong roots.
You are still breathing...
I miss her so much.
(SPEAKING PAWNEE)
(GLASS SPEAKING PAWNEE)
I will be right here...
I'm right here.
As long as you can still
grab a breath, you fight.
You breathe. Keep breathing.
(GLASS'S WIFE SPEAKING PAWNEE)
When there is a storm...
And you stand in front of a tree...
(GUNSHOT)
If you look at its branches,
you swear it will fall.
But if you watch the trunk,
you will see its stability.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(FITZGERALD GRUNTING)
FITZGERALD: Three hundred bucks
goes a long way toward retirement.
Go down to Texas, find me
a decent piece of land,
and start pissing in the wind.
Get me the hell out of this
godforsaken place.
(JIM SCRAPING FLASK)
Ree done that to you?
I'm just asking.
Yeah, they done it.
They took their sweet time with it.
At the start, I didn't feel nothing.
I just heard the sound...
of the knife scraping
against my skull and...
them all laughing and whooping
and hollering and whatnot.
Then the blood came.
It was cold. It started
streaming down my face,
in my eyes, and...
breathing it in.
Choking on it.
That's when I felt it.
Yeah, felt all of it.
I got my head turned inside out.
JIM: Jesus.
Them Indians down Texas way...
they may rob you, but they
ain't gonna take your topknot.
JIM: When was it?
Goddamn it,
will you quit that noise now, will you?
Quit it.
FITZGERALD: I'm falling further back
from Henry and the boys
on account of tending to you.
Got to get up the damn mountain,
but winter keeps chasing us down.
If you ready to take the sacrament...
I can do that for you.
What you holding to, Glass?
You know...
it would be better...
if you were to take that
last breath of yours now...
for all of us.
Now you hung tough.
And that's something.
I'm begging you.
Them Ree are so close I can smell 'em.
You can smell 'em, too.
You got to think of your boy. All right?
'Cause you're gonna kill him.
You'll kill us all.
(MUTTERING)
I can muzzle you if you like.
Take away this suffering quick and easy.
No one ever has to know that you give up.
All you have to do is blink
if you want me to do that.
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
Save your boy and blink.
You just have to blink.
Yeah. There it is.
You'd best hope the good Lord'll
get His ass here quick, huh?
Maybe He'll forgive your sins, maybe not.
Thus I do commend thee to the Lord.
(GLASS CHOKING)
Through Jesus Christ the Lord
of all reality and mercy...
and the Father
and the Creator, I hold thee...
Get away! Get away!
You okay? Jim! Jim! Help!
HAWK: Help!
Calm down.
Jim! Help!
Don't shout! You're gonna get us all killed!
Keep away!
I'll tell the Captain what you did.
They'll hang you!
They'll hang you! Jim, help!
We have an understanding.
What's fucking wrong with you people?
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Shit.
(GLASS CONTINUES MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(CONTINUES MUFFLED SCREAMING)
JIM: I got one beaver, Hawk.
Breathing changed?
I hadn't noticed.
Damn, he's cold as ice.
Here you go, Mr. Glass.
This will help you. Keep you warm.
It's all right.
Where's Hawk?
He ain't with you?
No.
No?
(GLASS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
I understand, Mr. Glass.
It's all right.
I think I'll get a fire going.
FITZGERALD: Yeah. Sounds like a good idea.
(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
JIM: Hawk!
Hawk!
FITZGERALD: Shh. Ree.
There's about 20 of them
down by the creek.
They're headed this way.
Grab your shit and let's go.
Shit. What do we do?
FITZGERALD: Run, right now.
What about Hawk?
He ain't our problem no more.
We can't just leave him.
Either he's gutted or scalped.
And if he ain't he can find us, can't he?
What about Glass?
He ain't our problem.
Like us, he's on his own.
We made a promise to the Captain.
A proper burial when the time was needed.
He needs that rifle!
He couldn't do nothing with it
if you tarred it to his hand.
We can't do this.
We got no fucking choice.
JIM: No, we can't. Look at him.
All right, shit, then, buddy. Get him up.
You want to take him?
(GLASS GROANING)
Come on now!
JIM: Easy. Slowly, Fitz. Easy with him.
(JIM GROANS)
FITZGERALD: Just get your shit.
- Get your shit!
- (GLASS SCREAMING)
Shut up.
Shut up!
JIM: Hold up!
(GLASS GROANING)
Fitz. What are you doing?
What does it look like?
Proper burial. Like you wanted.
JIM: No, not like this.
FITZGERALD: Why not?
He's alive, Fitz. He's alive.
So shoot him.
(GLASS SHOUTING)
I have to go. I have to go.
I'm sorry, Mr. Glass. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- (PROTESTING INDISTINCTLY)
(WHEEZING)
(JIM GROANS)
MURPHY: Captain! This way!
There's a path down here!
ANDERSON: There ain't shit down there!
We got to climb over!
JONES: Glass said to stay east!
ANDERSON: Glass can go to hell!
HENRY: What's the map say?
Keep climbing. We climb, Captain.
We keep climbing.
Till we reach Old Gabe.
We climb.
We got to wait for Murph.
ANDERSON: Yeah. You wait for him.
Captain?
Sir...
Murphy says there's a way down there.
Who we following?
ANDERSON: You follow who you want!
I'm going up!
Stubby, keep going up!
JONES: Murph! Come here!
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
(WHEEZING)
(GRUNTING LOUDLY)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING PAWNEE)
I'm not leaving you, son.
I'm right here.
FITZGERALD: Fire's done.
I can't even feel my feet.
Didn't we put enough distance
between us and them Ree?
A dozen Ree can make
twice as good time as we can.
- Twenty.
- What?
You said you saw twenty Ree.
Yeah? What you talking about?
- You woke me up.
- Mmm-hmm.
You said you saw twenty Ree by the creek.
Well, yeah, twenty, a dozen...
it don't matter.
I wasn't gonna hang around
counting fucking feathers.
As a matter of fact...
what was you doing down
by the creek all by yourself?
I'd already brought up plenty of water.
Hey!
Answer me, Fitzgerald.
I asked you a question.
Don't question me
on account of you feel guilty.
Answer me or I'll blow your head off.
You got a short-term memory, boy.
Your ass would be floating around
the Missouri right now if it wasn't for me.
You want to ask questions?
What you want to ask?
If you want to know, ask it.
Hmm?
You want to know why you left
Mr. Glass back there for dead, huh?
Or why you left your little boyfriend
running around?
You want to know if he's still alive?
I'll tell you why.
It's 'cause you ain't a man yet.
It's 'cause you was scared shitless.
You're scared now.
The Ree.
What of them?
Tell me, did you see 'em?
- Put your rifle down.
- Did you see the Ree?
No.
Not a single one.
You fucking lied to me? You lied to me!
(COUGHS)
(GASPS)
I had to scare some sense into you, boy.
Glass was dead. Hawk we don't know about.
No point in either of us
dying either, you understand?
The way I see it,
I saved your life twice now.
I ought to be God to you.
And God giveth... and God taketh away.
- (GUN CLICKS)
- (GASPS)
Lucky fucker.
Next time you want to shoot somebody...
you might want to use powder,
prime your rifle.
Come on. Let's git. Grab your shit.
(SNIFFLES)
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GLASS GRUNTING)
(SNIFFS)
(SPEAKING ARIKARA)
Fresh blood. This could be Powaqa.
A dead boy.
A Pawnee boy.
Let's go.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(COUGHING)
(COUGHS)
(SCREAMING)
(ALL PANTING)
(GLASS SNORING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(HORSES APPROACHING)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(ARIKARA WARRIOR SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
(YELPS)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(BLOWING)
Who did this?
FITZGERALD: I don't know.
Could be Captain Leavenworth's boys.
Mmm. Yeah.
Put some eyes on the back
of your head. (SNIFFLES)
These Injuns ain't never
as dead as you think they are.
Look at 'em, huh?
They're always stealing our shit.
(GRUNTS)
(SNORTS)
(SNIFFING)
(GASPS)
FITZGERALD: We got horses over here!
Hey, Bridger.
We got horses!
JIM: What you want to do about these pigs?
FITZGERALD: The Lord's on our side, kid.
FITZGERALD: You all right there, kid?
Your head in the right place?
I guess.
I can't help thinking about
whether we did the right...
Ain't our place to wonder.
The good Lord...
got us on a road
whether we choose it or not.
My pop, he weren't
a religious man, you know?
If you couldn't grow it,
kill it, or eat it,
he just plain old didn't believe in it.
And this one time he head on
up the old Saba hills.
San Saba hills?
He joined a couple Texas
Ranger buddies of his to hunt.
Pretty routine. He done it
like a hundred times before.
Should have been a 3-day kill,
but on the second day,
it all went fucked.
Somehow that night he lost his buddies.
And to top it off, them Comanches
went and took the horses.
So he was starving and delirious...
and he crawls up into this mott, this...
group of trees out
in the middle of nowhere
just sticking up in this ocean of scrub...
and he found religion.
At that moment, he told me...
he found God.
Uh-huh.
And it turns out that God...
He's a squirrel.
Yeah. A big, old meaty one.
"I found God," he used to say.
"And while sitting there
and basking in the glory
"and sublimity of mercy..."
"I shot and ate that son of a bitch."
Mmm.
Yeah. You might want to
close your eyes, kid.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(BISON GALLOPING)
(PANTING)
(WOLVES BARKING)
(BISON BELLOWING)
(CONTINUES PANTING)
(SNORING)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN PAWNEE)
(MAN CONTINUES SHOUTING)
(PANTING)
(GLASS SPEAKING PAWNEE)
(GLASS GRUNTING)
(HIKUC GRUNTS)
(RETCHING)
(SIGHS)
(BOTH SPEAKING PAWNEE)
I'm injured.
What happened to you?
A bear.
Grizzly.
My men... left me for dead.
Killed my son.
I lost my family too.
Sioux killed my people.
I'm going south to find more Pawnee.
My heart bleeds...
But revenge is in the creator's hands.
You will ride with me...
(HORSE WHINNIES)
(GROANS)
(HIKUC SPEAKING PAWNEE)
Your body is rotten.
Need to heal.
You could die.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
FITZGERALD: Yeah! There she is.
We did it.
You ought to be proud of yourself, boy.
Yeah.
We followed orders.
We just skipped the funeral part.
Don't go down there
and start growing no conscience.
'Cause sure as night'll come they'll
have us swinging from a couple ropes.
We did what we had to do.
(JIM URGES HORSE)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(ALL SHOUTING EXCITEDLY)
FITZGERALD: We had the extra
day so we managed to dig...
a little deeper, lay rocks on top
so scavengers couldn't get at him.
It was done right and all.
He was buried right.
Sir, can we...
The truth is that...
(FITZGERALD CLEARS THROAT)
when Hawk disappeared,
I was worried about savages.
And I was ready to get, to move on out.
Yeah, but, Bridger here argued to stay.
He argued to stay...
so he could at least
build a cross or something...
to put on top of Glass's grave,
and that's what he did.
That's what we did.
I'm glad you pulled
your weight, Mr. Bridger.
He more than pulled his weight, Captain.
This man here, he was my partner.
Am I to assume that the agreed
arrangement did not change?
Uh, fortunately for me, it did not.
HENRY: Mmm-hmm.
(CEILING CREAKING)
Thank you...
for your courage, honor, and service.
Deal or no deal, Mr. Bridger,
you deserve something for what you did.
Thank you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Kid's been beating himself up
awful bad the whole trip.
We all saw the shape Glass was in.
There was no more to be done. Right?
FITZGERALD: Yeah.
We all saw him.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(EXHALES SHAKILY)
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING)
(GLASS GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GLASS'S WIFE SPEAKING PAWNEE)
When there is a storm...
And you stand in front of a tree...
If you look at its branches,
you swear it will fall.
(WHEEZING)
But if you watch the trunk,
you will see its stability.
(CONTINUES WHEEZING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(GLASS CRYING)
(GLASS GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
(MEN LAUGHING)
(MEN CHATTERING IN FRENCH)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SCOUT SHOUTING IN ARIKARA)
There are traces of a camp...
(BOTH SPEAKING ARIKARA)
Where?
Entering the moon forest.
Maybe from two days ago.
They are moving east.
Tell the others.
Let's move quickly,
Powaqa could be with them!
(TRAPPERS SINGING IN FRENCH)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Bring me the girl...
Those five horses weren't for free.
(TRAPPERS LAUGHING)
(HORSE NEIGHS)
(POWAQA STRUGGLING)
(TOUSSAINT SPEAKS FRENCH)
(POWAQA BEGGING INDISTINCTLY)
(POWAQA SCREAMS)
(TOUSSAINT MOANING)
(POWAQA CRYING)
(TOUSSAINT GRUNTING PLEASURABLY)
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
- Shh...
Don't make a sound.
(SPEAKING PAWNEE)
I will get a horse.
(POWAQA SPEAKING ARIKARA)
I'll cut off your balls.
(TRAPPERS SPEAKING FRENCH)
Where is Toussaint?
Come here...
(TRAPPERS SCREAMING)
(TRAPPERS SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
(PLAYING UPBEAT FOLK MUSIC)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- FITZGERALD: May I join you?
- HENRY: Yes.
Yeah?
Yes.
I was wondering when we might
be getting paid for that haul.
'Cause them pelts we collected
are still out there, you know...
under a couple foot of dirt and snow.
But that ain't my fault.
I'm waiting for Captain Leavenworth
to arrive with his army.
Then we'll have enough men...
to shoot some civilization into those
fucking Arikara and get back our pelts.
All right. All right.
When's that supposed to happen?
I don't know.
But until then, nobody gets paid.
Listen here, all right?
I was hired to trap 'em.
I wasn't hired to guard 'em.
The way I see it, now you, you got a safe.
It's probably full of money.
You signed a contract to protect your boss
and your boss's property.
And that safe isn't full anymore.
It's short about $300.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
It means, according to my records...
you purchased more goods on the expedition
than what you are owed by the company.
Now, Happy New Year, Fitzgerald.
(UPBEAT FOLK MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
(URGES HORSE)
(ARIKARA WARRIORS WHOOPING)
(PANTING)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHING)
(SIGHS)
GUARD: Fryman! White man at the gate!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Speak English.
I have no weapon.
- (SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Open her up!
Get the Captain!
HENRY: Where are your men?
All dead.
Who was he?
I don't know. Something to eat, please?
Food comes at a price.
I have no money.
Then you don't eat.
Give back some of them stolen pelts
you buy from the Injuns.
- Not now, Jones.
- Huh?
Silver. How is this? Silver.
This all you got?
We was nine.
My friend, he die in the snow.
And the other was...
kill by wolf. I see it.
By wolf, yeah, kill.
Where'd you get this?
Canteen.
He drop it.
He kill Toussaint, he drop it...
Who? Who?
I don't know. I don't see.
It could be Hawk.
Yeah, could be.
JONES: That half-breed runt
couldn't steal no horse.
- Maybe it was Weston.
- STUBBY BILL: Or Beckett.
How far from here?
(STAMMERS) Thirty mile.
Northwest, near the Yellowstone.
The Yellowstone!
Get the horses saddled.
Torches and supplies.
Ten dollars a man.
Anderson, you stay here.
ANDERSON: Yes, sir.
Feed him and watch him.
I'll get you a drink.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
HENRY: When we get to the Yellowstone,
we split into two groups!
HENRY: Hawk!
JIM: Hawk, you out there?
(GUNSHOT)
- Whoa! Whoa!
- (HORSES WHINNYING)
HENRY: Keep your guard up!
Eyes in front!
Who are you?
FRYMAN: Beckett? Is that you?
(MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
HENRY: Glass?
Glass!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ, what happened?
Where is he?
(WHEEZING)
HENRY: Jones, take him. Go.
I'm riding ahead. Bill, take Bridger.
Take Bridger!
Have you seen Fitzgerald?
No, sir.
Get up. Get up!
- You seen Fitzgerald?
- No, sir.
Fitzgerald?
- Whoa, easy.
- Where did he go?
- Who?
- Fitzgerald. Where did he go?
I have no idea.
Tell me or I'll take your head off.
I swear to God... (GROANS)
Tell me. Tell me!
Texas!
He said he was going to Texas.
He said he was gonna reenlist.
Then he started talking about property.
"A decent piece of land."
He's heading for Texas. That's all I know.
Stay here.
Fitzgerald!
(METAL CLANKING)
(OBJECT CLATTERS)
(GASPS)
Goddamn it!
GUARD: Jones! Get the Captain!
Fryman!
JONES: Open the gate!
GUARD: Open it up!
JONES: Murphy, get the Captain.
Get him to the doctor. Now!
You said he was dead!
I thought he was, I swear!
(HENRY GRUNTING)
JIM: He lied to me!
HENRY: You're a liar.
You left him out there!
Say the Lord's Prayer.
Say the Lord's Prayer!
Our Father, Who art in heaven.
Who art... (SOBBING) I can't!
Shut up! Shut up!
From here out, you're a prisoner
charged with treason!
Take him to the cage! Take him
to the cage or you'll hang alongside him!
I thought he was gonna die!
Fitz lied to me!
I couldn't help him!
Glass!
Fitz lied to me!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(DOGS BARKING)
(GLASS BREATHING HEAVILY)
How is he?
DOCTOR:
He'll be fine, but there is swelling.
He needs to rest.
I'll be back to check up on him.
GLASS: He ran off, didn't he?
Bridger's telling the truth.
How's that?
Fitzgerald lied to him.
He was just following orders.
He wasn't there when Fitzgerald
stabbed my boy to death.
Is that what happened?
He killed Hawk.
I need a horse and gun.
No, you need to rest and eat.
I'm going after him.
No.
You'll never find him without me.
If we wait till morning he'll get away.
No, he won't.
He's afraid.
He knows how far I came for him.
Same as that elk.
When they get afraid,
they run deep into the woods.
I got him trapped.
He just doesn't know it yet.
How can you be so sure?
'Cause he has everything to lose.
All I had was that boy.
And he took him away from me.
I can't let you go back out there.
Not again.
I ain't afraid to die anymore.
I done it already.
I'm going with you.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SIGHS)
(DOGS BARKING)
(GLASS URGING HORSE)
GLASS: That's his horse, all right.
No way he could've ridden him
through the night.
HENRY: How far ahead?
Half a day at the most.
Could be Ree.
If they aren't his, we lose him.
Unless he reenlisted so he
could justify killing again...
these tracks right here are his.
(GLASS URGING HORSE)
HENRY: I can't remember my wife's face.
Last week, she was still with me.
Now she's gone.
I worry I won't recognize her
when I get back home.
Is it true you killed an officer?
I just killed the man
who was trying to kill my son.
(SNIFFING)
Smoke.
How close?
No more than a mile up that way.
I'm gonna head up to the west.
You go down to the east.
Let's see if we can find some tracks.
And if it's the Ree?
If it's the Ree, you turn right back around
and meet me back here. (URGES HORSE)
(GLASS'S WIFE SPEAKING PAWNEE)
Now, I wouldn't expect to find
a man of your stature...
so far away from his stove
on a morning as cold as this, Captain.
You lost?
I'm here to take you back to Fort Kiowa...
where you will be tried for murder.
Is that so?
I ain't crazy about your plan.
Besides, I got one of my own.
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPS)
(HORSES WHINNYING)
(YELLS)
(PANTING)
(RUSTLING)
(YELPS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
We had a deal, Glass!
I tried to tell your boy, all right?
I tried to tell him,
but he wouldn't listen
and he kept on screaming.
He was gonna get everybody killed.
But you and me... we had a deal.
You know what happened out there.
And on my soul, the Lord... He knows...
what happened out there.
There was no deal.
You killed my boy.
Well, maybe you should've raised a man,
instead of some girlie little bitch.
=
Encoded By nItRo
www.300mbfilms.com & 300mbfilms.org
(YELLING)
(GROANS)
Goddamn it.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(GLASS SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(FITZGERALD HOWLS IN PAIN)
You came all this way
just for your revenge, huh?
Well, you enjoy it, Glass.
'Cause there ain't nothing
gonna bring your boy back.
No, it won't.
(HORSES APPROACHING)
(GLASS SPEAKING PAWNEE)
Revenge is in God's hands...
not mine.
(FITZGERALD SCREAMING)
(EXHALES)
(FITZGERALD STOPS SCREAMING)
(GLASS'S WIFE WHISPERING IN PAWNEE)
(GLASS EXHALING DEEPLY)
---The End---
>>>>
EnCoded By nItRo & UpLoaded By XpoZ
**xpoztorrent.blogspot.com**