Subtitles by Renatinha Tankinha
Some words have been
translated to American English
-I'm really sorry.
-Does he wear glasses
or contact lenses?
-Glasses.
-You'll have to hurry up.
-He decided that his
brown leather shoes
were the best pair to wear.
His back hurt a little,
but not like some other times
in the past when
the pain was intolerable.
He was thinking his wife
didn't love him at all anymore.
He didn't burst into
tears and he
didn't think that the first
thing most people do
when they realize someone
doesn't love them anymore
is cry.
-Sir, do you mind taking
a look into the camera here for me?
That will do.
Thank you.
Have you ever been
on your own before?
-No, never.
-Are you allergic to any foods?
-No.
-Your last relationship
lasted how many years?
-Around twelve.
-Do you remember how
long exactly, sir?
-Eleven years and
one month.
-Sexual preference?
-Women.
-However I...I had
one homosexual experience.
In the past. In college.
Is there a bisexual
option available?
-No sir, this option
is no longer available
since about last summer,
due to several operational problems.
-Hmm. -I'm afraid you have
to decide right now if you
want to be registered as a
homosexual or a heterosexual.
-I think I should be
registered as a heterosexual.
-Any children, sir?
-No.
-And the dog?
-My brother.
He was here a couple of years
ago but he didn't make it.
You might remember him.
Medium build.
Forty-eight years old.
Bald patch, blond hair.
-I'm afraid not, sir.
Ok, I would like you
to write your name clearly on this form.
In capital letters.
And sign it, please.
Ok, thank you very much.
Ok, so, you are not allowed to use
the volleyball or the tennis courts.
These are only for the couples.
You can use the facilities for
individual sports such
as squash and golf.
You can stay in the hotel
for up to forty-five days,
You will be staying
in the single room.
If everything goes
well and you make it,
you can move to a double room.
-I'm afraid you cannot
keep any of your personal belongings.
We will provide everything
you need as far as
garments, accessories and
shoes are concerned.
-You can keep this.
-Thank you.
-Shoe size, please?
-Forty-four and a half.
-Forty four or forty five?
There are no half sizes.
-Forty five.
-If you need a haircut,
call reception one day ahead.
Smoking is not allowed.
That way, you will be able
to run for longer during the
hand  without getting tired.
And your breath won't
smell when you kiss.
Enjoy your stay.
-Excuse me.
If we need to get a
haircut,
we must call the reception the
day before, is that right?
-That's right.
-Great.
-His room number was 101.
A tranquilizer gun was
hanging on the wall above his bed.
On the table were twenty
tranquilizer darts,
a black plastic watch,
a pair of sunglasses,
and a cologne for men.
Inside the wardrobe were
four identical Grey pants,
four identical button-down
shirts in white and blue,
a belt, socks, underwear,
a blazer,
a striped tie, and a
white bathrobe.
He looked out the window.
The unconscious bodies
of the captured
loners were lying
on the wet ground.
Thank God they wore
those waterproof ponchos.
He thought.
-Room... 115
two loners...two extra days
Room 272.
One loner.
One extra day.
-Hello.
I'm the hotel manager
and this gentleman is my partner.
We'd like to welcome you.
You're one of the lucky ones.
You have one of our
superior rooms, which
means you have a view.
Did you read the panphlet?
-Yes, I did.
-very good.
Now, the fact that you'll
turn into an animal
if you fail to fall in love
with someone here,
is not something that
should upset you or get you down.
Just think: as an animal, you'll have
a second chance to find a companion.
But even then
you must be careful.
You need to choose a companion
that is a similar type of animal to you.
A wolf and a penguin can
never live together.
Nor could a camel and a hippopotamus.
That'd be absurd.
Think about it.
I understand this discussion
is a little unpleasant for you.
But it is my duty to prepare you
psychologically for all
possible outcomes.
Now, have you thought
of what animal
you'd like to be if
you end up alone?
-Yes, a lobster.
-Why a lobster?
-Because lobsters live...
for over one-hundred years.
are blue-blooded like
aristocrats.
And stay fertile
all their lives.
I also...like the sea...
very much.
I water ski and swim quite
well. Since I was a teenager.
-I must congratulate you.
The first thing most people
think of is a dog.
Which is why the
world is full of dogs.
Very few people choose
an unusual animal,
which is why they
are endangered.
A lobster's an excellent choice.
Could you stand for us, please?
This is to show you how easy
life is when there are two of
something rather than one.
We tend to forget
that from time to time.
The handcuff will be
removed at the same time tomorrow.
-Sorry about him.
-I hope you enjoy your stay with us.
Goodbye.
-Have a good day.
-Good morning.
Room 101.
forty-four days left.
Breakfast is served.
-His first day was
one he'd never forget.
Near his table at breakfast,
sat a young woman
with her head tilted back.
Later he would learn that
she often got nosebleeds.
Next to her sat her best friend.
He thanked the waiter
who served him his coffee
and thought about
his wife for a moment.
A woman who seemed
to like butter cookies
offered one to a man drinking
a Campari and soda for breakfast.
He then looked behind
him and saw a woman
who he would later find
out was absolutely heartless.
And some others
in the couples' area
whom he'd never meet
during his stay at the hotel.
That morning, he was really hungry.
He could have eaten a whole chicken.
But ate almost nothing.
-Hello.
-I've decided to go for
a walk outside with my new friend.
Let me introduce you.
This is Robert.
He stays in the room next
to mine and has a lisp.
-Pleased to meet you.
I'm staying in room 101.
-I...I'm on the
same floor. I'm 186.
-Would you like to join us?
-Why not?
-One of these days, it's
gonna be me on one of those yachts.
-What are those yachts?
-The final ordeal before
letting you go, and the hardest one.
Fifteen days of vacation,
just a couple alone
-Did anybody believe it?
-I did.
-Have you seen John's leg?
-No.
-John, would you...
show your leg?
-Oh, yeah.
-Room 187 day two.
-Hello, everyone.
My mother was left on her own when
my father fell in love
with a woman who was better
at math than she was.
She had postgraduate degree, I think.
Whereas my mother
was only a graduate.
I was nineteen at the time.
My mother entered the
hotel but didn't make it
and was turned into a wolf.
I really missed her.
I found out she'd
been moved to a zoo.
I often went there to see her.
I'd give her raw meat.
I knew that wolves liked raw meat.
But I couldn't figure out
which of the wolves was my
mother, so I used to give a
little bit to each of them.
One day I decided
to enter the enclosure.
I really missed her
and I wanted a hug.
I climbed the fence
and jumped in.
All the wolves charged
at once and attacked me.
All but two, who
stood motionless.
My guess is that one of those
two must have been my mother.
The zoo guards got to me
quite quickly and took me to the hospital.
Thankfully, I didn't lose my
leg. I just have this limp,
which is also my defining characteristic.
My wife died six days ago.
She was very beautiful
and I loved her very much.
She had a limp, too.
-Thank you, John,
you can return to your seat.
Let's move on to our next guest:
room 104 day two.
-Hello, everyone.
This is only my
second day here.
But already I feel like I'm
in the middle of a wonderful group.
My defining characteristic is
that I have a very beautiful smile.
-Have you ever danced
with anybody?
-Sorry?
-Have you ever danced
with anybody?
-Yes!
-What sort of dancing
did you do?
-Just depends on the music.
Do you need to sit down?
-No, no, no. I'm getting ready to dance.
-Oh.
-Can I sit here?
Sorry.
-Of course.
Let me introduce you
to my best friend.
That woman you were talking
to has no feelings whatsoever.
She feels nothing at all.
-She's the best hunter
in the hotel.
Silent and very fast.
She's the women's
record holder.
192 captives.
-Would you like to dance?
-I'm sorry I got blood in your shirt.
But don't worry. There are  many ways
to remove blood stains in clothing.
One way is to rinse the clothes
with cold water then rub with sea salt.
Another way is to
scrub the stains
with a cotton ball
dipped in ammonia.
The third way is
to mix flour and water
into a paste
like toothpaste
Especially if the clothes
are delicate or brightly colored.
But just never use warm
water on blood, ever.
-Great.
-I think I have to rest
for a little bit.
My legs hurt.
-That's Ok.
Well, let me know when
you feel better and we can dance again.
-Leave the room
in an orderly fashion.
Do hurry up but
please be careful.
We don't need to
get hurt or injured.
And good luck with the hunt.
-I wish I didn't have this limp.
I used to be very
good at running, but not anymore.
I'm sure I'll be slower than them.
-If I were you, I'd think of some
tricks that choose the element of surprise.
-Instead of speed.
-You're right.
That's what I'll do.
Room 186.
One loner.
One extra day.
38 days that are left.
Plus one, plus nine.
Room 180.
The days of your
stay remain unchanged.
Room 290.
Four loners.
Four extra days.
One hundred and fifty-four
days left plus four.
158.
Room 101.
The days of your
stay remain unchanged.
32 days left.
Breakfast is served.
Man eats alone.
-How many darts did you use yesterday?
-Twelve.
Please take off your
pants and sit on the bed.
-Can we not do this today?
It's awful.
-I know.
But I'm afraid we
have to do it.
And you have no idea
how much it helps psychologically
in your search for a partner.
-Man eats with woman.
-Is your room number 186?
-Yes, it is.
-I imagine you know that
masturbation is not permitted
in the rooms or in any
other area of the hotel.
-Yes.
-And yet, it has been brought
to my attention that you continue to do it.
-Today, we can erect
quicker than in other days.
That's good.
-Please, just a little longer.
-Have a good day.
-That's awful.
Just awful.
-Were you looking at a
photograph while you were masturbating?
-Yes.
-What did the photograph show?
-A naked woman on a horse.
In the country.
-If I were in your shoes,
I would not be ogling
the naked woman, but the horse.
I'm sure that once was
a weak and cowardly man just like you.
-Woman walks alone.
-Help!
-This is not necessary. Please.
It was an accident.
I just got carried away.
-Please.
-This is not necessary.
-Please. Place your hand in the toaster,
-This could be a warning.
But I've been good otherwise. I...
Ow! Ow!!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Ow! Ow!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, please!
Please, please, I'm sorry!
-Woman walks with man.
-What they do
as soon as you enter the room
is to wash your head and
your body really well.
-How do you know?
-My uncle used to
know a waiter who worked here.
-No waiters know about the procedure.
They are not allowed inside that room.
-Nevertheless
They peel off the skin,
which has become soft,
due to the water and the soap.
Afterward, they remove the heart,
the eyes, and other
vital organs of the body
with a laser or scalpels
Then the procedure changes
according to the animal when it's chosen.
-That makes total sense.
I mean, I suppose
mammals demand a different
kind of work than
Ferrets for example.
-Exactly.
Afterward, they throw the
remaining body parts into the casks
outside the hotel's restaurant
and distribute the blood
to the hospitals in the city.
-Why is that?
-The blood is used for surgeries
where there are no blood donors available.
-New guests arrived yesterday.
-Yes, I saw them.
-I think I saw a
woman with a limp.
-It's just a sprained ankle.
She'll be walking normal
again in a few days.
-That's a shame.
-That is a shame indeed.
-One night, on the coach,
He sat next to the woman
who liked butter cookies.
He gazed out of the window.
Not looking at
anything in particular.
Just trying to avoid
talking to her.
-How's Bob?
-He's fine.
-I'd give anything to go
on a walk with you and Bob one afternoon.
-The dog's not allowed
out of the room, I'm afraid.
-There are some excuses that no
one can argue with. He thought.
Some excuses are, without
doubt, better than others.
And that was a really good one.
-These cookies are
for Bob.
I want you to give
them to him
whenever you want to reward
him for something.
Tell him they're from me.
-Thank you.
-Could I come to your
room sometime for a chat?
I could give you a blow job.
Or you can just fuck me.
I always swallow after
fellatio and I have absolutely
no problem with anal
sex if that's your thing.
My ex-husband always used to say I had
the most beautiful eyes he'd ever seen.
But let's not talk about him.
My room number is 180
So my telephone
extension is 180.
I hope I catch some loners tonight.
I haven't caught any
in the last few nights.
Hope you catch lots, too.
-Thank you very much.
-If I don't find a suitable
partner soon,
I'm going to kill myself by throwing
myself out of one of the rooms.
Out the window.
I want you to know that.
My room is on the first floor.
-"I hope I catch some loners today",
She said.
"And I hope you catch lots, too."
She then told him that
if she didn't find a suitable partner soon,
she was going to kill herself
by jumping from one of the room windows.
320, maybe.
Or one higher up.
480.
That would be even better.
When she stopped talking,
he stared at her blankly,
not knowing what to say.
He then looked out at the woods
and thought once more
how good his excuse had been.
-Not bad. A bit higher.
-You thought about
what animals
you want to be if
you don't make it?
-A lobster.
-I'm going to be a parrot
if I don't make it.
Why don't you become parrots, too?
And then we'll all be together.
-You're a complete idiot.
Picking one of the few
animals that can talk
when you have a
speech impairment?
You'll lisp, even as an animal.
As for you, they'll cut you
and put you in a pot of boiling water
until you die, and then
they'll crack open your claws
with a tool, like pliers,
and they'll suck up
whatever flesh you have with their mouths,
you're pathetic, both of you.
I'm not going to be
turned into some animal.
I'll come and visit you, though.
With my partner.
When we're walking together
in some park or...
when we're swimming in the sea,
or when we're in one of our trips.
-I'm not afraid.
-Room 187 please.
It's no coincidence
that the targets are shaped like
single
people, and not couples.
-Hello!
-Hello.
-Your swimsuit is very nice.
-Thanks.
-Thank you very much.
-You're welcome.
Do you like to swim breaststroke,
front-crawl, butterfly, or back stroke?
I like also deep-ling.
-You know, I love breaststroke.
No, really. My friends
often tease me
saying "stop swimming breaststroke
all the time"...
And then they laugh.
-Breaststroke is great.
It's excellent exercise for the back.
-When swimming breaststroke,
Make sure you wear swim shorts.
Because it really limits
movement in the buttocks.
But you knew that, didn't you?
-I think your nose is bleeding.
-Really?
-Oh, no.
This happens to me all the time.
it's really, really annoying.
-Oh, no! I have a nose-bleed
problem, too.
-I saw what you did.
Must have hurt.
-Is it coming out?
-No...
Yes.
-Can I use a tissue?
I'm going to ask you a question,
I want you to answer me honestly.
What's worse?
To die of cold and hunger in the woods,
to become an animal that will
be killed and eaten by some other animal,
or to have a nose-bleed
from time to time?
-To become an animal that will
be killed and eaten by some other animal
-Exactly.
-Hmm.
She doesn't suspect
that you're lying?
-No.
-I'm very happy because
we have a new couple.
They met just two day ago
but they are very much in love
and perfectly suited.
They both have the
same problem with their noses.
They'd be quite a family.
Tomorrow they will
be transferred to a double room,
with a larger closet and
a larger bathroom.
They will remain in
the double room for two weeks,
And then they will be transferred to
the yachts for a further two weeks.
We wish you every success
and we hope you will
return to the city as a couple.
-I'm very happy!
-Me too!
-Congratulations.
The course of your relationship
will be monitored closely
by our staff and by me personally.
If you encounter any
problems, any tensions,
any arguments you cannot
resolve yourselves,
you'll be assigned children,
that usually helps. A lot.
-Good morning.
Room 101.
Seven days left.
Breakfast is served.
You have
really nice hair.
-I know.
-How do you like mine?
-Well, I think you
have quite dry hair.
The color's Ok, though.
The most important thing
is that you're not bald.
However, when it comes to men,
baldness is always a
possibility you can't avoid.
Is your father bald?
-No, he isn't.
And even if I
someday lose my hair,
there are things I can
do to get my hair back.
I can have a hair transplant.
You can always tell when
somebody's had a hair transplant.
I know.
-Nice hair is not
something you can get.
It's something you're born with.
And the fact that your
father isn't bald
shouldn't put you at ease.
-Have you decided what you are
going to do on your last day?
-I'm still thinking about it.
-Good morning, ladies.
So,
today is your last day.
And, as is custom, you
can choose
how you would like
to spend your last night
What I always say in
these situations is it
would be wise to do
something you can't do as an animal.
For example, read a
work of Catholic Literature.
or sing a song you really like.
It would be silly to choose
for example, a walk in the grounds
or to have sexual intercourse
with another person,
because those are
things you can do
as an animal.
But first, your best
friend has written something
she'd like to read to you,
which is really very touching.
-"We always sat together at school.
and whenever I had a problem,
I talked to you about it
because you always
gave the best advice.
When we didn't manage to
find dance partners at the school prom,
the fact that we were together
at that difficult moment gave me strength.
I'm sorry that things have come to this.
I'm sure if you had a
few more days,
you would find someone
just like I did.
Because you're an admirable person,
and you have very hair
and very nice breasts.
I was always jealous of
your hair, you know that.
You were, are and always
will be my best friend,
and I'll think of you often.
And I'll always wear those silver
earrings you gave me for my birthday.
I'll miss you.
And however many new
girl friends I make in a few days,
when I move back
into the city,
I don't think I'll
find another as true."
-I'd like to watch
the movie 'Stand by me',
with River Phoenix,
Kiefer Sutherland, and Richard Dreyfuss
Alone.
-Excellent choice.
Lovely film.
-Please...leave...a message.
-Hello.
You're probably in the bathroom,
that's why you can't hear the phone ring.
Nothing like a cold
shower in the morning!
Well, I'll...Call you...
a little bit later.
After you finish your shower.
We'll talk later.
Bye.
-One day, as he was playing golf,
he thought that it's more
difficult to pretend
that you do have
feelings when you don't,
than to pretend you don't
have feelings when you do.
He also thought that
he liked her accent.
And he'd always preferred
women with short hair.
So he decided that she was the one.
During the hunt,
he would follow her,
and as soon as she shot a loner,
he would say to her
"I wish we had real guns instead
of these silly tranquilizer ones.
Why don't you kill him
with your bear hands?"
And the moment she put her
hands around the loner's throat,
he would say "I hope
he dies right away."
-What happened?
-She jumped from the
window of room 180.
There was blood
and crackers everywhere.
-I hope she dies right away.
On second thoughts...
I hope she suffers quite
a bit before she dies.
I just hope her pathetic screams
can't be heard from my room.
Because I was thinking
of having a lie down.
And I need peace and quiet.
I was playing golf
and I'm quite tired.
The last thing I need is
some woman dying slowly and loudly.
-I can't hear you with
all the screaming.
We'll talk some other
time when it's quieter.
Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
-One message.
-Hello.
You're probably in the bathroom,
that's why you can't hear the phone ring.
Nothing like a cold
shower in the morning.
Well, I'll...
call you
a little bit later,
after you finish your shower.
We'll talk later.
Bye.
-Mind if I join you?
Good Martini.
-I think we are a match.
-Yes, I think so, too.
-The keys to the
double room, please.
I wish you the best of luck.
We all wish you the best of luck.
-We can only sleep on the left
side of the bed or the right.
-The right.
You?
-The left.
Perfect.
Should I turn off the light
or would you like to read?
-I'd like to read.
Does the light bother you?
-No.
I'm not bothered
by light or noise.
I'm a deep sleeper.
-Hello.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
-This is our new daughter.
Her name's Elizabeth.
Elizabeth, give the nice man a kiss.
He's a friend of mine.
-The last thing I want right now
is a kiss from a silly little girl.
-Oh!
-Ow!
-Come on.
-Don't cry, Elizabeth, you
should thank me.
Now you'll have a limp.
You'll be more like your father,
-Good morning.
-Morning.
- I killed your brother.
I left him to die very slowly.
He may not be dead yet
even as we speak.
I was kicking him for ages.
-It doesn't matter.
-He whined a little
strange kind of bark.
Something like this.
Must have been from the pain.
-Didn't hear anything?
-No.
-You really are a deep sleeper.
Would you like some coffee?
-I'd love some.
As soon as I wash my face
and brush my teeth off.
-I can't wait to hear the story
you promised to tell me last night.
About that student of
yours at the university.
And his awful, final project.
-It's really a very funny story.
His name was Ryess.
R-Y-E-S-S. Ryess.
These are not tears. It's just water.
I just washed my face.
-I knew you were lying.
I can't understand why you did it.
When you know as well as anyone
that a relationship
cannot be built on a lie.
We're going to the
hotel manager right now.
And you'll get the
punishment you deserve.
-What's the punishment for this?
-They turn you into the
animal no one wants to be.
-I saw your partner heading
back that way.
He looked frantic.
Is everything Ok?
-At first he wanted to kill her
in some horrible and painful way,
like the death she had
inflicted on his brother.
He thought about kicking
her in the stomach...over and over again
and then stabbing her on the same spot.
In the stomach.
Then he thought it wouldn't
be much point, because
she was already
unconscious, so wouldn't
feel any pain from the
kicks or the knife.
-You have to shoot me.
So they won't suspect I helped you.
-A hotel maid helped him.
He couldn't understand why she did it.
So he decided to
turn her into an animal.
He dragged her to the room
where the transformations took place.
I asked him many times what
sort of animal he turned her into, but
he always gave me the same answer,
"That's none of your concern."
That night, he left the hotel
once and for all.
He began to run without
knowing where he was headed.
But he was headed towards us.
This was the start of his new life.
Back then, he didn't know
how much it hurts to be alone.
How much it hurts when
you cannot reach to rub
pain relief ointment on your back.
And you're constantly in pain.
-Find him in the woods.
He escaped from the hotel.
-Are you a doctor, by any chance?
-No.
-That's a pity.
We need a doctor around.
We had one but they caught
him a couple of months ago.
-I'm an architect.
-That's Ok.
You're still welcome.
You can stay with
us for as  long as you like.
You can be a loner
until the day you die.
There is no time limit.
-Thank you very much.
-By the way,
any romantic or sexual relations
between loners are not permitted.
And any such acts are punished.
Is that clear?
-Can I have a conversation
with someone?
-Of course you can.
So long as there is no
flirting or anything like that.
That applies to dance nights as well,
We all dance by ourselves.
That's why we only play electronic music.
-What happened to your mouth?
-He can't speak.
He was given the red kiss.
-What's the red kiss?
-We slashed his lips with a razor
on the lips of another loner
and forced them to kiss each other.
It was a couple of days ago now.
But the cuts are deep
and they're still in pain.
They were flirting, you know?
-Some punishments are worse
than other punishments.
Having your thumb cut is
worse than having your head shaved.
And having a hard-boiled
egg under your armpit
is worse than
having your leg kicked.
The punishment I'm afraid of
isn't the red kiss,
but another one that is
called the red intercourse.
I have never seen it happen,
but it is not difficult
to imagine what it means.
Oh my god.
I am so afraid of it.
-Move!
Hide!
Move!
-That was the first time I saw him.
He was hiding behind
a tree close to mine.
He seemed quite presentable.
The next day,
in the city,
he found out that I
was nearsighted, too.
That night,
in my sleep, I dreamt that we lived
in a big house together in the city,
with a large, well-lit kitchen,
and I was wearing dark blue pants,
and a tight cream blouse,
and he took my clothes
off and fucked me up the ass.
And as he was fucking me,
a thug came into the kitchen
and took the steak
knives from the second drawer
and attacked us,
stabbing the knives into
our bellies one by one.
I woke up terrified.
-Try harder
Don't give up. You know
you should have been more careful.
Try harder, or
they're going to find you
and you'll be turned
into an animal.
A weak one.
We must get a move on now.
It's really too
dangerous to stay here.
If you manage to free yourself,
run as fast as you can and come find us.
If you manage to free yourself
but think you'll die from the beating,
go straight to your grave.
Have you dug your own grave?
Yes.
Very good.
That's enough for now.
I'm going to go hunting for truffles.
They're delicious and quite rare.
A kilo can fetch a lot of money.
-You're going to need a pig.
They're impossible to find otherwise.
I know.
Don't be long. Gotta get
then back in fifteen minutes.
-Ok.
-Hello, David.
-Hello, Robert.
-What you did to that
woman was dreadful.
-She killed my brother.
I would have done the
same thing if she killed you.
You...you're like
a brother to me.
Oh, you're my best friend
in the whole world.
-I don't think I'm your best
friend in the whole world.
You used to spend much more time with John.
-Oh, who's John?
-John, the limping man.
-Oh, yeah. I didn't even
remember his name.
Or his face.
You're the one I think of
whenever I need a friend.
Nevertheless, did John make it?
-They're getting ready
for the yacht.
It all begins this week.
-Everyone says they're
going to make it,
as they are perfectly
suited and the child
will help them with the
fighting and the arguing.
-That's great.
-You're not thinking
about coming back?
You know, If you told the hotel
manager about your brother,
she'd probably forgive you.
-No.
It's really nice to be on your own.
There's no one
tying you down,
you listen to music
whenever you like,
you masturbate whenever you want,
go for walks whenever you like,
have a chat whenever you like...
I don't miss companionship at all.
I just miss you, because
you're my one true friend.
Are you gonna shoot me?
-I'm afraid so.
Only have two days left.
-What did you say?
I can't understand
the way you speak.
-I'm going to shoot you.
I only have two days left.
I need more time.
-You actually believe
a day will make a difference?
Have you seen how
ugly you are?
You haven't got a chance.
If I was a woman I...
-Don't tell anyone I helped you.
If you want to repay me,
there is a way.
If you kill a rabbit,
bring it to me to eat.
Do you promise?
-Yes.
-Bye.
-Boujur
-Bonjur.
You brought what I asked for?
Of course.
The gun is in the pocket
with the electronic keys with the
numbers of the double rooms.
Try not to lose the keys.
I need to return them
I propose we act on Saturday.
After the ball Everyone is tired...
and most employees are
gone on the week-end.
And the shampoo?
I forgot.
I'll bring two bottles next time.
Do you know how fantastic you are?
Please make a note for the
shampoo so you don't forget.
I need to tell you something
What?
This is my last mission.
I can't do it anymore.
I can't stand living in that horrible
mansion with that fat dentist.
He keeps asking if I've flossed.
He makes me clean my teeth
after every meal no matter how small it is.
After we're finished setting
up for the big night
you can come and live with us.
I'll find another mole.
I don't think I'll ever find
someone as efficient as you
but I need to respect your wishes.
Be patient just a few more days...
and don't forget to take
your birth control pill. Ok?
Thank you.
No, thank you.
You were fantastic.
-You carefully fillet
the rabbit with a sharp knife
and cut off its head.
You then slice open its belly
and stuff it with well washed
red and green peppers,
not too spicy, and a
little garlic and mint.
You then soak it in lemon juice
and leave it a while
to marinate the flesh
before you skewer it on a stick
and roast it over
the fire for about an hour.
That's my favorite food.
Rabbit.
Woman. Brunette.
fifty years old.
Marriage certificate expired
two months ago.
-My husband's away on a
business trip.
-Yeah. Ok, can I
have a look?
Hands.
No dirt under nails
or mud on her shoes.
Nine belt size robe.
-So your husband is away?
-Yes.
-Where?
-Far,
-Good Morning, sir.
Are you here alone?
-Good morning, officer.
No, I'm here with my partner.
She's inside one of the stores.
Shopping.
Right now.
-Can I see your certificate, please?
-My partner keeps it in her purse.
You see,
I am losing it
all the time.
-I see.
And what store is
she shopping in?
-Oh.
Here she is.
-I'm sorry, darling.
They had such a huge variety
of pain relief ointment,
I bought you this one; I hope it's
the one you were looking for.
-That's wonderful, dear.
Can I have my certificate, please?
-Of course, darling.
Would you like to
see mine also, officer?
-No, that's Ok.
-Thank you, sir.
You have a good day.
-Thank you officer. You
have a good day.
-Madam.
-Sir.
-If I'm walking too
slowly just say it,
and I'll pick up my pace.
-This pace is fine.
Maybe don't squeeze
my hand so tight;
my palm's getting
a little sweaty.
-Better?
-Yes.
Much better.
-Are you planning on buying
anything else nice for yourself
while we're here?
-Yes.
Contact lens solution.
and a Parker roller-ball.
-I didn't know you were near sighted.
I'm near sighted, too.
-Will you stay a few days?
-I'm afraid not, papa.
We're heading back again today.
Tomorrow I'm going away
on a business trip.
You know how demanding my job is.
Don't ask if I can stay
a few days every time I come.
-Do you all work
for the same company?
-Yes.
-My daughter says me
it's very fine company.
Do you agree?
-It's a rather good company.
-It is.
-One of the best, I'd say.
-Hmm.
-The only problem...
with the job is that
I don't have enough time...
for my wife, and kids.
-We have four beautiful children.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
But even if we never had children,
I would never dream...
of leaving my wife.
Even if it was just the two of us.
On our own.
We'd go on trips.
We'd go to Portofino,
in Italy,
or go to Greek island,
for the summer,
and so our relationship
would be as intense
as it was at the start.
I love
my wife so much.
I could die for her.
That's how much I love her.
-For your first day
in the city, you did great.
That part about
holiday destination in the
Mediterranean was brilliant.
-Thank you very much.
When did you become near sighted?
-When I was sixteen.
You?
-When I was twelve.
-What was the make
of your first pair of glasses?
-I don't remember.
-Do you have astigmatism, too?
-Yes.
-Would you like me to rub
some balm on your back?
I wanna bet you can't
reach on your own.
-I'd like that.
-Here?
-A little lower, please.
-Yes.
-Hello everyone, and
good luck.
Your room numbers
are as follows:
Room 306: the hotel
manager and her partner.
They both...they both
have nice voices.
Room 240: couple who
both like to ski.
Room 282:
couple who both
studied social sciences.
Name of the yacht Bliss,
couple prone to nosebleeds.
-You and you take 306.
You and you take 240,
You take 282
and you two, take the yacht.
-Can I go to the yacht?
-Ok, then, so you
take the yacht
And you take 282.
And...uh...
us three,
we'll take the manager's room.
We have forty minutes.
-Wake up.
Get up.
Sit in that seat over there.
Put your hand behind your back.
-A basketball weighs between
550 and 650 grams.
-Did you know that?
-No, I didn't know that.
-Yes.
The weight's different
for men's and women's games,
but that's roughly
how much it weighs.
Do you know how much
a volleyball weighs?
-No. But I'd like to find out.
-Good evening.
I have something to tell you.
His nose doesn't really
bleed on its own.
He bangs it against
the wall,
or a piece of hard wood, or
something like that.
Or he cuts it with a pen knife
when you're not looking.
You two are not suited.
-Shut up. Dad, tell him to
leave, I'm sleeping.
-And...and I'm quite sure
that stain on his t-shirt isn't blood,
but cherry juice or tomato
ketchup or red watercolor paint,
Or something like that.
or beetroot juice.
-Do you love her?
-With all my heart.
-How much to you love her?
On a scale of one to fifteen?
-Fourteen.
-Fourteen is a very impressive score.
-He loves her very much indeed.
-Who do you think we should kill?
Who will be able to live
on their own better?
Here is the knife, mom,
kill him
-You better get out
while you still can.
-Ok...Ok...
-That's all you came to say to me?
-You...
If this woman dies,
Do you think you'll
manage it on your own?
Or will you get involved
with someone else?
-No.
I.. I can live alone, she can't
I'm on my own for hours
when she got out the hotel.
I like sitting in the room.
Relaxes me.
Calms me.
I like it a lot.
I can definitely live...
on my own.
-Be quiet.
-Take it.
Shoot her.
-Help!
No! No!
-Where were you?
I was looking for you.
-I was masturbating
behind those trees...
Over there.
-Why aren't you dancing?
-My leg's a little sore.
-Did you dig your grave?
-Not yet.
-I don't mean to pressure you,
or to ruin the mood
now that we're celebrating,
but at some point
you'll have to do it.
Don't expect anyone else
to dig your grave for you.
Or to carry your corpse.
We'll throw some dirt
over you, but that's about it.
Tomorrow, find a spot you like,
where the ground isn't
too rocky and make a start.
Enjoy the rest of your evening.
-Thank you/
-As soon as his last patient left,
I entered his office and said to him:
Honey, the dinner is ready.
However, I'm not sure
I can eat right now.
One of my front teeth hurts a lot.
Can you take a look,
please, dear?
"Yes, sure, no problem."
he said.
In a minute he turned his
head and took the drill,
and I shoved it to his chest.
-That story sounds really
interesting, but I have to leave.
I just remembered I left some
batteries next to a tree down there.
And the last thing I
want is to lose them.
Sorry.
-Did you...catch rabbits?
-No, someone brought me them.
-Who?
-A friend of mine.
-Do you want one?
-No.
You don't need to accept
rabbits form other people.
If you need more rabbits, just ask.
And I'll bring you more.
Catching rabbit is difficult,
but I'll try to do better.
There's not need for you
to be indebted to the others.
-Thank you very much.
-The man who brought
you the rabbits,
is he nearsighted?
-I don't know.
I don't think so.
-Ok.
-Is that a sparrow
up in that tree?
-I can't even see that far.
I don't think so.
-Are you nearsighted?
-No.
-You're lying.
-it's the truth.
-What...does it say here?
- "Y K K"
-You knew that already.
All zippers say the same thing.
-I'm not nearsighted.
I don't understand why
you won't believe me.
I can see really clearly.
I used to be a pilot.
-You're wearing contact lenses.
-I don't wear contact lenses
and I'm not nearsighted.
I swear.
-You are,
-You think I'm an
idiot and can't tell.
Let me see!
I wanna see your eyes.
-Look up.
Look up.
Up, up.
Look down now.
Look left.
Look right.
Up again.
-I'm sorry.
I thought you were trying to fool me.
I'm sorry.
For this synchronization
exercise, we have to
fully concentrate, because
we have to press
play at exactly the same time.
-Why don't we just use one headset?
-Because that's the whole point.
This is an exercise for us.
We have to be totally synchronized.
-I'm ready.
-Ok.
5...
4...
3...2...
We developed a code so
that we can communicate
with each other even in front of the others
without them knowing what we are saying.
When we turn our heads
to the left it means
"I love you more than
anything in the world"
and when we turn our heads to the right,
it means "watch out, we're in danger".
We had to be very careful in
the beginning not to mix up
"I love you more than
anything in the world" with
"watch out, we're in danger".
When we raise our left arm it means
"I want to dance in your arms",
when we make a fist
and put it behind our backs
it means "let's fuck".
The code grew and grew as time went by
and within a few weeks
we could talk about
almost anything without
even opening our mouths.
-Stop it!
That's enough.
Show my parents some respect.
They're playing music.
-That's Ok.
-No, mother.
It is not Ok.
-Please continue.
-You want us to perform the
same piece or something else?
-Something else.
Didn't her parents
play beautifully?
-Yes, they did.
It was wonderful.
-We love each other
and we suit each other.
And that's the reason why
we decided to leave the
woods and stay together
forever in the city.
Tomorrow,
during the hunt,
we're going to disappear and
everyone will think we've been captured.
And that we're going to be turned
into dogs, or canaries, or something.
I think the first thing I'm
going to do when I get into the city
is buy a bathrobe,
and then we'll go to
a pool with a high diving board
perfect for diving.
-"And we'll do lots
of different things together,
Serious things, not silly ones,
like go for walks in the
park or playing the-
guitar together.
It stops there.
There's notes at the back, but
I don't think it's important.
Read the notes.
Portofino. Italian fishing village
and upmarket resort famous
for its picturesque harbor.
Population: 439.
Beaches nearby:
Paraggi beach,
Camogli,
Chiavari and Lavagna.
Serifos.
Greek island located in the western
Cyclades.
Where did you find that?
By the river.
Someone must've dropped it during the hunt.
Give it to me.
I'll take care of it.
-Can you imagine why you were brought
to such a quiet place today?
-No.
-Because I think it's the
perfect spot for your grave.
Now cover yourself with soil.
Use your hands.
Over your face too.
You wouldn't want your face
to get eaten by dogs, would you?
If you die before me, I'll
visit you as often as I can.
I promise.
-I think we should leave right now.
The three of us coming here in a sudden
two, four...is
is very dangerous.
Why didn't we think of
that earlier?
Highly likely the doctor will suspect us,
I suggest that we leave the
first chance we get.
Right now, in a fact.
-Don't be afraid.
No one will suspect a thing.
I bet you weren't expecting the surprise.
Isn't it wonderful?
-Yes, it is.
Still, I'd like a few days
just to think it over so that...
I can...
maybe have the surgery when
we next come to the city?
-What's there to think about?
If it's better to see clearly
or to be nearsighted?
Is that it?
That's absurd. You
know that.
Anyway, this doctor is
the best there is.
And it's really very difficult
to get an appointment.
I called him months ago
to get him to see you today.
-She's blind.
-Thank you.
-Throw down you knife
and stand up.
-Why did you have to blind me?
You could have blinded him.
-I have no idea what
you're talking about.
The drugs are messing with your head.
If I were you, I'd try to be
a little more braver about the whole thing.
Now get up and give me your knife.
Or I'll hit you and take it by force.
Here I come.
-I swear I'm going to kill you.
-Let go of my hair,
you're hurting me.
-Just think...
...that when...
...someone goes blind...
...one of the other senses...
...is heightened.
-You could also capture
a dog in the woods
and train it to guide you.
Dogs can do that, you know.
I'll help you capture a dog myself.
Now calm down.
Well, I'm going to leave
you here,
and I don't think you'll manage to
find it on your own.
-Are you enjoying the view?
-Sure.
-What happened to your hand?
-I was cutting a tree branch with
a knife and I cut myself by accident.
You look...handsome today,
did you get your hair cut?
-Thank you,
No, I didn't get a haircut.
I'm going to get my hair cut today.
Look what I brought you.
-Oh, thank you so much,
I'm so hungry! I'll eat it right away.
-It's...a bigger flashlight.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
It's so big I thought
it was a rabbit.
-Huh.
-the biggest flashlight I've ever seen.
-Oh.
Are you ready for tonight?
-Of course I am.
I want to tell you something,
but please don't be angry.
-Ok, what's wrong?
-I can't see anything.
I'm blind.
-What do you mean?
-There's not point in lying to
you, you'll find out sooner or later.
Our leader blinded me in the city.
She must have realized
that I love you and...
you love me...and..
that we were going to run
away to the city, Together.
I'm sorry.
-You can't see at all?
-No, not at all.
-And when you asked...
if I had my hair cut?
-I was just saying that...
So you wouldn't realize I can't see.
I'm sorry!
-Don't cry.
Crying will make your eyes hurt more.
We'll find a way.
-What blood type are you?
-B.
♫ From the first time I saw
her, I knew she was the one. ♫
♫ She stared in my eyes,
and smiled. ♫
♫ And her lips were the color of roses. ♫
♫ The grew down on the river,
all bloody and wild, ♫
You like berries?
Blueberries? Blackberries?
-No, no.
-Can you play the piano?
-No.
Plastic cup.
-That's right.
Very good.
Do you speak German?
-No.
-I could teach you German.
It would take at least a year
for you to be able to speak
the basics not fluently,
so there's no point.
You know, German is one of
the most difficult languages to learn.
Because its grammar
is very complicated.
I've brought you something.
Fish.
-Huh.
♫ on the second day,
I brought her a flower. ♫
♫ She was more beautiful than any
woman I'd seen. ♫
♫ And I said do you know ♫
♫ where the wild roses grow? ♫
♫ So sweet and scarlet and free ♫
-Kiwi.
-That's right.
10 out of 10 again.
Can I give you a kiss?
-I can't thank you enough
for all the activities and games and...
for keeping me company, but...
you know we can't do this anymore.
Would you like to play
another round of
Touch, guess, think, win?
-No.
That's enough for today,
In any case...I've run out
of things to test you with.
Maybe tomorrow.
Or...one of these days.
-Tomorrow morning?
-Uh, we'll see.
-Bye.
-Good afternoon.
-How are you?
-Fine.
-I'm hungry.
You haven't brought me
a rabbit in days.
Or things for me to touch and guess.
-I've got good news.
I've had a great idea.
Have you a minute?
-What kind of idea?
-I raise my left foot,
I bring...
my elbow to my knee
and tap it twice.
I bring my foot to my
knee and tap it three times,
I lie face down
and kneel down.
I touch my left cheek.
And then lie face up.
-You sure you're
prepared to do that?
-Yes, of course I'm sure.
I wouldn't propose it otherwise.
-When?
-Tomorrow.
-Tomorrow?
-We should speed up a little.
-I can't go much faster.
These pants are too tight,
I'm sorry.
It was dark and I
couldn't see clearly.
And I didn't have
time to try them on.
Sorry.
-Nevermind.
-There's a bus coming.
It was the hotel coach.
They didn't see us.
-Profile.
Fingers.
Elbows.
-Would you like me
to show you my belly?
-No.
I...I remember your belly very well.
Smile.
Can I have a knife and fork please?
Not a butter knife.
Steak knife.
-Yes, sir.
-Thank you.
I'm going to do it with a knife.
-Do you want me to come with you?
-I'd rather you didn't.
-Don't worry.
It's strange at first...
but then you get used to it.
And your other senses are heightened.
Touch, for example.
-And hearing.
I know.
I won't be long.
-Thank you very much.
Subtitles by Renatinha Tankinha