SAY, BUDDY, WILL YOU
STAKE A FELLOW AM--
HEY, MISTER.
WILL YOU STAKE A FELLOW
AMERICAN TO A MEAL?
OCHENTA CENTAVOS.
THE LOTTERY, SEÑOR?
BEAT IT. I AIN'T BUYING
NO LOTTERY TICKETS.
GO ON, BEAT IT.
4,000 PESOS
THE BIG PRIZE.
GET AWAY FROM ME,
YOU LITTLE BEGGAR!
THE WHOLE TICKET
IS ONLY 4 PESOS.
IT'S A SURE WINNER.
I AIN'T GOT 4 PESOS.
BUY A QUARTER
OF A TICKET
FOR 1 PESO SILVER.
IF YOU DON'T
GET AWAY FROM ME,
I'M GONNA THROW THIS WATER
RIGHT IN YOUR FACE.
THEN 1/10 OF A TICKET,
SEÑOR, FOR 40 CEN--
SEÑOR, BUY 1/20.
1/20 COSTS YOU
ONLY 20 CENTAVOS.
LOOK, SEÑOR.
ADD THE FIGURES UP.
YOU GET 13.
WHAT BETTER NUMBER
COULD YOU BUY?
IT'S A SURE WINNER.
HOW SOON'S THE DRAWING?
ONLY 3 WEEKS OFF.
GIVE ME 1/20 SO'S
I DON'T HAVE TO LOOK
AT YOUR UGLY FACE.
ES UN NUMERO
EXCELENTE, SEÑOR.
GRACIAS.
COME AGAIN NEXT TIME.
I ALWAYS HAVE THE WINNERS,
ALL THE LUCKY NUMBERS.
GOOD LUCK.
13. [CHUCKLES]
EXCUSE ME.
CIGARETTE?
THANKS.
IT'S HOT.
YEAH.
WHAT A TOWN...
TAMPICO.
YOU SAID IT, BROTHER.
IF I COULD JUST
GET ME A JOB
THAT WOULD BRING IN
ENOUGH TO BUY PASSAGE,
I'D SHAKE ITS DUST
OFF MY FEET
SOON ENOUGH, YOU BET.
YEAH.
WELL, IF I WAS A NATIVE,
I'D GET ME A CAN
OF SHOE POLISH
AND I'D BE IN BUSINESS.
THEY'D NEVER LET A GRINGO.
SIT ON A BENCH TILL YOU'RE
THREE-QUARTERS STARVED.
YOU CAN BEG
FROM ANOTHER GRINGO.
YOU CAN EVEN
COMMIT BURGLARY.
YOU TRY SHINING SHOES
IN THE STREET,
PEDDLING LEMONADE
OUT OF A BUCKET,
AND YOUR HASH IS SETTLED.
YOU'LL NEVER GET ANOTHER JOB
FROM AN AMERICAN.
YEAH, AND THE NATIVES
WOULD HOUND AND
PESTER YOU TO DEATH.
SOME TOWN TO BE BROKE IN.
WHAT TOWN ISN'T?
HEY, UH...
WILL YOU STAKE A FELLOW
AMERICAN TO A MEAL?
[CASH REGISTER RINGS]
HEY, MISTER.
WILL YOU STAKE
A FELLOW AMERICAN TO A MEAL?
SUCH IMPUDENCE
NEVER CAME MY WAY.
EARLY THIS AFTERNOON
I GAVE YOU MONEY.
WHILE I WAS HAVING
MY SHOES POLISHED,
I GAVE YOU MORE MONEY.
NOW YOU PUT THE BITE
ON ME AGAIN.
DO ME A FAVOR,
WILL YOU?
GO OCCASIONALLY
TO SOMEBODY ELSE.
THIS IS BEGINNING
TO GET TIRESOME.
EXCUSE ME, MISTER.
I NEVER KNOWED IT WAS YOU.
I NEVER LOOKED
AT YOUR FACE.
I JUST LOOKED AT YOUR HANDS
AND THE MONEY YOU GAVE ME.
BEG PARDON, MISTER.
I PROMISE I'LL NEVER PUT
THE BITE ON YOU AGAIN.
THIS IS THE VERY LAST
YOU GET FROM ME.
JUST TO MAKE SURE YOU DON'T
FORGET YOUR PROMISE,
HERE'S ANOTHER PESO.
THANKS, MISTER.
THANKS.
BUT FROM NOW ON,
YOU HAVE TO MAKE
YOUR WAY THROUGH LIFE
WITHOUT MY ASSISTANCE.
HEY, BUDDY.
CAN YOU STAKE A FELLOW
AMERICAN TO A MEAL?
I WON'T GIVE YOU
A RED CENT,
BUT IF YOU WANT
TO MAKE SOME MONEY,
I'LL GIVE YOU A JOB.
YEAH?
WHAT'S THE CATCH?
THERE'S NO CATCH.
I GOT A JOB FOR YOU
IF YOU WANT IT.
IT'S HARD WORK,
BUT GOOD PAY.
DID YOU EVER
RIG A CAMP?
SURE.
WELL, THE FERRY'S
MAKING OFF.
ONE OF MY MEN
HASN'T SHOWED UP.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO HIM.
HE'S PROBABLY FILTHY DRUNK
IN SOME DIVE.
WHAT'S THE PAY?
8 BUCKS AMERICAN
A DAY.
WELL, DON'T JUST STAND THERE.
MAKE UP YOUR MIND.
THE FERRY DOESN'T WAIT.
I'M YOUR MAN.
COME ON.
HELLO THERE.
HELLO YOURSELF.
Man: OK, YOU GUYS.
GET ABOARD.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[BELL CLANGING]
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU TWO?
CAN'T YOU TAKE IT?
WELL, IT'S 130
IN THE SHADE,
AND THERE AIN'T
ANY SHADE UP THERE
ON THAT DERRICK.
WELL, JUST FIGURE YOU'RE
A COUPLE OF MILLIONAIRES
IN YOUR OWN
PRIVATE STEAM BATH.
AND THE SOONER
WE'RE THROUGH,
THE SOONER WE'LL BE BACK
IN TOWN DRINKING COLD BEER.
WE'LL BE FINISHED
WITHIN 2 WEEKS.
I'M GIVING YOU
FELLAS A BONUS.
YEAH, WELL,
IT'S COMING TO US,
WORKING 16, 18 HOURS
A DAY LIKE WE DO.
AH, DON'T GO CRYIN'
TO YOUR MAMAS.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I'M PAYING TOP SALARIES
AND A BONUS.
HOW ABOUT OUR PAY, ANYWAY?
AND WHEN DO WE GET IT?
I AIN'T SEEN A BUCK
OUT OF YOU YET, PAT.
AH, YOU'LL GET
YOUR DOUGH, ALL RIGHT.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
WHEN WE GET BACK
TO TAMPICO.
WHAT COULD YOU DO
WITH MONEY OUT HERE, ANYWAY,
EXCEPT GAMBLE
AND LOSE IT?
YOU'LL BE PAID
AS WE STEP OFF THE FERRY.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
THAT AGENT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE WITH THE DOUGH.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT COULD'VE HAPPENED.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT, THOUGH.
I'LL GO OVER TO THE OFFICE
AND PICK UP THE MONEY MYSELF.
YOU MEN STAY HERE.
HEY, PAT, ANY OBJECTION
TO A COUPLE OF US
COMING ALONG WITH YOU?
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
DON'T YOU TRUST ME?
YOU THINK
I'D RUN OUT ON YOU?
NO, PAT, I DON'T THINK
YOU'D DO A THING LIKE THAT,
BUT I AIN'T GOT A CENT--
NOT EVEN ENOUGH TO BUY ME
A GLASS OF BEER.
SAY, YOU TWO GUYS
MEET ME
OVER AT
THE CANTINA MADRID.
IT'S A QUARTER
OF 2:00 NOW,
AND I'LL BE OVER THERE
NO LATER THAN 3:00.
PAT McCORMICK? SI.
HE COME IN FROM
TIME TO TIME.
I NO SEE HIM LATELY.
Man: PAT McCORMICK?
WHAT ABOUT
PAT McCORMICK?
HE WAS SUPPOSED TO
MEET US HERE.
DOES HE OWE YOU
ANY MONEY?
YEAH.
SAY, HOW LONG
YOU GUYS
BEEN AROUND
TAMPICO, ANYWAY?
WHAT'S THAT
GOT TO DO WITH IT?
ONLY FOREIGNERS AND
HALF-BAKED AMERICANS
FALL FOR
McCORMICK'S TRICKS.
HOW DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN HE HIRES
DUMB GUYS LIKE YOU
TO WORK FOR HIM.
WHEN IT COMES
TIME TO PAY OFF,
HE TAKES A POWDER.
HOW MUCH WE GOT LEFT
OF THAT 10
HE GAVE US, DOBBSY?
$2.50.
NOT EVEN ENOUGH
FOR ONE BED.
I KNOW A JOINT
THAT'S FULL OF RATS,
SCORPIONS,
AND COCKROACHES.
THE COTS ARE ONLY
50 CENTAVOS A NIGHT.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MEN COUGHING]
...A DIME A DOZEN IF THEY
CAN BE HAD AT ALL.
STREETS ARE FULL OF GUYS
PUSHING EACH OTHER.
Man: GOLD IN MEXICO?
WHY, SURE THERE IS.
NOT 10 DAYS FROM HERE
BY RAIL OR PACK TRAIN,
THERE'S A MOUNTAIN
WAITING FOR THE RIGHT GUY
TO COME ALONG,
DISCOVER A TREASURE,
AND THEN TICKLE IT
TILL IT LETS HIM HAVE IT.
THE QUESTION IS,
ARE YOU THE RIGHT GUY?
AH, REAL BONANZAS
ARE FEW AND FAR BETWEEN.
THEY TAKE A LOT OF FINDING.
SAY, ANSWER ME THIS ONE,
WILL YOU?
WHY IS GOLD WORTH
SOME 20 BUCKS AN OUNCE?
I DON'T KNOW.
BECAUSE IT'S SCARCE.
1,000 MEN, SAY,
GO SEARCHING FOR GOLD.
AFTER 6 MONTHS,
ONE OF THEM'S LUCKY--
ONE OUT OF THE 1,000.
HIS FIND REPRESENTS
NOT ONLY HIS OWN LABOR
BUT THAT OF
999 OTHERS TO BOOT.
THAT'S 6,000 MONTHS,
OR 500 YEARS,
SCRABBLING OVER MOUNTAINS,
GOING HUNGRY AND THIRSTY.
AN OUNCE OF GOLD, MISTER,
IS WORTH WHAT IT IS
BECAUSE OF THE HUMAN LABOR
THAT WENT INTO THE FINDING
AND THE GETTING OF IT.
NEVER THOUGHT OF IT
JUST LIKE THAT.
THERE'S NO OTHER
EXPLANATION, MISTER.
GOLD ITSELF
AIN'T GOOD FOR NOTHING
EXCEPT FOR MAKING
JEWELRY WITH, GOLD TEETH.
GOLD'S A DEVILISH
SORT OF A THING, ANYWAY.
YOU START OUT, YOU TELL
YOURSELF YOU'LL BE SATISFIED
WITH 25,000 HANDSOME
SMACKERS WORTH OF IT.
SO HELP MY LORD
AND CROSS MY HEART.
FINE RESOLUTION.
AFTER MONTHS OF
SWEATING YOURSELF DIZZY
AND GROWING SHORT
ON PROVISIONS
AND FINDING NOTHING,
YOU FINALLY COME DOWN
TO 15,000, THEN 10.
FINALLY, YOU SAY, "LORD,
LET ME JUST FIND $5,000.
I'LL NEVER ASK FOR ANYTHING
MORE THE REST OF MY LIFE."
$5,000 IS
A LOT OF MONEY.
YEAH, HERE IN THIS JOINT
IT SEEMS LIKE A LOT,
BUT, I TELL YOU, IF YOU WAS
TO MAKE A REAL STRIKE,
YOU COULDN'T BE
DRAGGED AWAY.
NOT EVEN THE THREAT
OF MISERABLE DEATH
WOULD KEEP YOU FROM TRYING
TO ADD 10,000 MORE.
10, YOU'D WANT TO GET 25.
25, YOU'D WANT TO GET 50.
50, 100.
LIKE ROULETTE,
ONE MORE TURN--
YOU KNOW, ALWAYS ONE MORE.
IT WOULDN'T BE
THAT WAY WITH ME.
I SWEAR IT WOULDN'T.
I'D TAKE ONLY
WHAT I SET OUT TO GET,
EVEN IF THERE WAS STILL
A HALF A MILLION
DOLLARS WORTH
LYING AROUND
WAITING TO BE PICKED UP.
I'VE DUG IN ALASKA
AND CANADA AND COLORADO.
I WAS WITH THE CROWD
IN THE BRITISH HONDURAS
BEFORE I'D MADE
MY FARE BACK HOME
AND ALMOST ENOUGH OVER
TO CURE ME OF THE FEVER
I'D CAUGHT.
DUG IN CALIFORNIA
AND AUSTRALIA,
ALL OVER THE WORLD,
PRACTICALLY.
I KNOW WHAT GOLD
DOES TO MEN'S SOULS.
YOU TALK AS THOUGH
YOU STRUCK IT RICH
SOMETIME OR OTHER, POP.
HOW ABOUT IT?
THEN WHAT ARE
YOU DOING IN HERE,
A DOWN-AND-OUTER?
THAT'S THE GOLD.
THAT'S WHAT IT MAKES OF US.
NEVER KNEW A PROSPECTOR YET
THAT DIED RICH.
MAKE ONE FORTUNE,
YOU'RE SURE TO BLOW IT
IN TRYING TO FIND ANOTHER.
I'M NO EXCEPTION
TO THE RULE.
AH, SURE,
I'M AN ODD OLD BONE NOW,
BUT, SAY, DON'T YOU GUYS
THINK THE SPIRIT'S GONE.
I'M ALL SET TO SHOULDER
A PICKAX AND A SHOVEL
ANYTIME ANYBODY'S
WILLING TO SHARE EXPENSES.
RATHER GO BY MYSELF.
GOING IT ALONE'S THE BEST WAY,
BUT YOU GOT TO HAVE
A STOMACH FOR LONELINESS.
SOME GUYS
GO NUTTY WITH IT.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
GOING WITH A PARTNER, TOO,
IS DANGEROUS--MURDER'S
ALWAYS LURKING ABOUT,
PARTNERS ACCUSING EACH OTHER
OF ALL SORTS OF CRIMES.
OH, AS LONG
AS THERE'S NO FIND,
THE NOBLE BROTHERHOOD
WILL LAST.
BUT WHEN THE PILES OF GOLD
BEGIN TO GROW,
THAT'S WHEN
THE TROUBLE STARTS.
ME, NOW, I WOULDN'T MIND
A LITTLE OF
THAT KIND OF TROUBLE.
AH, I THINK
I'LL GO TO SLEEP
AND DREAM ABOUT
PILES OF GOLD
GETTING BIGGER
AND BIGGER AND BIGGER.
DO YOU BELIEVE
WHAT THAT OLD MAN
WHO WAS DOING
ALL THE TALKING
AT THE OSO NEGRO
SAID THE OTHER NIGHT
ABOUT GOLD CHANGING
A MAN'S SOUL
SO'S HE AIN'T
THE SAME KIND OF A GUY
THAT HE WAS
BEFORE FINDING IT?
GUESS THAT ALL
DEPENDS ON THE MAN.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I SAY.
GOLD DON'T CARRY
ANY CURSE WITH IT.
IT ALL DEPENDS
ON WHETHER OR NOT
THE GUY WHO FINDS IT
IS THE RIGHT GUY.
THE WAY I SEE IT,
GOLD CAN BE AS MUCH OF
A BLESSING AS A CURSE.
HEY, UH, DOBBSY.
YEAH?
LOOK WHO'S COMING OUT
OF THE HOTEL BRISTOL.
IS THAT PAT McCORMICK,
OR AM I SEEING THINGS?
IT'S HIM.
LET'S GET HIM.
LET'S GET HIM HARD.
WHY DON'T YOU AND ME
GO AND BUY ME
SHOPPING THINGS, HUH?
FOR INSTANCE, I COULD USE
A NEW PAIR OF SHOES. ZAPATOS.
HELLO, FELLAS.
HOW ARE YOU?
I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU.
MR. DOBBS
AND MR. CURTIN,
SEÑORITA...
LOPEZ.
OH, YEAH. LOPEZ.
I WANT YOU FELLAS
TO COME AND HAVE
A DRINK WITH ME.
PERDONA, MI VIDA.
I HAVE SOME BUSINESS
TO ATTEND TO
WITH THESE GENTLEMEN.
YOU GO BACK UP TO THE
HOTEL AND WAIT, HUH?
I WON'T BE LONG.
UNOS MINUTOS,
NO MAS, CHIQUITA.
Lopez: OK.
WELL, FELLAS,
LET'S HAVE THAT DRINK.
WHERE YOU BEEN
KEEPING YOURSELVES?
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
ALL OVER FOR YOU.
3 SHOTS OF RYE.
MAKE MINE BRANDY.
2 BRANDIES.
RYE'S GOOD
ENOUGH FOR ME.
WELL, BOYS, I SUPPOSE
YOU'RE WONDERING ABOUT
THAT MONEY
THAT'S COMING TO YOU.
THE FACT IS,
I HAVEN'T BEEN PAID OFF
ON THAT CONTRACT YET
MYSELF.
IF I HAD THE MONEY,
YOU'D GET IT FIRST THING.
YOU KNOW THAT.
I'LL PUT YOU BOTH
ON MY NEXT CONTRACT.
IT'LL COME THROUGH
BY MONDAY
AND WE CAN SET OUT FRIDAY.
HERE'S MUD IN YOUR EYE!
WE WANT WHAT'S COMING
TO US,
AND WE WANT IT
RIGHT HERE AND NOW.
WELL, DIDN'T I JUST GET
THROUGH TELLING YOU--
BETTER COME ACROSS, PAT.
WELL, BOYS, I TELL YOU
WHAT I'LL DO.
I'LL GIVE YOU 25%.
I GUESS I CAN
MAKE IT 30%,
AND THE BALANCE,
SAY, THE MIDDLE
OF NEXT WEEK, HUH?
NOTHING DOING.
RIGHT HERE AND NOW.
EVERY CENT YOU OWE US
OR YOU WON'T WALK OUT OF HERE.
YOU'LL HAVE
TO BE CARRIED OUT.
OH, NOW, LET'S DON'T
STOP BEING FRIENDS.
HOW ABOUT
ANOTHER DRINK?
2 MORE BRANDIES
FOR THE GENTLEMEN,
AND PUT THE BOTTLE
ON THE BAR.
IF YOU'VE GOT ANY IDEAS ABOUT
GETTING US LIQUORED UP...
OH, NO. I'M JUST
INVITING YOU
TO HAVE A FRIENDLY
DRINK WITH ME.
[PANTING]
I'M LICKED, BOYS.
I'M LICKED.
Curtin:
GIVE US OUR MONEY.
YEAH.
I CAN'T SEE.
50...100...
200...300.
THAT'S IT,
AIN'T IT, CURT?
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
LET'S BEAT IT BEFORE
THE LAW ARRIVES.
HERE'S FOR THE DRINKS
AND THE USE OF THE CANTINA.
YOU KNOW
SOMETHING, CURT?
WHAT?
WE AIN'T VERY SMART,
HANGING AROUND TAMPICO
WAITING FOR A JOB.
THE MONEY'S GETTING
SHORTER EVERY DAY,
AND PRETTY SOON
WE'RE RIGHT BACK
WHERE WE WERE--
ON THE BUM AGAIN,
PUSHING GUYS
FOR DIMES
AND SLEEPING AROUND
IN FREIGHT CARS.
GOT ANY IDEAS?
YEAH. THAT OLD MAN
IN THE OSO NEGRO
STARTED ME TO THINKING.
WHAT ABOUT?
WHY NOT TRY GOLD DIGGING
FOR A CHANGE?
WELL, IT AIN'T
ANY RISKIER
THAN WAITING AROUND HERE
FOR A BREAK.
AND THIS IS THE COUNTRY
WHERE THE NUGGETS OF GOLD
ARE JUST CRYING FOR YOU
TO TAKE THEM
OUT OF THE GROUND,
MAKE THEM SHINE
IN COINS,
ON THE FINGERS AND NECKS
OF SWELL DAMES.
ONE THING,
LIVING IN THE OPEN'S
CHEAPER THAN IT IS
HERE IN TAMPICO.
OUR MONEY
WOULD LAST LONGER.
SURE. THE LONGER IT LASTS,
THE GREATER OUR CHANCE
OF DIGGING SOMETHING
UP WOULD BE.
WE'D HAVE TO HAVE
EQUIPMENT, ALL RIGHT--
PICKS AND SPADES,
PANS, BURROS.
WONDER HOW MUCH
IT WOULD ALL COST.
THAT OLD MAN
WOULD KNOW.
YEAH. HE COULD GIVE US
SOME POINTERS, ALL RIGHT.
HE'S TOO OLD TO TAKE ALONG
WITH US, OF COURSE.
WE'D HAVE TO PACK HIM
ON OUR BACKS.
YOU CAN'T TELL ABOUT
SOME OF THOSE OLD GUYS.
IT'S SURPRISING SOMETIMES
HOW TOUGH THEY ARE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT GOLD
LOOKS LIKE IN THE GROUND.
I'VE ONLY SEEN IT
IN JEWELRY STORE WINDOWS
AND PEOPLE'S MOUTHS.
YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT PROSPECTING?
UH, NOT MUCH WHEN YOU
COME RIGHT DOWN TO IT.
WE MIGHT HAVE REAL USE
FOR AN EXPERIENCED GUY
LIKE THAT OLD-TIMER.
LET'S GO HUNT HIM UP
RIGHT AWAY.
WILL I GO? WHAT A QUESTION.
OF COURSE I'LL GO.
ANY TIME, ANY DAY.
I WAS ONLY WAITING FOR
ONE OR TWO GUYS TO ASK ME.
HUNT FOR GOLD?
ALWAYS AT YOUR SERVICE.
I GOT 300 AMERICAN BUCKS
READY CASH HERE IN THE BANK.
200 I'M ALL SET TO INVEST.
IT'S THE LAST MONEY
I GOT IN THE WORLD,
AND THAT'S ON ACCOUNT
OF I'M ALL FINISHED UP.
BUT IF YOU DON'T TAKE A RISK,
CAN'T MAKE A GAIN.
HOW MUCH DOUGH
YOU GUYS GOT TO PUT IN?
I GOT 150 BUCKS,
AND CURTIN HERE
HAS GOT THE SAME.
500 BUCKS
AIN'T HARDLY ENOUGH
TO BUY THE TOOLS AND WEAPONS
AND ESSENTIAL PROVISIONS.
WEAPONS? WHAT DO
WE NEED WEAPONS FOR?
MEAT'S ONE THING
AND BANDITS ANOTHER.
BANDIT COUNTRY'S
WHERE WE'D BE GOING.
WE OUGHT TO HAVE
600 BUCKS BETWEEN US.
THAT MUCH, EH?
CAN'T YOU DIG UP
ANY MORE?
NOT A RED CENT.
SEÑOR!
SEÑOR! GIVE ME
MY MONEY, SEÑOR!
10% PERCENT I GET FOR
SELLING THE WINNING TICKET!
GET AWAY FROM ME,
WILL YOU?
AW, PLEASE, SEÑOR.
WHOEVER DRAWS
THE LUCKY NUMBER
ALWAYS GIVES A PRESENT
TO THE SELLER--
I TELL YOU, I DON'T WANT
ANY LOTTERY TICKET!
IF YOU DON'T,
YOU HAVE BAD LUCK
REST OF YOUR LIFE!
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT DID YOU FIRST SAY?
HE'S TRYING TO TELL YOU HE
SOLD YOU THE WINNING TICKET.
HEY--HEY,
WAIT A MINUTE.
THIS WHAT YOU MEAN?
SI, SEÑOR.
YOU SAY
IT'S A WINNER?
SI. A 200-PESO PRIZE.
TRES-SIETE-DOS-UNO.
HEY! THAT'S MY NUMBER!
SURE ENOUGH!
OH, JUST LOOK AT THAT FAT,
RICH, PRINTED NUMBER.
THAT'S THE KIND
OF SUGAR PAPA LIKES.
OH, 200 PESOS. WELCOME,
SWEET LITTLE SMACKAROOS.
HERE, SON. HERE'S A PRESENT
FOR YOU, WITH MY BLESSING.
MUCHAS GRACIAS,
SEÑOR.
WELL, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SHAKE THE HAND
THAT BOUGHT THAT TICKET?
CONGRATULATIONS.
CONGRATULATIONS
YOURSELF.
YOU STAND TO PROFIT
OUT OF THIS THE SAME AS I DO.
HOW DO YOU MAKE
THAT OUT?
WELL, DIDN'T HE JUST SAY
WE NEEDED 600 BUCKS?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT
WE GOT NOW, AIN'T IT?
YEAH, BUT--
BUT WHAT?
HOW COME YOU'RE
PUTTING UP FOR ME?
THIS IS AN ALL-OR-NOTHING
PROPOSITION, AIN'T IT?
IF WE MAKE A FIND,
WE'LL BE LIGHTING OUR CIGARS
WITH $100 BILLS.
IF WE DON'T,
THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN WHAT YOU PUT UP
AND WHAT I PUT UP
AIN'T ENOUGH TO KEEP ME
FROM BEING RIGHT BACK
WHERE I WAS
THIS AFTERNOON--
POLISHING A BENCH
WITH THE SEAT OF MY PANTS.
PUT HER THERE, PARD.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
WE'LL BUY OUR BURROS HERE,
THEN HEAD NORTHWEST
AWAY FROM THE RAILROAD.
NO USE LOOKING ANYWHERE
NEARBY A RAILROAD
OR ANY KIND OF ROAD AT ALL,
FOR THAT MATTER,
BECAUSE CONSTRUCTION ENGINEERS
MAKE IT THEIR BUSINESS
TO EXAMINE EVERY BIT
OF GROUND AROUND THE ROAD
WHILE THEY BUILD THEM.
WE GOT TO GO WHERE
THERE'S NO TRAILS AT ALL,
WHERE YOU CAN BE
POSITIVE THAT NO SURVEYOR
OR ANYBODY WHO KNOWS
ANYTHING ABOUT PROSPECTING
HAS EVER
BEEN THERE BEFORE.
BEST PLACES
ARE THOSE WHO...
ANYBODY WHO WORKS
ON A SALARY WOULDN'T GO,
BECAUSE HE WOULDN'T
THINK IT WORTH HIS WHILE
TO RISK HIS HIDE.
[LOUD JOLT]
[GUNSHOT]
''ECHENSE AL PISO PRONTO!
''MI VALIJA!  ''ANDALE!
I GOT 3 OF THEM.
CREDIT ME WITH 3.
HOW MANY DID YOU GET?
A COUPLE, I GUESS.
I'M ONE UP ON YOU.
BET I GOT MORE
THAN YOU DID, POP.
I GOT 3.
NICE SHOOTING, EH?
LOOK AT THAT BULLET HOLE
ABOUT 2 INCHES FROM
WHERE MY HEAD WAS.
THAT WAS CLOSE, EH?
THE BULLETS WERE SURE
FLYING THICK AND FAST
IN HERE FOR A MINUTE.
SOUNDED LIKE THERE WAS
A SWARM OF BEES
IN THIS COACH.
THAT BANDIT
WITH THE GOLD HAT
THAT RODE
ALONGSIDE THE TRAIN--
I HAD MY SIGHTS ON HIM,
NICE AS YOU PLEASE.
THE TRAIN GAVE A JOLT
AND I MISSED HIM.
SURE WISH I'D GOT HIM.
BIG BOULDER ON THE TRACK,
SO TRAIN STOP.
BANDITS GET BIG SURPRISE
BECAUSE SOLDIERS ON THE TRAIN
WAITING FOR THEM.
NOT MANY PASSENGERS
GET KILLED.
HERE'S WHERE WE'RE
BOUND FOR HEREABOUTS.
DON'T SHOW PROPERLY
WHETHER IT'S MOUNTAIN,
SWAMP, OR DESERT.
THAT SHOWS THE MAKERS
OF THE MAP THEMSELVES
DON'T KNOW FOR SURE.
ONCE ON THE GROUND,
ALL WE GOT TO DO
IS OPEN UP OUR EYES
AND LOOK AROUND.
YEAH, AND BLOW
OUR NOSES, TOO.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
I KNEW A FELLOW ONCE
WHO COULD SMELL GOLD
LIKE A JACKASS
CAN SMELL WATER.
¿ESTOS BURROS SON LOS MEJORES
QUE HAY EN LA REGION?
SI.
[BRAYING]
UNA "A" CON
UNA MEDIA LUNA ARRIBA.
ESE, LO MISMO.
UNA "A" CON
UNA MEDIA LUNA ARRIBA.
ESTE OTRO, IGUAL.
ESTE TAMBIEN IGUAL.
ESE, LO MISMO.
UNA "A" CON
UNA MEDIA LUNA ARRIBA.
OIGAN, POR ESE RUMBO
QUE USTEDES LLEVAN,
A CINCO DIAS
DE JORNADAS DE AQUI,
HAY UN RIO MUY CAUDALOSO
EN EL VERANO,
PERO SECO EN INVIERNO.
Y MAS ALLA,
HAY MONTAÑAS TAN ALTAS
COMO LAS NUBES.
OOH! EL TERRENO
ES MUY PELIGROSO.
HAY QUE ABRIRSE PASO
A MACHETE.
WHAT'S ALL THAT ABOUT?
WE'RE GOING TO A COUNTRY
VERY WILD AND DANGEROUS.
HAVE TO CUT AWAY
THROUGH JUNGLES
AND CLIMB MOUNTAINS
SO HIGH,
THEY RISE
ABOVE THE CLOUDS.
THE TIGERS
SO BIG AND STRONG,
THEY CAN CLIMB TREES
WITH BURROS
IN THEIR MOUTHS.
GOOD. GLAD TO HEAR
SUCH TALL TALES,
'CAUSE THAT MEANS
MIGHTY FEW OUTSIDERS
HAVE EVER
SET FOOT THERE.
WELL,
LET'S GET GOING.
NO, SEÑOR.
OH.
ASI.
HEY...
IF THERE WAS GOLD
IN THEM MOUNTAINS,
HOW LONG WOULD IT
HAVE BEEN THERE?
MILLIONS AND MILLIONS
OF YEARS, WOULDN'T IT?
WHAT'S OUR HURRY?
COUPLE OF DAYS
MORE OR LESS
AIN'T GONNA MAKE
ANY DIFFERENCE.
REMEMBER WHAT YOU SAID
BACK IN TAMPICO
ABOUT HAVING TO PACK
THAT OLD MAN ON OUR BACKS?
THAT WAS WHEN
I TOOK HIM
FOR AN ORDINARY
HUMAN BEING,
NOT PART GOAT.
LOOK AT HIM CLIMB,
WILL YOU?
WHAT GETS ME
IS HOW HE CAN GO
ALL DAY LONG IN THIS SUN
WITHOUT ANY WATER.
MAYBE HE'S
PART CAMEL, TOO.
IF I'D KNOWN WHAT
PROSPECTING MEANT,
I'D HAVE STAYED
IN TAMPICO
AND WAITED FOR ANOTHER JOB
TO TURN UP.
HEY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
LOOK.
LOOK AT IT
GLITTER.
IT'S YELLOW,
TOO, LIKE...
LIKE...
GOLD.
HOWARD! HOWARD! HOWARD!
HOWARD! COME BACK!
WE'VE FOUND SOMETHING!
HEY, LOOK!
HEY, LOOK, CURT!
THERE'S A VEIN OF IT
HERE IN THIS ROCK.
AND LOOK HERE!
LOOK,
IT'S ALL AROUND.
IT'S PLENTY FOR YOU!
ONLY GOLD SHINES
AND GLITTERS LIKE THAT.
WE'VE STRUCK IT, CURT.
LOOK.
FROM THE LOOKS
OF THINGS,
WE'VE STRUCK IT
RICH.
LOOK, IT'S
ALL OVER HERE.
I THINK WE'VE FOUND A--
A MOTHER LODE.
HOWARD! HOWARD!
COME ON, LOOK!
LOOK! HERE!
LOOK AT THIS ROCK.
IT'S FULL OF GOLD!
VEINS OF IT.
THAT WOULDN'T
PAY YOUR DINNER
FOR A CARLOAD.
IT AIN'T GOLD?
PYRITES. FOOL'S GOLD.
OH, NOT THAT
THERE AIN'T PLENTY
OF THE REAL STUFF
HEREABOUTS.
WE'VE WALKED OVER IT
4 OR 5 TIMES.
THAT PLACE YESTERDAY
LOOKED LIKE RICH DIGGINGS,
BUT THE WATER
FOR WASHING THE SAND
WAS 11 MILES AWAY--TOO FAR.
AND THE OTHER PLACES--WELL,
THERE WASN'T ENOUGH GOLD
TO PAY US
A GOOD DAY'S WAGES.
NEXT TIME YOU FELLAS
STRIKE IT RICH,
HOLLER FOR ME, WILL YOU,
BEFORE YOU START
SPLASHING WATER AROUND.
WATER'S PRECIOUS.
SOMETIMES IT CAN BE
MORE PRECIOUS THAN GOLD.
BURRO!
[WIND HOWLING]
WHAT'S UP?
NORTHER,
LOOKS LIKE.
A NORTHER?
WHAT'S A NORTHER?
BIG WINDS FROM THE NORTH
THIS TIME OF YEAR.
WHEN THEY BLOW HARD,
THIS DESERT COUNTRY
STANDS RIGHT UP
ON ITS HIND LEGS.
RECKON THERE'S ONLY
A FEW MORE MILES
OF THIS HEAVY STUFF.
PRETTY SOON WE'LL BE
OUT OF THIS VALLEY.
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
[SNORING]
HEY, YOU FELLAS,
HOW ABOUT SOME BEANS?
WANT SOME BEANS?
GOING THROUGH SOME MIGHTY
ROUGH COUNTRY TOMORROW.
YOU BETTER HAVE SOME BEANS.
[PLAYS NOTES]
[PLAYING LIVELY TUNE]
YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M THINKING?
I'M THINKING
WE OUGHT TO GIVE UP,
LEAVE THE WHOLE OUTFIT...
EVERYTHING BEHIND,
AND GO BACK TO CIVILIZATION.
WHAT'S THAT YOU SAY?
GO BACK?
HA HA! WELL,
TELL MY OLD GRANDMOTHER!
I GOT 2 VERY ELEGANT
BEDFELLOWS
WHO KICK AT THE FIRST
DROP OF RAIN
AND HIDE IN THE CLOSET
FROM THUNDER RUMBLES.
MY, MY, MY!
WHAT GREAT PROSPECTORS!
2 SHOE CLERKS READING
A MAGAZINE
ABOUT
PROSPECTING FOR GOLD
IN THE LAND
OF THE MIDNIGHT SUN--
SOUTH OF THE BORDER
OR WEST OF THE ROCKIES.
SHUT YOUR TRAP!
SHUT UP OR I'LL
SMASH YOUR HEAD FLAT!
GO AHEAD! GO AHEAD!
THROW IT!
IF YOU DID, YOU'D NEVER
LEAVE THIS WILDERNESS ALIVE!
WITHOUT ME,
YOU TWO WOULD DIE HERE
MORE MISERABLE
THAN RATS!
OH, LEAVE HIM ALONE!
CAN'T YOU SEE THAT
THE OLD MAN'S NUTS?
NUTS? NUTS, AM I? HA!
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
MY 2 FINE BEDFELLOWS!
YOU'RE SO DUMB, THERE'S
NOTHING TO COMPARE YOU WITH!
YOU'RE DUMBER THAN
THE DUMBEST JACKASS!
LOOK AT EACH OTHER,
WILL YOU?
YOU EVER SEE ANYTHING
LIKE YOURSELF
FOR BEING DUMB SPECIMENS?
HA HA HA HA!
AH HA HA HA HA HA!
YOU'RE SO DUMB,
YOU DON'T EVEN
SEE THE RICHES
YOU'RE TREADING ON
WITH YOUR OWN FEET!
YEAH, DON'T EXPECT TO FIND
NUGGETS OF MOLTEN GOLD.
IT'S RICH,
BUT NOT THAT RICH.
AND HERE AIN'T
THE PLACE TO DIG.
IT COMES FROM SOMEPLACE
FURTHER UP. UP THERE.
UP THERE'S
WHERE WE GOT TO GO.
UP THERE!
IS THAT IT?
THAT'S IT, ALL RIGHT.
THE GOLD, I MEAN.
IT SURE DON'T LOOK LIKE
I THOUGHT IT WOULD.
IT'S NOT MUCH DIFFERENT
THAN SAND.
YEAH, IT'S JUST
LIKE PLAIN SAND.
IT DON'T GLITTER.
I THOUGHT IT
WOULD GLITTER.
OH, IT'LL GLITTER
WHEN IT'S REFINED.
THAT'S
SOME OTHER GUY'S JOB.
ALL WE GOT TO DO IS MINE IT
AND GET IT BACK THERE.
YOU KNOW, GOLD AIN'T LIKE
STONES IN A RIVER BED.
IT DON'T CRY OUT
TO BE PICKED UP.
YOU GOT TO KNOW
HOW TO RECOGNIZE IT.
AND FINDING IT AIN'T ALL--
NOT BY A LONG SHOT.
YOU GOT TO KNOW
HOW TO TICKLE IT
SO SHE'LL COME OUT LAUGHING.
YEAH, IT'S MIGHTY RICH.
IT'LL PAY GOOD.
HOW GOOD?
OH, ABOUT 20 OUNCE
TO THE TON.
THAT'S SOME $20 AN OUNCE.
HOW MANY TONS CAN
WE HANDLE A WEEK?
DEPENDS ON
HOW HARD WE WORK.
BETTER PITCH OUR CAMP
DOWN THE MOUNTAINSIDE A BIT.
WHY DO THAT WHEN
THE DIGGING'S UP HERE?
IN CASE ANYBODY
HAPPENS BY,
WE CAN TELL THEM
WE'RE HUNTERS
AND GET AWAY WITH IT,
MAYBE.
WOULDN'T IT BE EASIER
TO FILE A CLAIM?
EASIER MAYBE,
BUT NOT SO PROFITABLE.
WOULDN'T BE NO TIME
TILL A MAN
FROM ONE OF THOSE
BIG MINING COMPANIES
WOULD BE UP HERE
WITH A PAPER IN HIS HAND
SHOWING WE HAD
NO RIGHT TO BE HERE.
WELL?
HOW DOES IT FEEL, YOU FELLAS,
TO BE MEN OF PROPERTY?
THE TANKS WILL LEAK SOME
AT FIRST
TILL THE BOARDS BEGIN TO
SWELL AND CLOSE THE SEAMS.
YEAH, I SURE HAD
SOME COCKEYED IDEAS
ABOUT PROSPECTING
FOR GOLD.
IT WAS ALL IN
THE FINDING, I THOUGHT.
I THOUGHT ALL YOU HAD
TO DO WAS FIND IT,
PICK IT UP,
PUT IT IN SACKS,
AND CARRY THEM OFF
TO THE NEAREST BANK.
YOU'RE LEARNIN'.
PRETTY SOON,
I WON'T BE ABLE
TO TELL YOU A THING.
TANK FULL YET?
RIGHT TO THE TOP.
OPEN THE SLUICE GATE.
HOW MUCH DO YOU
FIGURE IT TO BE NOW?
OH...
ABOUT $5,000 WORTH,
I RECKON.
WHEN ARE WE GOING
TO START DIVIDING IT UP?
ANYTIME YOU SAY.
WHAT'S THE USE OF
DIVIDING IT AT ALL?
I DON'T SEE ANY POINT.
WE'RE
ALL GOING BACK TOGETHER
WHEN THE TIME COMES.
WHY DON'T WE WAIT UNTIL
WE GET PAID FOR THE STUFF
AND THEN JUST DIVIDE
UP THE MONEY?
EITHER WAY SUITS ME.
YOU FELLAS DECIDE.
I'M FOR DIVIDING IT UP
AS WE'RE GOING ALONG.
MAKE EACH GUY RESPONSIBLE
FOR HIS OWN GOODS.
I RECKON I'D JUST AS
SOON HAVE IT THAT WAY.
I DON'T LIKE
THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF GUARDING YOUR
TREASURE ANY TOO WELL.
WELL, WHO ASKED YOU TO?
HA HA! THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU NEVER ASKED ME.
ONLY I THOUGHT
I WAS THE MOST
TRUSTWORTHY OF THE 3.
YOU?
HA! HOW COME?
I SAID THE MOST
TRUSTWORTHY.
AS FAR AS BEING
THE MOST HONEST,
NO ONE CAN SAY.
I DON'T GET YOU.
ALL RIGHT, SUPPOSE
YOU'RE IN CHARGE
OF TAKING CARE
OF THE GOODS.
ONE DAY, I'M DEEP
IN THE BRUSH,
AND CURTIN'S ON HIS WAY
TO THE VILLAGE
TO GET PROVISIONS.
THAT'D BE YOUR BIG CHANCE
TO PACK UP
AND LEAVE US IN THE COLD.
ONLY A GUY THAT'S
A THIEF AT HEART
WOULD THINK ME LIKELY
TO DO A THING LIKE THAT.
RIGHT NOW, IT WOULDN'T
BE WORTH YOUR WHILE,
BUT WHEN THE PILE
HAS GROWN, SAY,
TO 300 OUNCES,
THINK OF SUCH THINGS
YOU WILL.
HOW'S ABOUT YOURSELF?
OH, I'M NOT QUICK
ON MY FEET ANY LONGER.
YOU FELLAS
ARE A LOT TOUGHER
THAN WHEN WE STARTED OUT.
BY THE TIME THE PILE HAS GROWN
TO BE REALLY TEMPTING,
I WON'T BE ABLE TO RUN
HALF AS FAST AS EITHER OF YOU.
YOU'D GET ME BY THE COLLAR
AND STRING ME UP IN NO TIME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK I'M THE MOST
TRUSTWORTHY OF THE OUTFIT.
LOOKING AT IT THAT WAY,
I GUESS YOU'RE RIGHT.
BUT MAYBE IT WOULD BE
A GOOD IDEA
TO CUT THE PROCEEDS UP
3 WAYS EVERY NIGHT,
TO RELIEVE YOU
OF A RESPONSIBILITY
YOU DON'T LIKE.
SWELL BY ME.
AFTER WE, SAY, WE'VE GOT
A COUPLE HUNDRED OUNCES,
IT'LL BE A NUISANCE
CARRYING LITTLE BAGS
HANGING FROM OUR NECKS.
AND EACH OF US WILL
HAVE TO HIDE HIS SHARE
OF THE TREASURE
FROM THE OTHER TWO.
AND HAVING DONE SO,
HE'D HAVE TO BE
FOREVER ON THE WATCH
THAT HIS HIDING PLACE
IS NOT DISCOVERED.
WHAT A DIRTY,
FILTHY MIND YOU'VE GOT.
OH, NO, NOT DIRTY.
NOT DIRTY, BABY.
ONLY I KNOW
WHAT KIND OF IDEAS
EVEN SUPPOSEDLY
DECENT PEOPLE GET
WHEN GOLD'S AT STAKE.
ALL RIGHT...
HERE SHE GOES 3 WAYS.
[RUMBLING]
DOBBS!
HOWARD!
HOWARD, COME QUICK!
[GROANING]
HE'S COMING AROUND.
LAY STILL A MINUTE
TILL YOU GET
YOUR SENSES BACK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
PART OF THE MINE
CAVED IN ON YOU.
[GROANING]
GOT A KNOCK ON THE HEAD.
NO BONES BROKEN?
NO, I...
I DON'T THINK SO.
WHO PULLED ME OUT?
CURTIN DID.
I OWE MY LIFE
TO YOU, PARTNER.
FORGET IT.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO
WITH YOUR HARD-EARNED MONEY,
OLD-TIMER, WHEN WE GET BACK
AND CASH IN?
I'M GETTING ALONG
IN YEARS.
OH, I CAN STILL
HOLD UP MY OWN END
WHEN IT COMES TO
A HARD DAY'S WORK,
BUT I'M NOT THE MAN
I WAS ONCE.
NEXT YEAR, NEXT MONTH,
NEXT WEEK, BY THUNDER,
I WOULDN'T BE
THE MAN I AM TODAY.
I RECKON I'LL SETTLE DOWN
IN SOME QUIET PLACE,
GET ME
A LITTLE BUSINESS--
HARDWARE, GROCERY STORE--
SPEND THE BETTER
PART OF MY TIME
READING COMIC STRIPS
AND ADVENTURE STORIES.
ONE THING'S FOR SURE--
I'M NOT GOING TO GO
PROSPECTING AGAIN,
WASTE MY TIME AND MONEY
TRYING TO FIND
ANOTHER GOLD MINE.
HOW ABOUT YOURSELF?
WHAT PLANS HAVE YOU,
IF ANY?
OH, I FIGURE ON
BUYING SOME LAND
AND GROWING FRUIT--
PEACHES, MAYBE.
HOW'D YOU COME
TO SETTLE ON PEACHES?
ONE SUMMER
WHEN I WAS A KID,
I WORKED AS A PICKER
IN A PEACH HARVEST
IN THE SAN JOAQUIN VALLEY.
BOY, IT SURE WAS SOMETHING.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE,
OLD AND YOUNG--
WHOLE FAMILIES
WORKING TOGETHER.
AT NIGHT,
AFTER A DAY'S WORK,
WE USED TO BUILD
BIG BONFIRES
AND SIT AROUND
AND SING TO GUITAR MUSIC,
TILL MORNING SOMETIMES.
YOU'D GO TO SLEEP
AND WAKE UP AND SING,
GO TO SLEEP AGAIN.
EVERYBODY HAD
A WONDERFUL TIME.
EVER SINCE THEN,
I'VE HAD A HANKERING
TO BE A FRUIT GROWER.
IT MUST BE GRAND
WATCHING YOUR OWN TREES
PUT ON LEAVES,
COME INTO BLOSSOM,
AND BEAR--
WATCHING THE FRUIT
GET BIG AND RIPE
ON THE BOUGHS,
READY FOR PICKING.
WHAT'S ALL THAT ABOUT?
WE'RE TELLING EACH OTHER
WHAT WE AIM TO DO
WHEN WE GET BACK.
OH.
ME, I GOT IT
ALL FIGURED OUT
WHAT I'M GOING TO DO.
TELL US ABOUT IT,
DOBBSY.
WELL, FIRST OFF, I'M GOING
TO A TURKISH BATH.
I'M GOING TO
SWEAT AND SOAK
TILL I GET ALL
THE GRIME AND DIRT
OUT OF MY SYSTEM.
THEN I'M GOING
TO A HABERDASHER
AND GONNA GET MYSELF
A BRAND-NEW SET OF DUDS--
A DOZEN OF EVERYTHING.
THEN, I'M GOING
TO A SWELL CAFE
AND ORDER EVERYTHING
ON THE BILL OF FARE.
AND IF IT AIN'T
JUST RIGHT--
OR MAYBE EVEN IF IT IS--
I'M GOING TO BAWL
THE WAITER OUT
AND MAKE HIM TAKE
THE WHOLE THING BACK.
WHAT'S NEXT
ON THE PROGRAM?
WHAT WOULD BE?
IF I WERE YOU BOYS,
I WOULDN'T TALK
OR EVEN THINK
ABOUT WOMEN.
IT AIN'T GOOD
FOR YOUR HEALTH.
YEAH, MAYBE YOU'RE RIGHT,
SEEING AS HOW
THE PROSPECTS ARE FAR OFF.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE OUGHT TO PUT
SOME KIND OF A LIMIT
ON OUR TAKE--AGREE
BETWEEN OURSELVES,
AND WHEN WE GET SO MUCH,
WE JUST PULL UP
STAKES AND BEAT IT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THE LIMIT OUGHT TO BE?
OH, SAY $25,000
WORTH APIECE.
25,000?
AH, SMALL POTATOES.
HOW MUCH DO YOU SAY?
OH, 50,000, ANYWAY.
75 WOULD BE
MORE LIKE IT.
THAT WOULD TAKE
A YEAR AT LEAST
IF THE VEIN HELD OUT,
WHICH WOULDN'T
BE LIKELY.
WHAT'S A YEAR
MORE OR LESS
WHEN THAT KIND OF MONEY'S
TO BE HAD?
25,000'S PLENTY
AS FAR AS
I'M CONCERNED,
ENOUGH TO LAST
ME OUT
THE REST
OF MY LIFETIME.
WELL, SURE.
YOU'RE OLD. I'M YOUNG.
I NEED DOUGH,
AND PLENTY OF IT.
25,000 IN ONE PIECE
IS MORE THAN I EVER EXPECTED
TO GET MY HANDS ON.
SMALL POTATOES.
THERE'S NO USE
MAKING HOGS OF OURSELVES.
HOG, AM I?
MAYBE YOU DON'T KNOW IT,
BUT I'D BE WITHIN MY RIGHTS
IF I DEMANDED HALF AGAIN
AS MUCH AS YOU GET.
HOW COME?
THERE'S NO DENYING
I PUT UP
THE LION'S SHARE
OF THE CASH, IS THERE?
SO YOU DID, DOBBSY,
AND I ALWAYS MEANT
TO PAY YOU BACK.
IN ANY CIVILIZED PLACE,
THE BIGGEST INVESTOR GETS
THE BIGGEST RETURN, DON'T HE?
THAT'S ONE THING
IN FAVOR OF THE WILDS.
NOT THAT I INTEND
TO DEMAND IT,
BUT I'D BE WITHIN
MY RIGHTS IF I DID.
NEXT TIME YOU GO
CALLING ME A HOG,
JUST REMEMBER WHAT I COULD
HAVE DONE IF I'D WANTED TO.
I THINK IT'D BE WISE
NOT TO PUT THINGS
STRICTLY ON
A MONEY BASIS.
HERE YOU ARE, DOBBS--
WHAT I OWE YOU...
WITH INTEREST.
I JUST DON'T LIKE BEING
CALLED A HOG, THAT'S ALL.
[BURRO BRAYS]
BETTER NOT GO JUMPING OUT
ON ME LIKE THAT.
I MIGHT HAVE
LET YOU HAVE IT.
YOU OUT FOR
A MIDNIGHT STROLL?
TIGER OUT.
I WANTED TO SEE
IF THE BURROS
WERE ALL RIGHT.
SO?
SORRY, DOBBSY.
I THINK I'LL SEE
IF THE BURROS
ARE ALL RIGHT.
GO AHEAD.
HELP YOURSELF.
WHAT'S UP?
NOTHING'S UP.
WHERE'S DOBBS?
POKING AROUND IN
THE DARK OUT THERE.
HE'S SURE TAKING
A LONG TIME OUT THERE.
I THINK I'LL GO
HAVE A LOOK-SEE.
WHERE'S CURTIN?
HE'S OUT THERE
SOMEWHERE.
SAID HE WAS GOING
TO HAVE A LOOK-SEE.
IT'S COME AROUND
TO ME AGAIN,
BUT I WON'T TAKE
MY TURN
IF YOU GUYS WILL
STOP WORRYING
ABOUT YOUR GOODS
AND GO TO BED.
WE GOT WORK
TO DO TOMORROW.
YOU CAN'T CATCH ME SLEEPING.
DON'T YOU EVER
BELIEVE THAT.
I'M NOT THAT DUMB.
THE DAY YOU TRY TO PUT
ANYTHING OVER ON ME
WILL BE A COSTLY ONE
FOR BOTH OF YOU.
ANY MORE LIP OUT OF YOU,
AND I'LL HAUL OFF
AND LET YOU HAVE IT.
IF YOU KNOW
WHAT'S GOOD FOR YOU,
YOU WON'T MONKEY AROUND
WITH FRED C. DOBBS.
OUGHT TO GET
A LOAD OF DOBBS.
HE'S DOWN THERE
TALKING TO HIMSELF
A MILE A MINUTE.
YEAH, SOMETHING'S
EATING HIM, ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT.
HE'S JUST SPOILING
FOR TROUBLE.
"WE'RE RUNNING SHORT
OF PROVISIONS, DOBBSY.
HOW ABOUT YOU GOING
TO THE VILLAGE?"
WHO DOES HOWARD THINK HE IS,
ORDERING ME AROUND?
WHAT'S THAT, DOBBS?
NOTHING.
BETTER LOOK OUT.
IT'S A BAD SIGN
WHEN A GUY STARTS
TALKING TO HIMSELF.
HELL, WHO ELSE
AM I GOING TO TALK TO?
CERTAINLY NOT YOU
OR CURTIN.
FINE PARTNERS
YOU TWO ARE.
GOT SOMETHING
UP YOUR NOSE?
BLOW IT OUT.
IT'LL DO YOU GOOD.
DON'T GET THE IDEA
YOU TWO ARE PUTTING
ANYTHING OVER ON ME.
TAKE IT EASY,
DOBBS.
I KNOW WHAT
YOUR GAME IS.
WELL, YOU KNOW MORE
THAN I DO.
WHY AM I ELECTED
TO GO TO THE VILLAGE?
WHY ME INSTEAD
OF YOU AND CURTIN?
DON'T THINK I DON'T
SEE THROUGH THAT.
YOU TWO HAVE THROWN
TOGETHER AGAINST ME.
THE 2 DAYS I'D BE GONE
WOULD GIVE YOU PLENTY OF TIME
TO DISCOVER WHERE
MY GOODS ARE, WOULDN'T IT?
IF YOU FEEL
ALONG THOSE LINES,
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE YOUR
GOODS ALONG WITH YOU?
AND RUN THE RISK
OF HAVING THEM TAKEN
FROM ME BY BANDITS?
IF YOU WAS TO RUN INTO
BANDITS,
YOU'D BE
OUT OF LUCK ANYWAY.
THEY'D KILL YOU FOR
THE SHOES ON YOUR FEET.
OH, SO THAT'S IT.
EVERYTHING'S CLEAR NOW.
YOU'RE HOPING BANDITS
WILL GET ME.
THAT WOULD SAVE YOU
A LOT OF TROUBLE, WOULDN'T IT?
AND YOUR CONSCIENCES WOULDN'T
BOTHER YOU NONE, NEITHER.
ALL RIGHT, DOBBS.
FORGET ABOUT IT.
AH, JUST LIKE
I THOUGHT.
WHAT'S THE IDEA?
PUT YOUR HANDS UP.
I THINK I'M GOING
TO HAUL OFF
AND PUMP YOU UP,
CHEST AND BELLY ALIKE.
GO AHEAD, BUT WOULD YOU
MIND TELLING ME
WHAT THIS IS ALL
ABOUT FIRST?
YOU WON'T GET YOU ANYWHERES
PLAYING DUMB!
WELL, I'LL BE.
SO THAT'S WHERE YOUR GOODS
ARE HIDDEN, EH, DOBBSY?
WHAT'S THE TROUBLE HERE?
SEEMS LIKE I ACCIDENTALLY
STUMBLED ON
DOBBSY'S TREASURE.
ACCIDENTALLY?
WHY WERE YOU TRYING
TO PRY UP THAT ROCK?
TELL ME THAT.
BECAUSE I SAW
A GILA MONSTER
CRAWL UNDER IT.
OH, BROTHER.
I GOT TO HAND IT TO YOU.
YOU CAN CERTAINLY
THINK UP A GOOD STORY
WHEN YOU NEED ONE.
OK, I'M A LIAR.
THERE ISN'T A GILA
MONSTER UNDER THERE.
LET'S SEE YOU STICK
YOUR HAND IN
AND GET YOUR GOODS OUT.
GO AHEAD.
SURE, I WILL.
DON'T YOU TRY
ANY BAD MOVES.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL STAY RIGHT WHERE I AM.
I WANT TO SEE THIS.
REACH IN AND GET
YOUR GOODS.
IF YOU DON'T,
WE'LL THINK YOU'RE YELLOW,
WON'T WE, HOWARD?
THEY NEVER LET GO,
DO THEY, HOWARD,
ONCE THEY GRAB
ON TO YOU?
YOU CAN CUT THEM
IN TWO,
AND THE HEAD WILL STILL
HANG ON
TILL SUNDOWN, I HEAR.
BY THAT TIME, THE VICTIM
DOESN'T USUALLY CARE,
BECAUSE HE'S DEAD
ANYWAY.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT,
HOWARD?
I RECKON.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, DOBBSY?
WHY DON'T YOU
STICK YOUR HAND RIGHT IN
AND GET YOUR TREASURE?
COULDN'T BE BECAUSE
YOU'RE SCARED TO, COULD IT,
AFTER THE WAY YOU'VE BEEN
SHOOTING YOUR MOUTH OFF?
SHOW US YOU AIN'T
YELLOW, DOBBSY.
I'D HATE TO THINK
THAT MY PARTNER
HAD A YELLOW STREAK
UP HIS BACK.
I'LL KILL YOU,
YOU DIRTY, THIEVING--
OK, HOWARD.
I GOT HIM COVERED.
DOBBS, ANOTHER BAD MOVE
OUT OF YOU
AND I'LL BLOW YOU
TO KINGDOM COME.
HOWARD, TURN THAT
ROCK OVER, WILL YOU?
[DOG BARKING]
Man: SON FORASTEROS,
¿VERDAD?
¿DE QUE PARTE SON?
''CONTESTEN!
¿QUE MAS PRUEBAS?
LA CARTERA CON EL BOLETO.
NO CABE DUDA.
USTEDES SON
LOS BANDIDOS.
DESPUES DEL ASALTO AL TREN
LES SEGUIMOS LA PISTA.
LA MISMA FECHA.
VAN A VER LO QUE LES VA
A PASAR POR BANDOLEROS.
''LEVANTALO!
¿Y DONDE ESTA
EL CEMENTERIO DEL PUEBLO?
''POR ALLA!
''SARGENTO!
''CONDUZCALOS UST!
DE FRENTE.
''MARCHEN!
FEDERALES ARE
VERY EFFICIENT.
YEAH.
BANDIDOS, EH?
YEAH. SEEMS BETWEEN THEM
THEY HAD A DIAMOND RING,
PEARL EARRINGS,
QUITE A LOT OF MONEY,
AND A RAILWAY TICKET
WITH THE DATE OF
THE AGUAS CALIENTE
TRAIN ROBBERY ON IT.
THEY'VE BEEN HERE
SEVERAL DAYS
DRINKING AND SHOOTING
OFF THEIR CANNONS.
THE VILLAGERS ARE AFRAID
TO STICK THEIR NOSES
OUT OF THEIR HUTS.
WHERE ARE THEY
TAKING THEM NOW?
THE CEMETERY.
OH.
BUENOS DIAS, AMIGO.
BUENOS DIAS,
MERCANTE.
UN CASTOL DE MAIZ,
HARINA, 12 KILOS,
AZUCAR, 12 KILOS.
YOU KNOW, THE FEDERALES
DON'T OPERATE
IN OUR AMERICAN WAY.
THEY AREN'T FINGERPRINT
EXPERTS, THAT IS.
THEY CAN FOLLOW ANY TRAIL.
AGAINST THEM,
NO HIDEOUT'S ANY USE.
THEY KNOW ALL THE TRICKS
OF THE BANDITS.
YEP, YOU CAN BET
YOUR SWEET SOUL
THEY'LL TRACE DOWN
EVERY LAST ONE
OF THAT GROUP
THAT ATTACKED
THE TRAIN.
IT'LL TAKE TIME--
MONTHS MAYBE--
BUT THEY'LL DO IT.
FRIJOLES, 10 KILOS.
PETROLEO, 18 LITROS.
NOT MANY AMERICANS
GET AROUND THIS WAY.
YOU'RE THE FIRST ONE
I'VE BUMPED INTO
FOR A LONG TIME.
IS THAT SO?
MIGHTY RUGGED
COUNTRY HEREABOUTS.
YEAH.
MY NAME'S CODY.
I'M FROM TEXAS.
CURTIN.
WHAT'S YOUR GAME?
I'M A HUNTER.
PROFESSIONAL?
YEAH.
WHAT ALL
DO YOU HUNT?
OH, TIGER CATS...
ANYTHING
OF COMMERCIAL VALUE.
HOW LONG DID YOU SAY
YOU'VE BEEN
IN THESE MOUNTAINS?
OH, A FEW MONTHS.
EVER SEEN ANYTHING THAT
LOOKED LIKE PAYDIRT?
NAH.
I'VE A HUNCH THERE'S
LOADS OF THE REAL GOODS
UP IN THOSE MOUNTAINS.
NO, I KNOW THE WHOLE
LANDSCAPE AROUND HERE.
IF THERE HAD BEEN
A SINGLE GRAIN OF GOLD,
YOU CAN BET
I'D HAVE SURE SEEN IT.
THERE'S NOTHING
DOING HERE FOR GOLD.
LISTEN, BROTHER, I CAN LOOK
AT A HILL 5 MILES AWAY
AND TELL YOU WHETHER IT CARRIES
AN OUNCE OR A SHIPLOAD.
¿CUANTO?
IF YOU HAVEN'T FOUND
ANYTHING UP THERE YET,
I'LL COME ALONG WITH YOU
AND PUT YOUR NOSE IN IT.
THERE'S INDICATIONS
IN THIS VALLEY,
LOTS OF INDICATIONS.
BY TRACING THE ROCKS,
I FIND THEY COME
FROM THAT RIDGE UP THERE,
WASHED DOWN BY
THE TROPICAL RAIN.
YOU DON'T SAY SO?
YES, I SAY SO.
[GUNSHOTS]
SO MUCH FOR
THOSE BANDITS.
YOU KNOW, YOU GOT TO
HAND IT TO THE MEXICANS
WHEN IT COMES
TO SWIFT JUSTICE.
ONCE THE FEDERALES
GET THEIR MITTS
ON A CRIMINAL,
THEY KNOW JUST WHAT
TO DO WITH HIM.
THEY HAND HIM A SHOVEL,
TELL HIM WHERE TO DIG.
WHEN HE'S DUG DEEP ENOUGH,
THEY TELL HIM TO PUT
THE SHOVEL DOWN,
SMOKE A CIGARETTE,
AND SAY HIS PRAYERS.
IN ANOTHER 5 MINUTES,
HE'S BEING COVERED OVER
WITH THE EARTH HE DUG OUT.
YEAH, YOU GOTTA HAND IT
TO 'EM, ALL RIGHT.
I MEANT WHAT I SAID
ABOUT GOING ALONG
WITH YOU.
THOSE ARE
MY TWO BURROS.
I'M ALL PACKED UP
AND READY TO START
IF YOU'LL LET ME
GO WITH YOU
BACK TO YOUR CAMP.
THANKS ANYWAY, BUT I PREFER
GOING IT BY MYSELF.
GOOD LUCK.
ADIOS.
BURROS!
I WENT A WAY AROUND
AND STAYED ON HARD GROUND
WHICH WOULDN'T SHOW
THE TRACKS.
EVERY TIME I HIT A HIGH POINT
AND LOOKED BACK,
I COULD SEE HE WAS
STILL COMING RIGHT ALONG.
I GUESS IT'S ONLY
A MATTER OF TIME
UNTIL HE SHOWS UP HERE.
I MOVE WE TELL HIM
STRAIGHT OFF TO BEAT IT.
AH, NO, THAT WOULD
BE FOOLISH.
HE'D SIT AROUND
FOR AN HOUR OR SO
PLAYING THE INNOCENT,
THEN GO AND REPORT US
TO THE OFFICIALS.
ONCE THEY WERE HERE,
WE COULDN'T STAY
ANY LONGER,
AND WE COULDN'T TAKE
OUR GOODS WITH US
WHEN WE LEFT.
ALL RIGHT, THEN THERE'S
NOTHING ELSE TO DO
BUT PULL THE TRIGGER
THE MINUTE HE APPEARS.
IT'S NO CRIME TO VISIT
THESE MOUNTAINS.
HE MIGHT BE A GUY
THAT JUST LIKES
TO WANDER AROUND.
CAN'T SHOOT HIM
FOR THAT.
BESIDES, IF YOU WERE
TO SHOOT HIM,
IT MIGHT COME OUT.
WE DON'T HAVE TO
SHOOT HIM, NECESSARILY.
WE CAN PUSH HIM OFF
ONE OF THEM ROCKS
AND CLAIM IT
AS AN ACCIDENT.
JUST WHO'S GOING
TO DO THE PUSHING--
YOU, DOBBSY?
WE'D TOSS FOR IT.
YOU'RE SURE HE WAS
TRAILING YOU, ARE YOU?
ABSOLUTELY.
HOW COME?
'CAUSE THERE HE IS.
COME OVER BY THE FIRE.
I KNOW QUITE WELL,
YOU FELLAS,
I'M NOT WANTED HERE.
BUT EVEN AFTER
WHAT YOU TOLD ME,
I SIMPLY COULDN'T RESIST
THE DESIRE
TO SIT AROUND AND JAW
WITH AN AMERICAN.
WHY DON'T YOU GO
WHERE THERE'S AMERICANS
MIGHT WANT TO TALK TO YOU?
DURANGO ISN'T TOO FAR OFF.
THEY GOT ONE OF THEM
AMERICAN CLUBS THERE.
I'M NOT AFTER THAT.
I'VE GOT OTHER THINGS
ON MY MIND MORE IMPORTANT.
SO HAVE WE.
DON'T YOU MAKE
ANY MISTAKES.
OUR BIGGEST WORRY RIGHT NOW
IS YOUR PRESENCE HERE.
WE GOT NO USE FOR YOU.
WE DON'T EVEN WANT YOU
FOR A COOK OR A DISHWASHER.
WE'RE FULL UP.
NO VACANCIES, UNDERSTAND?
AND IN CASE I DON'T
MAKE MYSELF CLEAR,
I THINK YOU'D BE
DOING YOURSELF A FAVOR
BY PACKING UP
AND GETTING OUT OF HERE
TOMORROW MORNING.
GO BACK WHERE YOU CAME FROM.
TAKE OUR BLESSINGS WITH YOU.
THANKS.
YEAH. GO AHEAD.
HELP YOURSELF.
WE DON'T MIND. WE DON'T
LET GUYS STARVE TO DEATH.
TONIGHT YOU'RE OUR GUEST.
BUT TOMORROW MORNING,
LOOK OUT!
NO TRESPASSING
AROUND HERE.
YOU KNOW, BEWARE
OF THE DOGS, GET IT?
GOT MYSELF 5 FOXES
AND A LION
WHILE YOU WERE AWAY
AT THE VILLAGE.
HOW ARE
THE HIDES?
PRETTY GOOD.
WHERE'D YOU
HIT THEM?
RIGHT THROUGH THEIR EYES.
EXCUSE ME
FOR BUTTING IN,
BUT THERE'S
NO GAME AROUND HERE
WORTH GOING AFTER.
IT WOULDN'T TAKE ONE WEEK
FOR A REAL HUNTER
TO CLEAN UP ALL AROUND
FOR 5 MILES
IN EACH DIRECTION.
YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
THERE'S NO GOOD HUNTING HERE.
THAT'S WHY
I'VE MADE UP MY MIND
TO QUIT THIS GROUND
INSIDE A WEEK
AND LOOK FOR
SOMETHING BETTER.
YEAH, STRANGER,
YOU'RE DEAD RIGHT.
IT'S AWFUL POOR GROUND.
TOOK US SOME TIME
TO FIND IT OUT.
POOR GROUND, YOU SAY?
DEPENDS ON WHAT
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
FOR GAME, YES.
MIGHTY GOOD GROUND
FOR SOMETHING ELSE.
YEAH?
WHAT MIGHT THAT BE?
GOLD.
GOLD?
HA HA HA HA!
HA HA HA HA HA!
I TOLD YOU
IN THE VILLAGE, MISTER,
THERE'S NO GOLD AROUND HERE.
BOY, IF THERE HAD BEEN
ONE SINGLE OUNCE OF IT,
I'D HAVE SEEN IT,
BELIEVE ME, I WOULD.
IF YOU HAVEN'T
FOUND ANY GOLD HERE,
THEN YOU'RE NOT AS SMART
AS YOU APPEAR TO BE.
WELL, MAYBE.
YOU MAY BE RIGHT.
WHO KNOWS?
YEAH. WE NEVER
THOUGHT ABOUT GOLD.
GIVES ME AN IDEA.
GUESS I'LL SLEEP ON IT.
WELL, I'LL HIT THE HAY.
YEAH. ME, TOO.
TILL IN THE MORNING,
MISTER.
I CAN'T FIGURE
THIS BIRD OUT.
IS HE WISE TO US
OR ISN'T HE?
WELL, WHETHER
HE IS OR NOT,
HE LOOKS FAIRLY
HARMLESS TO ME.
WELL, LOOKS CAN BE
MIGHTY DECEIVING.
NO DENYING THAT.
I'M KEEPING MY BOOTS ON
THIS NIGHT.
HE MIGHT TAKE IT
IN HIS HEAD
TO MURDER US
ALL IN OUR SLEEP.
YEAH.
ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN.
WELL, THEN?
ALL RIGHT,
TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU TWO GUYS
GO TO SLEEP,
AND I'LL BE WATCHDOG
FOR A COUPLE HOURS.
THEN YOU AND CURTIN
CAN TAKE YOUR TURNS.
OK. YOU GOT
YOUR GUN HANDY?
YEAH. RIGHT HERE.
[BURROS BRAYING]
GOOD MORNING, FRIEND.
WHERE'D YOU GET THAT WATER
TO MAKE COFFEE?
I JUST TOOK IT
OUT OF THERE.
OH, YOU DID,
DID YOU?
WE DIDN'T CARRY
THAT WATER UP HERE
FOR YOU TO
MAKE COFFEE, SEE?
I'M SORRY. I DIDN'T KNOW
WATER WAS SO HARD TO GET.
WELL, YOU KNOW IT NOW!
I'LL FILL IT UP
FOR YOU.
WHAT'S UP?
I CAUGHT THIS GUY
STEALING OUR WATER.
NEXT TIME
YOU TRY THAT,
I'LL LET IT
OUT OF YOU
THROUGH LITTLE
ROUND HOLES.
I THOUGHT PERHAPS
I WAS AMONG CIVILIZED MEN
WHO WOULDN'T BEGRUDGE ME
A LITTLE FRESH WATER.
WHO'S NOT CIVILIZED?
I COULD EASILY DO
THE SAME FOR YOU.
IT'S NOT SETTLED YET
WHO'D COME OUT ON TOP.
THIS TIME, I TOOK IT.
THANKS FOR
YOUR KIND ATTENTION.
IF I WERE YOU, STRANGER,
I'D PACK UP AND GO
WHILE THE GOING'S GOOD.
I MEAN TO STAY
RIGHT HERE.
THE BRUSH AND THE MOUNTAINS
ARE FREE, AREN'T THEY?
SURE. THAT'S RIGHT,
TO WHOEVER'S
FIRST ON THE SPOT.
THAT HOLDS FOR HUNTERS,
BUT NOT FOR GOLD MINERS,
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
THEY HAPPENED TO HAVE
REGISTERED THEIR CLAIM.
WHO SAYS WE HAVE
A CLAIM TO REGISTER?
WHATEVER YOU SAY
OR DON'T SAY,
TOMORROW, I START
TO DIG FOR GOLD HERE.
I KNOW VERY WELL
YOU GUYS CAN BUMP ME OFF
ANY MINUTE YOU WISH,
BUT THAT'S A RISK
WORTH RUNNING
CONSIDERING THE STAKES.
LET'S LAY ALL OUR CARDS
ON THE TABLE.
AS I SEE IT, YOU GUYS HAVE
GOT TO DO ONE OF 3 THINGS--
KILL ME, RUN ME OFF,
OR TAKE ME IN WITH YOU
AS A PARTNER.
LET'S CONSIDER THE FIRST.
ANOTHER GUY
MAY COME ALONG TOMORROW,
MAYBE A DOZEN OTHER GUYS.
YOU START
BUMPING PEOPLE OFF,
JUST HOW FAR ARE YOU
PREPARED TO GO WITH IT?
ASK YOURSELVES THAT.
ALSO, DON'T FORGET,
THE ONE ACTUALLY TO DO
THE BUMPING OFF
WOULD FOREVER BE
IN THE POWER OF THE OTHER TWO.
THE ONLY SAFE WAY
WOULD BE FOR ALL 3 OF YOU
TO DRAG OUT YOUR CANNONS
AND BANG AWAY
AT THE SAME INSTANT
LIKE A FIRING SQUAD.
WE WOULDN'T STOP AT ANYTHING
TO PROTECT OUR INTERESTS.
I CLAIM
KILLING ME ISN'T IT.
BUT OF COURSE,
THAT'S FOR YOU TO DECIDE.
AS FOR CHOICE NUMBER 2,
IF YOU RUN ME OFF,
I MIGHT VERY WELL INFORM ON YOU.
WE'D GET YOU
IF YOU DID THAT.
IF WE HAD TO GO
ALL THE WAY TO CHINA.
25% OF THE VALUE
OF YOUR FIND
IS THE REWARD
I'D GET PAID,
AND THAT'D BE
MIGHTY TEMPTING.
THAT'S A PRETTY
STRONG ARGUMENT
IN FAVOR OF OUR DOING
NUMBER ONE, MISTER.
I DON'T DENY IT,
BUT LET'S SEE WHAT
NUMBER 3 HAS TO OFFER.
IF YOU TAKE ME IN
WITH YOU AS A PARTNER,
YOU DON'T STAND
TO LOSE ANYTHING.
I'LL NOT ASK TO SHARE
IN WHAT YOU'VE MADE SO FAR,
ONLY IN THE PROFITS
TO COME.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU SAY?
DO YOU MIND, STRANGER,
LETTING US TALK THIS OVER
ALONE AMONG OURSELVES?
NOT AT ALL.
GO AHEAD.
I HAVE TO LOOK AFTER
MY BURROS, ANYWAY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
SENDING HIM AWAY
IS OUT OF THE QUESTION.
EITHER WE BUMP HIM OFF
OR MAKE HIM A PARTNER.
FRED C. DOBBS
AIN'T A GUY
LIKES BEING TAKEN
ADVANTAGE OF.
DO THE MUG IN,
I SAY.
TOLD US HOW,
DIDN'T HE?
ALL 3 OF US
HAUL OUT OUR CANNONS
AND LET HIM HAVE IT.
WHAT DO WE GAIN
BY BUMPING HIM OFF?
IF HE WAS ASKING TO SHARE
IN WHAT WE MADE,
IT'D BE DIFFERENT.
I DON'T MIND BEING TAKEN
SOME ADVANTAGE OF,
SO LONG AS IT ISN'T MONEY
OUT OF MY POCKET.
AND WHOEVER ELSE
HAPPENS ALONG--
THEY'RE TO BE
INVITED IN, TOO?
COME ONE,
COME ALL, EH?
YOU GOT A POINT
THERE, DOBBSY,
NO QUESTION
ABOUT THAT.
BUT, UH, KILLING...
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
AIN'T YOU UP TO IT?
SURE, I'M UP TO IT.
LET THE MAJORITY DECIDE.
WHAT'S YOUR VOTE,
PARTNER?
FOR OR AGAINST?
FOR.
OK.
LET'S MAKE IT
SHORT AND SWEET FOR HIM.
SO IT'S NUMBER ONE,
IS IT?
BETTER TAKE A LOOK
DOWN THAT HILL FIRST.
CAN'T MAKE OUT
WHAT THEY ARE.
MUST BE SOLDIERS.
OH, SO THAT'S
YOUR STINKING GAME, IS IT?
INFORMING. I KNEW
YOU WAS AN INFORMER.
I KNEW IT ALL THE TIME.
YOU'RE WRONG,
BROTHER.
THIS MEANS
ALL OUR FUNERALS.
WHAT'S THAT?
IF THAT'S WHAT
I THINK IT IS,
MAY THE LORD BE WITH US.
THEY'RE NOT SOLDIERS.
THEY'RE BANDITS,
AND THEY'RE NOT
AFTER GOLD,
BUT AFTER
GUNS AND AMMUNITION.
SOMEONE AT THE VILLAGE
MUST'VE TOLD THEM
ABOUT THE AMERICAN
HUNTER UP HERE.
THEY DON'T LOOK LIKE
SOLDIERS TO ME, EITHER.
THAT'S WHAT THEY ARE,
ALL RIGHT--BANDITS.
WE'D BETTER START
THINKING OF A WAY
TO DEFEND OURSELVES,
LIKE TRY AND HIDE
IN THE ROCKS,
BUT THEN WE LOSE THE BURROS
AND THE WHOLE OUTFIT.
NO, THE BEST THING IS
TO MAKE A FIGHT OF IT.
YOU SEEM TO HAVE
GOOD EYES.
YOU STAY UP HERE ON THIS
LOOKOUT FOR THE TIME BEING
AND WATCH
THEIR MOVEMENTS.
CURTIN, YOU ROUND UP
ALL THE BURROS
AND HERD THEM IN
THAT THICKET OVER THERE.
DOBBS, LET'S YOU AND ME
WRAP UP
ALL OUR BELONGINGS
AND DUMP THEM
IN THE TRENCH.
THEY'RE TURNING
ON THE TRAIL.
HOW MANY OF THEM
ARE THERE?
ABOUT A DOZEN.
THEY'LL BE THE BEST PART
OF AN HOUR GETTING HERE,
SO WE'D BETTER HAVE
SOMETHING TO EAT.
COME ON DOWN,
FRIEND.
''ALTO!
HOWARD. LOOK, HOWARD.
THE ONE IN THE GOLD HAT.
REMEMBER?
YEAH. BANDIT FROM
THE TRAIN ROBBERY.
THEY THINK
WHOEVER WAS HERE IS GONE.
...JEFE.
Y EN QUE FORMA.
AQUI TODO ES PIEDRA.
MIRE, JEFE...
SOME WANT TO GO BACK
ON DOWN THE MOUNTAIN.
OTHERS WANT TO STAY UP HERE
AND USE THIS SITE
AS A HEADQUARTERS
TO RAID THE VILLAGES
IN THE VALLEY.
HOW ABOUT POURING IT
INTO THEM
AND BUMPING OFF AS MANY
AS WE CAN REAL FAST?
NO, NO. LET'S HOLD
OUR HORSES.
CALLATE LA BOCA NOMAS.
SIEMPRE PENSANDO EN TRAGAR.
''ALTO!
''PARENLE, PARENLE!
[WHISTLES]
VENGAN ACA, TODOS.
VENGAN A VER
ESTA PALOMITA
QUE ME ENCONTRE
EN SU NIDO.
ESTA ECHADITA.
OIGA, SEÑOR,
WE ARE FEDERALES--
YOU KNOW,
THE MOUNTED POLICE.
IF YOU'RE THE POLICE,
WHERE ARE YOUR BADGES?
BADGES? WE AIN'T
GOT NO BADGES.
WE DON'T NEED
NO BADGES.
I DON'T HAVE TO SHOW YOU
ANY STINKIN' BADGES!
BETTER NOT
COME ANY CLOSER.
NO SEA TONTO,
HOMBRE.
WE DIDN'T TRY
TO DO YOU ANY HARM.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY TO BE
A LITTLE MORE POLITE?
GIVE US YOUR GUN,
AND WE'LL LEAVE YOU
IN PEACE.
I NEED MY GUN MYSELF.
OH, THROW THAT
OLD IRON OVER HERE.
WE'LL PICK IT UP
AND GO ON OUR WAY.
YOU GO ON YOUR WAY
WITHOUT MY GUN AND GO QUICK!
[GUNSHOT]
ALL RIGHT.
VAMONOS
PARA ATRAS.
PARA ATRAS TODOS.
LOOK HERE, AMIGO.
YOU'VE GOT
THE WRONG IDEA.
WE DON'T WANT TO GET
YOUR GUN FOR NOTHING.
WE WANT TO BUY IT.
LOOK.
I HAVE A GOLD WATCH
WITH A GOLD CHAIN,
MADE
IN YOUR OWN COUNTRY.
THE WATCH
AND THE CHAIN,
THEY'RE WORTH
AT LEAST 200 PESOS.
I'LL TRADE YOU
FOR YOUR GUN.
YOU BETTER TAKE IT.
THAT'S A GOOD
BUSINESS FOR YOU.
YOU KEEP YOUR WATCH,
I'LL KEEP MY GUN.
OH, YOU'LL KEEP IT?
YOU WILL KEEP IT?
WE WON'T GET IT?
I'LL SHOW YOU!
ME LLEVA LA--
¿Y ESTO?
''BUENO, MUCHACHOS!
''VAMOS!  ''AGARREN LA CABALLA
Y ESCONDANLA ALLI ATRAS!
SE METEN A LA MALEZA.
''PRONTO!
''PIQUENLE!
''ADELANTELE!
[GUNSHOTS]
ANYBODY GET HURT?
LOOKS LIKE
WE WON THAT ROUND.
THAT GUY WITH
THE GOLD HAT, AIN'T HE--
YEAH, WE SPOTTED HIM,
TOO. THE TRAIN ROBBER.
MAYBE THEY GOT
ENOUGH, HUH?
NO. I DOUBT IT.
NOW THAT THEY KNOW THAT
THERE'S ANYWAY 4 GUNS,
THEY'LL BE MORE
DETERMINED THAN EVER.
WHAT DO YOU SUPPOSE
THEY'LL PULL NEXT?
NO TELLING.
ALL WE CAN DO
IS SIT TIGHT.
OH, CODY?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
[GUNSHOTS]
HE'S DEAD.
GOT IT RIGHT
THROUGH THE NECK.
ONE LESS GUN.
[CHOPPING]
CHOPPING.
WOOD FOR CAMP.
THAT'S FUNNY.
IF THEY'RE UP TO
WHAT I THINK THEY ARE,
IT AIN'T FUNNY AT ALL.
WHAT'S THAT?
BUILDING BARRICADES
THAT MOVE.
IT'S AN OLD INDIAN TRICK.
CRAWL ALONG AND PUSH
THE BARRICADES BEFORE THEM,
YOU CAN'T SEE
WHERE TO SHOOT.
BROTHER, I'D BE
WILLING TO TRADE
MY SHARE OF THAT GOLD MINE
RIGHT NOW
FOR 3 OR 4 HAND GRENADES.
BETTER GET TO YOUR POSTS.
[CHOPPING STOPS]
''VAMOS, MUCHACHOS!
''VAMOS!
[HOOFBEATS]
HEY, THEY'RE
BEATING IT.
WHAT DO YOU
MAKE OF THAT?
YOUR GUESS
IS AS GOOD AS MINE.
WAIT A MINUTE, DOBBS.
MAYBE IT'S A TRICK
TO LURE US OUT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
THEY AIN'T GOOD ENOUGH ACTORS
FOR THIS KIND
OF A TRICK.
HEY, PARTNERS!
UP HERE! HERE'S A SIGHT
IF THERE EVER WAS ONE!
[DISTANT GUNSHOTS]
FEDERALES. LOOK AT THEM.
I COULD KISS
EVERY ONE OF THEM.
THEY MUST HAVE GOTTEN IT
FROM THE VILLAGERS
THERE WERE BANDITS
HEADED UP THIS WAY.
WHY DIDN'T THE BANDITS
WAIT UP HERE
AND MAKE A FIGHT OF IT?
'CAUSE THEY KNOW
ALL THE TRICKS, THAT'S WHY.
WITH US AT THEIR BACKS
AND THE FEDERALES FACING THEM,
THEY WOULDN'T
HAVE A CHANCE.
OH, GO GET 'EM.
SIC 'EM TIME.
CHEW 'EM UP AND DON'T
SPIT 'EM OUT. SWALLOW 'EM.
BOY, AM I HAPPY.
TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I WAS ALREADY EATING DIRT.
WONDER WHO HE IS.
OH.
HAS HE GOT
ANY FOLKS?
SUPPOSING HE HAS?
LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT HIS BELONGINGS.
HMM.
FEW HUNDRED PESOS.
NAME WAS JAMES CODY.
DALLAS, TEXAS.
THERE'S A LETTER
FROM DALLAS, TOO.
MUST BE HIS HOME.
RECKON SHE'S HIS GIRL.
NOT BAD.
"DEAR JIM,
"YOUR LETTER
JUST ARRIVED.
"IT WAS SUCH
A RELIEF
"TO GET WORD
AFTER SO MANY
MONTHS OF..."
SILENCE.
"SILENCE.
"I REALIZE,
OF COURSE,
"THAT THERE AREN'T
ANY MAILBOXES
"THAT YOU CAN
DROP A LETTER IN
OUT THERE
IN THE WILD."
YOU BETTER READ IT.
"BUT THAT DOESN'T KEEP ME
FROM WORRYING ABOUT YOU.
"LITTLE JIMMY IS FINE,
"BUT HE MISSES HIS DADDY
ALMOST AS MUCH AS I DO.
"HE KEEPS ASKING,
WHEN'S DADDY COMING HOME?
"YOU SAY IF YOU DO NOT
MAKE A REAL FIND THIS TIME,
"YOU'LL NEVER GO AGAIN.
"I CANNOT BEGIN TO TELL YOU
HOW MY HEART REJOICES
"AT THOSE WORDS
IF YOU REALLY MEAN THEM.
"NOW I FEEL FREE
TO TELL YOU,
"I'VE NEVER THOUGHT
ANY MATERIAL TREASURE,
"NO MATTER HOW GREAT,
"IS WORTH THE PAIN
OF THESE LONG SEPARATIONS.
"THE COUNTRY IS
ESPECIALLY LOVELY THIS YEAR.
"IT'S BEEN
A PERFECT SPRING--
"WARM RAINS
AND HARDLY ANY FROST.
"THE FRUIT TREES
ARE ALL IN BLOOM.
"THE UPPER ORCHARD
LOOKS AFLAME
"AND THE LOWER
LIKE AFTER A SNOWSTORM.
"EVERYBODY LOOKS FORWARD
TO BIG CROPS.
I DO HOPE YOU ARE BACK
FOR THE HARVEST."
"OF COURSE, I AM HOPING
"THAT YOU WILL AT LAST
STRIKE IT RICH.
"IT IS HIGH TIME FOR LUCK
TO START SMILING UPON YOU,
"BUT JUST IN CASE
SHE DOESN'T,
"REMEMBER, WE'VE ALREADY
FOUND LIFE'S REAL TREASURE.
FOREVER YOURS, HELEN."
WELL, I GUESS WE BETTER
DIG A HOLE FOR HIM.
YEAH, NOT SO GOOD.
NOT SO GOOD
AS YESTERDAY.
YOU WANT MY OPINION,
IT'S GOING TO BE A WHOLE
LOT LESS FROM NOW ON.
WE'VE TAKEN ABOUT ALL
THE GOLD THIS MOUNTAIN HAS.
HOW MUCH DO YOU FIGURE
WE GOT TO DATE?
NOT AS MUCH AS WE WAS
AIMING TO COLLECT.
NOT 40,000.
NOT THAT MUCH.
I'M WILLING TO LOWER
MY HINDSIGHTS.
OH, WE GOT UPWARDS
OF 35,000 APIECE,
AND, I TELL YOU, WE OUGHT
TO BE PLENTY THANKFUL.
LET'S CALL IT QUITS
AND PACK UP AND LEAVE.
AND THE SOONER THE BETTER
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED.
I DON'T WANT TO KEEP
THAT DAME WAITING,
WHOEVER SHE IS.
TAKE ANOTHER WEEK
TO BREAK DOWN THE MINE
AND PUT THE MOUNTAIN
BACK IN SHAPE.
DO WHAT
TO THE MOUNTAIN?
MAKE HER APPEAR LIKE
SHE WAS BEFORE WE CAME.
I DON'T GET IT.
WE'VE WOUNDED THIS MOUNTAIN.
IT'S OUR DUTY
TO CLOSE HER WOUNDS.
THE LEAST WE CAN DO TO SHOW
OUR GRATITUDE
FOR ALL THE WEALTH
SHE'S GIVEN US.
IF YOU GUYS DON'T WANT
TO HELP ME, I'LL DO IT ALONE.
YOU TALK ABOUT THAT MOUNTAIN
LIKE IT WAS A REAL WOMAN.
SHE'S BEEN
A LOT BETTER TO ME
THAN ANY WOMAN
I EVER KNEW.
KEEP YOUR SHIRT ON,
OLD-TIMER.
SURE, I'LL HELP YOU.
WELL, I RECKON
THAT'S ABOUT EVERYTHING.
EACH MAN'S BURROS
WITH HIS GOODS
HAD BETTER BE
HIS OWN RESPONSIBILITY.
WELL, BYE, MOUNTAIN,
AND THANKS.
YEAH. THANKS, MOUNTAIN.
THANKS.
[PLAYING HARMONICA]
I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT HER--
CODY'S WIDOW,
I MEAN, AND THE KID.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE OUGHT TO
GIVE THEM A FOURTH,
JUST AS IF HE'D BEEN
OUR PARTNER
FROM THE START.
WHAT, A FOURTH
OF ALL OUR GOODS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
ARE YOU CRAZY?
HADN'T HAVE BEEN
FOR CODY,
WE WOULDN'T HAVE WALKED
AWAY FROM THAT MOUNTAIN.
ASK HOWARD.
YEAH, THE BUZZARD WOULD HAVE
GOT FAT ON US, ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, IT MIGHT JUST AS WELL
HAVE BEEN ONE OF US,
BUT IT WASN'T.
IT WAS OUR GOOD LUCK
AND HIS BAD.
WHATEVER
YOU GUYS DO,
I'M GOING TO
GIVE A FOURTH.
WELL, I GOT MORE
THAN I NEED ANYHOW.
HALF WHAT I GOT'S ENOUGH
TO LAST ME OUT.
A FOURTH? SURE.
YOU TWO GUYS MUST HAVE BEEN
BORN IN A REVIVAL MEETING.
[PLAYING HARMONICA]
WE GOT COMPANY.
STEADY, BOYS.
BUENAS NOCHES.
SEÑORES,
¿PODEMOS SENTARNOS
A DESCANSAR UN POQUITO?
POR FAVOR.
CON MUCHO GUSTO.
COMO NO, AMIGOS.
¿QUIEREN TOMAR CAFE
CON NOSOTROS?
SI. GRACIAS, SEÑORES.
CURTIN.
COFFEE.
GIVE THEM
SOME TOBACCO.
HEY.
GRACIAS.
WE GIVE THEM
OUR TOBACCO,
THEY GIVE US THEIRS.
I DON'T GET IT.
WHY NOT EVERYBODY
SMOKE HIS OWN?
TAKE SOME
AND THANK THEM.
THEY'RE AFTER SOMETHING.
TAKING THEM A WHILE
TO COME TO THE POINT.
SAYING WHAT YOU WANT
RIGHT OFF THE BAT
ISN'T CONSIDERED POLITE
AMONG INDIANS.
THEY GOT NOTHING
BUT TIME, HUH?
PUES VERA USTED, SEÑOR.
MI HIJITO SE CAYO AL AGUA.
LO SACAMOS TAN PRONTO
COMO PUDIMOS.
NO SE MUEVE NI NADA.
Y NO QUIERE REVIVIR.
PERO YO CREO
QUE NO ESTA MUERTO.
NECESITAMOS AYUDA,
POR FAVOR.
¿CUANDO SUCEDIO ESTO
A SU HIJITO?
ESTA TARDE, SEÑOR.
OH. SAYS HIS LITTLE BOY
FELL IN THE WATER
AND THEY FISHED HIM OUT.
HE WON'T COME TO.
HE AIN'T DEAD,
BUT HE JUST WON'T COME TO.
OH, TOUGH.
I'LL GO HAVE A LOOK
AT THE BOY.
I'LL BE BACK
IN A LITTLE WHILE,
BEFORE MORNING PROBABLY.
BUENO, AMIGOS.
LOOK AFTER MY GOODS
WHILE I'M GONE, HUH?
TEQUILA.
EL ESPEJO.
[CHILD MOANS]
MILAGRO.
BENDITO SEA DIOS.
BUENAS NOCHES.
ARTIFICIAL RESPIRATION DID IT
AND A FEW BOY SCOUT TRICKS.
I THINK IT WAS MORE SHOCK
THAN DROWNING.
HE HADN'T SWALLOWED
MUCH WATER.
MAYBE HE WAS STUNG
WHILE DIVING.
WHAT GETS ME IS
HOW THESE INDIANS KNEW
WE WERE IN THIS NECK
OF THE WOODS, ANYHOW.
WHEN YOU'RE NEAR THEIR VILLAGES,
THEY ALWAYS KNOW.
DON'T ASK ME HOW.
THEY JUST KNOW.
[HOOFBEATS]
¿POR QUE SE VAN
DE LA COMARCA?
TENEMOS NEGOCIOS IMPORTANTES
EN DURANGO.
NO SE VAYAN
TAN PRONTO.
QUEREMOS QUE ESTEN
CON NOSOTROS
UNA SEMANA.
MUCHAS GRACIAS
POR LA INVITACION,
PERO NECESITAMOS ESTAR
EN DURANGO EN DOS SEMANAS.
WHAT'S UP?
HE'S INSISTING WE RETURN
WITH HIM TO HIS VILLAGE
AND BE HIS GUESTS.
TELL HIM TO FORGET IT.
TELL HIM HE DON'T
OWE US A THING.
MI RECOMPENSA
FUE EL GUSTO QUE SENTI
CUANDO EL NIÑO
ABRIO LOS OJOS.
TENGO QUE PAGARLE
MI DEUDA.
SI NO, SE ENOJARIAN
TODOS LOS SANTOS DEL CIELO.
IF HE DOESN'T
PAY OFF HIS DEBT,
ALL THE SAINTS IN HEAVEN
WILL BE ANGRY.
THIS IS NO LAUGHING MATTER.
I'M AFRAID HE'S DETERMINED
TO TAKE US WITH HIM,
EVEN IF IT MEANS FORCE.
I'LL HANDLE THIS.
HOMBRE, NO PUEDE QUEDAR.
NO. NO. ¿SABE?
WAIT A MINUTE, YOU GUYS.
YOU CAN'T FIGHT
YOUR WAY OUT OF THIS.
PUT YOUR GUNS AWAY.
WE'LL HAVE EVERY INDIAN
IN THE MOUNTAIN ON OUR TRAIL.
THEY'LL BE SCOUTING
IN HALF AN HOUR.
AMIGOS.
NO HAGAN NADA.
EL SEÑOR Y EL SEÑOR
NO IMPORTAN.
EL DOCTOR
SI IMPORTA.
WELL, WHAT'D HE SAY THEN?
HE SAID IT DON'T
MAKE ANY DIFFERENCE
ABOUT YOU GUYS,
BUT I HAVE TO COME.
OH, IT'S LIKE THAT, EH?
HE JUST WANTS YOU?
LOOKS LIKE IT.
THEN WHY DON'T YOU GO ALONG
WITH THEM, STAY A FEW DAYS,
WE'LL MEET YOU IN DURANGO.
WE'LL WAIT FOR YOU THERE.
WHAT ABOUT MY GOODS?
WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE THEM WITH YOU?
IF THEY FOUND OUT,
THEY MIGHT FORGET
HE WAS THEIR HONORED GUEST
AND BUMP HIM OFF.
WHAT DO I DO, DUMP THEM
OUT HERE ON THE GROUND?
WE'LL TAKE THEM WITH US
IF YOU WANT US TO
AND WAIT FOR YOU
IN DURANGO.
WELL...I GUESS THAT'S
ABOUT THE ONLY SOLUTION.
NOW, LET'S
YOU REMEMBER THIS
THE NEXT TIME YOU TRY
TO DO A GOOD DEED.
MAYBE AFTER I'VE STAYED
WITH THESE FELLAS
A LITTLE WHILE, THEY'LL
GIVE ME A HORSE TO RIDE.
IN THAT CASE, I MAY BE
A DAY OR 2 BEHIND YOU
IN DURANGO.
OH, THAT'LL BE SWELL.
GOOD LUCK, HOWARD.
YEAH. YEAH, ALL THE LUCK
IN THE WORLD.
WE'LL BE LONESOME
WITHOUT YOU.
BUT, YOU KNOW, MY SUNDAY SCHOOL
TEACHER USED TO--
USED TO SAY YOU GOT TO LEARN
TO SWALLOW DISAPPOINTMENTS
IN THIS SAD LIFE.
HURRY UP AND JOIN US.
YEAH, AND LOOK OUT
FOR THOSE INDIAN DAMES.
THEY TELL ME
THEY'RE PRETTY SMART.
ONE OF THEM SQUAWS
MIGHT MARRY YOU.
MAYBE I'LL DO JUST THAT,
PICK ME OUT A GOOD-LOOKING
SQUAW AND MARRY HER.
THEY'RE EASY TO DRESS
AND FEED AND ENTERTAIN.
THEY DON'T NAG AT YOU,
EITHER.
WELL, SO LONG, PARTNERS.
HA HA HA!
SEE YOU IN DURANGO.
HEY.
[BURRO BRAYING]
AIN'T IT ALWAYS
HIS BURROS
THAT WON'T
MARCH IN LINE,
STRAY OFF THE TRAIL,
AND SMASH THEIR PACKS
AGAINST THE TREES
AND THE ROCKS?
I WISH THEY'D
STRAY OFF FAR ENOUGH
TO FALL DOWN ABOUT
2,000 FOOT OF GORGE.
WHAT WAS IN YOUR HEAD
WHEN YOU OFFERED TO
CARRY HIS GOODS FOR HIM
IF HE COULDN'T MANAGE
BY HIMSELF?
HE KNEW
WHAT HE WAS DOING
WHEN HE TURNED THEM OVER
TO US.
MIGHTY CUTE OF HIM,
WASN'T IT?
WHAT'S THE USE OF RAILING
AGAINST THE OLD MAN?
IT WON'T DO ANY GOOD.
SAVE YOUR BREATH
FOR THAT NEXT PIECE OF TRAIL.
I'M STOPPING HERE
FOR THE NIGHT.
IF YOU WANT TO GO ON,
IT'S OK WITH ME,
BUT TAKE HIS BURROS
WITH YOU.
AIN'T MY RESPONSIBILITY.
IT'S EARLY YET.
WE'LL MAKE 4 OR 5 MILES
MORE BEFORE DARK.
NOBODY ORDERED YOU
TO STAY HERE.
YOU CAN GO 20 MILES MORE
FOR ALL I CARE.
ORDERED ME?
YOU?
WHO'S ORDERING WHO
TO DO ANYTHING?
YOU TALK LIKE YOU'RE BOSS
OF THIS OUTFIT.
MAYBE YOU ARE.
LET'S HEAR YOU SAY IT.
ALL RIGHT.
WE CAN'T GO ANY FURTHER.
WHO SAYS I CAN'T?
DON'T MAKE ME LAUGH.
I CAN GO 4 TIMES AS FAR
AS A MUG LIKE YOU,
BUT I DON'T WANT TO.
I COULD IF I WANTED,
BUT I DON'T WANT TO,
SEE, MUG?
OH, WHAT'S THE USE
OF HOLLERING?
WE'RE STARTED ON SOMETHING
AND WE GOT TO FINISH IT,
LIKE IT OR NOT.
WE'LL CAMP HERE.
WONDER WHAT
THE OLD MAN'S DOING NOW.
EATING A MEAL
OF ROAST TURKEY
AND DRINKING A BOTTLE
OF TEQUILA, PROBABLY.
THIS THE FIRST DAY WE'VE
HAD TO HANDLE EVERYTHING
WITHOUT HIS HELP.
ONCE WE GET THE HANG OF IT,
IT'LL BE A LOT EASIER.
HOW FAR AWAY DO YOU
SUPPOSE THE RAILROAD IS?
OH, NOT SO FAR
AS THE CROW FLIES.
WE AIN'T CROWS.
I FIGURE WE CAN
REACH THE HIGH PASS
IN 2 DAYS MORE.
AFTER THAT, IT'LL BE
3 OR 4 DAYS TO THE RAILROAD.
THAT'S FIGURING NO HARD LUCK
ON THE TRAIL, OF COURSE.
[LAUGHING]
WHAT'S THE JOKE,
DOBBSY?
AREN'T YOU GOING
TO LET ME IN ON IT?
IN ON IT?
SURE, I WILL.
SURE.
[LAUGHING]
WELL, GO AHEAD AND SPILL IT.
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
I WAS JUST THINKING
WHAT A BONEHEAD PLAY
THAT OLD JACKASS MADE
WHEN HE PUT ALL HIS
GOODS IN OUR KEEPING.
HOW DO YOU MEAN?
FIGURED LET US DO HIS
SWEATING FOR HIM, DID HE?
WELL, WE'LL SHOW HIM.
WHAT ARE YOU GETTING AT?
OH, MAN, CAN'T YOU SEE?
IT'S ALL OURS.
WE DON'T GO BACK
TO DURANGO AT ALL.
¿SABE? NOT AT ALL.
I DON'T
FOLLOW YOU, DOBBSY.
OH, DON'T BE SUCH A SAP.
WHERE DID YOU EVER
GROW UP?
ALL RIGHT, TO MAKE IT CLEAR
TO A DUMBHEAD LIKE YOU,
WE TAKE ALL HIS GOODS
AND GO STRAIGHT UP NORTH
AND LEAVE
THE OLD JACKASS FLAT.
YOU AREN'T SERIOUS,
ARE YOU?
YOU DON'T REALLY MEAN
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
FRED C. DOBBS DON'T SAY
NOTHING HE DON'T MEAN.
AS LONG AS I'M HERE AND
CAN DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT,
YOU WON'T TOUCH A SINGLE GRAIN
OF THE OLD MAN'S GOODS.
I KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT YOU MEAN.
YOU WANT TO TAKE IT
ALL FOR YOURSELF
AND CUT ME OUT.
NO, DOBBS. I'M ON THE LEVEL
WITH THE OLD MAN,
JUST AS I'D BE ON THE LEVEL
WITH YOU IF YOU WEREN'T HERE.
GET OFF YOUR SOAPBOX,
WILL YOU?
YOU ONLY SOUND FOOLISH
OUT HERE IN THIS WILDERNESS.
I KNOW YOU
FOR WHAT YOU ARE.
FOR A LONG TIME, I'VE HAD
MY SUSPICIONS ABOUT YOU.
NOW I KNOW
I'VE BEEN RIGHT.
WHAT SUSPICIONS
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
OH, YOU'RE NOT PUTTING
ANYTHING OVER ON ME.
I SEE RIGHT THROUGH YOU.
FOR A LONG TIME,
YOU'VE HAD IT IN YOUR MIND
TO BUMP ME OFF AT THE FIRST
GOOD OPPORTUNITY
AND BURY ME OUT HERE
IN THE BUSH LIKE A DOG,
SO'S YOU CAN TAKE NOT ONLY
THE OLD MAN'S GOODS,
BUT MINE IN THE BARGAIN.
AND WHEN YOU GET
TO DURANGO SAFELY,
YOU'LL HAVE
A BIG LAUGH, WON'T YOU,
THINKING HOW DUMB
THE OLD MAN AND I WERE.
YOU MAKE ANOTHER
MOVE TOWARD ME
AND I'LL PULL
THE TRIGGER.
COME ON.
GET YOUR HANDS UP.
COME ON! GET 'EM UP!
WAS I RIGHT, OR WAS I?
YOU AND YOUR
SUNDAY SCHOOL TALK
ABOUT PROTECTING
PEOPLE'S GOODS.
YOU.
COME ON, STAND UP
AND TAKE IT LIKE A MAN.
COME ON! GET UP!
[GUNSHOT]
LET GO OF IT.
THE CARDS ARE DEALT
THE OTHER WAY NOW, DOBBS.
YEAH.
NOW, LISTEN TO ME.
I--
DOBBS.
LOOK, YOU'RE ALL WRONG.
NOT FOR A MOMENT DID
I EVER INTEND TO ROB YOU
OR DO YOU ANY HARM.
IT'S JUST LIKE I SAID,
I'D FIGHT FOR YOU
AND YOURS
JUST THE SAME AS I'D FIGHT
FOR THE OLD MAN'S.
IF YOU REALLY MEAN THAT,
GIVE ME BACK MY GUN.
MY PAL.
WOULDN'T IT BE BETTER
THE WAY THINGS ARE
TO SEPARATE TOMORROW,
OR EVEN TONIGHT?
THAT WOULD SUIT YOU
FINE, WOULDN'T IT?
WHY ME MORE THAN YOU?
SO YOU CAN PULL ONE
ON ME FROM BEHIND,
SNEAK UP AND SHOOT ME
IN THE BACK.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL GO FIRST.
AND WAIT FOR ME
ON THE TRAIL, AMBUSH ME?
WHY WOULDN'T I DO IT
RIGHT HERE NOW
IF I MEANT TO KILL YOU?
I'LL TELL YOU WHY--
BECAUSE YOU'RE YELLOW.
YOU HAVEN'T GOT NERVE ENOUGH
TO PULL THE TRIGGER
WHILE I'M LOOKING YOU
STRAIGHT IN THE EYE.
IF YOU THINK LIKE THAT,
THERE'S NOTHING TO DO
BUT TO TIE YOU UP EVERY NIGHT.
[LAUGHING]
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I'LL MAKE YOU
A LITTLE BET.
3 TIMES 35 IS...
105.
I'LL BET YOU $105,000
YOU GO TO SLEEP
BEFORE I DO.
[LAUGHING]
GET UP THERE AT THE HEAD
OF THE TRAIN.
GET UP!
THE CARDS ARE DEALT
THE OTHER WAY NOW
AND FOR THE LAST TIME.
NO MORE SHUFFLING.
WHAT CARDS
YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I'M GONNA FINISH THIS
RIGHT NOW.
NO MORE TAKING ORDERS
FROM YOU
LIKE I HAD TO DO TODAY,
GET ME?
YOU GOING TO MURDER ME?
NO, BROTHER.
NOT MURDER.
NO, YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
I'M DOING THIS
TO SAVE MY LIFE
THAT YOU'D BE TAKING
FROM ME
THE MINUTE
I WASN'T LOOKING AT YOU.
THE OLD MAN
WILL CATCH UP WITH YOU.
OH, HE WILL, WILL HE?
WELL, I GOT AN ANSWER
FOR THAT ONE, TOO.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M GOING TO TELL HIM?
I'M GONNA TELL HIM
YOU TIED ME TO A TREE
AND MADE YOUR GETAWAY,
TAKING ALL THE GOODS--
YOURS, MINE, AND HIS.
HE'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
AND NOT ME.
UP. MARCH.
TODAY I HAD
TO MARCH TO YOUR MUSIC.
NOW YOU MARCH TO MINE.
WHERE?
TO YOUR FUNERAL.
COME ON. KEEP GOING.
GET UP.
SLEEPY, HUH?
YOU'LL BE ASLEEP SOON ENOUGH.
SOUND ASLEEP.
[2 GUNSHOTS]
MAYBE I DIDN'T KILL HIM.
MAYBE HE JUST STAGGERED
AND FELL DOWN
WITHOUT BEING HIT.
YOU KEEP IT.
IT'S YOURS, ANYHOW.
NO, NO.
NO, THEY WON'T FIND HIM.
I'LL DIG A HOLE FOR HIM
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
THIS FIRE DON'T...
DON'T GIVE MUCH HEAT.
CONSCIENCE.
WHAT A THING.
IF YOU GOT A CONSCIENCE,
IT'LL PESTER YOU TO DEATH.
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE
YOU GOT ONE,
WHAT CAN IT DO TO YOU?
MAKES ME SICK,
ALL THIS TALKING AND FUSSING
ABOUT NONSENSE.
[LEAVES RUSTLING]
NACHO, VEN A AYUDARME.
¿QUE LE PASO, SEÑOR?
AYUDAME A LLEVARLO
A MI CHOZA.
MAYBE I BETTER LEAVE HIM
LIKE HE IS.
AIN'T VERY LIKELY
ANYBODY WILL FIND HIM.
IN A WEEK'S TIME,
THE BUZZARDS AND THE ANTS WILL
HAVE DONE AWAY WITH HIM ANYWAY.
[BURRO BRAYING]
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GETTING INTO ME.
MAYBE A TIGER.
UH-OH.
WHAT IF HIS EYES ARE OPEN,
LOOKING AT ME?
THE BEST THING TO DO IS TO
GET TO THE RAILROAD IN A HURRY.
BURRO!
IT'S BETTER
NOT TO HAVE BURIED HIM.
I DID RIGHT. YEAH.
WHAT I SHOULD HAVE DONE,
MAYBE, IS BURY HIS CLOTHES
AND LEAVE HIM
TO THE ANTS AND THE BUZZARDS.
BUZZARDS.
IF SOMEBODY
SAW THEM CIRCLING,
THEY'D KNOW
SOMETHING WAS DEAD.
BUZZARDS
AIN'T SPOTTED HIM YET.
LUCKY FOR ME.
CURTIN! CURTIN!
CURTIN!
WHERE ARE YOU? CURTIN!
GOT TO GET
HOLD OF MYSELF.
I MUSTN'T LOSE MY HEAD.
THERE'S ONE THING CERTAIN--
HE AIN'T HERE.
I GOT IT--A TIGER.
YEAH.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
THE TIGER.
MUST HAVE DRAGGED HIM OFF
TO HIS LAIR, THAT'S WHAT.
PRETTY SOON,
NOT EVEN THE BONES WILL BE LEFT
TO TELL THE STORY.
[LAUGHING]
DONE AS IF BY ORDER.
[CHILDREN LAUGHING
AND SHOUTING]
[ROOSTER CROWS]
AQUI LE TRAIGO
ESTE PERICO.
OH.
MUCHAS GRACIAS.
[SQUEALING]
PARA USTED, DOCTORCITO.
BUENO. BUENO.
[CHUCKLING]
¿QUE DICE, AMIGO?
PUES VERA USTED,
SEÑOR DOCTOR.
LAZARO, AQUI,
ES CARBONERO.
OYO ALGO EN LA MALEZA.
Y AL FIJARSE,
VIO UN HOMBRE
CUBIERTO DE SANGRE
Y CASI MUERTO.
¿COMO ES
ESE HOMBRE?
PUES CREO QUE ES
UNO DE SUS COMPAÑEROS.
ESTA MUY MALO.
MI PISTOLA.
I CAME TO IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE NIGHT.
MY GUN WAS
ON THE GROUND BESIDE ME.
HE MUST HAVE LEFT IT
THERE
TO MAKE IT LOOK
LIKE SUICIDE.
I FIGURED HE'D COME BACK
IN THE MORNING
TO SEE IF I STILL HAD
A FLICKER OF LIFE.
I THOUGHT ABOUT WAITING
FOR HIM
AND LETTING HIM
HAVE IT THEN,
BUT THERE WAS A GOOD
CHANCE IN MY CONDITION
I MIGHT MISS.
SO I DECIDED TO CRAWL AWAY
LIKE A POISONED DOG.
TAKE IT EASY, SON.
YOU'RE TALKING TOO MUCH.
DON'T YOU WORRY
ABOUT ME.
I'LL PULL OUT OF THIS
IF ONLY TO GET THAT GUY.
SO IT APPEARS THAT
OUR FINE MR. DOBBS
HAS MADE OFF WITH OUR GOODS
AND IS ON HIS WAY
NORTH, HUH?
YEAH.
WELL, I RECKON WE CAN'T
BLAME HIM TOO MUCH.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN, HE'S NOT A REAL
KILLER AS KILLERS GO.
I THINK HE'S AS HONEST
AS THE NEXT FELLA. OR ALMOST.
THE BIG MISTAKE WAS LEAVING
YOU TWO FELLAS OUT THERE
IN THE DEPTHS
OF THE WILDERNESS
WITH MORE THAN 100,000
BETWEEN YOU.
MIGHTY BIG TEMPTATION,
PARTNER, BELIEVE ME.
HE SHOT ME DOWN
IN COLD BLOOD.
AFTER I WAS DOWN,
HE SHOT ME A SECOND TIME
JUST TO MAKE SURE.
MAYBE IF I'D HAVE BEEN YOUNG,
BEEN OUT THERE WITH EITHER
ONE OF YOU,
I MIGHT HAVE
BEEN TEMPTED, TOO.
MAYBE I WOULDN'T HAVE
FOLLOWED THROUGH,
BUT I RECKON I SURE ENOUGH
WOULD HAVE BEEN TEMPTED.
THERE NOW.
YOU'RE ALMOST AS GOOD AS NEW.
NOW TO FIND THAT THIEF
AND GET OUR GOODS BACK.
YO VOY A DURANGO.
CAVARE TODA MI FORTUNA.
PRESTAME UN CABALLO.
SEGURO QUE SI.
Y HASTA VAMOS
CON USTED
PARA QUE NO
LE PASE LO MISMO
QUE A SU COMPAÑERO.
THEY'RE NOT ONLY
GONNA GET ME A HORSE,
BUT THEY'RE GOING ALONG
WITH ME
TO PROTECT ME FROM ANY HARM.
AND YOU AIN'T GOIN'.
WHO SAYS SO?
NO, THERE'S A LOT
OF HARD RIDING TO IT.
YOU WOULDN'T BE UP TO IT.
YOU AREN'T
LEAVING ME BEHIND, SEE?
BUT YOU'RE WEAK
AS A NEWBORN KITTEN.
DON'T WORRY. I'LL LOOK
AFTER OUR INTERESTS.
I'M GOING.
WELL...I RECKON
YOU'RE GOING.
ADIOS, SEÑORA.
GRACIAS.
BURRO.
UHH.
OIGA, AMIGO,
¿NO TIENE UN CIGARRO?
HAVE YOU GOT
ANY CIGARETTE?
NO, I HAVEN'T.
I GOT A LITTLE TOBACCO,
IF THAT'LL DO.
BUENO.
NO PAPER
TO ROLL IT IN?
YEAH.
RIGHT HERE.
HERE YOU ARE.
GOING TO DURANGO?
YEAH.
THAT'S WHERE I'M HEADED.
I GOT TO SELL MY BURROS.
GOT TO GET SOME MONEY.
I HAVEN'T GOT
A RED CENT.
MATCHES.
MONEY?
WE NEED MONEY, TOO.
YEAH. I COULD USE
A GOOD MULE DRIVER,
MAYBE 2 OR 3.
HA HA HA HA!
QUIERE UNOS ARRIEROS.
[LAUGHING]
HOW MUCH IS THE PAY?
2 PESOS.
OF COURSE, I CAN'T
PAY IN ADVANCE.
I GOT TO WAIT
TILL I GET TO TOWN
SO I CAN GET THE MONEY.
HEY, DID I KNOW YOU
FROM SOMEPLACE?
MAYBE I KNOW YOU.
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
ARE YOU ALONE?
OH, NO.
NO, I'M NOT ALONE.
I GOT A COUPLE OF
FRIENDS COMING ALONG
ON HORSEBACK.
YEAH. THEY OUGHT TO
BE HERE ANY MINUTE.
PABLO, ASOMATE AL CAMINO
A VER SI VES DOS HOMBRES
A CABALLO.
HEY.
THAT'S FUNNY--
A MAN ALL BY HIMSELF
IN A BANDIT COUNTRY
WITH A STRING OF BURROS,
AND HIS FRIENDS
BEHIND HIM ON HORSEBACK.
[WHISTLING]
ESTAN MAS LEJOS
DE LO QUE EL SE CREE.
NI SIQUIERA EL POLVO
SE DIVISA.
YOUR FRIENDS MUST BE
VERY FAR BEHIND YOU.
PABLO CANNOT SEE ANY DUST
EVEN FROM THEIR HORSES.
THEY'LL BE ALONG
ANY MINUTE, I TELL YOU.
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
YOU'RE THE GUY IN THE HOLE.
THE ONE WHO WON'T
GIVE US THE RIFLE.
HA HA HA!
I AIN'T NEVER LAID EYES
ON YOU TILL NOW.
WHAT YOU GOT
IN THE BAGS?
SEEMS TO ME LIKE HIDES.
YEAH.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
THEY ARE--HIDES.
OUGHT TO BRING
QUITE A LOT OF MONEY, HUH?
YEAH.
SURE YOU DON'T WANT
TO COME ALONG WITH ME
AND HELP ME
WITH THE BURROS?
BURRO.
[BRAYING]
GET AWAY FROM MY BURRO.
WE CAN SELL THOSE BURROS
FOR JUST AS GOOD
AS PRICES YOU GET.
GET AWAY FROM MY BURRO,
I TELL YA!
YOU CAN'T FRIGHTEN EVEN
A SICK LOUSE WITH THAT.
YOU CAN ONLY SHOOT
ONE OF US,
AND HE WOULDN'T
MIND TOO MUCH
BECAUSE THE FEDERALES
ARE AFTER HIM ANYWAY.
SO WATCH WHERE
YOU'RE GOING.
WE'LL TAKE THE CHANCE.
GET BACK THERE.
[ALL LAUGHING]
UHH!
TATA, DAME ESA BOTA.
ES LA COMPAÑERA DE ESTA.
YO LA VI PRIMERO.
¿A MI
QUE ME IMPORTA?
¿QUE NO VIO CUANDO
LE DI EL PIEDRAZO?
LAS COSAS SON PARA MI.
A USTED NO LE TOCA NADA.
''DAME ESA BOTA,
TE DIGO!
¿PERO POR QUE?
TE JURO--
''QUE YA ESTAN PELEANDO!
''YA SE VAN LOS BURROS
POR SU CULPA!
''VAYAN A DETENERLOS!
''BURROS!
TOTAL POR ESTO NO NOS DAN
NI 20 PESOS, HERMANO.
ESPERATE UN TANTITO.
A VER QUE HAY
EN ESTOS BULTOS.
A LO MEJOR
YA NOS SALVAMOS.
OYE, ACA HAY
PURA ARENA.
¿POR QUE TENDRA...
''BURRO!  ''BURRO!
''BURRO!
''BURROS!
VENGA, PATRON.
MIRELO PRIMERO.
¿CUANTO?
¿LE GUSTA?
TIENE LO NUEVECITO.
DEME 1.75. PARA QUE VEA
QUE ANDO REGALANDO.
1.75 ES MUY CARO.
LE GARANTIZO
QUE NO ENCUENTRA MEJOR
EN TODA LA REGION.
A VER, ENSEÑELE LOS BURROS
AL PATRON, MUCHACHOS.
MIRE, LLEVESE ESTE.
SE LO ACONSEJO.
VAYA, VAYA.
SE LO ACONSEJO, JEFE.
ANDELE.
MIRE AQUI.
OTRA MAS BARATA.
ES MUY CARO.
[SILENCE]
PUES YA HACIA MUCHO
QUE NO FUMABA DE ESTE.
Y DIGAME...
¿Y TIENEN FIERRO
LOS BURROS?
SEGURO QUE TODOS
TIENEN FIERRO, PATRON.
¿COMO ES?
¿QUE? EL FIERRO?
EL FIERRO.
ESTE...
SI, SABE USTED.
ES UNA RUEDA ENCIMA
CON UNA RAYA ATRAVESADA.
A VER SI ES CIERTO.
NO ES CIERTO, COMPADRE.
''AY, QUE MEMORIA
LA MIA, HOMBRE!
¿NO SERA POR LA CALOR?
USTED NO CONOCE
EL FIERRO
PORQUE ESTOS BURROS
NO SON SUYOS.
¿COMO QUE NO SON MIOS?
¿PUES NO CREE QUE ESTO
YA ES MUCHO?
PUES A POCOS
SOMOS BANDIDOS.
PRECISAMENTE ESO.
¿A POCO NO SON
USTEDES
LOS BANDIDOS QUE
ASALTARON EL TREN?
''ANDEN!  ''ARREAO
CON ESTE!
[SHOUTING]
''DESGRACIADOS MONTONEROS!
COMO ESTA
HACIENDO CALOR.
COMO QUE VAMOS
CAMINO AL INFIERNO.
''SARGENTO!
''COLOQUELOS EN SU SITIO!
VAMOS, AFUERA.
SALGAN DE AHI.
''PELOTON!
''POSICION DE TIRADOR!
''EN PIE!
''CARGUEN ARMAS!
MI SUBTENIENTE,
¿ME DEJA AGARRAR
MI SOMBRERO?
''TOMELO!
''APUNTEN!
''FUEGO!
SHOOTING.
EXECUTION, PROBABLY.
SI, SEÑOR. DEBEN DE SER
LOS FEDERALES.
SEÑORES.
SEÑORES, LES TENGO
MUY MALAS NOTICIAS.
SU COMPAÑERO FUE
MUERTO A SANGRE FRI
POR TRES BANDIDOS.
DOBBS IS DEAD.
WHAT?
BANDITS GOT HIM.
OUR GOODS--
WHAT ABOUT
OUR GOODS?
¿DONDE ESTAN
NUESTRAS COSAS?
SUS COSAS Y LAS PIELES
ESTAN EN MI OFICINA.
WHAT? WHAT?
HE SAYS OUR GOODS
ARE SAFE IN HIS OFFICE.
IT'S NOT HERE, HOWARD.
IT'S NOT HERE.
KEEP YOUR SHIRT ON.
¿SABE ALGO SOBRE
UNOS COSTALITOS?
COMO ASI.
Y MUY PESADOS.
NO. DE ESO NO SE NADA.
AH...
YA ME ACUERDO.
¿DIJISTE
UNOS COSTALITOS
DE LONA?
SI.
¿DONDE ESTAN?
NO SE.
NO LOS VI.
YO SOLO SE
LO QUE DIJERON
LOS BANDIDOS.
WHAT? WHAT?
¿ACUERDATE DE LO QUE
DIJERON LOS SACOS?
ACUERDATE.
DIJERON QUE TENIAN
UNOS COSTALITOS
CON ARENA.
QUE ERAN PARA QUE
PESARAN MAS LAS PIELES
CUANDO LAS VENDIERAN.
HE HEARD
THE BANDITS TALKING
WHILE THEY WERE
WAITING TO BE SHOT.
HE SAID THAT THEY THOUGHT
IT WAS BAGS OF SAND
HIDDEN AMONG THE HIDE
TO MAKE IT WEIGH MORE
WHEN DOBBS WENT
TO SELL THEM IN DURANGO.
WHERE ARE THEY?
SI, ¿DONDE ESTAN
LOS SACOS?
EN EL CONVENTO
POR EL PAREDON VIEJO.
ALLI ES DONDE
DIJERON LOS BANDIDOS
QUE ABRIRIAN LA CARGA.
THEY'RE IN THE RUINS
OUTSIDE TOWN. COME ON.
LOOKS LIKE
A NORTHER.
BUSCA A LOS COSTALITOS.
''ENCONTRE UNO!
AQUI HAY OTRA BOLSA.
[LAUGHING]
OH, LAUGH,
CURTIN, OLD BOY!
IT'S A GREAT JOKE
PLAYED ON US BY THE LORD
OR FAITH OR NATURE--
WHATEVER YOU PREFER--
BUT WHOEVER OR
WHATEVER PLAYED IT
CERTAINLY HAD
A SENSE OF HUMOR!
THE GOLD HAS GONE BACK
TO WHERE WE FOUND IT!
AH HA HA HA!
[ALL LAUGHING]
THIS IS WORTH
10 MONTHS
OF SUFFERING
AND LABOR,
THIS JOKE IS.
[BOTH START LAUGHING AGAIN]
WELL, HOWARD,
WHAT NEXT, I WONDER?
WELL, I'M ALL FIXED,
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
AS A MEDICINE MAN.
I'LL HAVE 3 MEALS A DAY
OR 5 IF I WANT THEM.
ROOF OVER MY HEAD
AND A DRINK
EVERY NOW AND THEN
TO WARM ME UP.
I'LL BE WORSHIPPED
AND FED
AND TREATED
LIKE A HIGH PRIEST
FOR TELLING PEOPLE THINGS
THEY WANT TO HEAR.
GOOD MEDICINE MEN
ARE BORN, NOT MADE.
COME AND SEE ME
SOMETIME, MY BOY.
EVEN YOU'LL
TAKE OFF YOUR HAT
WHEN YOU SEE
HOW RESPECTED I AM.
WHY, ONLY DAY BEFORE
YESTERDAY,
THEY WANTED TO MAKE ME
THEIR LEGISLATURE,
THEIR WHOLE LEGISLATURE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS,
BUT IT MUST BE
THE HIGHEST HONOR
THEY CAN BESTOW.
YEAH, I'M ALL FIXED
FOR THE REST OF
MY NATURAL LIFE.
HOW ABOUT YOURSELF?
WHAT DO YOU AIM TO DO?
I HAVEN'T GOT
ANY IDEA.
OH, YOU'RE YOUNG YET.
YOU GOT PLENTY OF TIME
TO MAKE 3 OR 4 FORTUNES
FOR YOURSELF.
YOU KNOW, THE WORST AIN'T SO BAD
WHEN IT FINALLY HAPPENS--
NOT HALF AS BAD AS
YOU FIGURE IT WILL BE
BEFORE IT'S HAPPENED.
I'M NO WORSE OFF
THAN I WAS IN TAMPICO.
IT ALL AMOUNTS TO
A COUPLE OF HUNDRED BUCKS
WHEN YOU
COME RIGHT DOWN TO IT.
NOT VERY MUCH COMPARED
TO WHAT DOBBSY LOST.
ANY SPECIAL PLACE
YOU'RE BENT ON GOING?
NAH. ALL PLACES
ARE THE SAME TO ME.
TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU CAN KEEP MY SHARE
OF WHAT THE BURROS AND
THE HIDES WILL BRING
IF YOU USE THE MONEY
TO BUY A TICKET TO DALLAS.
SEE CODY'S WIDOW.
BETTER THAN WRITING.
AND BESIDES,
IT'S JULY AND...
THE FRUIT HARVEST.
HOW ABOUT IT?
IT'S A DEAL.
WELL, LET'S GET GOING.
WELL,
GOOD-BYE, CURTIN.
GOOD-BYE, HOWARD.
GOOD LUCK.
SAME TO YOU.