Your move:
bishop to knight four.
knight to rook three.
Poor baby,
you're starting to lose it,
aren't ya?
king to rook one.
rook to knight six.
Checkmate. Checkmate.
You cheating bitch.
Childs, what's he doing?
Circling the camp.
Who is he?
Said "Norge"
or something
on the side.
It's Norwegian.
George, are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm okay.
Are you?
Yeah.
What's going on there?
Watch it.
Easy.
Easy, easy, easy. Yes.
First goddamn week
of winter.
Oh, come on. Four stitches.
Barely grazed you.
What were they doing
flying that low,
shooting at a dog, at us?
Stir-crazy. Cabin fever.
Who knows?
U. S. N umber 31,
calling McMurdo.
Come in. Over.
U. S. N umber 31,
calling McMurdo.
U rgent. Come in. Over.
Great.
Come on, come on.
Nobody!
Nobody.
Get a hold of somebody.
Get a hold of anybody.
We gotta report this mess.
Look, I haven't been
able to reach shit
in two weeks.
I doubt if anybody's
talked to anybody
on this entire continent,
and you want me
to reach somebody!
Maybe we're at war
with Norway.
I was wondering when
the El Capitan was gonna get
a chance to use his popgun.
How long have they
been stationed there?
It says here
only eight weeks.
Well,
that's not long enough
for guys to go bonkers.
Bullshit, bwana.
Five minutes is enough
to put a man over down here.
Damn straight.
I mean, look at Palmer.
He been the way he is
since the first day.
How many in their party?
They started with 10.
There'd be eight others left.
How do we know? Guys as
crazy as that could have
done a lot of damage
to their own
before they got to us.
Nothing we can do
about that.
Yes, there is.
I wanna go up.
In this weather?
Bennings?
Winds are gonna
let up a tad
next couple of hours.
A tad?
Can't condone it
much myself, but
it is a short haul.
An hour there,
an hour back.
Shit, Doc,
I'll give you the lift.
No problem.
Forget it, Palmer.
Hey, thanks for
thinking about it though.
Loaded with kerosene.
I count 15 cans.
MacReady! Mac,
get your gear on!
Mac, it may not
clear up for a week.
Yeah.
We're the
closest ones to them.
It's all right by me, Doc.
I'm just letting you know
we're taking a chance.
Quit the griping,
MacReady.
Those clouds keep
moving over the sun,
we're gonna get a whiteout.
We get caught in that,
you can scratch
one doctor and one pilot.
This is real thin.
It'll clear as soon as
you get up.
It's up to you, Mac.
If you don't wanna fly,
we don't fly.
You really wanna save
those crazy Swedes, huh?
Norwegians.
Which way, Doc?
Southwest.
You're gonna have to
read the map.
'Cause I'm gonna be busy.
Mac's really
taking it up, huh?
He knows
what he's doing.
Nauls, will you turn
that crap down?
I'm trying to get some sleep.
I was shot today.
Read, bwana. Will do.
Writing's on the waII
Very superstitious
Anybody there?
Hey, Sweden!
They're not Swedish, Mac.
They're Norwegian.
Mac!
My God.
What the hell happened here?
Come on, Doc.
Portable video unit.
Anything?
It's all in Norwegian.
What are you doing, Doc?
Could be important work.
I wanna take it back.
Well, it's getting late.
Let's hurry it up.
I'll check out
the last few rooms.
Hey, Copper, come here!
Maybe they found a fossil,
the remains of some animal
buried in the ice,
and they chopped it out.
But where is it?
Look at this.
What is that?
Is that a man
in there or something?
Whatever it is,
they burned it up in a hurry.
Help me find a shovel, Doc.
We found this.
Jesus Christ.
Blair, I'd like you
to start an autopsy
right away.
Did you reach anybody yet?
Reach anybody?
We're a thousand miles
from nowhere, man,
and it's gonna get worse
before it gets better.
Well, stick to it, Windows.
Stick to it.
Nothing wrong with
this Norwegian,
physiologically anyway.
No drugs, no alcohol.
Nothing.
Well, what we got here
is what appears to be, anyway,
a normal set
of internal organs.
Heart,
lungs, kidneys, liver.
Intestines.
Seem to be normal.
One, door number two
and door number three.
And I think that Dawn Screen
here has got the one
to trade in the most.
I went to you first.
You brought your friend Anna.
You've been consuIting Anna
aII through the show anyhow.
You may as weII
consuIt her one more time.
I know how this one ends.
Clark, will you put
this mutt with the others
where he belongs?
Yeah, okay.
Go ahead.
What are you waiting for?
I don't know what the hell's
in there, but it's weird and
pissed off, whatever it is.
Bennings, go get Childs.
What is this? What's going on?
Hey, Palmer, what is this?
I don't know.
Childs, Mac wants
the flamethrower!
Mac wants the what?
That's what he said.
Now, move!
Damn it.
Stay back.
Hey, Mac, what is it?
Don't! No!
Get away!
Get back! Get back!
Get your ass over here!
Burn it.
Damn it, Childs. Torch it!
Oh, my God.
Oh!
Look. Son of a bitch. Oh.
You see,
what we're talking about here
is an organism
that imitates other
life-forms, and it
imitates them perfectly.
When this Thing
attacked our dogs,
it tried to digest them,
absorb them,
and in the process,
shape its own cells
to imitate them.
This, for instance...
That's not dog.
It's imitation.
We got to it before
it had time to finish.
Finish what?
Finish imitating
these dogs.
Easy, easy. Good.
Easy, easy.
Clark.
Yeah?
Did you notice anything
strange about the dog,
anything at all?
Strange? No.
What was the dog
doing in the rec room?
I don't know.
He was just wandering
around camp all day.
Are you saying to me
the dog wasn't put in
the kennel until last night?
Right.
How long were you
alone with that dog?
I don't know. An hour.
Hour and a half, maybe.
What the hell
you looking at me
like that for?
I don't know.
What?
It's probably nothing.
It's nothing at all.
How much more
of this crap is there?
Oh, about nine hours,
I'd say.
We can't learn
anything from this.
Guess not.
Where'd they take
these shots?
Seems like they were spending
a lot of their time
in a little place
northeast of their camp
about five or six miles.
What's that?
It looks like
something
buried under the ice.
And look at that.
They're planting
thermite charges.
Whatever it was,
it was bigger than that
block of ice you found.
Here. This is it.
The place where they were
spending most of their time.
Pretty nasty out, Mac.
35 knots.
Screw it.
I'm gonna go up anyway.
Half a mile due east.
Jesus, how long
do you figure
this has been in the ice?
Well, the backscatter
effect's been
bringing things up
from way down around here
for a long time.
I'd say... I'd say the ice
it's buried in is
100, 000 years old, at least.
And those Norwegians
blew it up?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Thousands of years ago,
it crashes, and this Thing...
Gets thrown out or crawls out,
and it ends up
freezing in the ice.
I just cannot believe
any of this voodoo bullshit.
Childs, it happens
all the time, man.
They're falling out
of the skies like flies.
Government knows
all about it. Right, Mac?
Do you believe
any of this
voodoo bullshit, Blair?
Childs. Childs.
Chariots Of The Gods, man.
They practically
own South America.
I mean, they taught the Incas
everything they know.
Come on, now, MacReady.
The Norwegians get a hold
of this, and they
dig it up out of the ice.
Yes, Garry,
they dig it up.
They cart it back.
It gets thawed out,
wakes up,
not in the best of moods.
I don't know. I wasn't there.
Which one of you
disrespectful men
been tossing his dirty drawers
in the kitchen trash can, huh?
From now on
I want my kitchen
clean, germfree.
Now how's this motherfucker
wake up after
thousands of years in the ice?
And how could it
look like a dog?
I don't know how.
'Cause it's different
than us, see?
'Cause it's from outer space.
What do you want from me?
Ask him.
You buy any of this,
Blair?
Mac, removing those
things out of the Iab
into the storeroom.
Can you come get your stuff?
Be there in a minute, Doc.
Through the door.
Right over here.
Right over...
Sorry, Mac.
You have to
move your stuff...
Doc says we gotta
lock him up. Stash him
in here and lock him up.
I have to talk to you.
I'm tired of talking,
Fuchs.
I just wanna get up
to my shack and get drunk.
Mac, it's important.
What is it?
Outside.
It's 40 below outside.
In the Thiokol.
Please, Mac.
We ought to just
burn these things.
Can't burn
the find of the century.
That's gonna win somebody
the Nobel Prize.
You got the keys?
Get them from Garry.
I wanna get some stuff
out of here.
There's something
wrong with Blair.
He's locked himself
in his room, and
he won't answer the door.
So I took
one of his notebooks
from the lab.
Yeah?
Listen.
"It could have imitated
a million life-forms
on a million planets.
"Could change into
any one of them
at any time.
"Now it wants
life-forms on Earth."
It's getting
cold in here, and
I haven't slept in days.
Wait.
"It needs to be alone
and in close proximity with
a life-form to be absorbed.
"The chameleon
strikes in the dark."
So is Blair cracking up,
or what?
Damn it, MacReady.
"There is still
cellular activity
in these burned remains.
"They're not dead yet."
Let's go, Bennings.
I gotta get some sleep.
Holy shit.
Go get the doc.
I'll get Garry.
We'll meet in Blair's room.
It's Bennings!
Bennings was right there.
Mac, I swear to God.
It had a hold of him.
Windows! Windows!
Keep away from him!
Get back! Stay back!
It isn't Bennings.
My God, what was
happening to him?
If it had more time it
would have looked, sounded
and acted like Bennings.
I don't know
what you're saying.
That was one of those Things
out there trying to
imitate him, Garry.
Come on.
MacReady, I know Bennings.
I've known him for 10 years.
He's my friend.
We've gotta burn
the rest of them.
All right, step back.
You sure that's all of them?
We cleaned out
the storehouse, the lab.
There is nothing left.
Where's Blair?
I can't find Blair.
Where's everybody else?
Windows is in the radio room
still trying to get through.
Everyone else
is in the rec room.
Well, you go on.
I'll be in in a minute.
Blair?
Don't!
You son of a bitch.
You understand me?
He's got a gun.
Get back.
Anybody interferes,
I'll kill them.
Jesus.
J ust leave it here.
We're gonna talk.
He smashed up
some of the chopper
pretty good.
Nobody talk to nobody!
Childs, go see
if he got to the tractor.
Nobody gets in
and out of here. Nobody.
You guys think I'm crazy.
Well, that's fine.
Most of you don't know
what's going on around here.
Well, I'm damn well
sure some of you do.
Christ.
He got most of the chopper
and the tractor, and he's
killed the rest of the dogs.
Garry, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Now, Childs, go around
to the map room door.
Talk to him.
Okay.
Norris, get a table
from the lab.
Do you think that Thing
wanted to be an animal?
No dogs make it
a thousand miles
through the cold.
Nah, you don't understand!
That Thing wanted to be us.
If the cell gets out
it could imitate everything
on the face of the earth
and it's not gonna stop!
Okay, Blair.
Come on, man,
you don't wanna hurt anybody.
I'll kill you.
Good shot, MacReady.
Excuse me.
Okay.
All right, bring him up.
Yeah.
Come on, Blair.
What about your shack?
I don't want him in my shack.
We'll lock him
in the toolshed.
Why am I in here?
For your own protection,
Blair.
How you doing, old boy?
I don't know who to trust.
I know what you mean, Blair.
Trust's a tough thing
to come by these days.
Tell you what.
Why don't you just
trust in the Lord?
Watch Clark.
What?
I said, watch Clark.
And watch him close.
Do you hear me?
And now
the radio's gone.
And so are
the choppers.
We're completely
cut off.
All we can do now is
hole up 'til spring,
wait for the rescue team.
No, we don't wait.
Somebody in this camp
ain't what he appears to be.
Right now that may be
one or two of us.
By spring,
it could be all of us.
So how do we know
who's human?
If I was an imitation,
a perfect imitation,
how would you know
if it was really me?
Is there some
kind of test, Doc?
Well, yeah, possibly.
I've been thinking about
a blood serum test.
What's that?
We could take a sample
of each person's blood, mix it
with uncontaminated blood.
I suppose if there's
a reaction, we'd know
who isn't human.
We've got whole blood
in storage.
Start working on it.
Keep an eye on Clark.
He was close to that dog.
Yeah.
Mac, we need
Blair's help.
He's the only one
who knows this organism.
He's too far gone.
But get the rest
of his notebooks.
Start going through them.
Garry!
Hey, you guys, come here!
What?
Somebody got to the blood.
Where's Clark?
Right here.
Wait a minute.
Was this broken into?
The lock is undamaged.
Somebody opened it, closed it,
then locked it.
Great.
Who's got access to it?
I guess I'm the only one.
And I got the only key.
Would that test
have worked, Doc?
I think so, yes.
Somebody else
sure as hell thought so.
Well, who else
could've used that key?
Nobody! I just
give it to Copper
whenever he needs it.
Could anybody have
gotten it from you, Doc?
I don't see how.
As soon as I'm finished,
I return it right away.
Great.
When was
the last time you used it?
Day or so ago.
I suppose somebody could have
lifted it off me...
Oh, come on!
That key ring of yours
is always hooked to your belt.
Accusing everybody...
Stop it! It ain't worth it!
Copper's the only one
who's got
any business with it.
Wait a minute!
You've been in here
on several occasions.
Doc thought of the test.
So what?
Is that supposed to clear him?
Windows! Windows!
Put that down!
No.
I'll put this
right through your head.
You guys gonna
listen to Garry?
You gonna let him
give the orders?
He could be
one of those Things.
Windows.
Wait a minute.
J ust take it easy.
Put the gun down.
Put it down.
You don't want
to hurt anybody.
Right.
On the floor.
It's on the floor.
I don't know about Copper,
but I give you my word,
I did not go near that blood.
But I guess you'll
all feel a little easier
if somebody else
was in charge.
Norris, I can't see
anybody objecting to you.
I'm sorry, fellas,
but I'm not up to it.
I'll take it.
Like hell you will.
It should be somebody
a little more
even-tempered, Childs.
All right.
I know I'm human.
And if you were all
these Things, then you'd
just attack me right now.
So some of you
are still human.
This Thing doesn't want
to show itself.
It wants to hide
inside an imitation.
It'll fight if it has to.
But it's vulnerable
out in the open.
If it takes us over,
then it has no more enemies,
nobody left to kill it.
And then it's won.
There's a storm
hitting us in six hours.
We're gonna find out
who's who.
All right, Doc, Garry
and Clark, move over there
away from the others.
Norris, you and Childs
shoot them up with morphine.
Tie them down in the rec room
and watch them.
Fuchs, you start working
on a new technique.
I need Doc's help.
You don't wanna drug me.
Mac, I'm not a prisoner!
Let me do it.
You're gonna break
the needle in my arm.
No, Doc, he's doing
a real fine job.
I'm gonna hide this tape
when I'm finished.
If none of us make it,
at least there'll be
some kind of record.
Storm's been hitting us
hard now for 48 hours.
We still have
nothing to go on.
One other thing,
I think it rips
through your clothes
when it takes you over.
Windows found some
shredded long johns,
but the name tag was missing.
They could be anybody's.
Nobody...
Nobody trusts anybody now.
And we're all very tired.
There's nothing else I can do.
J ust wait.
R.J. MacReady,
helicopter pilot,
U. S. Outpost, number 31.
You come up with anything yet?
One or two ideas.
But, MacReady,
I've been thinking.
If a small particle of
this Thing is enough to
take over an entire organism,
then everyone should prepare
their own meals.
And I suggest
we only eat out of cans.
All right.
Who's that?
Anybody see Fuchs?
Somebody blew out
a fuse in the lab.
Lights were out for an hour.
Anyone of us
could've gotten to him.
All right, we gotta find him.
Nauls, why don't you
come with me
and we'll look outside.
Palmer, you and Windows
check the inside.
I ain't going with Windows.
I ain't going with him.
I'll go with Childs.
Hey, fuck you, Palmer!
I ain't going with you!
Who says I want you
going with me?
Cut the bullshit!
Windows, you come with us.
Norris, you stay here.
Any of them move,
you fry them.
You hear anything,
cut loose on the sirens.
We all meet back here
in 20 minutes regardless.
And everybody watch whoever
you're with... real close.
Hey, Blair.
Blair, have you seen Fuchs?
I don't wanna
stay out here anymore.
I wanna come back inside.
I hear funny things
out here.
Have you
come across Fuchs?
It ain't Fuchs.
I'm not gonna harm anybody.
There's nothing wrong with me.
And if there was,
I'm all better now.
I'd like to come back inside.
Now you've got my promise.
We'll see.
Wait a minute, man.
I wanna come back inside,
don't you understand?
I'm all right.
I'm much better... and
I won't harm anybody.
You gotta let me
come back inside.
Hold it!
Is it Fuchs?
Yeah.
Why would it burn him?
Flare.
Maybe he tried to burn it.
Maybe he burned himself
before it could get to him.
Great!
Now what are we gonna do?
You go inside.
Tell the others
we found Fuchs.
We'll be in
as soon as we can.
Where are we going?
U p to my shack.
What the hell for?
'Cause when I left yesterday,
I turned the lights off.
How long have
they been out there?
Forty, 45 minutes.
We better start closing off
the outside doors.
Hey! All of you, come here!
Open up! Open up this door!
Open up! Open up!
Close that door.
Where's MacReady?
I cut him loose of
the line up by his shack.
Cut him loose?
Yeah.
We were up checking around
his place, I found this.
Look.
It was stashed
in his oil furnace.
Wind must've dislodged it,
but I don't think
he saw me find it.
I made sure I got
ahead of him on the towline
on the way back.
I cut him loose.
MacReady?
He's one of them.
When do you think
it got to him?
I don't know.
It could've been
anytime, anywhere.
If it did get to him.
Look, Childs, come on.
When the lights went out.
That would've been perfect.
Right.
You said guys were missing.
Windows, where were you?
I told you
to shut your mouth!
This is just
what it wants!
To pit us against each other.
Let's open it.
Hell no!
You think he's changed
into one of those Things?
He's had time.
Nothing human could've
made it back here in this
weather without a guide line.
Let's open it now.
Why are you so anxious
to let him in here?
Because it's so close.
May be our best chance
to blow it away.
Let him freeze.
Childs, what if
we're wrong about him?
Well, then, we're wrong!
The supply window!
All right, all right,
we got no choice now!
Damn it! He's got the keys!
What's going on?
The towline snapped.
Bullshit, Childs.
He's got to know
damn well I cut it!
You're a dead man, MacReady!
Or a dead whatever
the hell you are!
Anyone messes with me
and the whole camp goes.
Come on, Childs, burn me.
Put those torches
on the floor and back off.
Back off. Way off.
You asshole.
You'd have done
the same thing.
Don't argue with him.
Where's the rest?
Come on, man, I mean it!
It's cool, MacReady, come on.
Yeah. Yeah, man, just relax.
Anybody touches me...
and we go.
He's not breathing!
Go untie the doc.
Get him in here.
And bring the others.
From now on,
nobody gets out of my sight.
Let me at him.
So, you sweethearts
were about to have
a little lynching party, huh?
I might just have to
put an end to you
on general principles, Nauls.
Did it ever occur to the jury
that anybody could've
gotten some of my clothes
and stuck them up the furnace?
We ain't buying that.
Quit that bickering
over there!
Windows,
wheel that defibrillator
over here.
Give me those paddles!
You're gonna
have to sleep sometime,
MacReady.
I'm a real light sleeper,
Childs.
If anyone tries to wake me...
Clear!
Clear.
We're on fire, MacReady!
We're on fire!
Get back! J ust wait!
All right, go!
Windows! Windows,
get in here!
You gotta be fucking kidding.
What do you got in mind,
MacReady?
A little test.
And, Windows, you and Palmer,
tie everybody down real tight.
What for?
For your health.
Let's rush him!
He's not gonna
blow us all up!
No, no, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Let's do what Mac says.
I mean,
he wasted Norris pretty quick,
didn't he?
That's close enough, Clark.
He ain't tying me up.
Then I'll have to
kill you, Childs.
Then kill me.
I mean it.
I guess you do.
Geez. This is bullshit, Mac!
Finish it, Palmer.
They're dead, Mac!
Windows?
Yo?
You tie up Palmer over here.
We're gonna draw
a little bit of
everybody's blood
'cause we're gonna find out
who's the Thing.
Watching Norris in there
gave me the idea that
maybe every part of him
was a whole.
Every little piece
was an individual animal
with a built-in desire
to protect its own life.
You see, when a man bleeds,
it's just tissue.
The blood from
one of you Things won't
obey when it's attacked.
It'll try and survive.
Crawl away from
a hot needle the same.
Now you.
That's good.
All right, move back,
over there.
I guess you're okay.
All right.
Put that on and watch them.
Now I'll show you
what I already know.
It's a crock of shit.
Let's try the doc and Clark.
Now Clark.
Then Clark was human, huh?
Which makes you a murderer,
don't it?
Palmer now.
This is pure nonsense.
It doesn't prove a thing.
I thought you'd
feel that way, Garry.
You were the only one
that could've
got to that blood.
We'll do you last.
Get him away from me!
MacReady, burn it!
What is it?
Come on!
Get me out of here!
Windows, blast him!
Windows!
Get me out of here!
MacReady, get in here!
Come on, hurry up!
He's coming back! Burn it!
Burn it, for God's sake!
H urry up, MacReady! Burn it!
Let's do it.
Get me out of here!
Cut me loose!
Cut me the hell... Come on,
get me out of here!
Come on, get me out of here!
Cut me loose, damn it!
I know you gentlemen
have been through a lot,
but when you find the time,
I'd rather not spend the rest
of this winter tied to
this fucking couch!
Childs.
We're going out to
give Blair the test.
If he tries to
make it back here
and we're not with him...
burn him.
Mac, the door's open!
How'd he get out?
The door was bolted
from the outside.
Blair?
Hey, Blair, you down there?
We got something for ya!
Blair's been busy
out here all by himself.
What is it?
Something he's been making.
It's a ship of some kind.
He stole the parts
from the helicopter.
The smart S. O. B.
put it together
piece by piece.
Where was he trying to go?
Anyplace but here.
Hey, you guys, come here.
Come here.
I think I saw Childs
outside the main entrance
of the camp.
What's he doing outside?
I don't know.
Got a flare?
He got back inside
and blew the generator.
In six hours, it'll be
a hundred below in here.
Well, that's suicide!
Not for that Thing.
It wants to freeze now.
It's got no way out of here.
It just wants to go to sleep
in the cold until
the rescue team finds it.
What can we do?
Whether we make it or not,
we can't let that Thing
freeze again.
Maybe we'll just
warm things up a little
around here.
We're not getting out
of here alive.
But neither is that Thing.
Generator room.
The generator's gone.
Any way we can fix it?
It's gone, MacReady.
All right.
We gotta bring
this whole place right down
into the ice.
Garry, plant yours
in the old storage room.
Nauls, down by the generator.
God!
How's it coming in there?
I said, how's it...
Yeah, fuck you, too!
You the only one who made it?
Not the only one.
Did you kill it?
Where were you, Childs?
Thought I saw Blair.
I went out after him
and got lost in the storm.
Fire's got the temperature up
all over the camp.
Won't last long, though.
Neither will we.
How will we make it?
Maybe we shouldn't.
If you're worried about me...
If we've got any surprises
for each other,
I don't think
we're in much shape
to do anything about it.
Well... what do we do?
Why don't we just
wait here for a little while?
See What Happens!