She isn't coming yet,
Toto. Did she hurt you?
She tried to, didn't she? Come on.
We'll go tell Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
Aunt Em! Aunt Em!
Aunt Em, just listen to
what Miss Gulch did to Toto!
-Dorothy, please! We're trying
to count! -But she hit him-
Don't bother us now, honey.
This old incubator's gone bad...
...and we're likely to
lose a lot of our chicks.
The poor little things.
Miss Gulch hit Toto on the back
with a rake just because she says...
...he gets in her garden and
chases her nasty old cat every day!
Dorothy, please!
But he doesn't do it every
day, just once or twice a week.
He can't catch her old cat, anyway!
And now she says she's going to-
Dorothy! We're busy!
All right.
How's she coming?
Take it easy.
You got my finger!
Why don't you get your
finger out of the way?
There you are.
-Right on my finger!
-It's a lucky thing it wasn't your head.
Zeke, what am I going
to do about Miss Gulch?
-Just because Toto chases her old cat-
-Listen, honey, I got them hogs to get in.
Dorothy, you ain't using
your head about Miss Gulch.
-You'd think you didn't have any brains.
-I have so got brains!
Why don't you use them?
When you come home
don't go by her place...
...then Toto won't get in her garden
and you won't get in no trouble.
Hunk, you just won't
listen, that's all.
Well, your head ain't
made of straw, you know.
Get in there before I
make a dimebank out of you!
Listen, kid...
Are you going to let that old
Gulch heifer try and buffalo you?
She ain't nothing to be afraid of.
Have a little courage, that's all.
I'm not afraid of her.
The next time she squawks, walk
up to her and spit in her eye.
That's what I'd do!
Zeke, get me out of here! Help!
Are you all right, Dorothy?
Yes, I'm all right.
I fell in and Zeke...
Why, Zeke, you're
just as scared as I am!
You gonna let a little old
pig make a coward out of you?
Look at you, Zeke-
What's all this jabber-wapping
when there's work to be done?
I know three farm hands who'll be
out of a job before they know it!
Dorothy was walking-
I saw you tinkering with that
contraption. You two get back to the wagon!
All right, Mrs. Gale.
Someday they're going to erect
a statue to me in this town-
Don't start posing for it now.
Here, can't work on an empty stomach.
Have some crullers. Just fried.
-Dorothy toppled into- -It's no
place for Dorothy around a pigsty!
Now, you go feed those hogs before
they worry themselves into anemia!
Do you know what Miss Gulch
said she was going to do to Toto?
Now, Dorothy, stop
imagining things.
You always get yourself
into a fret over nothing.
Help us out today and find a place
where you won't get into any trouble.
Some place where there
isn't any trouble.
Do you suppose there
is such a place, Toto?
There must be.
It's not a place you can
get to by a boat or a train.
It's far, far away...
...behind the moon...
...beyond the rain...
~ Somewhere, over
the rainbow... ~
~ ...way up high ~
~ There's a land
that I heard of... ~
~ ...once in a lullaby ~
~ Somewhere, over
the rainbow... ~
~ ...skies are blue ~
~ And the dreams that
you dare to dream ~
~ Really do come true ~
~ Someday I'll
wish upon a star ~
~ And wake up where the
clouds are far behind me ~
~ Where troubles melt
like lemon drops, ~
~ Away above the chimney tops ~
~ That's where you'll find me ~
~ Somewhere, over
the rainbow... ~
~ ...bluebirds fly ~
~ Birds fly over the rainbow ~
~ Why then, oh, why can't I? ~
~ If happy little
bluebirds fly... ~
~ ...beyond the rainbow ~
~ Why, oh, why can't I? ~
Mr. Gale.
Howdy, Miss Gulch.
I want to see you and your
wife right away about Dorothy.
What has Dorothy done?
What's she done? I'm all but
lame from the bite on my leg!
-You mean, she bit you?
-No, her dog!
She bit her dog, eh?
No!
That dog's a menace.
I'll take him to the Sheriff
and make sure he's destroyed.
Destroyed? Toto?
Oh, you can't! You mustn't!
Auntie Em! Uncle Henry!
You won't let her, will you?
Of course, we
won't. Will we, Em?
Please, Aunt Em!
Toto didn't mean to.
He didn't know he was doing anything
wrong. I ought to be punished.
I let him go in her garden. You
can send me to bed without supper.
Hand over the dog, or I'll bring
a damage suit and take your farm!
There's a law protecting
folks from dogs that bite!
What if she keeps him tied up?
He's really gentle, with
gentle people, that is.
Well, that's for the Sheriff to decide.
Here's his order allowing me to take him.
Unless you want to
go against the law.
Yes...
We can't go against the law. I'm
afraid poor Toto will have to go.
Now you're seeing reason.
Here's what I'm taking him in,
so he can't attack me again.
No, no! I won't
let you take him!
You go away! I'll
bite you myself!
Dorothy!
You wicked old witch!
Uncle Henry, Auntie Em,
don't let them take Toto!
Don't let her take
him, please! Stop her.
-Put him in the basket, Henry.
-The idea!
Don't, Uncle Henry.
Oh, Toto!
Almira Gulch, just because
you own half the county...
...doesn't mean you have the
power to run the rest of us!
For 23 years I've been dying to
tell you what I thought of you!
Well, being a Christian
woman, I can't say it!
Toto, darling! Oh,
I've got you back!
You came back!
Oh, I'm so glad!
They'll be coming back
for you in a minute.
We've got to get away!
We've got to run away!
Well, well, well!
Houseguests, huh?
And who might you be?
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
Let's see. You're...
You're travelling in
disguise. No, that's not right.
You're going on a
visit. No, I'm wrong.
You're running away.
How did you guess?
Professor Marvel never
guesses. He knows!
Why are you running away?
No, no. Don't tell me.
They don't understand you at
home. They don't appreciate you.
You want to see other lands, big
cities, big mountains, big oceans.
It's just like you could
read what was inside of me.
Toto, that's not polite!
We haven't been asked yet.
He's perfectly welcome.
As one dog to another, huh?
Now, let's see. Where were we?
Please. Why can't we go with you and
see all the crowned heads of Europe?
Do you know any?
You mean, the thing.
I never do anything without
consulting my crystal first.
Let's go inside here. Just
come along. I'll show you.
That's right. Here, sit
right down here. That's it.
This is the same genuine,
magic, authentic crystal...
...used by the priests of Isis and Osiris
in the days of the pharaohs of Egypt...
...in which Cleopatra first saw the approach
of Julius Caesar and Mark Anthony and...
...and so on and so on.
You'd better close
your eyes, my child...
...for a moment, in order to be
better in tune with the infinite.
We can't do these
things without...
...reaching out
into the infinite.
That's all right. Now, you can open
them. We'll gaze into the crystal.
What's this I see?
A house with a picket fence...
...and a barn with
a weathervane...
...of a running horse.
That's our farm!
Yes. There's a woman.
She's wearing a
polka-dot dress.
Her face is careworn.
That's Aunt Em.
Yes. Her name is Emily.
That's right. What's she doing?
Well, I can't quite see.
Why, she's crying!
Someone has hurt her. Someone
has just about broken her heart.
Me?
Well, it's someone
she loves very much...
...someone she's been very kind to,
someone she's taken care of in sickness.
I had the measles once and she
stayed right by me every minute.
What's she doing now?
What's this?
Why, she's putting
her hand on her heart!
She's dropping down on the bed!
Oh, no!
Well, that's all. The
crystal's gone dark.
You don't suppose she could
really be sick, do you?
I've got to go home right away!
I thought you were
going along with me!
No, I have to get to her
right away! Come on, Toto!
Come on! Come on!
Goodbye, Professor
Marvel, and thanks a lot!
Better get under cover, Sylvester!
There's a storm blowing, a whopper...
...to speak in the
vernacular of the peasantry!
Poor little kid. I hope
she gets home all right.
Hurry up and get them horses loose!
Where's Hickory? Hickory! Hickory!
Doggone it! Hickory!
It's a twister! It's a twister!
Dorothy!
Come on, everybody
in the storm cellar!
Henry! I can't find Dorothy!
She's somewhere out in the storm!
Dorothy!
Auntie Em!
Auntie Em! Uncle Henry!
We must be up
inside the cyclone!
Miss Gulch!
Toto, I have a feeling
we're not in Kansas anymore.
We must be over the rainbow!
Now, I know we're not in Kansas.
Are you a good
witch or a bad witch?
Who, me?
I'm not a witch at all. I'm
Dorothy Gale, from Kansas.
Well, is that the witch?
Who, Toto?
Toto's my dog.
Well, I'm a little muddled.
The Munchkins called me because a
new witch has just dropped a house...
...on the Wicked Witch of the East. And
there's the house, and here you are...
...and that's all that's left
of the Wicked Witch of the East.
What the Munchkins
want to know is...
...are you a good
witch or a bad witch?
But, I've already told
you, I'm not a witch at all.
Witches are old and ugly.
What was that?
The Munchkins. They're
laughing because I am a witch.
I'm Glinda, the
Witch of the North.
You are?
I beg your pardon!
But I've never heard of
a beautiful witch before.
Only bad witches are ugly.
The Munchkins are happy. You freed
them from the Wicked Witch of the East.
But, if you please,
what are Munchkins?
The little people who live in
this land. It's Munchkin Land...
...and you are their
national heroine, my dear.
It's all right, you may
all come out and thank her.
~ Come out, come out
wherever you are ~
~ And meet the young lady
who fell from a star ~
~ She fell from the
sky, she fell very far ~
~ And Kansas, she says, ~
~ is the name of the star ~
~ Kansas, she says, is
the name of the star ~
~ She brings you good news,
or haven't you heard? ~
~ When she fell out of Kansas
a miracle occurred ~
~ It really was no miracle
What happened was just this: ~
~ The wind began to switch,
the house to pitch ~
~ And suddenly the hinges
started to unhitch ~
~ Just then the Witch,
to satisfy an itch ~
~ Went flying on her broomstick
thumbing for a hitch ~
~ And, oh, what
happened then was rich ~
~ The house began to pitch, ~
~ the kitchen took a slitch ~
~ It landed on the Wicked Witch
in the middle of a ditch ~
~ Which was not a healthy
situation for the Wicked Witch ~
~ The house began to pitch, ~
~ the kitchen took a slitch ~
~ It landed on the Wicked Witch
in the middle of a ditch ~
~ Which was not a healthy
situation for the Wicked Witch ~
~ Who began to twitch, and
was reduced to just a stitch ~
~ Of what was once
the Wicked Witch ~
~ We thank you very sweetly ~
~ For doing it so neatly ~
~ You've killed
her so completely ~
~ That we thank
you very sweetly ~
~ Let the joyous
news be spread ~
~ The Wicked Old Witch
at last is dead! ~
~ Ding-dong the Witch is
dead Which old witch? ~
~ The Wicked Witch! Ding-dong
the Wicked Witch is dead ~
~ Wake up, you sleepyhead
Rub your eyes, get out of bed ~
~ Wake up, the
Wicked Witch is dead ~
~ She's gone where the goblins
go Below, below, below ~
~ Yo-ho, let's open up and sing
and ring the bells out ~
~ Ding-dong the merry-oh, ~
~ sing it high, sing it low ~
~ Let them know the
Wicked Witch is dead ~
~ As Mayor of the
Munchkin City ~
~ In the county
of the Land of Oz ~
~ I welcome you most regally ~
~ But we've got to
verify it legally ~
~ -To see ~
~ -If she ~
~ Is morally, ethically ~
~ Spiritually, physically ~
~ Positively, absolutely ~
~ Undeniably and
reliably dead. ~
~ As Coroner I must aver ~
~ I thoroughly examined her ~
~ And she's not
only merely dead ~
~ She's really most
sincerely dead ~
~ Then this is a day of independence
for all the Munchkins... ~
~ ...and their descendants ~
~ If any ~
~ Yes, let the joyous
news be spread ~
~ The Wicked Old Witch
at last is dead! ~
~ Ding-dong the Witch is dead
Which old witch? The Wicked Witch! ~
~ Ding-dong the
Wicked Witch is dead ~
~ Wake up, you sleepyhead
Rub your eyes, get out of bed ~
~ Wake up, the
Wicked Witch is dead ~
~ She's gone where the goblins
go Below, below, below ~
~ Yo-ho, let's open up and sing
and ring the bells out ~
~ Ding-dong the merry-oh, ~
~ sing it high, sing it low ~
~ Let them know the
Wicked Witch is dead! ~
~ We represent the
Lullaby League ~
~ The Lullaby League,
the Lullaby League ~
~ And in the name of
~ We wish to welcome you
to Munchkin Land ~
~ We represent the
Lollypop Guild ~
~ The Lollypop Guild,
the Lollypop Guild ~
~ And in the name of
~ We wish to welcome you
to Munchkin Land ~
~ We welcome you
~ From now on
you'll be history ~
~ -You'll be history ~
~ And we will
glorify your name ~
~ You'll be a bust ~
~ -Be a bust ~
~ In the hall of fame ~
I thought you said she was dead.
That was her sister, the
Wicked Witch of the East.
This is the Wicked Witch of the West.
She's worse than the other one was.
Who killed my sister? Who
killed the Witch of the East?
Was it you?
No, no. It was an accident.
I didn't mean to kill anybody.
Well, my little pretty, I
can cause accidents, too!
Aren't you forgetting
the ruby slippers?
The slippers, yes!
The slippers!
They're gone!
The ruby slippers! What
have you done with them?
Give them back to me or I'll-
It's too late! There they are...
...and there they'll stay!
Give me back my slippers!
I'm the only one who
knows how to use them.
They're of no use to
you. Give them back to me.
-Give them back!
-Keep tight inside of them.
Their magic must be very powerful,
or she wouldn't want them so badly.
You stay out of this, Glinda,
or I'll fix you as well!
Rubbish! You have no power here.
Begone, before somebody
drops a house on you, too!
Very well, I'll bide my time.
And as for you, my fine lady...
...it's true I can't attend to
you here and now as I'd like...
...but just try to
stay out of my way.
Just try!
I'll get you, my pretty,
and your little dog, too!
It's all right. You
can get up. She's gone.
It's all right.
You can all get up.
What a smell of sulphur!
I'm afraid you've made a bad enemy
of the Wicked Witch of the West.
The sooner you get out of Oz altogether,
the safer you'll sleep, my dear.
I'd give anything to get
out of Oz altogether, but...
...which is the way back to
Kansas? I can't go the way I came.
No, that's true. The only
person who might know...
...would be the great and
wonderful Wizard of Oz himself!
The Wizard of Oz? Is
he good or is he wicked?
Very good, but very mysterious.
He lives in the Emerald City...
...and that's a long journey from here.
Did you bring your broomstick with you?
No, I'm afraid I didn't.
Well, then, you'll have to walk.
The Munchkins will see you safely
to the border of Munchkin Land.
And remember, never let those ruby
slippers off your feet for a moment...
...or you will be at the mercy
of the Wicked Witch of the West.
But how do I start
for Emerald City?
It's always best to
start at the beginning...
...and all you do is follow
the Yellow Brick Road.
But, what happens if I-
Just follow the
Yellow Brick Road.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
My!
People come and
go so quickly here!
Follow the Yellow Brick Road.
~ Follow the Yellow Brick Road ~
~ Follow, follow, follow, follow,
Follow the Yellow Brick Road ~
~ Follow the Yellow Brick
~ You're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
~ You'll find he is a whiz of a
Wiz If ever a Wiz there was ~
~ If ever, oh ever, a Wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because ~
~ Because, because, because,
because, because ~
~ Because of the
wonderful things he does ~
~ You're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
Follow the Yellow...
Now which way do we go?
Pardon me. That way
is a very nice way.
Who said that?
Don't be silly, Toto.
Scarecrows don't talk.
It's pleasant
down that way, too.
That's funny.
Wasn't he pointing
the other way?
Of course, people
do go both ways.
You did say
something, didn't you?
Are you doing that on purpose,
or can't you make up your mind?
That's the trouble. I
can't make up my mind.
I haven't got a
brain, only straw.
How can you talk if
you haven't got a brain?
I don't know.
But some people without brains do
an awful lot of talking, don't they?
Yes, I guess you're right.
Well, we haven't really
met properly, have we?
Why, no!
How do you do?
Very well, thank you.
I'm not feeling at all well.
It's very tedious being stuck up here
all day long with a pole up your back.
That must be terribly
uncomfortable. Can't you get down?
Down? No, you see,
I'm... Well, I'm...
Well, here, let me help you.
That's very kind
of you, very kind.
I don't quite see how...
Of course, I'm not bright
about doing things...
...but if you'll just bend the nail down
in the back, maybe I'll slip off and...
Oh, yes.
There goes some of me again!
Does it hurt you?
Oh, no. I just keep picking it
up and putting it back in again.
My! It's good to be free!
Did I scare you?
No, no. I just thought
you hurt yourself.
But I didn't scare you?
No, of course not.
I didn't think so.
You see, I can't
even scare a crow.
They come from miles around just to
eat in my field and laugh in my face.
I'm a failure because
I haven't got a brain!
What would you do with
a brain if you had one?
Do? Why, if I had
a brain, I could...
~ I could wile away the hours ~
~ Conferrin' with the flowers ~
~ Consultin' with the rain ~
~ And my head I'd be scratchin'
While my thoughts were busy hatchin' ~
~ If I only had a brain ~
~ I'd unravel every riddle
For any individual ~
~ In trouble or in pain ~
~ With the thoughts you'll be thinkin'
You could be another Lincoln ~
~ If you only had a brain ~
~ Oh, I would tell you why ~
~ The ocean's near the shore ~
~ I could think of things
I never thunk before ~
~ And then I'd sit
and think some more ~
~ I would not be
just a nothin' ~
~ My head all full of stuffin'
My heart all full of pain ~
~ I would dance and be merry ~
~ Life would be a ding-a-derry ~
~ If I only had a brain ~
Wonderful!
If our scarecrow back in Kansas could
do that, the crows'd be scared to pieces!
-They would?
-Yes.
Where's Kansas?
That's where I live.
I want to get back there so
badly I'm going to Emerald City...
...to get the Wizard
of Oz to help me.
You're going to see a wizard?
Do you think if I went with you this
wizard would give me some brains?
I couldn't say.
But even if he didn't, you'd be
no worse off than you are now.
Yes, that's true.
You'd better not. I've got a witch mad
at me and you might get into trouble.
Witch?
I'm not afraid of a witch.
I'm not afraid of anything!
Except a lighted match.
I don't blame you for that.
But I'd face a whole box full of them
for the chance of getting some brains.
I won't be any trouble
because I don't eat a thing.
I won't try to manage
things because I can't think.
Won't you take me with you?
Of course, I will!
Hooray! We're off
to see a wizard!
Well, you're not
starting out very well.
I'll try! Really, I will.
-To Oz?
-To Oz!
~ We're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
~ We hear he is a whiz of a Wiz
If ever a Wiz there was ~
~ If ever, oh ever, a Wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because ~
~ Because, because, because,
because, because ~
~ Because of the
wonderful things he does ~
~ We're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
Apples!
Oh, look!
What do you think you're doing?
We've been walking a long
ways and I was hungry and...
Did you say something?
-She was hungry!
How would you like to have someone come
along and pick something off of you?
Oh, dear! I keep forgetting
I'm not in Kansas.
Come along, Dorothy, you
don't want any of those apples.
Are you hinting my apples
aren't what they should be?
Oh, no! It's just that she
doesn't like little green worms!
You!
I'll show you how to get apples.
Hooray! I guess that
did it! Help yourself.
Why, it's a man!
A man made out of tin!
-What?
-Yes.
Look!
Oilcan.
Did you say something?
He said, "Oilcan."
"Oilcan" what?
Oilcan?
Here it is!
-Where do you want to be oiled first?
-My mouth.
-He said his mouth.
The other side.
My goodness, I can talk again!
Oil my arms, please,
oil my elbows.
Here.
Did that hurt?
No, it feels wonderful. I've
held that axe up for ages.
Goodness!
How did you ever get like this?
About a year ago, I was
chopping that tree...
...when suddenly
it began to rain.
And right in the middle
of a chop, I rusted solid.
I've been that way ever since.
Well, you're perfect now.
My neck. My neck.
Perfect?
Bang on my chest if
you think I'm perfect.
Go ahead, bang on it.
Beautiful! What an echo!
It's empty.
The tinsmith forgot
to give me a heart.
No heart?
No heart.
All hollow.
~ When a man's an empty kettle ~
~ He should be on his mettle ~
~ And yet I'm torn apart ~
~ Just because I'm presumin' ~
~ That I could
be kind of human ~
~ If I only had a heart ~
~ I'd be tender, I'd be gentle ~
~ And awful sentimental ~
~ Regarding love and art ~
~ I'd be friends
with the sparrows ~
~ And the boy who
shoots the arrows ~
~ If I only had a heart ~
~ Picture me, a balcony ~
~ Above a voice sings low ~
~ I hear a beat... ~
~ ...how sweet! ~
~ Just to register emotion,
jealousy, devotion ~
~ And really feel the part ~
~ I could stay
young and chipper ~
~ And I'd lock
it with a zipper ~
~ If I only had a heart ~
-Are you all right?
-I'm afraid I'm a little rusty yet.
Oh, dear!
That was wonderful!
You know...
We were wondering why you couldn't
come with us to the Emerald City...
...to ask the Wizard
of Oz for a heart?
Suppose the Wizard wouldn't
give me one when we got there?
But he will! He must!
We've come such a
long way already.
You call that long?
Why, you've just begun!
Helping the little lady along,
are you, my fine gentlemen?
Well, stay away from her...
...or I'll stuff
a mattress with you!
And you!
I'll use you for a beehive!
Here, Scarecrow!
Want to play ball?
Lookout! I'm
burning! I'm burning!
I'm not afraid of her. I'll see
you get safely to the Wizard now...
...whether I get a brain or not!
"Stuff a mattress with me," hah!
I'll see you reach the Wizard,
whether I get a heart or not.
"Beehive," bah! Let her try
and make a beehive out of me!
You're the best friends
anybody ever had.
And it's funny, but I feel as
if I've known you all the time.
But I couldn't have, could I?
I don't see how. You weren't around
when I was stuffed and sewn together...
...were you?
And I was standing over there
rusting for the longest time.
Still, I wish I could remember. But
I guess it doesn't matter anyway.
We know each other
now, don't we?
-That's right.
-We do.
-To Oz?
-To Oz!
~ We're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
~ We hear he is a whiz of a Wiz
If ever a Wiz there was ~
~ If ever, oh ever, a Wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because ~
~ Because, because, because,
because, because ~
~ Because of the
wonderful things he does ~
~ We're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
I don't like this forest!
It's dark and creepy!
Of course, I don't know, but I think
it'll get darker before it gets lighter.
Do you suppose we'll
meet any wild animals?
We might.
Animals that eat straw?
Some, but mostly lions
and tigers and bears.
Lions!
And tigers!
And bears!
Lions and tigers
and bears! Oh, my!
-Lions and tigers and bears!
-Oh, my!
Oh, look!
Put 'em up! Put 'em up!
Which one of you first?
I'll fight you both
together, if you want.
I'll fight you with one
paw tied behind my back!
I'll fight you
standing on one foot!
with my eyes closed.
Pulling an axe on me, eh?
Sneaking up on me, eh? Why...
-Here, here. Go away and let us alone.
-Scared, huh?
Afraid, huh?
How long can you stay
fresh in that can?
Come on, get up and fight,
you shivering junkyard!
Put your hands up, you
lopsided bag of hay!
Now, that's getting
personal, Lion.
Yes, get up and
teach him a lesson.
Well, what's wrong
with you teaching him?
Well, I hardly know him.
I'll get you anyway, Pee-Wee.
Shame on you!
What did you do that
for? I didn't bite him.
No, but you tried to.
It's bad enough picking on a straw man,
but when you pick on poor little dogs...
You didn't have to go
and hit me, did you?
Is my nose bleeding?
Well, of course not.
My goodness, what a
fuss you're making!
Naturally, when you go around picking
on things weaker than you are...
...you're nothing but
a great, big coward!
You're right, I am a coward!
I haven't any courage at all.
I even scare myself.
Look at the circles
under my eyes.
I haven't slept in weeks.
Why don't you try
counting sheep?
That doesn't do any
good. I'm afraid of them.
That's too bad.
Don't you think the
Wizard could help him, too?
I don't see why not.
Why don't you
come along with us?
We're on our way to see the
Wizard now. To get him a heart.
And him a brain.
I'm sure he could
give you some courage.
Wouldn't you feel degraded to be seen
in the company of a cowardly lion?
I would.
No, of course not!
Gee, that's awfully nice of you.
My life has been
simply unbearable.
Well, it's all right now.
The Wizard'll fix everything.
It's been in me so long...
...I just gotta
tell you how I feel.
Well, come on!
~ Yeah, it's sad, believe me, missy
When you're born to be a sissy ~
~ Without the vim and verve ~
~ But I could show my prowess ~
~ Be a lion not a mouse ~
~ If I only had the nerve ~
~ I'm afraid
there's no denyin' ~
~ I'm just a dandelion ~
~ A fate I don't deserve ~
~ I'd be brave as a blizzard ~
~ I'd be gentle as a lizard ~
~ I'd be clever as a gizzard ~
~ If the Wizard is a
wizard who will serve ~
~ Then I'm sure to get a brain ~
~ A heart ~
~ A home ~
~ The nerve. ~
~ We're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
~ We hear he is a whiz of a Wiz
If ever a Wiz there was ~
~ If ever, oh ever, a Wiz there was
The Wizard of Oz is one because ~
~ Because, because, because,
because, because ~
~ Because of the
wonderful things he does ~
~ We're off to see the Wizard
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz ~
So, you won't take warning, eh?
All the worse for you!
I'll take care of you
now instead of later!
When I gain those ruby slippers,
my power will be the greatest in Oz!
And now, my beauties...
...something with
poison in it, I think.
With poison in it...
...but attractive to the eye...
...and soothing to the smell!
Poppies!
Poppies will put them to sleep.
Sleep.
Now they'll sleep.
There's Emerald City!
We're almost there
at last! At last!
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Just like I knew it would be.
He really must be a wonderful
wizard to live in a city like that!
Come on. What are
we waiting for?
Nothing! Let's hurry!
Yes, let's run!
Come on, come on!
Hurry! Hurry!
Look!
Come on!
The city!
It's wonderful!
The Emerald City!
What's happening?
What is it?
I can't run anymore.
I'm so sleepy.
Give us your hands and
we'll pull you along.
No, please.
I have to rest
for just a minute.
Toto...
Where's Toto?
You can't rest now.
We're nearly there.
Don't cry, you'll
rust yourself again!
Come to think of it, forty
winks wouldn't be bad.
Don't you start it, too!
No! We ought to try
and carry Dorothy!
I don't think I could,
but we could try.
-Let's.
-Yes.
Now look at him!
This is terrible!
Here, Tin Man, help me.
This is terrible! I
can't budge her an inch!
This is a spell, this is!
It's the Wicked
Witch! What'll we do?
Help!
It's no use screaming at a time like
this. Nobody will hear you! Help!
Help!
It's snowing!
No, it isn't!
Yes, it is!
Maybe that'll help!
But it couldn't help!
It does help! Dorothy,
you're waking up!
Unusual weather we're
having, ain't it?
Look, he's rusted again!
-Give me the oilcan, quick!
-Here! Oil him.
-He is rusted.
-Here.
Here. Quick!
Curses! Curses! Somebody
always helps that girl!
But shoes or no shoes, I'm still
great enough to conquer her.
And woe to those
who try to stop me!
Come on, let's get out of here.
Look, Emerald City is closer
and prettier than ever!
You're out of the dark
To the Emerald City
as fast as lightning!
~ You're out of the woods
You're out of the dark ~
~ You're out of the night ~
~ Step into the sun,
step into the light ~
~ March up to the gate
And bid it open ~
~ Open ~
Who rang that bell?
We did!
Can't you read?
-Read what?
-The notice!
What notice?
It's on the door, as plain
as the nose on my face!
"Bell out of order,
please knock."
Well, that's more like it.
Now, state your business.
We want to see the Wizard.
The Wizard?
But nobody can see the great Oz!
Nobody's ever seen the great
Oz! Even I've never seen him!
Well, then, how do
you know there is one?
Because he's...
You're wasting my time!
Please! Please, sir!
I've got to see the Wizard.
The Good Witch of
the North sent me.
Prove it!
She's wearing the ruby
slippers she gave her!
So she is!
Well, bust my buttons!
Why didn't you say
that in the first place?
That's a horse of a
different color! Come on in!
Cabby! Cabby! Just
what you're looking for!
Take you any place
in the city, we does!
Would you take us
to see the Wizard?
The Wizard? The Wizard?
Yes, of course.
But first I'll take you to a little
place where you can tidy up a bit.
Thank you so much.
We've been gone such a
long time, and we feel so...
What kind of a horse is that? I've
never seen a horse like that before!
No, and never will again, I fancy.
There's only one of him, and he's it.
He's the Horse of a Different
Color you've heard tell about.
~ Ha, ha, ha ~
~ Ho, ho, ho ~
~ And a couple
of tra-la-las ~
~ That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ Bzz, bzz, bzz
Chirp, chirp, chirp ~
~ And a couple
of la-di-das ~
~ That's how the crickets crick all
day In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ We get up at 12:00
And start to work at 1:00 ~
~ Take an hour for lunch
And then at 2:00 we're done ~
~ Jolly good fun! ~
~ Ha, ha, ha ~
~ Ho, ho, ho ~
~ And a couple
of tra-la-las ~
~ That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ Ha, ha, ha ~
~ Ho, ho, ho ~
~ Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha ~
~ That's how we
laugh the day away ~
~ With a ho, ho,
ho Ha, ha, ha ~
~ In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ Pat, pat here, pat, pat there ~
~ And a couple of brand new straws ~
~ That's how we keep you young and
fair In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ Rub, rub here, rub, rub there
Whether you're tin or brass ~
~ That's how we keep you in repair
In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ We can make a dimple
smile Out of a frown ~
~ Can you even dye my eyes
To match my gown? ~
~ Jolly old town! ~
~ Clip, clip here, clip, clip there
We give the roughest claws ~
~ That certain air of savoir faire
In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ Ha, ha, ha ~
~ Ho, ho, ho ~
~ Ha, ha, ha, ha ~
~ That's how we laugh the day away
In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
~ That's how we
laugh the day away ~
~ Ha, ha, ha Ha, ha, ha ~
~ In the Merry Old Land of Oz ~
Who's her? Who's her?
It's the Witch! She's
followed us here!
"Surrender Dorothy."
Dorothy? Who's Dorothy?
The Wizard will explain it!
To the Wizard!
Whatever shall we do?
We'd better hurry if we're
going to see the Wizard!
Here! Here, here!
Everything is all right.
Stop that now.
It's all right!
Everything is all right!
The great and powerful Oz has
got matters well in hand. I hope.
And so you can all go home!
And there's nothing
to worry about!
Get out of here now,
go on! Go on home and...
Go home.
If you please, we want to
see the Wizard right away.
All four of us.
Orders are: Nobody
can see the great Oz!
Not nobody, not nohow!
But, please. It's
very important.
And I got a permanent
just for the occasion.
Not nobody, not nohow!
But she's Dorothy!
The Witch's Dorothy?
Well, that makes a difference.
Wait here. I'll
announce you at once!
Did you hear that? He'll
announce us at once!
-I've as good as got my brain!
-I can fairly hear my heart beating.
-I'll be home in time for supper!
-In another hour I'll be King of the Forest.
Long live the King!
~ If I were King of the Forest ~
~ Not Queen, not
Duke, not Prince ~
~ My regal robes of the forest ~
~ Would be satin, not
cotton, not chintz. ~
~ I'd command each thing,
be it fish or fowl ~
~ With a woof and a
woof, and a royal growl ~
~ As I click my heel
All the trees would kneel ~
~ And the mountains bow
And the bulls kowtow ~
~ And the sparrow
would take wing ~
~ If I... if I were King! ~
~ Each rabbit would
show respect to me ~
~ The chipmunks
genuflect to me ~
~ Though my tail would lash
I would show compash ~
~ For every underling ~
~ If I... if I were King ~
~ Just King! ~
~ Monarch of all I survey ~
~ Monarch... ~
~ ...of all I survey! ~
Your Majesty, if you were King,
you wouldn't be afraid of anything?
Not nobody, not nohow!
-Not even a rhinoceros?
-Imposserous!
-How about a hippopotamus?
-Why, I'd trash him from top to bottomus!
-Suppose you met an elephant?
-I'd wrap him up in cellophant!
-What if it were a brontosaurus?
-I'd show him who was King of the Forest!
-How?
Courage!
What makes a king
out of a slave?
Courage!
What makes the flag
on the mast to wave?
Courage!
What makes the elephant charge his tusk
in the misty mist, or the dusky dusk?
What makes the
muskrat guard his musk?
Courage!
What makes the sphinx
the Seventh Wonder?
Courage!
What makes the dawn
come up like thunder?
Courage!
What makes the Hottentot so hot?
What puts the "ape" in apricot?
What have they got
that I ain't got?
Courage!
You can say that again.
The Wizard says, "Go away! "
Go away?
Looks like we came a
long way for nothing.
And I was so happy!
I thought I was on my way home.
Don't cry, Dorothy.
We'll get you to the Wizard.
We certainly are.
Auntie Em was so good to me,
and I never appreciated it.
Running away and
hurting her feelings.
Professor Marvel
said she was sick.
She may be dying...
...and it's all my fault.
I'll never forgive myself!
Never, never, never!
Please, don't cry anymore.
I'll get you in to
the Wizard somehow.
Come on. I had an
Aunt Em myself once!
Wait a minute, fellows.
I was just thinking...
I really don't want to
see the Wizard this much.
I better wait for you outside.
-What's the matter?
-He's just scared again.
Don't you know the Wizard
will give you some courage?
I'd be too scared
to ask him for it.
Well then, we'll
ask him for you.
I'd sooner wait outside.
Why? Why?
Because I'm still scared!
-What happened?
-Somebody pulled my tail!
You did it yourself!
Come on.
Come forward!
Tell me when it's over!
Look at that! Look at that!
I want to go home!
I am Oz...
...the great and powerful!
Who are you?
If you please, I am Dorothy...
...the small and meek.
We've come to ask-
Silence!
Jiminy Crickets!
The great and powerful Oz
knows why you have come.
Step forward, Tin Man!
You dare to come to
me for a heart, do you?
You clinking, clanking, clattering
collection of caliginous junk!
Yes, sir.
Yes, Your Honor.
You see, a while back...
...we were walking down
the Yellow Brick Road, and-
Quiet!
And you, Scarecrow...
...have the effrontery
to ask for a brain...
...you billowing
bale of bovine fodder!
Yes, Your Honor. I
mean, Your Excellency.
I mean, Your Wizardry!
Enough!
And you, Lion!
Well?
You ought to be
ashamed of yourself...
...frightening him like that
when he came to you for help!
Silence, whippersnapper!
The beneficent Oz has every
intention of granting your requests!
What's that? What'd
he say? What'd he say?
But first, you must
prove yourselves worthy...
...by performing
a very small task.
Bring me the broomstick
of the Witch of the West.
But if we do that, we'll
have to kill her to get it!
Bring me her broomstick...
...and I'll grant your requests.
Now, go!
But what if she kills us first?
I said, "Go!"
"I'd turn back if I were you! "
Oh, look!
I believe there're
spooks around here.
That's ridiculous!
Spooks! That's silly.
Don't you believe in spooks?
No. Why, only-
Tin Man!
Are you all right?
I do believe in spooks.
I do, I do, I do, I do.
I do believe in spooks!
I do, I do, I do, I do, I do!
You'll believe in more than that
before I'm finished with you.
Take your army to the Haunted Forest
and bring me the girl and her dog.
Do as you like with the others,
but I want her alive and unharmed!
They'll give you no
trouble. I promise you that.
I've sent a little insect on ahead
to take the fight out of them.
Take special care of those ruby slippers.
I want those most of all. Now, fly!
Fly! Bring me that
girl and her slippers!
Fly! Fly! Fly!
Help!
Help! Help!
Go away now!
Toto! Toto! Help! Toto!
What happened to you?
They tore my legs off
and threw them over there!
Then they took my chest
out and threw it over there!
-Well, that's you all over.
-They sure knocked the stuffing out of you.
Don't stand there
talking! Put me together!
We've got to find Dorothy!
Now, let's see...
What a nice little dog.
And you, my dear, what
an unexpected pleasure.
It's so kind of you to
visit me in my loneliness.
What are you going to do with
my dog? Give him back to me!
All in good time, my little
pretty, all in good time.
Please, give me back my dog!
Certainly, certainly...
...when you give
me those slippers.
But the Good Witch of
the North told me not to.
Very well.
Throw that basket in
the river and drown him.
No! No. No. Here.
You can have your slippers
but give me back Toto!
That's a good little girl.
I knew you'd see reason!
I'm sorry. I didn't do it.
Can I still have my dog?
No! Fool that I am, I
should have remembered...
...those slippers
will never come off...
...as long as you're alive.
But that's not what's
worrying me. It's how to do it.
These things must
be done delicately...
...or you hurt the spell.
Run, Toto! Run!
Catch him, you fool!
Run, Toto!
Run, Toto! Run!
He got away! He got away!
Which is more than you
will! Drat you and your dog!
You've been more trouble
to me than you're worth...
...but it'll soon be over now!
Do you see that? That's how much
longer you've got to be alive!
And it isn't long, my
pretty. It isn't long!
I can't wait forever
to get those shoes!
I'm frightened.
I'm frightened, Auntie
Em, I'm frightened!
Dorothy?
Dorothy, where are you?
It's me, it's Auntie Em.
We're trying to find
you! Where are you?
I'm here in Oz, Auntie Em!
I'm locked up in
the Witch's castle...
...and I'm trying to get
home to you, Auntie Em!
Auntie Em, don't go
away! I'm frightened!
Come back! Come back!
"Auntie Em. Auntie
Em, come back!"
I'll give you
Auntie Em, my pretty!
Look! There's Toto!
Where'd he come from?
Why, don't you see? He's
come to take us to Dorothy!
Come on, fellows!
I hope my strength holds out.
I hope your tail holds out.
What's that?
That's the castle
of the Wicked Witch!
Dorothy's in that awful place?
I hate to think of her in
there. We've got to get her out!
Don't cry now. We haven't
got the oilcan with us...
...and you've been
squeaking enough.
Who's them?
I've got a plan
how to get in there.
Fine. He's got a plan.
-And you're going to lead us.
-Yeah.
-Me?
-Yes, you.
-I gotta get her out of there?
-That's right.
All right, I'll go in
there for Dorothy...
...Wicked Witch or
no Wicked Witch...
...guards or no guards,
I'll tear 'em apart.
I may not come out alive
but I'm going in there.
There's only one thing
I want you fellows to do.
What's that?
Talk me out of it.
-No, you don't!
-Oh, no!
Now, wait a minute.
I've got another idea.
Do you think it'll be
polite, dropping in like this?
Come on.
Where do we go now?
Yeah.
There!
Wait! We'd better make sure.
Dorothy, are you in there?
It's us!
Yes, it's me!
She's locked me in!
It's her. We gotta get
her out! Open the door!
Hurry! Please, hurry!
The hourglass is almost empty!
Stand back!
Toto! Toto!
-Did they hurt you?
-I knew you'd come!
I knew you would!
Hurry, we've got
no time to lose!
Going so soon?
I wouldn't hear of it.
Why, my little
party's just beginning.
Trapped! Trapped
like mice, rats!
That's right. Don't
hurt them right away.
We'll let them think
about it a little first.
Seize them! Stop
them, you fools!
Stop them! Seize
them! Seize them!
There they go!
Now we've got them!
Half you go this way,
half you go that way!
Hurry! Hurry!
Where do we go now?
This way, come on!
Back! Back!
Well!
Ring around the rosie!
A pocket full of spears!
Thought you'd be
pretty foxy, didn't you?
The last to go will see the
first three go before her!
And her mangy little dog, too!
How about a little
fire, Scarecrow?
No! No! No!
Help! I'm burning! I'm burning!
Don't throw that water!
You cursed brat!
Look what you've done!
I'm melting! Melting!
What a world! What a world!
Who would have thought a good little girl
could destroy my beautiful wickedness?
Look out! Look out!
I'm going.
She's dead. You've killed her.
I didn't mean to kill
her, really I didn't.
It's just that he was on fire!
Hail to Dorothy! The
Wicked Witch is dead!
Hail! Hail to Dorothy!
The Wicked Witch is dead!
The broom!
May we have it?
Please. And take it with you.
Thank you so much!
Now we can go back to the Wizard and
tell him the Wicked Witch is dead!
The Wicked Witch is dead!
Can I believe my eyes?
Why have you come back?
Please, sir. We've
done what you told us.
We've brought you the broomstick
of the Wicked Witch of the West.
We melted her.
You liquidated her, eh?
Very resourceful!
Yes, sir. So we'd like you to keep
your promise to us, if you please, sir.
Not so fast! Not so fast!
I'll have to give the
matter a little thought!
Go away, and come back tomorrow!
Tomorrow?
But I want to go home now!
You've had plenty
of time already!
Yeah!
Do not arouse the wrath of
the great and powerful Oz!
I said, "Come back tomorrow!"
If you were really great and
powerful, you'd keep your promises!
Do you presume to
criticize the great Oz?
You ungrateful creatures!
Think yourselves lucky that I'm
giving you audience tomorrow...
...instead of 20 years from now!
The great Oz has spoken!
Pay no attention to that
man behind the curtain.
The great Oz has spoken!
Who are you?
I am the great and powerful...
...Wizard of Oz.
You are?
I don't believe you!
No, I'm afraid it's true.
There's no other wizard except me.
You humbug!
Yeah!
Yes, that's exactly
so. I'm a humbug.
You're a very bad man!
No, my dear. I'm
a very good man.
I'm just a very bad wizard.
What about the heart
that you promised Tin Man?
And the courage that you
promised Cowardly Lion?
And Scarecrow's brain?
Why, anybody can have a brain.
That's a very mediocre commodity.
Every pusillanimous creature
that crawls on the earth...
...or slinks through
slimy seas has a brain!
Back where I come from
we have universities...
...seats of great learning, where
men go to become great thinkers.
When they come out, they
think deep thoughts...
...with no more
brains than you have.
But they have one thing
you haven't got: A diploma!
Therefore, by virtue of the
authority vested in me...
...by the Universitatus
Committeeatum E Pluribus Unum...
...I hereby confer upon you...
...the honorary degree of Th.D.
"Th.D."?
Yeah, that's "Doctor
of Thinkology."
"The sum of the square roots of any
two sides of an isosceles triangle...
"...is equal to the square
root of the remaining side."
Joy! Rapture!
I've got a brain!
How can I ever thank you enough?
Well, you can't. As for you, my fine friend,
you are a victim of disorganized thinking.
You're under the
unfortunate delusion...
...that simply because you run away
from danger you have no courage.
You are confusing
courage with wisdom.
Back where I come from we
have men who are called heroes.
Once a year they take their
fortitude out of mothballs...
...and parade it down the
main street of the city.
And they have no more
courage than you have.
But they have one thing
that you haven't got:
A medal!
Therefore, for
meritorious conduct...
...extraordinary valor, conspicuous
bravery against wicked witches...
...I award you the Triple Cross.
You are now a member of
the Legion of Courage!
Shucks, folks, I'm speechless!
As for you, my galvanized
friend, you want a heart!
You don't know how lucky
you are not to have one.
Hearts will never be practical
until they can be made unbreakable.
But I still want one.
Back where I come from there are men
who do nothing all day but good deeds.
They are called...
...good-deed-doers and their
hearts are no bigger than yours.
But they have one thing you
haven't got: A testimonial!
Therefore, in consideration
of your kindness...
...I take pleasure at this
time in presenting you...
...with a small token of
our esteem and affection.
And remember, my
sentimental friend...
...that a heart is not
judged by how much you love...
...but by how much you
are loved by others.
It ticks! Listen!
Look, it ticks!
Read what my medal says.
"Courage"!
Ain't it the truth?
They're all wonderful.
-What about Dorothy?
-Yes, how about Dorothy?
-Dorothy next!
-Yes, Dorothy.
I don't think there's anything
in that black bag for me.
You force me into a
cataclysmic decision.
The only way to get Dorothy back to
Kansas is for me to take her there myself!
Will you? Could you?
Are you a clever enough
wizard to manage it?
Child, you cut me to the quick!
I'm an old Kansas man myself...
...born and bred in the heart
of the western wilderness...
...premier balloonist
par excellence...
...for the Miracle Wonderland
Carnival Company. Until one day...
...while performing spectacular
feats of stratospheric skill...
...never before attempted by civilized
man, an unfortunate phenomenon occurred.
The balloon failed
to return to the fair.
It did?
Weren't you frightened?
Frightened? You are talking to a man
who has laughed in the face of death...
...sneered at doom and
chuckled at catastrophe.
I was petrified.
Then suddenly the wind changed
and the balloon floated down...
...into the heart of this noble city
where I was instantly acclaimed Oz...
...the First Wizard Deluxe!
Times being what they
were, I accepted the job...
...retaining my balloon against
the advent of a quick getaway.
And in that balloon, my dear
Dorothy, you and I will return...
...to the land of
"e pluribus unum"!
This is positively the finest
exhibition ever to be shown.
Yes, well, be that as it may...
...I, your Wizard
per ardua et alta...
...am about to embark upon a hazardous
and technically unexplainable journey...
...into the outer stratosphere!
To confer, converse and otherwise
hobnob with my brother wizards.
And I hereby decree
that until what time...
...if any, that I
return, the Scarecrow...
...by virtue of his highly superior
brains, shall rule in my stead...
...assisted by the Tin Man, by
virtue of his magnificent heart...
...and the Lion, by
virtue of his courage!
Obey them as you would me.
Thank you.
Toto!
Come back! Toto!
Don't go without me!
I'll be right back!
Stop that dog!
This is highly irregular procedure!
This is absolutely unprecedented!
Ruined my exit!
Come back! Come back!
Don't go without me!
Please, come back!
I can't come back! I
don't know how it works!
Goodbye, folks!
Goodbye!
Now I'll never get home!
Stay with us then, Dorothy.
We all love you.
We don't want you to go.
That's very kind of you...
...but this could
never be like Kansas.
Auntie Em must have stopped
wondering what happened to me by now.
Scarecrow, what
am I going to do?
Look!
Here's someone who can help you!
-Will you help me? Can you help me?
-You don't need to be helped any longer.
You've always had the
power to go back to Kansas.
I have?
Why didn't you tell her before?
Because she wouldn't have believed
me. She had to learn it for herself.
What have you learned, Dorothy?
I think that it wasn't enough just to
want to see Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
And it's that if I ever go looking
for my heart's desire again...
...I won't look any further
than my own backyard...
...because if it isn't there...
...I never really
lost it to begin with.
Is that right?
That's all it is!
But that's so easy! I should
have thought of it for you.
-I should have felt it in my heart.
-No. She had to find it out for herself.
Now those magic slippers will
take you home in two seconds!
-Toto, too?
-Toto, too.
-Now?
-Whenever you wish.
Oh, dear, that's too
wonderful to be true!
It's going to be so
hard to say goodbye.
I love you all, too.
Goodbye, Tin Man.
Don't cry.
You'll rust so dreadfully.
Here. Here's your oilcan.
Goodbye.
Now I know I've got a
heart 'cause it's breaking.
Goodbye, Lion.
You know, I know
it isn't right...
...but I'm gonna miss the way
you used to holler for help...
...before you
found your courage.
I would never have found it
if it hadn't been for you.
I think I'll miss
you most of all.
Are you ready now?
Yes.
Say goodbye, Toto.
Yes, I'm ready now.
Then close your eyes and tap
your heels together three times.
And think to yourself:
"There's no place like home.
There's no place like home."
There's no place like home.
Wake up, honey.
There's no place...
Dorothy! Dorothy, dear.
It's Aunt Em, darling.
Auntie Em, it's you!
Hello, there! Anybody home?
I just dropped by because I heard the
little girl got caught in the big...
Well, she seems all right now!
She got quite a bump on the head. We
thought for a minute she'd leave us.
But I did leave you, Uncle
Henry. That's just the trouble.
And I tried to get
back for days and days.
There, there, lie quiet now.
You just had a bad dream.
Sure.
Remember me, your old pal, Hunk?
And me, Hickory?
You couldn't forget
my face, could you?
No. But it wasn't a
dream. It was a place.
And you, and you, and
you, and you were there.
But you couldn't
have been, could you?
We dream lots of
silly things when we-
No, Aunt Em, this was a
real, truly live place.
And I remember that some
of it wasn't very nice...
...but most of it was
beautiful. But just the same...
...all I kept saying to everybody
was, "I want to go home! "
And they sent me home.
Doesn't anybody believe me?
Of course we
believe you, Dorothy.
But anyway, Toto, we're home!
Home!
And this is my room,
and you're all here!
And I'm not going to leave here ever,
ever again, because I love you all!
Auntie Em, there's
no place like home!