[Horn honks]
[Traffic noise]
[Rattles door]
[Bird chirping]
[Bell ringing]
[Ringing getting louder]
[Door creaks]
[Opens drawer]
[Woman sighs]
[Door creaks]
[Clapping twice]
[Claps once]
[Chairs scraping on floor]
[Silverware clinking]
[Spits]
[Ball bouncing]
[Unzips bag]
[zips has]
[Unzips coat]
[Zips coat]
[Thumping against door]
[Rattling window]
[Running footsteps]
[Rustling]
[Unzips bag]
[Thud]
[Door closes]
[Door slams]
[Rattling]
[Vehicle engine running]
[Zip]
[Jingling]
[Rattling]
[Engine slows]
[Slams door]
[Engine revving]
[Leaves crunching]
[Punches landing]
[Click]
[Bed springs squeaking]
[Zip]
[Door slams]
[Keys jingling]
[Latch clicks]
[Footsteps echoing]
[Carts rattling]
[Car alarm]
[Throwing punches]
[Kicking]
[Metal creaking]
[Running footsteps]
[Leaves rustling]
[Ripping foil]
[POP]
[Leaves rustling]
[Snap]
[Bottle clinks]
[Leaves rustling]
[Vomiting]
[Train wheels clacking]
[Throwing punches]
[squeak]
[Slam]
[Rustling]
[Slap]
[Clattering]
[Door closes]
[Doors closing]
[Van moving away]
[Boy thumping hand on truck]
[Knocking]
[Truck beeping]
[Pounding]
[Snow crunching]
[Lighters clicking]
[Latch clicks]
[Door slams]
[Engine turns over]
[Shuts off engine]
[Latch clicks]
[Door closes]
[Thumping on truck]
[Thumping]
[Lighter clicks]
[Van approaches]
[Door closes]
[Doors closing]
[Door rattles]
[Door slams]
[Unzips coat]
[Breathing hard]
[Creak]
[Glasses clink]
[Chair scrapes on floor]
[POP]
[Plastic crackling]
[Clink]
[Footsteps approaching]
[Clinking]
[Bag rattling]
[Thumping]
[Girl pounding]
[Doors slamming]
[Click]
[Latch rattles]
[Slapping]
[Bed springs squeaking]
[Glass clinks]
[Zip]
[Door closes]
[Creak]
[Van approaching]
[Doors closing]
[Door closes]
[Engine starts]
[Unzips backpack]
[Lighter clicks]
[Urinating]
[Flushes toilet]
[Water running]
[Train wheels clacking]
[Unzips purse]
[Breathing hard]
[Package hits floor]
[Running footsteps approaching]
[Door opens]
[Unzips boots]
[Ringing doorbell
insistently]
[Latch clicks]
[Locks cupboard]
[Strikes match]
[Gas hissing]
[Latch clicks]
[Turns off stove]
[Metal rattling]
[Water running]
[Rips]
[Click]
[Instruments rattling]
[Breathing quickly]
[Gasping]
[Crying]
[Hyperventilating]
[Cap falls on table]
[Sobbing]
[Sobbing loudly]
[People talking indistinctly]
[Unzips folder]
[Zips folder]
[Doors closing]
[Engine hesitates,
then starts]
[Sanding]
[Sanding stops]
[Chalk scraping]
[Loud rattling
and filing]
[Hits wood against table]
[Rattling, filing,
and sanding stop]
and sanding resume]
[Water running]
[Brakes squeal]
[Door closes]
[Snow crunching]
[Unzips coat]
[Tool clatters to ground]
[Click]
[Rustling papers]
[Thud]
[Clattering]
[Hangers rattling]
[Drawer opens,
clattering]
[Click]
[Metal rattling]
[Glass breaking]
[Rattling]
[Drops metal tool]
[Slam]
[Water running]
[Shuts off water]
[Breathing hard]
[Pants hit floor]
[Bed springs squeaking]
[Girl crying]
[Boy breathing hard]
[Paper rustling]
[Glass clinks,
water running]
[Glass breaks]
[Snow crunching]
[Keys jingling]
[Latch clicks]
[Smashing]
[Papers clatter to floor]
[Creak]
[Smashing]
[Clattering]
[Sniffling]
[Latch clicks]
[Retreating footsteps]
[Door slams]