THE METHOD
In an hour's time,
the IMF-World Bank summit
will begin in Madrid.
Tens of thousands of young people
have arrived here,
gathered by over 800
anti-globalization organizations.
They will be demonstrating
against some of the men
who decide this planet's future.
There might be trouble.
What if I don't go to school?
Then there will be trouble!
Now, finish that!
They have tried to break
the police barricade...
Have you seen what's happening?
Shouldn't I take the car?
- Oh, Sandra!
- For God's sake!
- Who did that?
- He did.
No, she did.
- He did it.
- No, it was her.
As in Seattle,
Prague and Geneva,
it is feared there may be
acts of violence
prompted by the more radical
anti-capitalist groups
who accuse the IMF
and the World Bank
of being used by corporations
in order to exploit child labor,
sell manipulated food and
destroy the planet's resources.
Meanwhile, the IMF authorities...
are forced to listen to protests
by the demonstrators.
But while the latter object
to neo-liberal policies
the former consider that free
trade is vital for the 3rd World
and only a free, globalized
market can help weaker economies...
No, not today, Roque.
To achieve the impulse they need
in order to grow.
We'll shortly hear
the outcome of this summit.
IMF-WB SUMMIT BEGINS TODAY
IN A BESIEGED MADRID
Police controls,
streets blocked to traffic
and crowd control barriers
are making the city
a hell for its inhabitants.
Access roads are jammed
and tailbacks can be measured
in kilometers.
They want to demonstrate
but they won't respect
our right to work.
They demonstrate against
multinational corporations
and run from our police
in shoes made by
those same corporations.
I'm going right here,
to the Dekia Tower.
Thanks.
AGAINST THE IMF-WB
ANOTHER WORLD IS POSSIBLE
Good morning.
- The Personnel Department?
- Your I.D., please.
- Floor 35.
- Thank you.
- Good morning.
I'm here for the selection test.
Very well.
Here you are.
Your letter.
Name?
It's right there.
Carlos de Aristegui Santos.
You have to fill out this form.
You can do it inside.
Excuse me.
I've filled out this form
already, or one very like it.
Yes.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Hello.
Hello, there.
Hello.
That seat is taken.
Excuse me, taken by whom?
By me.
Nieves.
Carlos.
How are things?
How are you?
Fine.
- And you?
- Very well.
It's been ages.
Two years, nearly three.
Did you apply too?
Yes, what a coincidence.
- Shall we fill out the form?
- Yes, of course.
We'll talk later.
Excuse me.
Would you mind
sitting over there?
- Of course not.
- Thank you.
Having your back to the door
brings bad energy.
Is this your first time here?
I've had two interviews.
Two?
I've had three.
Well, the first was really
a psycho-technical test.
Yes, I had that too.
Have you all come before too?
Anyone know what
this Gronolm method is?
Grönholm, right?
Grönholm.
Yes.
Well, no, but I guess it's
the selection method they use.
I know that.
It even says so here.
"Grönholm
personnel selection method".
Do you know what it is?
I guess it's the method of
bringing the candidates together
and making us interact
to see who stands out.
Group dynamics, it's called.
It's like those clauses
used by lawyers in multinational
companies to cover their backs.
Yes, to avoid lawsuits.
- Good morning.
- Hello.
It's logical, isn't it?
Today, you can be sued
for almost anything.
But why do they need
to be so careful with us?
I've filled this out already.
Excuse me, I've already filled
out a form like this.
In fact, I've filled out two,
one for each interview I've had.
And my résumé gives
almost the same details.
I don't see why
I should do it again.
Everyone's doing it.
Yes. And?
And?
I don't think I'm the only one
here who thinks this is...
I don't know.
Slightly humiliating.
- You know?
- No one's forcing you to do it.
- What?
- It's not obligatory.
Well...
Only fill it out
if you want to be assessed.
Is there a reason for this?
Maybe to try our patience?
Because if that's so,
I'll fill it out
for a third time.
I don't know why
it bothers you so much.
I don't know, but I think that
with such an inflexible attitude
it's...
I'm saying it for your own good,
it's not my problem.
It's incredible.
I have to keep filling out forms
and yet I'm the inflexible...
All right, all right.
You've shown that
you don't lower yourself.
But let the rest of us do it
if we want to!
Thank you.
Thanks, love.
You're welcome.
What's your name?
Montse.
Excuse me.
I don't know if you noticed,
but the form wasn't
exactly like the others.
For example, it included
the Grönholm clause.
What now, guys?
- What do we have to do?
- Wait, I guess.
Will we be interviewed together?
I was told so.
A joint interview
with the candidates.
It's what I told you.
Group dynamics.
The candidates are given
a series of theoretical cases,
or problems that might
come up in the job,
and they have to discuss
the best solution.
So we have to wait
for someone from the firm.
A psychologist, probably.
Is it necessary?
Yes, because usually
the dynamic of these tests is...
- How come you're here?
- I live in Madrid now.
So I see.
Since when?
Almost 18 months now.
And how come...
How come you've never called me
in all this time?
Well,
no one has said anything
but if anyone from the firm comes
they've got nowhere to sit.
Maybe no one will come.
- What?
- Maybe not.
Maybe no one will come.
In the U.S. They have a kind
of test for selecting personnel.
They summon the candidates
and lock them in a room.
Lock them in?
Yes, to see how they react,
how they inter-relate,
- if anyone is conflictive...
- Who talks more, who talks less.
How are they assessed if no one
from the company is there?
I bet there are microphones
and they're listening.
- And cameras.
- Cameras?
- Where?
- I don't know, hidden.
In the lampshades, anywhere.
Is that legal?
- As if that were a problem.
- It could be.
Maybe that's why we had to sign
the Grönholm clause.
If it's illegal to use cameras,
signing clauses
won't make it legal.
I'm going to ask the secretary
what we're waiting for.
What is this? A joke?
Are we locked in?
What if I need
to use the bathroom?
Are they turning on?
Yes, so it seems.
Let's see what the machines
have to say.
Nothing, it seems.
- I've got a note.
- What does it say?
- Haven't you got one?
- No.
Shall I read it?
"Good morning, everyone.
Dekia congratulates you
on getting this far.
You have passed the previous
interviews and tests,
amply demonstrating
your experience and capacity
to occupy the post.
However, today it will be decided
who is the most suitable.
If at any moment
you consider that any
of the tests are unacceptable,
you can abandon the process.
No one is obliged to do anything
but while you remain here
you must accept
the conditions set out
in the Grönholm method."
This Grönholm method
is starting to worry me.
Maybe we should ask what it is
before we carry on.
The fact is,
if we're going to be shut
in all day
someone could at least
show his face.
It's another note.
"The first test..."
No, please.
"The first test is the following.
We've told you that you are
the final candidates
but not the seven
final candidates.
One of you is a member of our
personnel selection department.
Your first task is to find out
which of you is not
a real candidate."
I thought it was only
an interview.
It's good.
What's good?
The test. It's really good.
When we came in, we thought we
were all equals, all candidates
but we're not.
I've read about this.
They pretend to be candidates
so they can observe us up close,
listen to what we say.
Well, let's do it.
Let's find the mole.
I think that if there is a mole,
it's you.
I'm sorry?
Carlos.
Carlos. I'm Ana.
Why do you think it's me, Ana?
Well, you seem to be
very enthusiastic,
trying to direct the test
from the start.
That's not bad.
Well, I think it could be you.
You do?
Why?
By accusing me
you draw attention from yourself.
- For example.
- That's not bad.
I think it could be
either of you.
I suggest that
we all introduce ourselves
and tell others
where we currently work.
A mole won't tell the truth.
Right, that's the fun of it.
So what do you think?
Shall I start?
All right.
I'm Julio Quintana,
I'm a lawyer and an economist.
My last job was manager
of Rocher's commercial subsidiary
in Spain.
Rocher?
Yes, Rocher,
it's a French corporation.
It deals with pesticides.
Before that, I set up
the subsidiary in Portugal,
now number one in the sector.
Aren't you a bit over-qualified
for this post?
You think so?
Shall I carry on?
I'm Nieves Martin, I run
the Special Products Department
for a publishing company.
Special Products?
Collections for newspapers
and magazines,
packs, hybrids, and events too.
Anything that helps to launch
a book or collection.
It seems interesting.
Why are you leaving it?
You are leaving it, aren't you?
I want to try new things
before it's too late for me.
Well,
I'll go next, if you want.
I'm Carlos de Arístegui,
I'm an economist.
One question.
Is "de" part of your surname
or do you add it spontaneously?
It's part of it.
I studied economics at Cambridge
and mastered in Communications
at the University of Columbia.
Where do you work?
Right now, in the Communications
and Marketing Department
of an English cell phone company
soon to be set up in Spain.
What company?
Whirkel.
Can you two corroborate
all of that?
You know each other, don't you?
- Yes.
- No.
Well,
we haven't seen each other
for nearly three years.
You were working in Barcelona
when we met, right?
Yes.
And you weren't
in your present jobs then?
No.
Can each confirm that the other
wasn't a psychologist then?
Yes, of course.
We only knew each other
for a few days
but he wasn't a psychologist.
That's no use.
They could both be lying.
If one of them is the mole,
he'll have lied.
The other won't say anything,
he has an advantage.
We're saying what our jobs are.
You can believe it or not.
That doesn't matter.
Let's continue
and we'll be in equal conditions.
I'm Ricardo Arcés
and I won't say where I work.
Why's that?
I don't want my company
to hear about this.
- We're not going to tell them.
- Everything gets out eventually.
There seems to be
a certain lack of collaboration
in the group.
Excuse me, what group?
We're competing for the same job.
Well, it's my turn.
I'm Ana Páez,
and I'm head of production
at Minena studios.
Basically, we record music
and my idea of opening a studio in
Ibiza has had fantastic results.
We've had lots of people there,
from Mike Oldfield
to Bustamante.
It's been less
for the sound quality
and more for a few days
on the beach.
Apart from that,
the idea was very,
very profitable for the company.
I'm Fernando de Monagas.
I do add the "de" spontaneously.
And I too refuse
to say where I work.
Not out of caution,
like our colleague Ricardo,
but because I don't intend
to make things easier for you.
As clear as that.
If someone is observing us,
the first thing they'll assess
is our capacity to get results.
And here the result
is to discover the mole.
Is that clear?
Crystal clear.
I don't think they'll assess
only the capacity
to impose ourselves on others.
What will they assess?
Our capacity to work as a team,
for example.
Yes, we're supposed
to discover the mole,
not compete with each other.
Sure,
and they'll name all of us
Head of Department, a team.
I'm betting on the gentleman
on my left.
I'm betting that
he's the mole, I mean.
And I'm doing it
before he introduces himself.
- May I ask why?
- Of course, obviously.
You mentioned the hidden cameras,
the American tests.
It was you who said that maybe
no one would come from the firm.
And, quite honestly,
it seems that for you
this Big Brother-style lock-in
- is wonderful.
- That's got nothing to do with it.
I just want to have
a positive attitude.
You've got it, believe me.
May I ask how you know so much
about these tests?
Yes, of course.
The fact is,
a few years ago,
I worked in Sonivision,
an electronic components factory.
Yes, Sonivision. It's
on the Barcelona road, km. 65,
area 4, lot 16.
By the way, I'm Enrique León,
and I'm now in a similar company,
called Sonco.
Did you work in human resources,
personnel selection?
No, no. I was financial director.
But it was a small company,
practically family-run,
and someone had to do it.
How do you know so much
about these American methods?
I got into the habit
of keeping myself informed
about selection techniques,
group dynamics...
- How do you do that?
- Magazines, Internet...
That's where you learned about
selection, group dynamics,
hidden cameras and so on.
Yes, it is.
I'm sorry, but I don't
believe you either.
I vote for you too.
- I don't think this is fair.
- Don't take it personally.
Sorry, it all points to you.
What do you say?
I think they're playing with us.
Who?
They told us there was
a false candidate,
but I think we're all real
candidates and there's no imposter.
I still think it's Enrique.
As you wish.
We have
five votes for Enrique,
one abstention.
What about you, Enrique?
Are you going to abstain
or vote for someone?
And what do you want to do now?
Search me, or maybe lynch me?
No, we'll just put your name
in this box.
Agreed?
Fantastic.
There's another note here.
Do you have it?
- Shall I read it?
- Yes.
Now you'll have to apologize.
"To face the next test, you must
first choose a group leader.
The person cannot be chosen
by majority vote.
He or she must be chosen
by consensus."
- They don't say who the mole is?
- No, that's all.
They're not going to tell us?
Because one of us here
is not one of us.
There is no mole.
So one of us is going to be
the team leader.
How do we choose?
We don't know each other, it'll
have to be on pure intuition.
Well, on pure intuition,
I propose Enrique as leader.
I refuse to pick the mole.
You're really set on that!
Why? If he were the mole
he'd be the perfect choice.
- No one would have an advantage.
- What I really mean
is that I'm not going
to elect anyone except myself.
- So, if we need a consensus...
- All right.
If you won't collaborate, fine,
but please let us name a leader
and then the company can decide.
That's very good, Julio.
And, in fact,
I'm going to propose you.
Not because he voted for me,
but because I really see him
as a good leader.
I propose that we vote.
- Written, so that it's secret.
- Yes, it's just a first step
to see what support Julio has,
or Enrique.
They're the only proposals.
And Fernando.
All right.
Let's see.
Julio.
Fernando.
Abstention.
Enrique.
And Carlos.
We've seen through a few of us.
Couldn't Julio have voted for me?
Three votes for Julio,
one abstention,
one each for Carlos, Enrique
and Fernando.
- I support Julio too.
- Four votes for Julio.
Yes, me too, of course.
Abstaining was very noble, Julio.
Yes.
No.
- That wasn't me.
- No?
Five votes for Julio.
What do you want from me?
Very well.
Given the circumstances,
I wish to announce that I have
nobly ceded my vote to Julio.
No, don't thank me.
There's just one vote to clarify.
Does anyone not support Julio?
Well, it's clarified.
Very well.
Thank you for your trust,
everyone.
DAVID VERSUS GOLIAT
Julio, isn't that you?
Wasn't that a few years ago?
Yes, May 2001.
A chemical plant, right?
Yes, a pesticide factory.
You reported your company
for causing pollution.
I did what had to be done
to avoid a disaster.
- When was it?
- May 2001, it says here.
You were on all
the news programs.
We've got a national hero
among us.
Thank you, really.
I would have preferred
it hadn't gone that far.
You're making it hard
for the rest of us.
What happened
after you reported them?
We managed to stop the pollution.
A disaster was avoided.
- Weren't there 200 lay-offs?
- 200, yes.
200.
We had to choose
the lesser of two evils.
I tried to sort it out
from inside the company.
I tried to convince the Board.
It meant making some investments
and that meant reducing profits
for a few years.
I have a question.
Did you include this
in your résumé
or did the company discover it?
I didn't include it.
I don't hide it either,
but the fact is
I don't think it's part
of my résumé.
So, they've done their homework.
There's a note.
You don't have it?
"Now decide what you would do
with Julio Quintana's application
if you were part of this
company's Personnel Department.
Your decision will determine
whether or not he remains
in the selection process."
Well,
I think we're starting to find
out what the Grönholm method is.
Will they have something
like that for each of us?
I think, as a starting point,
that today, ecology and respect
for the environment
is a factor no decent company
can disregard...
If I may, Enrique.
I think we have to tackle
the problem head on.
We have to decide
if we trust Julio, right?
Sorry about this.
But you did betray
the company you were working for.
I didn't betray anyone.
I warned them, I told you.
I tried to talk to the Board.
I'm not denying
you did all you could,
- but you did betray the company.
- I didn't betray it.
They left me no other choice
if I didn't want to be part of
a disaster in the River Duero.
I don't want to pass judgment
on what you did.
- Well, you are.
- No, I'm not.
You are, from the moment
you called it betrayal.
We have to decide
as if we were them,
not judge Julio.
I think the secret vote
worked very well before.
I won't accept you calling
what I did a betrayal.
I tried everything I could,
they left me with no choice.
It's important you didn't betray
the company for your own benefit
but for the common good.
The river
would never have recovered.
Anyway, sooner or later,
the plant would have closed
and the company's image
would have been worse.
Just look at what
the article says about him.
I'm sorry to insist,
but we're not discussing
the morality of Julio's decision.
We're discussing whether
we'd give him the job
if we had the responsibility
for doing so.
Really, the question is
where should decisions be taken.
- Looking at it that way...
- No, not even then.
What we have to discuss
is the consequences
of our decisions.
If the company asked you,
would you do something illegal?
I would pick Julio,
and I'll tell you why.
In the end what matters
for a company
are the results of our decisions.
In fact, the best companies
are those which absorb
the best ideas,
wherever they come from.
In the case
of the chemical plant,
or whatever Julio's company was,
the problem laid within
the Board of Management.
It was their responsibility,
quite clearly,
for having accepted
a suicidal risk
in emptying waste into the river
and for not foreseeing
consequences
such as Julio's denunciation.
Exactly.
In fact, a rival company
didn't waste time
in hiring you, right?
All right, I don't have the data
to judge this case.
Maybe the rivals hired him
to improve their own image,
or he negotiated his departure
before reporting the damage.
I'm sorry, it's nothing personal.
It doesn't matter what we do?
Of course it matters.
I don't agree with leaving
moral judgments aside.
It's inevitable
to make them,
and it's good to make them.
I think that what Julio did
was right,
and the company was wrong.
What's more,
I'd have done the same
if I'd had no other choice.
None of us doubts that your aim,
your intention, was correct.
But our duty now
is to decide if
in these circumstances, today,
we'd give you the job.
And there is one detail
that makes me think I wouldn't.
Not that you put other interests
before those of your company
but that you were mistaken
in how you did it.
If you were so obviously right,
and the Board was so wrong on
both a moral and business level,
how could you not make them
see it?
It probably was
a company error too.
Sure. But it's Julio
that we're judging here.
My conclusion, therefore,
is that you were unable
to establish a correct,
efficient communication
with the Board.
That's why I wouldn't
give you the job.
- Shall we vote?
- Yes.
I have to say that,
after the debate,
which I thought
was very interesting,
I wouldn't accept Julio's
application to join this company.
Sorry.
If I were the company
I might not want to employ Julio,
but I'm not sure I want to vote.
That's very clever of you.
Voting means accepting
responsibility for expelling Julio.
That's what they call it,
expulsion.
The company has given us
that responsibility
without consulting us,
and free of charge.
And you've accepted it
without a word
and assumed that it's what
the company expects of you.
But
if it isn't so?
Are you sure it's what
the company wants from you?
So we've got three, three
and one abstention.
Technically, it's a draw
The company can decide, right?
Ana?
I did what I could.
Julio...
Your jacket.
Fucking Grönholm method.
What's up?
Drop the screen bullshit.
Come and tell me to my face.
It must have been a mistake.
I'm sorry,
but I've been told
the selection test is over.
The team of psychologists
has decided
to reject your applications
to join this company.
I'm joking!
We have a little problem
with the computer connections.
I'll fix right away.
- Were you joking with Julio too?
- No, that wasn't an error.
Excuse me.
- Am I in your way?
- No, go right ahead.
Let's see.
They should turn on now.
That's it.
Well?
How about a break
to go to the bathroom?
Are there cameras here too?
Can you draw conclusions
from how someone pisses?
Nuts, isn't it?
- What?
- Everything.
It's very well thought out,
you must admit.
And you learn a lot.
The debate, for example.
At first, I thought one thing
and that girl, Nieves,
made me change my mind.
The system is very good.
Yes, very good.
What do you think?
Maybe you're the infiltrator,
with all your questions.
What about the business
with Julio?
One less candidate, right?
You think so?
The only thing I'm wondering
is if they really have
a secret about each one of us
to use when they feel
it's necessary.
Coffee?
Thank you.
Congratulations.
Why?
Your defense of Julio.
You made it very tough.
If it was so good,
why did you vote against it?
Well,
I like to be begged.
Look at them.
The new school.
I don't think
there's a new school.
You don't?
Do you see any difference?
No, none.
Nothing very romantic.
I was offered a better job than
I had in Barcelona, and I came.
Well...
Do you like being in Madrid?
I haven't had time to find out
I haven't stopped working.
Yes, because you came
just after we met.
- When was the Tunis Conference?
- Easter, 2003.
- We had a good time.
- A very good time.
It's a pity we met here,
isn't it?
Why?
Because now I have to beat you.
On the contrary.
That makes it even more exciting.
"The year 2013.
World War III has broken out
and the planet is suffocating
beneath a radioactive cloud.
Fortunately, you are all safe
as you had time
to get to an atomic shelter
equipped with everything
necessary to survive for 20 years.
Unfortunately,
the shelter was designed
for a family of five people
so one of you will have to leave.
Decide who should do it,
but first each one must defend
his right to stay,
using demonstrable arguments.
Whoever is expelled
from the shelter
will also abandon
the selection process."
These are our résumés.
- Must we stick to our résumés?
- No, not as such.
It's so we can check
what each one says.
I guess.
Some things that aren't in a
résumé can be useful in a shelter.
Such as what?
Cooking, for example.
It's what I was going to say.
I'm a great cook,
I can do wonders.
The thing is, it says here
"demonstrable arguments".
I don't know
if what you say is true.
Why don't you start?
You've got it all clear.
Very well.
As you know, I've worked
and am still working
for electronic components
companies.
If you look at my résumé
you'll see I've done courses
in electronics and electricity.
So I'd be able to build a radio.
If there are survivors outside
or life comes back.
Build it?
Weren't you
the financial director?
Yes, but the courses I did
went into great detail.
Look at my résumé.
Yes, I've looked at it.
Sufficient detail
so you can build a radio?
That's what I'm saying.
Ask me about it, if you want.
Won't the shelter have a radio?
- Why? Who says so?
- Nobody. I'm presuming.
If it doesn't say so
you can't presume anything.
And there'll be electrical
maintenance to be done too.
I think good cooking
is more important.
Well...
Has anyone done military service?
Then I could take charge
of organization and rationing.
You'll forget the meaning
of the word "mutiny".
Yes, sir, on the double.
Two days arrest outside
the shelter, without a gas mask.
- Do I have to do pushups?
- Yes, later.
In front of me.
Why do we need someone in charge
of organization and rationing?
Excuse me?
Because it's always needed.
- Who says so?
- You, for example,
when we were talking about Julio.
I was talking about
running a company
not living in a shelter.
What's more,
we're all adults and
there's a thing called dialogue.
Of course,
but we're not arguing about
playing cards or checkers.
20 years in an atomic shelter
isn't a vacation, Nieves.
We can take turns
to organize the rationing.
Great, great.
Nieves, imagine it was your turn,
for example,
and I decide
I want double rations
because I feel like it,
I woke up with an appetite.
If we start like that...
I won't do anything on my own,
if that's your question.
- But between us, we can stop you.
- I'm talking about you, not them.
Are you going to persuade them
to act together?
Are you going to make them all
turn on me?
Are you the mole
trying to provoke things?
You wish.
I'm talking to her, not you.
Yes.
I'll do all that. What's more,
I'll try to get you
left outside the shelter.
You're dangerous.
How much more dangerous am I
than Carlos or Enrique?
Just enough, don't get big ideas.
But I'm funnier too, aren't I?
- Hilarious.
- Of course!
Tell me this.
- You trust them more than me?
- Of course.
I could accept that
authority is needed,
but I'd never be alongside
a military officer.
You know the military service
is just an excuse.
You'd vote for me because you'd
be safer under my authority.
If you behave, that is.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that you,
as a woman among so many men,
prefer that there's authority
so you feel more protected.
Fernando, sweetheart,
where have you escaped from?
Fernando,
you're a trained lawyer.
Why didn't you say so?
That would guarantee you
a place in the shelter.
What use is a lawyer in a world
devastated by nuclear radiation?
- If he were a physicist...
- The law is always needed,
even after the bomb.
You can't deny that.
- What use is law without authority?
- Shit, John Wayne.
All I'm saying
is that if anyone eats
a double ration
I'll beat the crap out of him,
and if anyone doesn't clean up,
he'll get the same treatment.
I give my word on that.
What if you don't comply?
Who'll control you?
You.
How sweet.
To settle the question,
shall we leave Fernando
with the role of judge,
and executioner if necessary.
What do you propose?
Me?
In case the judge
gets carried away,
I offer my services as doctor.
As my résumé states, I studied
two and half years of Medicine
so I know quite a bit.
Not bad.
That was a clever move, Ricardo.
And after all that fuss about
not saying where you worked,
we can read it here at our ease.
Joint Manager of the Transport
Department of Mercolex.
Did you go to class?
When you were a student.
Yes, I did. Why?
No reason.
You've taken away my argument.
I was going to offer myself
as doctor.
You studied medicine too?
No, but...
I go mountain climbing and I've
done some first aid courses,
anatomy...
Come on, that's pushing it a bit,
isn't it?
No, why?
I've done first aid courses too
and I don't call myself a doctor.
Yes, you're right.
I was playing for time.
I can't find...
I can't find anything else
of use in my résumé.
Well, yes.
I've got something.
I'll tell you a story
every night.
It might sound a bit odd,
but I studied literature
for a few years and I read a lot.
I can make your life underground
much more bearable.
Really, Carlos,
it was a very good attempt.
But, if you'll forgive me,
right now I think that you and
Ana are the worst qualified.
Because you say so?
There's a doctor,
there's a judge,
- a technician.
- And a cook.
Yes. Don't you like
how she cooks?
It's not that, Fernando.
It's not included in her résumé.
And what use is a radio
if the planet is destroyed?
Well,
I was just giving my opinion.
Nieves,
you're last.
All right.
I offer to be
the mother of all your children.
Irrefutable!
The mother
of post-atomic humanity.
All right,
I hadn't thought about that.
I can fulfill that role too.
That just leaves you, Carlos.
Excuse me, Ana.
I don't want to be rude,
but aren't you a bit old?
No.
Are you sure?
Very sure.
- I'm not twenty, I know, but...
- Nor thirty.
I still have a few fertile years.
And I have a child,
which guarantees I can have them.
I'm sorry to insist.
For how long will you be
able to be a mother still?
Aren't you at a dangerous age
already?
The risk is still acceptable.
Or do you only like adolescents?
Well,
I don't think
this is getting us anywhere.
No, it's very good. They have
to argue to see who wins.
I think that between a good meal
and telling a story...
What?
It's obvious!
Have you read Jack London?
- What?
- Jack London.
He has a story
about some Eskimos
who migrate
when the seasons change.
There's a man who's old,
weary,
almost blind.
He feels he can't keep up
with the tribe.
So the whole group stops
and they say goodbye to him,
one by one,
his children too.
They leave him there,
just like that,
with a little pile of firewood.
The old man sits in the snow,
calmly,
remembering his life,
and when the wood runs out
he freezes to death.
Is that one of the stories
you'd tell us?
Why not?
It's very educational.
A lot of people
could learn from it.
Who do you think you are?
Will you be more useful
with your stories?
Why do you dare call me old?
You little ass-licker.
They can screw me.
Will you offer them your ass?
It would be best if you all chose
and kept us from
insulting each other.
She's right.
I think we should vote.
Who wants me to stay
in the shelter?
I'm voting for the cook.
Nieves?
I'll do the same as before,
if you don't mind.
I'm abstaining.
Do I put Ana's name in the box?
Before you throw me out,
I want to ask a question.
Is it because I'm a woman?
Because I'm over forty?
Or both things?
We're not throwing you out.
Then don't vote.
Do like Ricardo.
Abstain, let the company decide.
Like you did with Julio?
They're not throwing you out
for the reasons you're saying.
It's because you couldn't defend
your presence in the shelter.
So I think.
What's going on down there?
You can't see anything here.
I'm sorry, Ana.
I did the same as you,
defend myself.
I don't believe what I said.
I was playing a role
to win the game.
Honestly.
Over there, please.
Won't you stay for lunch?
There's enough for everyone.
Is this all there is to drink?
Yes, alcoholic drinks aren't
allowed in this company.
I apologize for offering you
a cold lunch,
but the demonstration is causing
problems with the restaurants.
It's fine, don't worry.
Is it my imagination
or does this smell bad?
You don't mind if I eat with you,
do you?
No, not at all.
Thank you.
How are you getting on?
Great, it's fantastic.
The method, I mean.
You think so?
Yes. Forget the Americans.
In my humble opinion,
I think it's very good.
A deadly silence.
Don't you like the food?
No, I'm not very hungry.
- Is the food bad?
- No, a bit cold, but it's not bad.
The smell is a bit...
It's very good.
You didn't like it either.
I don't know,
maybe we had a bad taste
in our mouths already.
Well...
No, thank you.
Why didn't you call back?
I left you several messages.
Remember the night on the beach?
If we'd done all we said,
we'd be living in Africa now.
Yes.
- On the seashore.
- In a cabin.
An arm's reach from the water.
Wonderful.
Running a bar on the beach.
To make ends meet.
Because we'd have to feed
all our children.
That's right.
Lots of African children.
A whole soccer team.
It was nice dreaming with you.
Likewise.
Why didn't you call?
Did you have a boyfriend,
a husband?
I don't mind,
the past is the past.
It's just to see
if I have a chance.
Did you have those children
without me?
I had one,
who looked a lot like you.
A little African boy,
handsome like you.
Excuse me.
What are you doing!
Forgive me, I'm really sorry.
I don't know how it happened.
- You don't know?
- No. I'm sorry.
I don't know what I was thinking.
It'll wash out.
I won't be long.
May I?
Yes, of course.
Thank you.
Are you all right?
Absolutely fine.
Forgive me,
but if I may say so,
you seem a bit strange.
A bit strange? When?
All the time.
Since you arrived.
I'd advise you to be more
participative,
more positive.
I don't know.
It irritates me how they
poke around in our résumés,
Why?
Look at Julio.
Don't you think
he deserved a second chance?
Yes. Well, I don't know.
You are what you've done
but also what you propose to do.
Maybe you have something to hide.
Maybe you're the mole.
Something silly.
It's not important,
but I forgot to put it
on the first form
I had to fill in
and then I didn't put it
on the later ones.
So I had to keep hiding it.
Like I said, it's silly.
I'd almost forgotten it.
But given the way they are,
they'd presume I was lying
and they wouldn't forgive me.
That's why I'm pissed off
by all the damn forms.
Yes, it makes sense to get us
to fill them out so often.
I just realized that.
And what is that lie...
that secret?
It doesn't matter.
Secret or lie,
call it what you want.
A few years ago,
when I was living in Argentina,
I worked for a state company
while I was a student.
Then it was privatized
and the new management
carried out what they called
"structural readjustments".
A covert way of firing people
because it had agreed
not to dismiss anyone.
There was union action to prevent
half the staff from being fired.
I supported the action, of course,
I was part of the staff.
Anyway,
I ended up being something like
the employees' spokesman.
A union delegate.
An executive
with a union background?
If these guys ask for references
from those guys...
Hello.
How are things?
I've been wanting
to talk to you alone all day
and this is the best moment.
Well...
I don't want to.
Don't want to what? Talk?
To do anything alone with you.
Do you think there are cameras
in here? I don't.
- It'd be too much, wouldn't it?
- Why do you ask?
It's the only place here
where we can be ourselves.
Where we can take off
our disguises.
You mean our clothes?
That too.
We'd understand each other
much better.
I'm sorry, Fernando.
No luck.
The "Iberian macho"
doesn't turn me on.
What a pity.
Do you say that every day
in the mirror?
Do you always look like that
when you say it?
To your regret, yes.
Only some situations turn you on,
right?
And only bastards like me
know what those are.
If you don't mind,
I have to wash.
I don't mind at all.
Go ahead.
You said I could trust you.
- Didn't you?
- Yes.
I still say it.
Then hang up my blouse and leave.
What are you doing?
Finish it off on your own.
Bitch.
Nieves!
You know the march was a success?
It's bigger
than the anti-war protest.
A pity we can't see the street.
Did you join the protest
or did you ask for a day off
to come here?
In your company, I mean.
Wearing a 1,000 euro suit
and protesting against
the World Bank?
Why not?
If you stop to think about it,
you never know.
Today you're here,
you feel part of Dekia.
And tomorrow...
Some of what they're saying
is true.
The IMF people
are destroying the world.
If I hadn't been screwed
in Argentina,
you think I'd be here now?
There are things that
a million marches can't change.
Are you sure?
You think nothing can be done?
Maybe you're right.
But you'll agree that
this world is crap right now.
I wish I could say otherwise.
The people marching down there...
I envy their conviction.
Don't you?
If you really believed
that marching could change
things, wouldn't you do it?
Well, if I believed...
That's what I mean.
I envy their conviction.
You're sitting on the fence!
You don't go and protest
but you ask for the day off.
No, don't distort things!
I asked for the day off
to come here.
And you keep everyone happy.
The employees think you're
a liberal and the bosses think
you're a sensible man
who doesn't want his car burned!
You want to make me
look like an opportunist
and it isn't so.
I understand the reasons
for the march as well as you do,
and I'll defend them
if necessary.
But certain categories of employees
can't go joining every parade.
Where is that written?
I don't know if it's written,
but that's how it is.
An executive can't just walk out
and join a protest,
as if he had no responsibilities.
Why not?
Because it would be
hypocritical.
This protest is against
how the world is being managed.
If, as you said, you understand
the reasons for it,
why not support it?
Whether you're a laborer
or a bank manager.
If you're a bank manager,
you pick up the phone,
you call the president
of the government
and tell him
what you think of it all.
Let's see.
Do we agree that
whether you're a student,
an executive, a businessman
or a simple worker,
you can think what you want
of the IMF and the World Bank?
If you don't care what's
at stake, you can look away.
- But in this case...
- It is important.
All right.
Thank you.
Talking about the protest?
If you knew what was going on
around here.
All the companies
have closed for the afternoon.
- Really?
- Yes, of course.
Right now, you can't even
walk on the street.
- That's why the food was cold.
- So you said.
Well...
What were you saying
about the protest?
- You don't mind me asking?
- No, of course not.
Nothing.
Who can be against it?
So you agree with it?
Someone in our position
can't agree with a protest.
Enrique,
it's one thing not to march,
but you admitted that
you agreed with the reasons.
What I mean is
I understand the reasons
but I don't agree.
I can't support a protest.
- What? You told me you did.
- No, don't twist things around.
- You just told me so.
- Don't include me with you!
I'm not in any union!
What I mean is...
I didn't mean that...
- What I mean...
- You're incredible.
What is this, Ricardo?
Let's not get upset.
I didn't mean to say that.
What was it?
What was it
that you didn't mean to say?
Nothing.
Excuse me, he told you
it wasn't important.
Are you telling me
what I can ask?
Is this part of the test or what?
He said it wasn't important
and I simply don't see why
you have to go on about it.
Forget it, Ricardo.
You needn't go on about it.
She's the one asking questions.
Anyway, you were the one
who went and gave me away.
Just a minute.
Enrique,
is there something
the company should know?
Maybe you should ask him.
Why?
I'm... Well... I'm sorry,
I don't mean to tell you
what you should ask anyone,
I would never dare, but...
Do you know something?
Do you or don't you?
Excuse me, I'm not willing
to go through this.
And neither should you.
- Don't you see it's humiliating?
- It's not humiliating.
Don't exaggerate.
This guy is too much!
Why not give him
your shoe to lick?
Excuse me, I think
I told you this at the start.
No one is forcing you
to stay here.
But while you're in this room
the company lays down the rules.
Do you see what's happening?
If you don't mind, I'd rather...
Don't you see they're asking you
to give me away?
Let's not get dramatic.
That's what they're asking.
She wants to know our opinion.
No, she wants you to tell her
about me.
Let's just calm down.
And what you know about me
is what I told you.
Because I trusted you.
Come on, come on.
Please, let's not get this
out of proportion.
It was just an oversight
on a form.
An oversight on a form
I don't want them to known about.
I think you're going overboard.
Have you nothing to say?
Are you just going
to let this happen?
Don't involve me.
It's your business.
I'm very sorry that
things have gone this far.
Yes, of course.
But, Enrique,
you know something
the company doesn't know
and should know,
and you won't say what it is.
I don't know.
Your idea of company loyalty
is a bit strange.
This is unbelievable.
Look, you're going to have
to leave now anyway, aren't you?
What does it matter
if I tell her?
I won't give you the pleasure
of seeing me leave.
So if you're going
to tell on me... Look at me.
Look at me.
If you're going to do it,
do it in front of me.
It was nothing.
Just that Ricardo,
in Argentina,
worked for a state company.
When it was privatized,
he became a union leader.
And he completely screwed
the new management,
which was probably Spanish.
That kind of people...
And then they talk
about stereotypes.
Argentineans...
You can't generalize.
- Thank you, Montse.
- Not at all.
You were fantastic,
really fantastic.
Well...
Well?
How are you?
Fine.
And you?
I'm fine, thank you.
Well, now you know.
I'm the mole.
Nieves...
Come on, we have to continue.
What do you think
of the method now?
Good, isn't it?
Of course it is.
So, tell me.
Yes.
What do you think?
About what you did.
- What I did?
- Yes.
You think it was correct?
What do you all think?
How would you qualify
what he did?
Have you got anything to say?
Yes.
Yes, that...
Of course.
That...
Well, that I agree.
I completely agree that...
I don't know what happened.
I let myself be carried away
by the moment, I guess.
I thought that the secretary,
Montse...
I thought that she...
It's so silly, isn't it?
I want to apologize,
to all of you,
for what I made you go through.
I still don't know what you think
about what you did.
About what?
Telling the company
what you knew about me.
Should you have done it or not?
Yes, yes. No.
I mean, I think
I shouldn't have done it.
- Yes or no?
- Yes or no, what?
Yes or no,
should you have done it?
No.
Yes. I don't know.
I don't know.
I don't know. I...
I don't... I can't know.
Do me a favor.
Apply again when
you've clarified your ideas.
We'll be delighted
to assess you again.
At present, you're of no use.
Good afternoon.
Well, with a bit of luck,
we'll be going home soon.
On to the next test?
Let's see.
- Which shall it be?
- Ricardo,
just one question.
Are there cameras or not?
Of course not.
Not because it's illegal.
We think it's unethical.
We don't do things like that.
Most companies
don't just have cameras,
they record the interviews too.
But, no.
We wouldn't dream of it.
We're enjoying ourselves today.
Don't you agree?
About what?
That this is fun.
I wouldn't say
it was fun exactly.
What would you say?
Exciting?
Intense.
That's not bad. Intense.
Because of Enrique?
For example.
I'd say Enrique was the one
who enjoyed it most.
He was sitting there all day,
really into it, focused.
Enrique didn't do badly.
He participated more than anyone.
- Coffee?
- No, thanks.
I'd like some.
Yes, of course.
Enrique is undoubtedly
pretty upset right now,
and may be for a few more days.
But, in the long term,
don't you think all this
will be of use to him?
As Enrique himself would say,
"Looking at it that way..."
Thank you.
Now, seriously,
some candidates thank me.
Even if they're eliminated.
They say they feel more prepared
for the daily struggle,
more aware of their possibilities
and their limitations.
Did you know that the army
invented selection tests?
After World War I, in Germany.
The Treaty of Versailles had
greatly restricted the German army,
so they decided to submit
officers to tests like these.
And to assess them better,
they always used
a psychologist too.
It was adopted
by the English army,
then by the American army,
and then
by companies.
You should learn something new
every day.
A difficult decision.
Choosing one of you, I mean.
You're all really good, honestly.
It's a pity only one can be left.
Montse, may I have the ball,
please?
Remember the jokes about
an Englishman
a Frenchman and a Spaniard?
Serrano ham.
- Crepes.
- Pudding.
Potato omelet.
Tartare.
Whiskey.
- Absinthe.
- Sarsaparilla.
Time.
English drinks are lousy!
Carry on, Fernando.
Soccer players.
Raúl.
Rooney.
- Zidane.
- Very good.
- Valeron.
- Owen.
Mendieta.
Zizou.
- He's the same.
- Yeah, but he's French.
But he's the same person.
Let's skip soccer too.
Fernando starts with
Contributions to Humanity.
What?
Serrano ham.
Guillotine.
The Inquisition.
- Shakespeare.
- Quijote.
Republic.
Can't you throw it to each other?
Iberian macho.
Contributions to humanity
aren't necessarily good.
Let's continue.
Carlos.
The Beatles.
Chupa-chups.
Sex,
but with people.
Another one who believes
the French invented sex?
No, but what a difference
from other countries.
Carry on, Fernando.
You have to deliver in time.
Fernando, to Carlos.
Financial advantages.
Yeah.
The pound doesn't depend
on other European economies.
The euro is growing stronger.
Wait.
Most of us
speak French and English.
You English can't say
the same thing.
Debatable.
But we'll continue.
We don't speak languages
because we know we're great.
- That's an advantage in business.
- Not in this case.
We speak Spanish,
the second language in the world.
The second is English.
- The first, then. Even better.
- The first is Mandarin Chinese.
Screw the Chinese.
Carlos, please.
We have a close relationship
with the U.S.A.
Big deal, we've got
the South American market.
We too have a close relationship
with the U.S.A.
We're all they can never be.
That's not a financial advantage.
Debatable, but we'll continue.
Do languages count now?
While you're talking advantages.
Are you only realizing now?
- Fernando's turn.
- But...
Oh, yeah.
Spain is the European economy
with the best forecast.
The fact is, France is the
world's fourth economic power.
Spain is an economic power too.
You're supposed to cite
advantages over the other two.
Go ahead, Carlos.
We have the most temporary jobs
and short-term contracts.
Very good for the businessman.
We have the highest GNP and
revenue of the three countries.
Spain is the fastest growing
European economy.
Time. To Fernando.
Shit.
I forget to say an advantage.
We don't have a fiscal deficit
at present.
We don't sell things
we don't have.
What did you say?
Time, Fernando. To Nieves.
Watch your step, kid.
Take it easy, they're just puns.
Fernando.
- Throw it to Nieves.
- Yes, sorry.
I'm sorry.
France has a great market
in Arab countries.
Spain is Europe's biggest
tourist destination.
We're talking about
financial advantages, Fernando.
What's so funny?
Sorry, it was a stupid pun.
Didn't you understand it?
Nieves, time.
To Fernando.
No, I didn't.
Will you translate it?
Time's passing.
It's my time.
Will you translate it?
He said you wanted
to be a stockbroker
and you ended up being...
A stocktaker.
Very good.
Time. Carlos gets the ball.
I didn't understand.
Can you explain it?
He's calling you a wanker.
One more step and I'll tear
your fucking head off.
Kiddo!
Congratulations, you've won.
You're the best.
Fucking great!
You're the most qualified.
You probably are.
You know why?
You believe it.
All that shit about responsible
companies and Japanese décor.
All that fucking shit
about democratic companies
and sustainable development.
That's all it is, believe me.
They tell you you're the best,
you believe it.
The most intelligent,
The best intentioned,
you believe it.
The most tolerant,
the most modern,
even the most human,
for crissake, and you believe it!
Know what you are?
This preppy doesn't care.
Preppies look the other way,
they learn that from birth.
So it's easy for him.
Forget about him.
But what'll become of you
when you stop believing?
Or when you regret
not having had that child,
and it's too late?
Because it's getting late.
Or when it's the "Iberian macho"
who wants nothing to do with you?
How long will that smile last
before it becomes a grimace?
There's one difference
between you and me.
Just one.
I learned long ago that you lose
the battle on your own.
On your own.
How are you?
I can't believe
you're the psychologist.
I thought you knew.
It occurred to me,
but you're a very good actor.
You don't know how good.
Because I am a candidate.
I was doing so badly
that during the break
I arranged with Montse
to set a trap for Enrique
so I'd gain a few points.
And they accepted it.
What a bastard.
You really are good.
Are you all right?
Would you like an aspirin?
We always have it twice as hard,
don't we?
Women, I mean.
Yes, we do.
But you've been incredible.
All day, in all the tests.
Really.
You were always my favorite.
It's what you see.
There are no psychologists.
It's just her and me.
We set it up, we assess it.
That's the method. Your
imagination projects the rest.
Incredible.
So Montse is a psychologist too?
Where does the Grönholm method
come from?
Nowhere.
But it sounds good, doesn't it?
Actors.
What do you mean?
Yes, well,
at times we even swap roles.
I play the psychologist,
he plays the secretary.
They only have to decide
who leaves
and what tests to apply.
They?
The team of psychologists.
What a question!
You think we do this on our own?
It all depends on who's left.
The test with the ball
was for Fernando.
Why?
We knew he didn't speak
languages.
I don't understand.
You were out to get him?
No, but let's say
it was his test.
Languages aren't a requirement
but we wanted to see how he'd
handle being at a disadvantage.
We knew you two would
take advantage of his weakness.
Don't worry about Fernando.
He was a dickhead.
And he was out already.
How do you mean?
Really, they were all out.
Except for you and Carlos.
They'd all been ruled out.
You already knew
that they weren't?
Of course. But the psychologists
needed more candidates
in order to assess you two.
She's getting the job, Carlos.
That's how it is.
Right now,
we should be saying to you,
"Goodbye, thank you for coming,
we'll be in touch", and so on.
Not just because
Montse has decided.
Psychologists or not,
women always stick together.
But Nieves did better
in the tests.
That's the truth.
You're not telling me all this
just to throw me out, are you?
I've made a deal with Montse.
We're giving you a last chance.
Most of the team
still prefer him.
I think he's been scoring better
up to now.
And, to be honest,
they're a bit chauvinist, too.
But, anyway,
in theory there's one last test
and they're giving you a chance.
You can still get the job.
There's one more test?
Let's say there is another test.
But Carlos doesn't know.
Break her down?
Look, this is exceptional.
I insisted. If you don't
manage it, the job's hers.
How can I break her down?
However you think.
Carlos, I had to fight for this.
Don't let me down.
You've got 15 minutes.
Ricardo is going to be
as if he'd been held up.
What you have to do,
while you pretend
to be waiting with Carlos,
is get him to leave.
Nieves, the job can still
be yours.
But you must persuade him
to give up.
Persuade him?
Yes, tell him anything,
like, his mother is in hospital.
Come on, Nieves.
And remember.
15 minutes.
Anything goes.
I had to shit, from nerves.
How are you?
Fine.
Sure?
If I can help you at all,
if you need to talk...
Fernando is a bastard.
He was so violent.
I was scared.
You really think
he was a bastard?
Nieves,
he nearly smashed your face
with the ball.
And then he went on about
the children you haven't had,
about how lonely you are.
Maybe he saw that was
your vulnerable side.
Let's skip it.
- You know this is his shirt?
- Yes, I'd realized.
It was so strange.
I'd washed the stain out of mine
and before I knew
he'd stolen it.
You met him in the bathroom?
Did you know...
Yes.
What did he say?
"Excuse me,
I'm going inside to jack off"?
No, I bet he said,
"Babe, I'll give you
the child you always wanted".
- Did he force you?
- I don't want to talk about it.
Of course not.
I just wanted to help, I guess.
If you need to talk...
- It's not necessary.
- Right.
I understand.
Ricardo's taking his time.
Carlos!
Nothing.
I'm so glad I found you.
Even if it was here.
One of us has to lose now.
Even if it's me, I don't care.
I won't let you get away.
I've thought a lot about you.
Why did you think about me?
Don't read more into what I say
than is really there.
I didn't idealize what happened
but I didn't forget it.
In all this time,
I've lived my life as usual,
but...
That night,
we made
all those plans.
We knew we were playing
but they could be true.
You understand?
And
in these three years,
it's not that I was missing
that life we invented,
but I haven't built anything.
What you said
about a little African boy,
was it true?
You'd have had a child with me?
Let's go.
Let's go now.
Forget the test.
- Now?
- Yes, now.
We've clearly shown
what we're worth.
If they want to choose, let them.
Are you sure?
How much more can they assess?
How far do we have to compete?
Until we tear
each other's eyes out?
I know there are lots
of applicants and just one job.
I understand we have to compete.
I'm even willing to accept
that life is like that.
If I have to be a wolf,
I'll be one.
I didn't care with the others.
But with you
I don't want to.
I don't.
I want to go to the beach
and get drunk
and dream
that we'll open that bar.
- You're going to persuade me.
- That's what I want.
Let's go.
Mademoiselle...
Merci.
Wait.
Shall we go?
What part of you
do I have to believe now?
This one, Carlos.
Of course!
Of course! Of course!
Why didn't I realize?
They gave you an objective too,
didn't they?
It doesn't matter.
I didn't reach it.
So we don't know
what would have happened.
Everything you said...
Was that why?
When you asked
about the African baby,
did you want
to know if I'd have had
a child with you,
or was it to pass the test?
It's not too late.
You can still get the job.
Do I have to do something
for you to get it?
What do I have to do?