Mind your step, Jenny.
Don't you worry none about me.
I can hold me gin.
I'm right as rain.
Ta-ta, love.
Mind how you go.
-Evening.
-Good evening.
-It's a raw night, isn't it?
-Yes. Raw.
-You'll ruin them fine clothes.
-Would you like this?
Come straight to the point,
don't you, love?
Well, my place is right along here.
No.
There.
We are in a hurry, aren't we?
Come on, then.
Come along.
Oh, right you are, sir.
Wouldn't want to break it.
Wow. That's lovely.
We got our own band.
Come on, then.
I'm hot and getting colder,
if you take my meaning.
-What's your name, dearie?
-John.
John.
Oh, John.
But my friends all call me Jack.
Will The Gazette continue
with your pieces on free love, H.G.?
Free love sells newspapers.
Gentleman, the Fleet Street Casanova.
Here, here.
I've got my little experiments
to pay for.
You're the hero of the working class.
Free love is all they can afford.
Oh, Lord.
Don't start him on socialism.
We'll have to listen
to a sermon on it.
Don't call it a sermon. You know
I don't believe in organized religion.
Socialism is the path man must tread
on the way to a utopian society.
We've heard all that. What's this
great announcement we're here for?
-A cure for gravity?
-I want to wait until we're all here.
Who's missing?
-Dr. Stevenson is here.
-Thank you. Send him in.
-Good evening, John.
-Herbert.
-Good evening.
-Hello.
We'd begun to despair. Have you dined?
There's still roast beef.
Thank you, no. Perhaps a little brandy
to take away the chill.
I'm sorry I missed supper, but
a physician's hours are not his own.
-Gentlemen.
-Good health.
Cheers.
What has Herbert left for me tonight?
Chess must wait.
You're just in time for the surprise.
Isn't he, H.G.?
The great big whatever-it-is?
-Am I?
-I was waiting for you.
-I am all attention.
-Very well.
Gentlemen, I have called you here
tonight to bid you farewell.
-Farewell?
-Where are you going?
-Another holiday in Scotland?
-No. No, I am traveling...
...but I'm not leaving London.
I don't expect to leave my laboratory.
-Riddles again.
-Gentlemen.
I am talking about traveling
through time.
In a machine constructed
for that very purpose.
What?
-Poppycock.
-Why?
Electric light, courtesy of Edison,
a modern Prometheus.
Good heavens. You were really serious.
I don't believe it. You've actually
built the bloody thing.
-Free love paid for most of it.
-I've no doubt.
I didn't think practical jokes
was in your line.
Twelve years ago, an engineer used
the sun to power a printing press.
My time machine
uses the same power source.
-You can't be serious.
-This thing is propelled by sunshine?
This cup catches
the rays of the sun...
...converting its heat
to electricity here.
Electricity does the rest. Juxtaposing
fields of energy creating friction.
The result is an ever-increasing
series of reactions...
...that literally rotates the machine
out of one time sphere into another.
Cruising speed is two years per
minute. Go into the past or future.
Two years per minute?
Acceleration keeps the machine and
occupant outside all time spheres...
-...conscious, but vaporized.
-How do you determine direction?
West, you gain yesterdays.
East, you accumulate tomorrows.
Balderdash!
Go north, you get to Glasgow.
The machine is designed
with several safety features.
The reversal rotation lock returns
the machine to its starting date...
...after the completion of a voyage.
If the occupant is injured
during a flight...
...the passenger is returned
to the point of departure.
Unless he uses this key
to countermand the device.
Without that key,
it's a bloody homing pigeon.
And what, may I ask, is this?
Well, John...
...this is the vaporizing equalizer.
Without it, the passenger journeys
without the machine...
...and without the machine,
there is no coming back.
Well, H.G., which is it to be?
The past or the future?
The past, surely.
He'll want to meet Cleopatra.
-The future.
-Why the future?
I belong there. In three generations,
social utopia will have come to pass.
There'll be no war, crime or poverty.
And no disease either, John.
Men will live like brothers,
and in equality with women.
-Oh, dear. Let's have the past.
-Here, here.
I can't agree with you. Check.
You astonish me. In the midst of all
your theorizing, you ignore the facts.
We live in a cosmic charnel house.
Mankind has not changed in 2000 years.
We hunt, we're hunted. That's
how it is. How it will always be.
The future will prove you wrong.
The future will tell.
Anyway, I have just one question
for myself. When do you leave?
-I'm not sure.
-Human frailty, at last.
Well, to be quite candid...
-...I haven't worked up the nerve.
-First time for that.
But I will. All I have to do is set
the date and activate the switches.
And I'll inherit the Hope diamond.
-Checkmate.
-How does he do it?
-Not again?
-Every time.
I know how he thinks. That's all.
-One day I shall win.
-When you learn how I think.
Sorry to interrupt. Two gentlemen from
Scotland Yard want a word with you.
What is the meaning of this?
Beg pardon, sir.
Might we have a word with you?
-The Ripper? In this vicinity?
-I'm afraid so, sir.
We've cordoned off the neighborhood.
We're asking for cooperation.
Will that be all right? Your
housekeeper will sleep better.
-By all means.
-Thank you, sir.
What's happened?
Apparently, the Ripper
has struck again.
-With your permission, sir.
-Please.
-He's not been heard from in years.
-Nor in this area.
No doubt about it, I'm afraid.
He has a very distinctive style.
-What have you there?
-You better look at this, sir.
-That's Dr. Stevenson's bag.
-That belongs to one of my guests.
-What's his name?
-John Leslie Stevenson.
-Chief surgeon at St. Bartholomew's--
-Also chief surgeon in White chapel.
-Nothing upstairs.
-All windows locked.
-Skylight?
-Closed.
-Checked the roof. No sign.
-In back?
A high brick wall.
He's not gone that way.
-He was with you just now?
-Yes.
He must have gone out the front,
as we came in.
It doesn't matter. We know who he is,
which is more than before tonight.
We'll round him up. If you come with
me, I'll see that you get home safe.
-There's bound to be an explanation.
-Beyond belief.
Thank you, dear. That's my umbrella.
I've never been so frightened. All the
times I've put that bag in the closet.
-I wonder he didn't take it with him.
-We'd never have known.
-He was always such a gentleman.
-Yes. A gentleman.
I wonder where he got to so fast.
The coppers searched high and low.
We were by the door the whole time.
If he fooled them this long,
no surprise he's done it again.
-What did you say?
-We were by the door the whole time.
When you learn how I think.
1979.
What have I done?
I've turned that bloody maniac
loose upon utopia.
-Mr. Wells--
-Bring me all the housekeeping money.
And any money you have of your own.
I'll make it up to you.
-How much?
-Fifteen pounds, sixpence.
-You want it all?
-All, if you please, Mrs. Turner.
-Something wrong, sir?
-Would you mind awfully?
Money may not answer.
I may have to trade with the natives.
Let me see. The key.
86 years. Two years per minute.
That makes 43 minutes.
Estimated time of arrival would be....
11:15.
Right.
Utopia.
Mr. Wells?
--Lindbergh 's over the Irish coast--
--support of the woman I love--
--we have to fear is--
--their finest hour--
--attacked Pearl Harbor--
--I shall return--
--this is London--
--whose throat you'd like to cut--
--proclaim the state of Israel--
--Queen Elizabeth Il is crowned--
--from North Korea--
--Ask not--
--President Kennedy is dead--
--Martin Luther King--
--one small step for man--
--Israeli athletes were killed--
--Vietnam cease-fire agreement--
--because of Watergate--
--second test-tube baby--
--Pope John Paul's successor--
--and executed four generals--
Mommy, look at that.
Mommy, come over here.
Mommy. Who's that man?
Jason, come away.
He probably works here.
The Wells exhibit is on loan
from the British Museum.
The objects in this hall
form a portrait of the public...
...and private life
of an extraordinary person...
...whose prophetic vision influenced
the shape of things to come.
On your left is the inlaid wood
secretary with a unique top...
...from Wells' rooms.
It was on this desk....
Hey! Get away from the exhibit.
Where do you think you are,
Disneyland?
-Pardon?
-You heard me. Get behind those ropes.
--was discovered by workmen
digging where Wells ' house once stood.
Come on.
The reasons for his building it
are unknown.
--that it didn't work
made him avoid discussing it.
-H.G. Wells was born in....
-Novel? Time Machine?
You people. Christ, Almighty.
Never.
Eight hours off.
What did you do to my car?
Can't you drive?
Some SOB can't read.
-Could you tell me what city this is?
-Oh, come on.
Could you please tell me
what city this...?
San Francisco?
California. Of course!
Eight hours difference.
Thirteen, 14, 15 pounds. This money
is quite old, you're aware of that.
-They're still good, aren't they?
-Sure.
A coin dealer would give you more.
Here, all you'll get is the current
exchange rate, which is...
...$25.50.
-Twenty-five dollars?
-Really, it's the same all over.
Money makes the world go round.
It's just worth less and less.
Money, yes.
Everyone needs money.
Has there been another gentlemen
here recently...
...another Englishman
with currency like mine?
Not that I recall.
And they would have sent him to me.
I see.
Get me a Big Mac, an order of fries
and a small Coke to go, please.
Thank you, dear.
Get me a Big Mac, fries
and tea to go, please.
Pommes frites.
Fries are pommes frites.
I never saw wood like this before.
I haven't seen stones in settings
like these since before the war.
-The war?
-Since the Second World War. You know.
-Did you say, "world war"?
-Since World War ll, I said.
-How much are they worth?
-Today's market? $6000 easy.
-Would you like to buy them?
-I couldn't give you top dollar.
That's all right. What's your offer?
-Four?
-Yes. Very well.
You don't want to think about it?
Okay. May I see some ID?
You know. Driver's license,
credit card, something like that.
-I'm afraid I don't have some.
-I can't do business without some ID.
-How do I know these aren't hot?
-Hot?
-Stolen.
-Stolen?
I assure you, I give you my word
as a gentleman.
Come on, what's this gentleman stuff?
How come you don't got any ID?
Let me do a computer check. If it's
clear, you'll have a check in a week.
I don't have a week.
I don't believe you exist.
But if you do, I need your help.
Just let me stay the night...
...and I'll be on my way in the
morning. I won't trouble you again.
I'm sorry. We're closing now.
Utopia.
200. 300. 400.
There you are, sir.
May I help you?
I'd like to see the foreign
currency officer.
-You're looking at him.
-You?
Surely there must be a gentleman?
Don't be a chauvinist. It's taken
me three years to get here.
Don't you believe in women's
liberation?
Women's liberation.
I'm sorry. I meant no disrespect.
In fact, I was all for it,
so I shouldn't complain.
You were all for it?
What changed your mind?
Nothing.
I don't know whether you can help me.
-May I help you?
-Thank you.
I'm certainly willing for you to try.
I'm looking for an Englishman who may
have tried to exchange money.
I'll say.
Then he was here?
Yesterday, big as life.
With a money belt that was bigger.
Must've weighed a ton. A friend?
We were traveling together,
and now I've lost him.
-His name was John Leslie Stevenson.
-That's him.
I wanted him to open an account but
he only cashed a few hundred dollars.
You wouldn't happen to know
what's become of him?
He asked me to recommend a hotel.
-An hotel?
-I sent him to the Hyatt Regency.
-Hyatt Regency?
-Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
You here on a visit?
Tourist type thing?
If you don't know anyone,
let me show you around.
We San Franciscans are pretty
proud of this old town.
Well...
...yes, perhaps that might be nice.
It's your option. You've got the card.
Give me a ring. My name's Amy.
-A ring?
-You know:
My number's on the card.
-What's your name?
-Herbert...
...Wells.
What was that?
That was a very cute man.
That was a pickup.
-Against bank rules.
-I don't care.
At least he's not gay.
Plus, I love the way he talks.
How about that suit? Early American.
He'll be back.
-What's up, doc?
-Pardon?
Where to?
Could you take me, as quickly
as possible, to the Hyatt--?
-Who is it?
-Your breakfast, sir.
-Bless my soul.
-May I come in?
Certainly, certainly.
You were literally the last person
on earth I expected to see.
There was no way to prevent the
machine's return. I lack the key.
-No.
-You do manage to find the nerve...
...after I tested
your machine for you.
How did you manage to track me down?
That was brilliant.
We'll add detective to your list
of accomplishments.
You're a regular Sherlock Holmes.
I'm not here to engage
in idle banter, Stevenson.
You've used me and my machine
to escape justice.
I must congratulate you on the device.
At dinner the other century,
I thought you'd lost your wits.
Fate intervened, and I ascertained
that you are a Columbus of a new age.
The dawn of time travel.
I salute you.
-Come with me.
-Of course. Where are we going?
To the museum.
I'm obliged to take you back to face
the consequences of your acts.
You can't be serious.
You're so Victorian.
How do I get back? By force?
Be reasonable, John.
We don't belong here.
-We violated--
-We don't belong here?
Let me show you something.
Sit down.
Come on, I won't bite. Sit.
Now, look....
Terrorists carried out their threat
and began shooting...
...the first five of 106 Israeli
schoolchildren held hostage--
You haven't gone forward, Herbert.
You've gone back.
We've just received word that
Mayor Margolin of Columbus was shot.
We don't belong here.
On the contrary...
...I belong here completely
and utterly.
I'm home.
It's you who do not belong here.
You, with your absurd notions of a
perfect and harmonious society. Drivel.
The world has caught up
and surpassed me.
Ninety years ago, I was a freak.
Today, I'm an amateur.
You go back. The future isn't
what you thought. It's what I am.
Do you know that you can
purchase a rifle? It's legal.
-These people encourage--
-Stop it!
It's catching, isn't it?
Violence.
You finding me is rather fortuitous.
For me, that is.
Otherwise, I'd be obliged
to search for you.
Are you going to give it to me?
-I have no idea what you mean.
-Of course you do.
I'm talking about the key.
I can't have you following me for
eternity, like the Flying Dutchman.
Give me the key and we'll be quits.
Key? I don't have it with me.
I've played countless games
of chess with you...
...and the one thing
you cannot do is bluff.
I want that key.
Oh, God.
Maid.
Señor.
Stevenson.
Is he okay?
I beg your pardon.
Just a moment, please.
Yes?
I'm looking for a patient
recently admitted.
-Name?
-John Leslie Stevenson.
-Not here.
-They told me he'd be here.
-This is San Francisco Hospital?
-Not here under that name. Next.
-He just arrived. A motorcar hit him.
-A motorcar?
-Pardon?
-A car.
Yes, a car.
He's a tall, flaxen-haired,
distinguished-looking Englishman.
Just a minute, please.
Sorry. An accident victim matching
your description died 20 minutes ago.
-We had him listed as John Doe.
-Died?
Impossible. I saw him sitting
up after the accident.
His chart says, "internal injuries."
It happens that way sometimes.
Wait. May I see the body?
Are you family? Are you a relative?
-He doesn't have any relatives.
-I'm sorry.
-Wait a minute, please.
-Excuse me.
O-R-A-J.
Gloriosky.
-Oh.
-Hello.
You'll let me take you to lunch.
Hello. What did you say?
I said, lunch on me.
What do you say?
Oh, well....
Just let me get my things.
That is what you had in mind?
-Certainly, if you like.
-Wait right there.
All set. Where to?
Well, it's your city.
I'll leave it up to you.
I know, something with a view.
Don't worry, it's safe. We haven't had
any trouble since the big one in 1906.
Big one?
The earthquake. Don't you know?
You haven't done your reading.
-It leveled the whole shebang.
-The shebang?
I see.
Delicious. Far superior to that
Scottish place where I breakfasted.
-Scottish?
-MacDougall's.
-What about your friend?
-Friend?
Dr. Stevenson.
He wasn't exactly my friend.
We had a falling out.
I won't be seeing him again.
I like that suit. Is that what they're
wearing in London?
It was when I left.
Are you from London? Everyone
I meet from England is from London.
Sorry, what were you saying?
I was asking if you're from London.
I have some friends there.
I thought you might know them.
I realize it's a big city.
Anyway, their name is Phillips.
He works for Coca-Cola. Any chance?
-No, I'm afraid not.
-Ah, yes.
You probably move
in different circles.
Are you a scientist or something?
Whatever makes you say that?
Just a hunch.
You give me the impression of
someone who's cloistered away...
...in a library, doing research
and never reads the newspaper.
I used to write for a newspaper.
The Pall Mall Gazette.
Really? Shows how much I know.
You're a reporter?
I wrote articles on whatever struck
my fancy. Social issues, mainly.
The last thing I did was a series
on free love.
Free love?
I haven't heard that term
since the eighth grade.
Tell me something.
Did you think it was forward of me
to invite you to lunch like this?
-Do you often--?
-Invite strange men to lunch? No.
But it's not often that a strange man
turns me on.
Or a strange woman.
I didn't mean to imply I was a dyke.
-A dyke?
-Sorry, lesbian.
I like my sex straight.
It's just that I go for months without
meeting anybody who does it for me.
A lot of people,
like my friend Carol....
I won't gossip,
but a lot of people can sleep around.
Not me. I really have to like the guy.
Otherwise, it's just no go.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't say that
right off the bat.
It's not Women's Lib.
I just get nervous.
When I get nervous,
I tend to babble.
-Do I make you nervous?
-Yes.
-You do, sort of.
-Why?
Because I like you.
You ought to see the Golden Gate.
What's that?
You're kidding.
How'd you decide to come here?
Stick a pin in a map or something?
-The Golden Gate.
-Want to drive across it?
-Oh, is it for motorcars?
R stands for "reverse,"
and D stands for "drive."
The right pedal causes us to accelerate
while the left retards our speed.
Of course. Honestly, Herbert, you act
like you've never been in a car before.
Nonsense, I was in one this morning.
You've a very good driver.
Damn straight. My husband used
to drive in stock car rallies.
He taught me good.
-What are you thinking about?
-A brave new world with such people.
-May I ask you a question?
-Sure.
You mentioned your husband.
My ex. Yeah, I was married
for a while, when I was very young.
We met during an antiwar
demonstration.
-The Second World War.
-What? How old do you think I am?
Oh, I'm sorry. The Third World War?
The Vietnam War.
Vietnam.
It's just that he wanted me to give up
work and have children.
The housewife routine.
Not for me.
He never took my ambitions seriously.
What about you? You married?
I wouldn't be here if I were.
Well, that's nice.
A lot of guys....
It's no big deal.
I like that.
I'm also divorced,
for similar reasons.
-She wanted you to be a housewife?
-She wanted me to be routine.
Well, that is one thing
you definitely are not.
First I thought it was your voice
or your clothes.
Now, I don't know.
Maybe it's that "little boy lost"
quality you give off.
-Brings out my maternal instincts.
-You're very perceptive.
Lost is what I am.
No.
Herbert.
It's only a movie.
I hate all that violence.
Did you ever see Red Shoes?
I really got off on that.
Careers.
Do you have plans for tonight?
I haven't made any.
-Are you tired of me yet?
-No, not in the least.
Great.
How about I cook you dinner?
I don't live very far from here.
-It's not too much trouble?
-I'm half Italian. I love to cook.
-What about the other half?
-Norwegian. Norwegians love to eat.
What on earth is that?
Isn't it incredible? They built it
for the Pan-American Expo of 1914.
Somehow, it's still standing.
I love living next to it.
Come on, I'll give you the cook's tour.
I bet you don't have anything
like this in London.
-You've never seen the Albert Hall.
-I've never even been to London.
-Where do you live?
-This way.
You should see it
when they turn the lights on.
-Is it marble?
-Would you believe plaster?
What on earth is Cosmopolitan?
Where are all your books?
I don't have all that many.
I don't seem to read much anymore.
Even when I have the time,
it's easier to watch TV...
...even though that's mainly crap.
What's that?
The phone.
Ted's idea.
Hello? Oh, hi.
It's my friend Carol, from the bank,
checking up on you.
Yeah.
No.
Who knows?
Carol, I'm trying, so will you please
let me get on with it?
I have to go now. Bye.
Carol says hi.
She asked if London
is really crawling with Arabs.
-Arabs?
-She wants to marry into oil.
This is almost ready.
I'm going to change.
I've been in my work clothes all day.
Please, you go right ahead.
You look very beautiful.
Herbert, if you don't take me
into your arms this minute...
...I'll scream.
Well, hello there.
Hello.
Why, Miss Jones, you're gorgeous.
-What?
-You don't close your eyes.
Well, neither do you.
These are the funniest buttons
I ever saw.
It's like it was some kind of costume.
Oh, my gosh.
Is the rest of this outfit
as interesting?
Amy. Amy.
I don't want to compromise you.
Are you certain I'm not
forcing you--?
Forcing me? My God, Herbert,
I'm practically raping you.
Yeah, that's true.
Here.
All naked, all right here.
The hottest, wildest, sexiest ladies
in San Francisco.
Come on and check it out.
This is the one.
This is where it's happening.
Come on in, buddy.
If you're old enough,
you're bold enough.
Come here, come here.
Let me show you.
Third largest in the West.
The weather should be sunny.
It's a nippy 51 degrees,
going up to 68...
...then dropping to
an overnight low of43.
Good morning.
-You want some coffee?
-Thank you.
--walked into city hall
and shot Mayor Margolin.
In local news, the second body
in 14 hours was found in North Beach.
Identified as prostitute Cindy Chow...
...the mutilated corpse was found in an
alley behind the City Lights Bookstore.
Police had no comment
on the two murders...
...stating only
that they were similar.
According to the police chief,
there are no leads.
In other news--
No.
Coffee's ready.
How do you take it?
Is milk okay instead of cream?
I have to talk to you.
-I'm running late.
-Amy, I have to talk to you now.
He's alive and out there.
I have no idea what to do.
You say you're after this man.
Are you a detective?
You work for Scotland Yard?
Let's just say their interests
are definitely involved.
I don't understand. Why can't
you just go to the police...
...tell them who they're looking for?
-What's wrong with that?
-They'd never believe me.
-You don't know that
-They'd never--
If you knew the story,
you'd never believe me.
-I'd believe you.
-Well, they wouldn't.
If I told the truth, they'd send
me to a lunatic asylum, not him.
All right. I led you to him, didn't l?
What were you doing,
visiting bank after bank?
Would you have slept with anyone
who knew where he was?
You don't suppose that for one minute.
No. I guess I don't.
I don't know, this is very confusing.
I'm late on top of everything else.
-Today is the executive staff meeting.
-Sorry.
I didn't want to burden you.
I'll get dressed and go.
No, no, no.
Oh, please, you stay.
I don't know what to say.
I like you. I like you very much.
I'd like to see you again.
I don't know how to help you,
if you can't go to the police.
-I don't know where you're staying.
-Yesterday was my first day.
Will you stay here for a while? Eat
something and try to sort things out.
I'll call you if I get
any bright ideas, okay?
Be sure and slam the door
when you leave or it doesn't lock.
One thing I wouldn't have
pegged you as, a detective.
Well, you look like the cat
that ate the canary. Did you?
-Hi, Carol, how's everything?
-"Hi, Carol, how's everything?"
You're the one who took off
the whole afternoon.
In one word, fabulous. He's....
I just can't describe it.
On second thought, please don't try.
I may just die of envy.
I want you to meet him. Could you come
for dinner Friday, around 7?
I'm sure it will be fine with Herbert.
Herbert?
You must really be hooked.
I think so. I'll just check my busy
social calendar. Talk to you later.
Hello again.
I've come to change some
more currency.
Yes, of course.
How much did you want
to exchange this time?
Oh, say 40 guineas.
Forty guineas.
I'm sorry, would you excuse me
for a moment? I'll be right back.
Take your time.
Herbert, Herbert.
Come on, come on.
Herbert, it's me.
-Listen, he's here.
-Amy?
-Who is?
-Who do you mean who? Who do you think?
What?
He's right at my desk
with a money belt.
He wants to change more sovereigns.
-Herbert, what do I do? I'm terrified.
-Amy, be calm. It's all right.
You're in a bank.
He's mad but he's not stupid.
Now, nothing's going to happen to you.
-Can you keep him there?
-What?
It's a lot to ask, but try.
Just until I'm there. I'm on my way.
-I'll try.
-What did you say?
I said I'll try.
Sorry about that. I checked
what the exchange rates are today.
They fluctuate every day.
I wouldn't want you to get gypped.
-Are you enjoying San Francisco?
-Very much.
That's wonderful.
-Find room at the Hyatt Regency?
-Yes, thanks to you I've--
Thanks to you.
You wouldn't happen to know
a man called Wells, would you?
I thought so.
Miss Amy Robbins.
He asked you to detain me
until he got here, right?
-I don't know what you mean.
-Oh.
I won't conduct my business here
anymore, if it's all the same to you.
Good day.
There's just one other item.
Be good enough to leave a message
for Wells from me.
Tell him I want that key.
Tell him to leave it for me at the
exhibit. Leave it...
...or face the consequences.
Have you got that?
Yes, I believe you have.
Herbert! You gotta bring the police
into this. Now if you don't, I will.
That man is crazy,
I could see it in his face.
And he threatened you.
Something about leaving
the key to the exhibit.
Let's tell the police. If you don't,
I will, but I don't know what to say.
You can't fool around
with a person like that.
"Robbins. 2340 Francisco."
His name is John Leslie Stevenson.
English, he's a surgeon.
Approximately 37 years of age,
flaxen-hair, clean-shaven...
...and stands well above
6 feet in height.
What makes you say that this,
Dr. Stevenson...
...is responsible for the death
of the girls?
I just know for a fact he is.
-I see. Do you have spiritual powers?
-Do I what?
Are you a medium or a mystic?
I make no claim to supernatural
gifts of any sort.
If I could reveal the source
of my information, I....
As a matter of fact,
I'm also a detective.
I was sent from London on the trail
of Stevenson, traveling incognito.
My name....
-My name is Sherlock Holmes
-Sherlock Holmes, I see.
Go on, go on.
I can't. I gave you a complete
description, I told you his name.
I've told you everything I know.
It was good of you to share
your insights, Mr. Holmes.
How can we reach you if we need
to speak to you?
Is that necessary?
I'm staying with a friend.
Must we involve her?
Not unless it's unavoidable we contact
you. We're known for our discretion.
Very well.
Her name is Miss Amy Robbins.
She lives at 2340 Francisco.
Thank you for your time, Mr. Holmes.
You don't believe me, do you?
I'd like to. My job would
be simpler if I could.
This printout says U.S. Customs
has no record...
...of John Leslie Stevenson coming
here. British Customs has no record...
...of a man by that name leaving.
There's no mention of a Mr. Holmes...
...coming into the country. Now he
could be using another name...
...but since we don't know where he
is, we can't question him.
-Can we?
-No.
Well, thank you for your time.
Good day.
Put this on file.
The entire affair was a fiasco.
-He didn't believe a word of it.
-Well, you tried.
Trying isn't enough, I'm afraid.
-Are we in or out here?
-Out.
-Would you care to join me for a walk?
-Sure.
You have to slam it. All right.
Old buildings have their
little quirks.
Why is it your responsibility?
I'm going to tell you the truth.
In the first place,
my name isn't Herbert Wells.
It's Herbert George Wells.
H.G. Wells.
In the second place,
I'm 113 years old.
I swear to God, I am telling
you the truth.
Please, please believe me.
-Where are you going?
-Home.
You don't believe me?
Christ, Herbert, what do you think?
Please go away, I don't want
to see you anymore.
Amy!
Please, Amy, listen to me!
I have listened to you. And a bigger
crock of shit I never heard.
Look, I don't know if you're crazy,
but I don't care.
Just go back to whatever hole
you crawled out of.
Go back to your machine.
Amy....
Wait! Amy!
Amy, what if I can prove
what I told you is true?
Won't you give me that chance?
I know I sound mad!
I knew how you'd respond. Didn't I say
yesterday you wouldn't believe me?
And I said I would.
All right. There is an H.G. Wells
exhibit with time machine.
There is some resemblance between
you and the man in those pictures.
The museum is closing.
But that doesn't prove anything.
-Now what?
-I want you to go to the powder room.
Hang on.
-Hello.
-Hi! Holy shit! Flowers.
Wow. Let me go put these
in water. Come on in.
-You're early.
-I couldn't wait.
You're cute. Last time I had flowers
was my graduation in high school.
You bring flowers to all your women?
Why don't you sit down
and I'll be right in, okay?
You want some grass?
Grass?
Marijuana. Don't they call it grass
where you're from?
England, right? I could tell
from your accent.
You're observant.
Are you a typical American woman?
Am I a typical American woman?
Me?
Yeah, more or less. You know.
I like to hang out.
And what about you?
-Are you a typical Englishman?
-Not really.
Neat watch.
Are we going somewhere?
No.
Well, what time is it?
Later than you think.
This is really dumb.
What's this gizmo?
Well, let's just say we wouldn't
want to go anywhere without it.
Right. This time I'll drive.
Come on. Get in.
You know what you're doing? What am I
saying? This is completely bananas.
I don't propose to take you a great
distance. Suppose we go to Saturday.
-How would that be?
-Just fine. My cleaning's due back.
That would make it November the 10th.
Don't expect too much. The entire
voyage will last a quarter of a second.
-You ready?
-Come on.
Good. Can we go now, please?
-You still maintain this is poppycock?
-That wasn't the word I had in mind.
Amy, you just wait. You wait.
We've got to go back.
We must go back.
We could easily avoid
this whole thing.
-You mean give him the key.
-No.
I mean come back with me.
-Back?
-Yes. Back to 1893.
I'm a 20th century woman. I have
a career and a mind of my own.
Be reasonable. How am I gonna
make it in 1893?
It's your life we're talking about.
My work is my life.
As much as yours or any other man's.
Please don't start sounding
like my husband.
-Wait a minute? What about forward?
-Forward?
You mean into the future. Yes!
Of course--
No.
No. We're forgetting something.Him!
I can't just leave him here.
So much for your place or mine.
Stop a bit.
You know we're making a big mistake.
We keep imagining time is our enemy.
It's not.
We know what's supposed to happen.
When and where. He doesn't.
This is one time I do know
how he thinks.
I even know before he thinks.
Look here. We're too late to prevent
the murder of number three.
But what about number four?
Let's see.
Dolores Marks. She was killed
in McLaren Park. Is that far?
Nothing's far in San Francisco.
She was killed. Or rather she will
be killed...
in McLaren Park.
All I have to do is surprise him.
I'll just sit tight here for a few
hours and then be off.
We. I'm coming too.
No. I absolutely forbid it.
Herbert, you can't drive.
You don't even know where the park is.
I'm safe. I've got till Friday
Too bad there aren't any
sport stores open.
Whatever for?
So we could buy a gun.
-He's dangerous, haven't you heard?
-I wouldn't purchase a weapon now.
What is this Victorian chivalry?
We're playing for keeps.
Exactly. And Stevenson was right
about one thing.
Violence is contagious. Like measles.
The problem is not that things aren't
more efficient. They're the same.
World war this. World war that.
We're obviously killing more
efficiently. But we're still killing.
Well, I'm not going to stoop
to that man's barbaric level.
The first man to raise a fist
is the man who has run out of ideas.
I love you.
Oh, no.
What's happening?
Goddamn it! The tire is flat.
-Can you mend it? Can it be repaired?
-Yes. It's gonna take time.
All right, Amy. Calm down.
You work as fast as you can
and I'll go telephone the police.
Where would I be likely to find one?
I don't know. There are phone booths
all around. Do you have a dime?
Herbert, do you have ten cents
for the call? Hurry!
-Here. It's 911.
-911.
-Read the instructions.
-I'll be right back.
Out of order? Damn!
911.
Did you get that? McLaren Park.
Get there as soon as possible.
Can I what? Wells. No, Holmes.
Sherlock Holmes.
McLaren Park, as soon as possible.
-Are you all right?
-Yeah, I think so.
Oh, no. No.
Keep moving.
Don't stop, do you hear me?
-Oh, my God.
-Come on, Amy. Go! Come on!
I don't wanna die.
First the zodiac and now this.
-Yeah, they're out for blood, I see.
-I see Mr. Holmes called.
-What time would that be?
Maybe he is psychic.
No.
We won't be here.
It's simple, we just won't be here.
Just for a little bit. I'll come back,
Where are you going?
It's something I've got to do.
And you do trust me, don't you?
I tell you what. What's the best
hotel in the city, your favorite?
The Huntington. I used to work there.
The Huntington. Write down
the telephone number.
If I'm not back in an hour, register
at the hotel. You've got the car.
-Promise you'll be back. Promise me.
-I promise. I promise.
Now you try and get some rest.
There's brandy in the flask
if you need it.
That's all right, I have some Valium.
-Sedatives.
-All right. Try and get some rest.
Hold it right there.
-What is the meaning of this?
-Shut up.
Amy!
-Look here.
-Listen, constable--
-Amy! Amy, get out of the house!
-Come on!
-Just get Lieutenant Mitchell--
-Look ahead.
-You're gonna have another murder.
-State your name, please.
I told you. Herbert George Wells.
What is this?
-Your valuables.
-Preposterous. Now please hurry.
-There is a lady in grave danger.
-Your watch, please.
My watch? This is ridiculous.
Please, where is Lieutenant Mitchell?
-You don't need that.
-Yes, we do.
Miss Amy Robbins is in very great--
Why do you need my glasses?
-I demand to see Lieutenant Mitchell!
-Relax.
I'm sorry, we have no one by the name
Amy Robbins registered at the hotel.
You've absolutely no right....
-Let me see Lieutenant Mitchell.
-No.
Now! Soon! Hurry! Please! Help!
I've told you. I've told you 50 times.
My name is H.G. Wells.
I came here in a time machine.
I'm pursuing Jack the Ripper...
...who escaped into the future.
If you don't do something,
What about the gun? They weren't
making that model back in 1893.
I purchased it to defend Miss Robbins
should the worst come to the worst.
-Where did you purchase it?
-A pawn shop. I don't remember it.
You're wasting your time.
Please listen to me.
Forget about the shop and the time
machine. Forget that I'm H.G. Wells.
Please just save the girl.
You'll have to do better than that.
Last time you were Sherlock Holmes.
-All right, let's take it from the top.
-My name is H.G. Wells.
I came here in a time machine.
The one at the museum.
-Just tell me what you want.
-I want the truth!
We're gonna stay here until I get it.
Take a look at this.
That's right. That's it.
Take a look.
Look, you cretinous idiot.
This is tomorrow's bloody paper.
You see what will happen
if you don't listen to me!
Mr. Wells, or whatever
your real name is...
...you know that novelty shops will
run a phony newspaper edition.
You may have been born yesterday, but
I wasn't. Where did you get the gun?
Herbert.
Herbert?
You want to break for dinner? Hey!
I'll strike a bargain.
I'll confess to anything you like!
I killed them all.
Now, please....
Please send a car to 2340 Francisco.
Send a car and I'll sign
whatever you want.
You're free to go.
I'm sorry.
Please believe me. I'm truly sorry.
Herbert.
Herbert, I'm over here.
He murdered Carol, my friend. I forgot
I invited her over to meet you.
-Amy?
-He's got the car.
Amy?
-The newspaper was wrong.
-Amy.
Not so fast.
We have a little unfinished business.
-What more do you want?
-You know what I want. Give me the key.
And you get the white queen.
All right.
-Let her go and I'll throw it to you.
-No.
My mother was atrocious, but she
didn't raise mentally deficient sons.
You throw me the key
and I'll release the girl.
-On your honor.
-You have my word as a gentleman.
Now there's just one thing.
I would've expected that you'd noticed
I am not a gentleman.
-Say goodbye.
-Goodbye, Herbert.
You know where we're going.
You haven't instructed him in the use
of one of these machines?
Go faster. Please.
Go faster.
If I go any faster I'm gonna wrap
us around a phone pole.
-Herbert!
-Stevenson!
Stevenson!
What is it, H.G. ? You're becoming
extremely tiresome.
-The girl.
-Which girl? You mean this one?
Let her go. Please, I beg you.
You can afford to be magnanimous.
Women throughout the centuries
are yours for the taking.
Is it so important?
I don't find her attractive. Do you?
You're not about to disagree?
No.
-No, what?
-No, I don't find her attractive.
-Shall I cut her throat then?
-No. Please.
John. You and I, we were friends once.
I admired you.
What are you babbling about, Wells?
You've become quite an old fool.
Yes. I am an old fool.
I know nothing.
And she means that much to you?
Yes.
Please.
I'm sorry.
H.G. , it's checkmate
and you've lost again.
Herbert!
What did you do?
I sent him to where he belongs.
Infinity.
That's the last anyone will hear
of Jack the Ripper.
It's time for us to say goodbye
before the police arrive.
You going back?
-Why?
-I've got to dismantle that machine.
Until we master ourselves we have
no proper use for time.
I've got those books to write.
Whatever they are.
Fiction, I hope.
Every age is the same.
It's only love that makes
any of them bearable.
And finally, I must go back because
that is where I belong.
And my life is almost as important
to me as yours.
Not quite.
Almost.
Herbert! You wait for me!
You wait for me!
Herbert!
It isn't life without you.
Please, look at me.
Don't expect miracles. I'm changing
my name to Susan B. Anthony.
Let's go.