SiliconChip
[ boy ]
all right, give me room.
Here we go.
- what's this game called ?
- this is lightcycle.
Damn !
[ master control program ]
you're getting brutal, sark.
Brutal
and needlessly sadistic.
Thank you,
master control.
We've kidnapped
some military programs.
I can arrange more
lethal matches.
Interested ?
Sure.
I'd love to go up against
one of those guys.
It'd make a nice break from
those accounting cream puffs
you keep sending me.
What branch
of the service ?
Strategic air command.
Nice !
Hey, look.
This is all a mistake.
I'm just a compound
interest program.
I work at a savings and loan.
I can't play these video games.
Sure you can, pal.
You look like a natural athlete
if I ever saw one.
Who, me ?
Are you kidding ?
I went out to check
on t-bill rates,
I ran out of breath.
Hey, look.  You guys
are gonna make my user,
mr. Henderson, very angry.
He's a full
branch manager.
Great.
Another religious nut !
I'd say, "welcome, friend,"
but not here, not like this.
I don't even know
what I'm doing here.
Do you believe
in the users ?
Yeah, sure.
If I don't have a user,
then who wrote me ?
That's what
you're doing here.
Master control program's
been snapping up all us
programs who believe.
If he thinks you're useful,
he takes over all your
functions so he gets bigger.
If he can't use you, he sends
you down here to the game grid
get your bits blasted.
What's your name ?
Crom.
I'm ram.
They'll train you
for the games, but...
[ whistles ]
I hope you make it.
Hey, what's been going on
in the other sectors ?
I've been stuck here
for 200 microcycles.
It's murder
out there.
You can't even travel around
in your own microcircuits...
Without permission from
master control program.
I mean, sending me
down here to play games.
Who does he calculate
he is ?
[ flynn ]
okay, clu,
Tonight we check everything
in the right-hand column.
Come on.  Come on.
Where are you ?
There you are.  Clu ?
Yes, sir.
We don't have much time
to find that file.
This is top priority.
I know, sir.
This isn't correcting
my bank statement...
Or phone bill problem--
this is a must.
I understand.
Now, I wrote you.
Yes, sir.
I taught you everything
about the system.
Thank you, but--
no buts.
That's for users.
You're the best program
that's ever been written.
You're dogged and relentless,
remember ?
Let me at 'em.
That's the spirit.
Keep that tank rolling.
I'll try to cover you
from this end.  Go !
You think we can merge
with this memory, bit ?
Yes.
Hmm.
Now flynn is saying
to look over in here,
But I don't see
what we're looking for.
Come on, you scuzzy data,
be in there.  Come on.
Uh-oh !
We've got company.
I don't believe this.
A recognizer.
There's too many !
What is this ?
Aahh !
Damn it !
- get out of here !
- yes-yes-yes.
Busted again !
God, and that was
my best program.
Got a pirate program here.
Says his name's clu.
[ master control program ]
what did he pull ?
He came into the system
with a stolen password.
We caught him trying to
raid our high-clearance memory.
No !  I must've gotten
in there by mistake.
- [ mcp ]
who programmed you ?
- I was simp--
Aah !
[ mcp ]
you're in trouble, program.
Make it easy on yourself.
Who's your user ?
Forget it,
mr. High and mighty
master control.
You aren't
making me talk.
Suit yourself.
Aah !
[ mcp ]
get me dillinger.
[ helicopter whirring ]
Good evening,
mr. Dillinger.
Thank you, peter.
You can go now.
Yes, sir.
[ master control speaks ]
No problem, master c.
If you've seen one
consumer electronics show,
you've seen them all.
What's up ?
Flynn ?
Yes.
He's still looking
for that old file.
Can't you just appropriate it ?
I have.
I put it in my memory,
which he hasn't located.
But he might find it.
I'm afraid so.
I spotted him this time
and kept him out,
But he's getting trickier
all the time.
I think we should
shut down all access...
Until we find that flynn,
just to be safe.
There's a 68.71% chance
you're right.
Cute.
Come on !
Hey, alan.
You think I could have
some of your popcorn ?
Yeah, sure.
- sit down.
- thank you.
[ clears throat ]
We've had to shut down
all group-7 personnel.
Just briefly.
Security.
Someone with that access
has been tampering.
I hope you don't
think it's me.
I don't even balance
my checkbook on downtime.
- I have an abacus
at home for that.
- I'm sure you understand.
It'll only be a couple of days.
What's the project
you're working on ?
It's called tron.
It's a security program
itself, actually.
It monitors all contacts
between our system
and other systems.
Finds anything going on
that's not scheduled,
it shuts it down.
I sent you a memo
on it.
Part of the
master control program ?
No, it'll run independently
and watchdog the mcp as well.
Sounds good.
We should have you running
in a couple of days.  I hope.
Okay.
Thanks.
Oh, boy.
[ mcp ]  mr. Dillinger,
I'm so very disappointed in you.
I'm sorry.
I can't afford to have
an independent programmer
monitoring me.
Do you realize
how many outside systems
I've gone into ?
How many programs
I've appropriated ?
Come on !
A couple of days.
Hi, dr. Gibbs.
Well, here goes nothing.
Yeah, interesting.
You hear what you just said ?
"here goes nothing."
well, what I meant was--
Actually, what we propose to do
is to change something
into nothing and back again.
You might just as well
have said, "here goes something,
here comes nothing."
Right.  Mm-hmm.
[ dr. Gibbs ]
this is the
big moment.
I know.  This will
narrow your theory that
the scanned u-v beam...
Is superior to
single pulse exposure.
[ woman on p.A. ]
laser activity will
exist in 30 seconds.
Put on your goggles.
Leave the bay.
[ lora ]
let's see if we've
got the green light.
- is the target area shielded ?
- they verified safety.
Twenty seconds.
Looks good.
Let her rip.
This is what we've
been waiting for.
Ten seconds.
- five seconds.
- [ machines whirring ]
Perfect !
[ coworkers clapping ]
Beautiful !
Hi, alan.
You two having fun
disintegrating things ?
Not disintegrating,
digitizing.
A laser dismantles
the molecular structure
of the object,
And molecules remain
suspended in the laser beam.
Then, when the computer
plays out the model,
The molecules fall back
into place, and voilá !
Great.  Can it
send me to hawaii ?
Yeah, but you've got to
purchase your program
30 days in advance.
How's it going upstairs ?
Frustrating.
I had tron almost ready...
When dillinger cut everyone
with group-7 access
out of the system.
Ever since he got
that master control program,
The system's got more bugs
than a bait store.
You gotta expect
some static.
After all, computers
are just machines.
They can't think.
Some programs will
be thinking soon.
[ chuckles ]
won't that be grand ?
Computers and programs
will start thinking,
and the people will stop.
I'm gonna stay around,
put some data through.
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Come on.
Did you say
group-7 access ?
Yeah.
What a hassle.
I was all set.
Did he say why ?
Something about tampering.
Tampering ?
Flynn has been thinking
about breaking into the system
ever since dillinger canned him.
And he had
group-7 access.
Flynn had access
to you too.
[ lora ]  I want to
go to flynn's place.
What for ?
To warn him.
Of what ?
That dillinger's onto him.
I don't see why I have
to do that guy any favors.
I don't know what you
ever saw in that guy,
anyway.
I loved him for his brains.
[ chuckles ]
Don't put any change
in the meter.  We're gonna
need it for the games.
Boy !  I haven't been
here in a long time.
¶ [ music ]
[ chattering ]
[ girl ]
hey, bobby, up here.
Where is he ?
I don't know.
Somewhere in here,
lost in one of his games.
Excuse me.
Do you know
where flynn is ?
Yeah, he's over there
on his machine.
[ boy ]
he's really on a roll !
One more reco before he ties.
Another reco and he gets
the world's record.
[ boy ]
he's going for the record.
The all-time record coming up.
This is it.
It's all over.
Flynn's gonna be
a part of history, all right !
Hey, flynn,
how'd you do it ?
It's all
in the wrists.
999,000 points !
Hey, good
to see you guys.
Nothing classes up the joint
like a clean-cut young couple.
We gotta talk.
You can't hear yourself
think in here.  Come on.
Come on.
I'll be down
in a minute.
How's the world
of serious science ?
Go up ahead.
Make yourselves
at home.
Be right up.
[ chuckles ]
the best programmer
encom ever saw,
And he winds up playing
space cowboy in some back room.
Okay, let me
handle this.
Go right ahead.
Have you been sneaking
into the encom system ?
You never were much
for small talk, were you ?
- she still leave her clothes
all over the floor ?
- no.
- alan !
- I mean, not that often.
You can see why
all his friends
are 14 years old.
Touché.
I have been doing
a little hacking,
as a matter of fact.
- you did break in.
- tried to.
I can't seem to quite
get the connection
with that sucker, though.
If I had
a direct terminal--
Flynn, are you embezzling ?
[ game beeping ]
Embezzling is such
an ugly word, mr. Bradley.
No, actually,
I'm trying to get some
solid evidence together.
- I don't get it.
- okay.
Sherman, set the way-back
machine for three years ago.
Kevin flynn,
One of encom's
brightest young
software engineers.
He's so bright,
he starts going in at night,
Sets up his own private
memory file...
And begins writing
a program for video games,
invented called...
Space paranoids.
You invented
space paranoids ?
Paranoids, matrix blaster,
vice squad--
a whole slew of 'em.
I was this close to starting
my own little enterprise.
But enter another
software engineer;
Not so young, not so bright,
but very, very sneaky;
Ed dillinger.
One night, our boy flynn,
he goes to his terminal,
tries to read up his file.
I get nothing on there.
There's a big blank.
All right, now we take you
three months later,
Dillinger presents encom
with five video games...
That he's invented.
The slime didn't even
change the names, man !
He gets
a big, fat promotion.
Thus begins
his meteoric rise to--
what is he now ?
- executive v.P. ?
- senior exec ?
Senior exec ?
Meanwhile, kids are putting
eight million quarters a week
into paranoid machines.
I don't see a dime, except
what I squeeze outta here.
I still don't understand
why you want to
break into the system.
Because, man, somewhere
in one of these memories
is the evidence.
If I got in far enough
I could reconstruct it.
My password,
dillinger's instructions
to divert the data--
It's too late for that !
Dillinger's cut off everybody
with group-7 access.
Wait.  Wait.
What are you saying ?
The guy knows
what you're up to.
Great.
You're kidding me ?
Well, now there is
nothing to stop him.
It's just dillinger
and the mcp running things
from on high now.
Not if my tron program
was running.  That'd
shut the system down.
You know, if your file
was in there--
Wait a minute.
If we can get in there,
I can forge us
a group-6 access.
Well ?
Shall we dance ?
[ dillinger ]
I shut down group-7
for a very good reason.
Ed, all I'm saying is
if our people can't get
access to their programs--
Well, you know how frustrating
it is when you're working
on a piece of research.
I sympathize,
but I have data coming from
the master control program...
Telling me there's
something screwy going on.
That mcp,
that's half our problem
right there.
The mcp is the most efficient
way of handling what we do !
I can't sit here
and worry about every little
user request that comes in.
User requests are
what computers are for.
Doing our business is
what computers are for !
Encom isn't
the business you started
in your garage anymore.
We're building accounts
in 30 different countries,
new defense systems.
We have one of the most
sophisticated pieces of
equipment in existence.
Oh, I know all that.
Sometimes I wish I were
back in that garage.
That can be arranged, walter.
That was uncalled for.
You can remove men like
alan and me from the system,
but we helped create it.
And our spirit remains in
every program we designed
for this computer.
Walter, it's getting late.
I've got better things to do...
Than to have religious
discussions with you.
Don't worry about encom anymore.
It's out of your hands now.
I don't think
I'm cleared for this.
I'm certainly not.
You wanna move aside ?
Give the kid
a little room.
This guy's a little
like santa claus.
I make these myself.
You want one ?
[ flynn ]
they never should have
gotten rid of me.
Now that is a big door.
Shut up.
It's my fault.
I programmed you
to want too much.
[ mcp ]
I was planning to hit
the pentagon next week.
The pentagon ?
It shouldn't be harder
than any other big company.
But now this is what I get
for using humans.
Wait a minute.
I wrote you !
I've gotten 2,415 times
smarter since then.
What do you want
with the pentagon ?
The same thing I want
with the kremlin.
I'm bored with corporations.
With the information
I can access,
I can run things
900 to 1,200 times
better than any human.
If you think
you're superior to us--
You wouldn't want me
to dig up flynn's file...
And read it up on
a v.D.T. At the times,
would you ?
You wouldn't dare !
Hi.
Hi.  Working late ?
Yeah.
Okay, come here.
I'm gonna put him
at my terminal.
I'm gonna meet you
in your office upstairs.
Don't fall asleep.
If and when I activate
your tron program,
You'll only have a few minutes
to use it before dillinger
catches the break in security.
As long as we
stay off the top floor,
Dillinger will never know
we've been in here.
[ alan ]
good luck, hotshot.
Ahem.
Flynn !
After you.
[ mcp ]
keep those programers
out of the system,
And get me that
chinese language file
I asked for.
End of line.
You are going
to stick with me ?
What for ?
You're the one who never
needed help, remember ?
Come on.
I'm scared of the dark.
All this technology scares me.
This way !
When did they put
this in ?
This is where I work.
I've got a direct terminal
in the laser target area.
You can stay there
all night if you have to.
Like a man says,
"there's no problems,
only solutions."
Okay, remember,
this laser is my life's work.
Don't spill anything.
Huh ?
Have fun, sweetheart.
Hey, it's the big
master control program
everybody's been talking about.
[ mcp ]
sit right there.
Make yourself comfortable.
Remember the time
we used to spend
playing chess together ?
Stop !  Please.
You realize
I can't allow this ?
How are you gonna run
the universe if you can't answer
a few unsolvable problems ?
Come on, big fella,
let's see what you've got.
[ mcp ]
I'd like to go against you
and see what you're made of.
You don't look a thing
like your pictures.
I'm warning you,
you're entering
a big error, flynn.
I'm gonna have to
put you on the game grid.
Games ?
You want games ?
I'll give you games.
Oh, man, this isn't happening.
It only thinks it's happening.
Vacate entry port,
program.
I said, move !
Aah !
Hey !
Look, if this is about
those parking tickets,
I can explain
everything, okay ?
Prepare all programs
for war games.
I've got a little challenge
for you, sark; a new recruit.
It's a tough case,
but but I want him treated
in the usual manner.
Train him
for the games,
Let him hope for a while,
then blow him away.
You got it.
I've been hoping
you'd send me somebody
with a little bit of guts.
What kind
of program is he ?
He's not any kind
of program, sark,
he's a user.
A user ?
That's right.
He pushed me
in the real world.
Somebody pushes me, I push back.
So I brought him down here.
What's the matter, sark ?
You look nervous.
Well, I--
I was just--
I don't know.
A user, I mean--
Users wrote us.
A user even wrote you !
No one user wrote me.
I'm worth millions
of their man-years.
What if I can't ?
You'd rather take
your chances with me ?
Want me to slow down
your power cycles for you ?
Wait !  I need that !
Then pull yourself together.
Get this clown trained.
I want him in the games
until he dies playing.
Acknowledge.
Acknowledged,
master control.
End of line.
Video game unit 18.
In here, program.
Who you calling
program, program ?
New guy ?
Another free program
off-line.
You really think the users
are still there ?
They'd better be.
I don't wanna bust out of here
and find nothing but a lot of
cold circuits waiting for me.
Hey.
Who are you guys ?
Hold it !
You wanna watch
those force fields.
You'll be having plenty
of chances to get hurt.
Don't worry about that.
Look, just so I can
tell my friends...
What this dream is about,
okay, where am I ?
You're a...
Guest of the
master control program.
Oh, great.
They're gonna make you
play video games.
No sweat.
I play video games
better than anybody.
Move out !
This way.
You, you come
this way.
There's been a mistake.
I've gotta see the guy
in charge.
You will.
[ guard yells, indistinct ]
Command program sark's
carrier is approaching.
He will explain
the training procedures.
Greetings.
The master control program
has chosen you...
To serve your system
on the game grid.
Those of you who continue
to profess a belief
in the users...
Will receive the standard
substandard training,
Which will result in
your eventual elimination.
Those of you
who renounce...
This superstitious
and hysterical belief,
Will be eligible
to join the warrior elite...
Of the mcp.
You will each receive
an identity disk.
Everything
you do or learn...
Will be imprinted
on this disk.
If you lose your disk
or fail to follow commands,
You will be subject
to immediate de-resolution.
That will be all.
[ guard ]
move out.
Hey, who's that guy ?
That's tron.
He fights for the users.
Tron ?
[ flynn ]
that's pretty good.
Watch this.
You gotta be good
if you wanna survive.
What's your name ?
My name's ram.
Hey, ram,
What were you,
you know, before ?
I was an actuarial program.
I worked for a big
insurance company.
Really gives you
a great feeling...
Helping folks plan
for their future needs.
Of course, if you think
of the payments as an annuity
over the years,
The cost is really
quite minimal.
Yeah, that's great.
Actuarial program.
Nice.
How about yourself ?
Oh, I don't remember
too much.
Name's flynn.
Sure, a little disorientation,
that's normal in transport.
It'll come back to you.
[ footsteps ]
[ ram ]
this is it.
Good luck, flynn.
Sir, conscript being moved
from pit cell to ring game.
You know--  hey !
You guys sure
are friendly.
Wait.
Let him fight
one of his own kind.
You think you're
gonna wipe me out,
don't you ?
No, I--
Hey !  I--
The new guy
was asking about you.
It's too bad
he's in a match now.
I'll probably
never meet him.
You might.
There's something
different about him.
Okay.
That was
a very fancy shot.
Okay, here's
an easy one.
Finish the game !
- no !
- kill him.
No.
You'll regret this.
Aah !
[ mcp ]
I want him in the games
until he dies playing.
This is the holding area
for the lightcycles.
- hey, flynn, you made it !
- wait here.
- you won !
- alan.
Where did you hear
that name ?
That's your name,
isn't it ?
The name of my user.
How did you know ?
I'm a program from
a user that knows alan.
He was disoriented
in transport, tron.
But I'm remembering
all kinds of stuff,
Like my user wants me
to go after the mcp.
My user wants that too.
I know.
[ computer voice ]
prepare to transport
to lightcycle grid.
We have transport.
Wow.
Blue leader to blue bikes.
Run these guys
into your jet walls.
Copy, blue leader.
[ tron ]
this is gold-1
to gold-2 and 3.
Split up.
Take them one-on-one.
- watch it !
- aah !
Taking him
into the maze.
This is it.
Come on.
Gold-3 to gold-2 and 1.
I'm getting out of here now
and you guys are invited.
[ ram ]
got it.
- ready ?
- ready.
- so long, sucker !
- aah !
Greetings, programs !
Video game warriors
escaping game grid.
This is an illegal exit.
You must return to game grid.
Repeat, this is
an illegal exit.
You must return to the grid.
Gold-2 to gold-3.
Those demons
are coming down.
Get them !
Send out every
game tank in the grid.
Get them !
[ flynn ]
I should never have written
all those tank programs.
Targets leaving
protective field.
Missed !
All units
exiting game arena.
Target units
accelerating !
Pursuit force
minus one tank.
Close ranks.
Oh, man.
On the other side
of the screen,
It all looked
so easy.
They must've gone
right past us.
We made it...
This far.
Pursuit force reporting.
We lost visual contact
with escaped units.
Awaiting further orders.
Get the pursuit forces back
into the canyons.  Those
programs never made it out.
We'll have them back
in no time, sir, long before
the interrupt interface.
We'd better,
null unit.
I'll be lucky if the mcp
doesn't blast me
into a dead zone.
I want those conscripts !
[ flynn ]
what is it ?
What do you see ?
Watch it.
Come on,
you little bugger.
[ ram ]
look at that.
When do we pay our visit
to the old master control ?
What ?
There's just
three of us.
Well, if you know anybody
who's got an army for rent,
that's fine,
But my user told me
to go take that sucker out,
Or I'm never getting
out of here.
We can't get
to the mcp...
Without the help
of my user.
I have to get to
that input/output tower,
And communicate with him.
Well, good.
Check in with alan.
Maybe he knows what's--
What's that ?
That... Is just...
What I need right now.
Oh, it's nice.
Incredible.
[ tron ]
boy, you forget how good
the power feels...
Until you get
to a pure source.
[ laughing ]
My friends,
my fellow conscripts,
we have scored.
I feel so much better.
Pursuit force reporting.
No sign of escaped units.
Moving into next sector.
Thank you.
I can feel it.
Feel what ?
You okay ?
Alan-1.
Let's move out !
Come on, flynn,
put a cork in it.
One second !
Ahhh !
Range, 9.
Mark, 45.
48 degrees.
Hold it.
Hold it.  Fire !
Ram, flynn,
do you read me ?
Pursuit force reporting.
Two escaped units de-rezzed.
No !
Tron unit heading
into next sector.
Ram ?
Ram !
Come on !
We gotta get outta here !
No sign of life.
Looks like we got 'em.
Continue pursuit of
remaining conscript.
Acknowledged.  Proceeding
towards sector frontier.
We're gonna make it, ram.
I just gotta find you
a place to rest.
Hang in there, ram.
This looks like a good spot.
Those tanks
won't find us here.
Okay.
I thought this was
supposed to be easy.
[ groans ]
[ beeping ]
Hey, what's going on ?
You see this ?
You shouldn't
be able to do that.
Now for some
real user power.
Hey, this looks promising.
This is just like
the old arcade grips.
Let's get this
show on the road.
Now we're smokin' !
How can you steal
a recognizer ?
Hey, you okay ?
You don't look so good.
We'll get you fixed up.
Hang on.
Come here.
Oh, my user !
Users are users.
They--
Are you a user ?
Flynn,
Help tron.
Ram !
Ram ?
Damn recognizer.
Thing just goes straight.
I gotta get to
that I/o tower.
Program alu, request
additional information
for sector two.
Prepare hangar for
game simulation transport.
Attention all units,
lock onto matrix code.
Prepare for
digital beam transport.
Activate hangar doors.
What's the progress
on the simulation ?
30, 56, 99
are correct.
Limited four and eight
are missing.
Don't scream.
Yori !
30, 56, 99
are correct.
Limited four and eight
are missing.
No, I--
Tron !
Oh !
Yori.
I knew you'd escape.
They haven't built a circuit
that could hold you.
Listen !
We have to make plans.
Where can we go ?
This way, quickly.
Hey !
Hold it right there !
Yes ?
What do you
mean, "yes" ?
Yes.
Is that all
you can say ?
No.
Anything else ?
Yes.
Positive and negative, huh ?
You're a bit.
Yes.
Where's your program ?
Isn't he gonna miss you ?
- no.
- I'm your program.
- yes.
- another mouth to feed.
Yes-yes-yes-yes-yes !
Watch out
for nested macros.
Who are these weirdos ?
Inoperative data pushers.
[ tron ]
control programs !
Come on.
Pretty good drivin',
huh ?  Oh !
[ bit ]
no !
Who asked you ?
[ warning siren ]
[ bit ]
no-no-no-no !
Aah !
This baby doesn't
handle so good in town.
No.
What's this do ?
How 'bout this one ?
No.  No.
[ flynn ]
here comes a headache.
Aah !
No-no-no-no !
We gotta stop
this thing !
Yes !
[ flynn ]
I'm glad you agree !
Uh, I'm fine.
No problem.
Oh, this town
is full of live ones.
This is where tron
said he was going.
Losing flynn.
I don't believe this.
Halt !
More guards.
They don't see us.
I'll go first.
Are you all right ?
Yeah.  Let's do
that some more.
I think the guard saw me.
Come on !
Halt.
Dumont.
I can't stand this commotion.
What do you want ?
I've come to communicate
with my user.
Difficult proposition.
Difficult proposition
at best.
Why, I could be de-rezzed
just for letting you in here.
They hate this tower.
They'd close it down
if they dared.
They keep me around
just in case one of them...
Wants to deal
with the other world
once in a while.
Dumont !
My user has information
that could--
Could make this
a free system again.
[ chuckle ]
no, really !
You'd have programs
lined up to use this place,
And no mcp looking
over your shoulder.
When you've been in the system
as long as I have,
You hear many promises,
many reassurances,
Many brave plans.
Please, dumont !
The guards are coming.
There they are
with the guardian.
All right, yori.
All right.
Who is your user, program ?
Alan-1.
He calls me.
May I pass ?
All that is visible...
Must grow beyond itself,
And extend into
the realm of the invisible.
You may pass, my friend.
The tower guardian
is helping him.
He thinks.
Bring in
the logic probe.
[ sark ]
more power !
It's begun.
[ alan ]
tron, location query.
Confirm.
Confirmed, alan-1.
[ alan ]  I am creating
the information on your disk...
That will erase the mcp
and change the system.
Dedicate yourself to getting
the disk into the heart...
Of the mcp.
This interface is
located at its base.
We will not be able
to communicate again
unless you succeed.
Go !
This is the key
to a new order.
This code disk
means freedom.
I think they're
breaking in.
Thank you, dumont.
Hurry !  The users
are waiting.
[ sark ]
dumont ?
Where's the program ?
What program ?
Take him !
Stay close.
If I can just get us
on the scanning transport beam,
This solar sail simulation
will take us across
the game sea,
Out of this domain,
back into the central computer.
Look out !
Aah !
Commander, you've enjoyed
all the power you've been given,
haven't you ?
I wonder how you'd take to
working in a pocket calculator.
We did take care of
that user you sent us.
Incompetent zero.
Now you've got two
renegade programs...
Flying all over the system
in a stolen simulation.
We'll get them.
It's only a matter of time.
You've almost reached
your decision gate,
And I can't spare you
any more time.
End of line.
- it's me-- flynn !
- flynn !
- greetings, program.
- you're alive !
Barely.
Yeah, I, uh--
Where's ram ?
He didn't make it.
Come on.
Lora.
This is flynn.
The one who busted me out.
Lora ?
Well, then I
owe him some thanks.
No, it's, uh,
no big deal.
I ought to know my way
around the lightcycle.
I wrote the program.
You wrote the program ?
It's time
I level with you.
- I'm what you guys
call a user.
- you're a user ?
I took a wrong turn
somewhere.
If you are a user,
Everything you've done
has been according
to a plan, right ?
[ laughs ]
you wish.
You guys know
what it's like.
You keep doing what it looks
like you're supposed to,
no matter how crazy it seems.
That's the way it is
for programs, yes.
Hate to disappoint you, pal,
but most of the time, that's
the way it is for users too.
Stranger
and stranger.
So, nice-looking ship
you got here.
What do you want done with
the tower guardian-- dumont ?
Put him with
the others ?
No, bit brain, prepare
him for inquisition.
I need a little bit
of relaxation.
First, rezz up
the carrier for pursuit.
One other thing.
Don't think anymore.
I do the thinking
around here.
[ yori ]
this isn't going to be easy.
If those grid bugs get us,
we've had it.
Had enough ?
What do you want ?
I'm busy.
Busy dying, you worn out
excuse for an old program.
Yes, I'm old.
Old enough to remember the mcp
when it was a chess program.
He started small,
and he'll end small.
Very funny, dumont.
Maybe I should keep you around
just to make me laugh.
What's happening ?
Power surge in the mcp.
- we have to
get off this beam.
- I can't.
There isn't another junction
for seven or eight nanoseconds.
- there's another beam !
- it's too far.
He's creating a junction.
Did we make it ?
Yeah.
Hurray for our side.
Is he de-rezzing ?
No, but I couldn't
tell you why not.
I'm all in one piece.
I guess
I'm still with you.
[ groans ]
tell the guy with
the jackhammer to lay off.
- how'd you do that ?
- elementary physics--
A beam of energy
can always be diverted.
Are we there yet, mommy ?
Sark !
Dumont !
Yori !
Tron ?
Tron's dead.
Who's that ?
That is a user, dumont.
He came here to help us.
Tron believed in him.
If the users can no longer
help us, we're lost.
So, we have erased
that program--
No.
- you were de-rezzed.
- not me, sark.
There's nothing
special about you.
You're just an ordinary program.
So are you, one that
should have been erased.
You're nothing.
Take that program
to the holding pit.
Please, don't take--
I'm taking
our friend here...
And some other religious
fanatics to master control.
When I disembark,
This ship and everything
that remains on board...
Will automatically de-rezz.
This means you.
Move on !
Immediate vectors
detached.
Route us
to the mcp.
I want to get rid
of this dead weight,
And catch a transport beam
to the game domain.
These walls--
yori, something's happening.
Hey.
You all right ?
I still have power.
Sark doesn't know that.
Leave me alone.
We've failed.
We're only gonna fail
if we give up !
Come on, look, the wall !
Yori.
You brought me back.
How ?  Why did
you bring me back ?
I need your help.
Come on !
Do something with
these controls !
I'm on it.
The mcp, it's the heart
of the whole system.
I feel a presence.
Another warrior is on the mesa.
[ tron ]
sark !
We're getting closer.
I don't know
how you survived.
Slave,
it doesn't matter.
Prepare to terminate.
All programs have
a desire to be useful.
But in moments, you will
no longer seek communication...
With each other or
your superfluous users.
You will each be part of me.
Together, we will be complete.
You should have joined me.
We'd have made a great team.
- you're very persistent.
- I'm also better than you.
[ mcp ]
sark ?
All my functions are
now yours.  Take them.
Sark ?
Look at that !
Your user can't
help you now,
my little program.
I got it.
Steer us over by the beam.
Right next to it.
What good will that do ?
I'm gonna jump.
It's the only way
to help tron.
Don't.
You'll be de-rezzed.
Don't worry.
Come on, let's go !
We did it !
That's nice.
We thought you
were dead.
Where's flynn ?
It was incredible.
He threw himself into the beam
and distracted the mcp...
Just long enough for you
to get the disk in.
He saved us.
He really did it.
Video warriors,
look at the I/o towers.
Every tower
is lighting up.
Priority one !
[ laughing ]
Try to look official.
Here comes the boss.
Pick me up in an hour.
Thanks.
Greetings,
programs.
SiliconChip