...:::: SiliconChip ::::...
Under The Skin [2013]
T- D-
s- z- Th-
B- T- V-
H- T- D- K- G-
s- z- P- B-
Ba-Ba- T- T-
K- K uh- Ch-
Th- V- Th-
Zzz- Sss- Bzz- Ch-
B-B-Buh- V-V-Vuh-
G-G-Guh- D-D-Duh-
B-B-Buh- B-B-Buh-
B-B-Beh- B-B-Beh- Bah-
N-N-Nuh- N-N-Nuh-
N-N-Nuh- No.
N-N-Nuh- N-N-Nuh- N-N-Nuh- No.
N-N-Nuh-
F- Feel- Field-
Fill- Filled- Filts-
Foil- Failed- Fell-
Felds- Pill- Pills-
Pall- Nall-
Foal- Foals-
Fold- Fold-
Pool-
Sell- Se-
I'm looking for the M8.
Eh-
Aye, you've gotta go
straight along that way and-
This is gonna be pure hard to explain.
- Do you know where the Asda is?
- No.
Yeah, I don't even know
what way you're pointin'. What?
- See, if you just drive straight along up there-
- Yes?
And see the traffic lights up there?
Take a right.
Then you'll go past lbrox Stadium, right?
And go straight through a roundabout.
Then take a left.
So it's right, then just-
And it's there. The motorway is there.
It's back of Asda. You'll see it.
- Back of Asda, see?
- Okay.
- Am I keeping you from something?
- No.
- Where are you going?
- Along here.
- For what? For work?
- No, I need to go meet somebody.
- Oh, you're going to meet someone.
- Aye.
- All right. Thank you.
- Sure.
I'm looking for a post office.
- Post office?
- Yes.
Where are you from?
- Where I am from?
- Yeah.
- Albania.
- Oh, are you?
- You have family here?
- Yes.
Oh, you do.
That's the reason I'm saying
you have to go another way...
for another-
it's after the shopping ce-
- Hi.
- Lost?
- Yeah, lost.
- What are you looking for?
- I'm looking for the M8.
- Up to the roundabout-
- Are you walking?
- Yep.
- Where are you walking to?
- Home.
- Oh, you're going home. To your family?
- No, no, just myself.
- Just yourself?
- Aye. it's great.
- Yeah? How?
- I can do whatever I like.
- So where are you coming from?
- Govan. Right there.
- Sorry?
- Govan.
- Govan? Do you work there?
- No, no.
Don't work there. I work for myself.
- Do you want a lift?
- Eh- Aye, why not?
You'll have to tell me how to get there.
- Just follow this road straight up.
- Okay.
Sure.
- So what do you do?
- Electrician.
Oh, you're an electrician.
- It's cold, right?
- Ah, it's a wee bit nippy, aye.
Yeah.
So what is it youse all doing?
I'm- I'm just, uh, driving-
just, uh... some furniture
for my family and-
- Oh, right?
- Yeah.
So you live alone?
- Yes.
- And you love it?
- Aye. it's great.
- What do you love about living alone?
- Nobody to nag you.
- Do I go straight through?
Yeah, just straight through.
Straight through the whole way.
It should be just cart around that street
and stay in the right hand lane.
- What's that?
- That's a tattoo of my name.
- Of your name?
- Yeah.
- What's your name?
- Andy.
- Andy. Hi.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
- Thank you very much.
Andy!
- Want me?
- You coming?
The spot back here, you get-
you put your hand out. Anybody can stop.
There's lonely old guys. Know what I mean?
It was- Hey, might as well check her out,
driving away in a big van.
Sure you can drive this, huh? Huh?
- No girlfriend? Really?
- Nah, I don't have a girlfriend at all.
You're very charming.
That's better.
Yeah? Sorted?
- You have a handsome face.
- Aye?
- Yeah.
- Thanks a lot. Cheers.
- Do you think I'm pretty?
- I think you're gorgeous.
- Do you?
- Aye, definitely.
Good.
And a friendly smile as well.
- Do I?
- Aye, right deep.
- What about your smile?
- Aye.
You've a nice smile yourself.
- Cheers.
- Good.
Good.
No, no, no, lads! No!
- Mommy!
- Whoo!
I thought...
you had your eye on my towel.
No. I wanted to speak to you.
Do you know if there's any good spots
to surf around here?
I'm not a surfer.
Just living in a little tent over there.
- Just hanging around.
- Yeah?
- Reading, swimming.
- You're not from here? Where are you from?
- I'm from Czech Republic.
- Why are you in Scotland?
I just... wanted to get away from it all.
Yeah? Why here?
Because it's-
it's nowhere.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa. Excuse me.
Can I talk to you
before you run away, darling?
I wanted to speak to you earlier,
right, but you disappeared.
I thought you went to the ladies'
or somethin'.
Anyway, right, fuck all that shite. Right?
I really want to buy you a drink, man.
You look absolutely stunning.
And I-
You know what?
I'm all alone. You're all alone.
What do you say? What's one drink?
What's one drink?
- I saw you on the road.
- What, you saw me on the road?
- Earlier, yeah.
- Are you having a laugh with me?
You saw me?
You wanna come get a drink and a dance?
- Are you alone here?
- Yeah, I'm all alone. Right?
The man from the car,
he buy the rose for you.
A man's body has been found
washed up on a beach...
near Arbroath.
His wife and child are reported missing.
The police say the body
has been identified...
as 36-year-old Kenneth McClellan
from Edinburgh.
The body was found by a tourist...
and is believed to have been
in the water for some time.
Mr. McClellan was married and worked as
a chemistry lecturer at Edinburgh University.
The alarm was raised when he failed
to turn up for work this morning.
His car was found
at the nearby Deer Park Golf Club.
His wife, 32-year-old Alison McClellan,
and 18-month-old son...
are believed to have been with him.
A police and coast guard search operation
involving a helicopter...
has been halted due to fog.
The next bulletin is on the hour.
Well, plenty to talk about,
as ever, with Kay.
You can call now- 10-500-92-95-00.
You can text as well- 80295.
- It's 8:17.
- Good morning, Gary.
Well, as we've heard,
for a whole host of reasons...
2014 is a very important year
for Scotland.
Of course, the referendum.
We're expecting that date today.
But the Commonwealth Games
and Ryder Cup-
- You seem very excited about that.
- lam.
He's jumping out of his seat at
the prospect of the year he's gonna have-
Fuckin' hell, you're gorgeous.
- You think so?
- It's your eyes.
Somethin' about your eyes.
Your eyes, your lips.
- That black hair.
- Yeah?
You just look...
amazing.
Hey, you okay?
Want a hand up? Want a hand?
Get out, eh? Get out!
Excuse me.
Uh, I'm a bit lost, really.
Am I headed towards Taynuilt?
Yeah.
I am? Is it far?
It's about 10 minutes away.
Ten minutes?
Are you- Are you headed there?
I'm going to the supermarket.
Is it on the way?
Yeah.
I could drop you off if you'd like.
Yeah?
Here. Let me turn this up for you.
That's better.
You're very quiet.
So why do you shop at night then?
People wind me up.
How?
They're ignorant.
What about your friends?
So you don't have any friends?
No.
How about a girlfriend?
How old are you?
I'm 26.
When was the last time
you had a girlfriend?
Never had one.
So don't you get lonely then?
You've very nice hands.
You've beautiful hands.
Do you want to look at me?
- This isn't Tesco's, is it?
- No.
I noticed you looking at me before.
And?
I liked it.
You're uncomfortable.
No. Just want to go to Tesco's.
So you never think about it then?
Think about what?
Being with a girl.
When was the last time
you touched someone?
Let me see your hands.
Cold.
I have to get back soon.
How was that?
Cold.
Do you want to do it again?
Yeah.
Do you want to touch my neck?
Here.
How was that?
Yeah.
Your hands are very soft.
I have a place about 30 minutes away.
Will you come with me there?
Cold.
I won't let that stop us.
Come to me.
Dreaming?
Yes.
Yes, we are.
The bus will be along in a minute.
Do you not think you should
be wearing a jacket, little lass?
The weather's terrible up here.
You'll catch your death of cold if you've
not got a jacket or a hat or something on.
You've not got the right clothes on at all.
You all right there?
Eh?
You okay?
Can I do something for you?
Chase yourself, dafty.
Leave the lassie alone.
She doesn't want anything to do with you.
Do you need any help?
Yes.
Right.
Let me just take your coat.
Spoon, Jar. Jar, spoon.
Spoon, Jar. Jar-
Wonder whether that's working, don't you?
Spoon, Jar. Jar, spoon.
Spoon, Jar.
Stop!
Pull it. Pull it.
Night.
You all right?
If you're frightened, let's go.
Come on.
It's all right.
That's it.
It's okay. it's okay.
It's okay.
All right.
Okay-
You did it.
You all right?
You just off for a ramble
in the woods then? Eh?
- Huh?
- You just off for a ramble in the woods?
Yeah, yeah? Oh, it's, uh-
Watch how you step here. it's a bit, uh-
it's a bit slippery round here,
but- this time of year.
It's all right in summer. Well, it's still wet
in summer, but not as bad as it is now.
But there's plenty of trails around here.
Have you been here before?
No? First time? Yeah?
Oh, you won't get lost.
They're all clearly marked.
But, uh, there's about 2,000 acres
of forest here...
so you shouldn't- you should have,
uh, plenty of places to go in there.
- You on your own?
- Yeah.
Yeah, on your own? Oh, well, it's a nice
place if you want some solitude...
you know, to “gather your thoughts”
and all that, yeah?
- So, uh, enjoy yourself anyway, okay?
- Thank you.